<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E91BFCC838A452D8AD60806059DEBC3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8164 IH: Resilient Defense Assistance Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8164</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220621">June 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to improve the climate resilience of the Armed Forces and certain security forces and facilities operated by allies and partners of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H54186B4C4DBB4D2F9DAB885EB8897305" style="OLC"><section id="H5E2B21750289495EA606BF7CC83FD52C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Resilient Defense Assistance Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H02DED65EE67D4F08A47000231E69426B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Climate resilience assistance and improvements of the Department of Defense</header><subsection id="H6E53C5CF882D475AABD573E2E9F1DB35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion of climate resilience services in certain programs of the Armed Forces</header><paragraph id="H7464705C3E714CEDA77C7C265C564999"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Combatant Commander Initiative Fund</header><text>Section 166a(b) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HD0A7160B336D42FE9CACC7DF6DEDBE7E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HF07B9351EF2C401287B82C59EC2F3235"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Climate resilience of military installations and essential civilian infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6CBE5488F584F54A3126398E335F0DE"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Military support to civilian and military authorities to combat illegal wildlife trafficking, illegal timber trafficking, and illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDD72F56D7374073AC734D16E415B47E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to build capacity of foreign security forces</header><text>Section 333(a) of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EB2A210D0E44CEB9E33349C2295EB4B"><paragraph id="H2B355A4324CA466DBB94BF2F2B2FF821"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities to maintain and improve the climate resilience of military installations and facilities available for use in international coalition operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7908405FB8864F209C3BDD64E4D3D637"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Activities to combat illegal wildlife trafficking, illegal timber trafficking, and illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C0EAB7B660040889CA2CA0699057F44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contributions To improve the climate resilience of certain security forces and facilities of allies and partners of the United States</header><paragraph id="HDDA96E932E13410489930EC0519F3358"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contributions</header><text>Part IV of subtitle A of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H1B88E69FF90E41BD9101CFEB96E80D88"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 2350, by striking <quote>(and construction incident to base operations support)</quote> and inserting <quote>(including actions to maintain or improve the climate resilience of bases and construction incident to base operations support)</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2EC6521EE8C4D87BF50551F6A33FBAA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 2806(a), by striking <quote>acquisition and construction</quote> and inserting <quote>acquisition, construction, and climate resilience</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2CBBF204A3A48028DBB7D2CE1D64717"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after such section the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H1156EA790D3E429885E1DD4814B7A00F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HADA993A987604B50B2FC96D01D2184E6"><enum>2806a.</enum><header>Contributions to improve the climate resilience of certain facilities of allies and partners of the United States.</header><subsection id="H46B977A16E2444D4BEE8A1A0CA8F7D23"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Contributions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts appropriated to carry out this section, the Secretary of Defense may make contributions to the Federal share of the cost of construction, and other projects, to preserve or improve the climate resilience of—</text><paragraph id="H00AF96C52A9044FF98249DD8340DF19B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>military facilities and installations of an ally or partner of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF063A71245F4D3AB8B461C38B478EE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a civilian airfield or seaport of an ally or partner of the United States that the Secretary determines is suitable for military use.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H323F21245B8948DEA4E1D8DF0200D2C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation on contributions</header><text>Funds may not be obligated or expended pursuant to this section unless such funds have been authorized by law for such purpose. </text></subsection><subsection id="HCE51371A36904C87B1781735F7A0D919"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional contributions</header><paragraph id="H9744249DB84445119F5294CA90EAEC10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary may make an additional contribution for a construction or other project for which the Secretary has made a contribution under subsection (a) if—</text><subparagraph id="HA586EB584ABC4B94B17F39FDB63F7B52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such additional contribution is in an amount that is greater than the amount appropriated to carry out this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9A23B2B423B45899359A03CADDE7163"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of the additional contribution is not greater than 200 percent of the maximum amount specified in section 2805(a) for a minor military construction project. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4924FD08AB46BDA0F2B87B4F33745B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An additional contribution described in paragraph (1) may exceed the limitation in such paragraph—</text><subparagraph id="HB744C53DE9894F9BB0362E87367AB011"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the sum of the additional contribution and the contribution under subsection (a) is not greater than 125 percent of the amount appropriated to carry out this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H405EEF06326E4A7F84B45D76E2209A65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>after the end of a 14-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary submits to Congress—</text><clause id="HDF76D9D1ED134DD084DFE5E2CCB43332"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notice of such additional contribution;</text></clause><clause id="H80B8ECC8CD834370941D351F0F3B0250"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasons for such additional contribution; and</text></clause><clause id="H9C6FC307B8DF49C19C984E493F41135C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the source of funds to be used for such additional contribution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8939FE47F04444AA77ED9A469E48FBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 to carry out section 2806a of title 10, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1)(C).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FAF12D7C3A540BFB23B4950AB48103C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/169">chapter 169</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2806">section 2806</external-xref> the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCD2FB54F0ABF4A6989839F4903C2EA2A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">2806a. Contributions to improve the climate resilience of certain facilities of allies and partners of the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABAA8F2681E34625A682063D385A923C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for the Defense Environmental International Cooperation program</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Defense $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 to carry out the Defense Environmental International Cooperation program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

