<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H636BAF696AF64FF5ADD88A143696481E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9222 IH: Caring for Mothers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9222</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221021">October 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to increase health insurance access for individuals placing their newborns up for adoption.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3E7C85ED9D544724A76D3DF98DEEEB64" style="OLC"><section id="HE0B5F8DC8FE94483AC7E3FE85ACE9F77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Caring for Mothers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9F49147388704CD6BCCF438AD307DFA2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing health insurance access for individuals placing their newborns for adoption</header><subsection id="HCADC589E35D94B61A1BA006558E295E2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart II of part A of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-11">42 U.S.C. 300gg–11 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9D8F52F688514D6EAF9A2DC9FFA0F06D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H821E504D63394F8C8995B64B4A68BCE0"><enum>2730.</enum><header>Availability of coverage for individuals placing their newborns for adoption</header><subsection id="H3E364BF8A9BD48AE93A3571F461CE483"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual enrolled in a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage who intends to adopt (or has already adopted) a child of a qualifying individual and who submits to such plan or coverage (as applicable) a request described in subsection (b) with respect to such qualifying individual, such plan or coverage shall enroll such qualifying individual under such plan or coverage and provide benefits under such plan or coverage in accordance with subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H488238B34A344BD5805A987011DA7E64"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Request</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), a request described in this subsection is a request submitted to a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage by an individual who is enrolled in such plan or coverage who intends to adopt (or has already adopted) a biological child of a qualifying individual that—</text><paragraph id="H6AC6EEF04B26459F933DC098EBCB5E54"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requests that such qualifying individual receive benefits under such plan or coverage in accordance with subsection (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B9C7BC0037B49618E3AB5B188A878A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contains an attestation that such individual intends to adopt (or already has adopted) such child;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC74A130B01524E3A8917E4FBE4047205"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case such child has not been so adopted at the time of the submission of such request, contains an attestation from such qualifying individual that such qualifying individual intends to have such individual adopt such child; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AA2BC221137468DB96D9C4FD7B149E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is signed by such individual and such qualifying individual.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED7018D93F2149C58C72B96BA61B2E37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coverage</header><paragraph id="H17BE63E3FF3B46C6AC447FD2F0919AAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, benefits provided under a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage to a qualifying individual enrolled pursuant to a request described in subsection (b) shall consist only of—</text><subparagraph id="HB4D3EC8F79F142D2B4DAB2BB2E4CF4F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pregnancy-related and postpartum care; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF2E48A7FD954B12B826C6CFF729DD83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mental health and substance use disorder services. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFA34FA6F2A54D3F8D17C060BAE50326"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coverage period</header><text>Coverage provided under a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage to a qualifying individual pursuant to a request described in subsection (b) shall begin on the first day of the first month beginning after the date such plan or coverage receives such request and shall end on the earliest of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HA882BD8FF7AB4DCB9780136253FD14D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The date the individual who submitted such request notifies such plan or coverage of such individual’s intent to terminate such coverage.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA7E58E024774388BDD6B8F58FB26389"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date on which coverage of such individual under such plan or group or individual health insurance coverage is terminated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE02BF14C18A41D585F1CF13E7FDC06B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date such qualifying individual notifies such plan or coverage of such qualifying individual’s intent to terminate such coverage.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6383C82234B9451B8710566E8550AFA9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The date that is 1 year after the date of the birth of the child that is the subject of the adoption described in subsection (a). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1251B2821C4F44CD8196EEC8C4A90418"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification on scope of requirement</header><text>The requirement on a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage under subsection (a) to provide benefits to a qualifying individual pursuant to a request described in subsection (b) shall apply only with respect to benefits described in subsection (c)(1) furnished with respect to the pregnancy that is the subject of the adoption described in subsection (b). </text></subsection><subsection id="H29BD7B5128CA4D2BAD054833308B01C5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualifying individual defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>qualifying individual</quote> means an individual who—</text><paragraph id="H42ED52846C3D46BB857792F03FBCB8CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is pregnant or who has given birth in the last 6 months; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5324DAA0552E4FA39FAAAFD0D89D3C4B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a citizen or national of the United States or an alien lawfully present in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDE8994A265647DB9A9984DA97FB026E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H16E3B5206E7140F9AD30E0526C507136"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require a qualifying individual who enrolls in a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage pursuant to this section, or an individual who requests enrollment of such qualifying individual in such plan or coverage, to effectuate any adoption; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ADB62F10F2048DC8E7726F70CFFEED1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>allow for the imposition of any penalty on such a qualifying individual or individual requesting such enrollment if such an adoption is not effectuated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD284DC0DAE5E43E0A9A3950ADDBEA4B0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

