<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H154C46810D81424CB266385A9352D6FF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8002 IH: Energy Independence Task Force Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8002</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220609">June 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Inter-Agency Task Force on Energy Independence to examine whether the Russian Federation funded activities of nongovernmental organizations in Western countries which limited the ability of those countries to achieve energy independence and made them more reliant on energy exported from Russia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F365B01326E496399DC7FAF87317E6A" style="OLC"><section id="HDE29C64AF30448E78A26B9171845C819" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Energy Independence Task Force Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H528068C087864950B6493AECE6D063E7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment and purpose of Task Force</header><subsection id="HC143D127D3E24E1585B3EE8EAA2BF424"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the executive branch a task force to be known as the <quote>Task Force on Energy Independence</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Task Force</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H288FA7A3E319405A96AB66851D97CC50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Task Force is to examine whether the Russian Federation or any agent or instrumentality of the Russian Federation funded activities of nongovernmental organizations in Western countries which limited the ability of those countries to achieve energy independence and made them more reliant on energy exported from Russia. </text></subsection></section><section id="H810F410664374F7EBE7FAC91B4D8CB9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Composition of Task Force</header><subsection id="H9D7C7E9DFF65493296A4564380066F42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members</header><paragraph id="HE00B2DB8FF684B8295F685A906CC9B8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>Subject to paragraph (3), the Task Force shall be composed of 10 members, of whom 2 shall be appointed not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act by each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HCBDFFD7BB604404AB25DA49961EF1A9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H504DC8D81C734712A889B672DD097E8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC8F817202444D18B23B4E1B9C7A680F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H784021703A5347E9B2EBA0C712F8C806"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Director of the Central Intelligence Agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1011317BAC54DEEB5548964C87660C6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8BDD739D4DD45C48F78F1598A654660"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Members of the Task Force shall be employees of offices of the executive branch who have expertise in any of the issues described in paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA575B8FCC7314F56A1359C8B051D2890"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Status as detailees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual serving as a member of the Task Force shall be detailed, without reimbursement, by the office in which the individual serves as an employee, without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege, and the individual’s appointment shall be subject to the approval of the head of the office in which the individual serves as an employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB69D61BC50944C4EBE7C39DEA70707CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chair, vice chair, and meetings</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a simple majority of the members of the Task Force are appointed under paragraph (1), such members shall meet to elect a chair and vice chair from among such members and shall determine a schedule of Task Force meetings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D3B7F42BA974137960180B789F158E9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No additional funds authorized</header><text>Amounts used for the salaries and expenses, including expenses for official travel, of an individual serving as a member of the Task Force shall be paid out of amounts appropriated for salaries and expenses of the office in which the individual serves as an employee, and no additional amounts are authorized to be appropriated for such salaries and expenses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H482F0A46034D41C4A682A351CD61CA58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Task Force shall meet and begin the operations of the Task Force not later than 30 days after the appointment of a simple majority of members of the Task Force.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB521D2E2E50F494AAFD8A8B496F1E687"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quorum and vacancy</header><paragraph id="H44637F341BC3400393535001BDA048A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A simple majority of the members of the Task Force shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A2E2B13C7945748FB26A595571F7A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>Any vacancy in the Task Force shall not affect its powers and shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made not later than 30 days after the vacancy occurs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2B2A24C71E734C95A416ACED200456CD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of Task Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Task Force shall determine and analyze the following:</text><paragraph id="HC3CDD625A1A64228B0FCA7D45757C91B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent of efforts backed by the Russian Federation or any agent or instrumentality of the Russian Federation to financially support nongovernmental organizations in Western countries that opposed nuclear energy and fracking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H613FD9822885462CB171A87886DAA489"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The success or failure of these efforts to suppress investment by Western countries in diverse energy portfolios.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D668FFFFB734D69B70A18BA398B93F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The extent to which the funding of these organizations has increased the reliance of Western countries on energy exported from the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A80CDB1CCA84F87AC8C1F2943D5197E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The assessment of the level of interdependence of Western countries with the Russian Federation, and the extent to which Western countries are subject to coercion by the Russian Federation, because Western countries lack a diverse energy portfolio.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H685ACAED19AA40C0A44BBB25E7911DE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the extent to which energy independence could affect the American economy and provide insulation for Western countries against Russian intimidation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3883AEE84E3F4A95968FC3EE9D7704CE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the structure of energy agreements between the Russian Federation and other energy companies used the participation of smaller, more discreet third-party companies to provide the Russian Federation with greater control over the agreements, including an assessment of the role of companies which were subsidiaries of Russian energy companies or which were controlled overtly or covertly by the Russian Federation or instruments of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2B67FC85D024FC798309EF811ED3C7C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An assessment of the Russian Federation’s control of and investment in energy companies of Western nations, including companies involved in energy distribution, electric power generation, storage of materials, pipeline maintenance, and similar activities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB984D8B7FEBE40C5A2B91DE535D9EA61"><enum>5.</enum><header>Powers of Task Force</header><subsection id="HA9D0208DDA3B48D8BB23CD70EFDBD316"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Task Force may hold such hearings, meet and act at such times and places, and receive such evidence as may be necessary to carry out its duties.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1C872F30949C4940976628DB6F8D1E32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General and the Secretary of Energy shall work with the heads of offices of the Federal Government to ensure that the Task Force has access to such information as the Task Force considers necessary to carry out its duties.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAC5B74D36E7743B4B3BB02C4CB888F68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance from Federal agencies</header><paragraph id="HD709CDC4B25844F995F5D7F049614657"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General Services Administration</header><text>On request of the chair of the Task Force, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Task Force, on a reimbursable basis, administrative support and other assistance necessary for the Task Force to carry out its duties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7CC433BBE4C4B4A8CF18819BDF314E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other departments and agencies</header><text>In addition to the assistance provided for under paragraph (1), departments and agencies of the United States may provide to the Task Force such assistance as they may determine advisable and as authorized by law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5633C15EB97C43CC8CF1F757E869B8A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subpoena power</header><paragraph id="H75E8E3CA07624AE48129C78F7D6C1CA6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence relating to any matter which the Commission is empowered to investigate by section 4. The attendance of witnesses and the production of evidence may be required from any place within the United States at any designated place of hearing within the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1BD0C6262364CBBA35C5DF0EA74F731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to obey a subpoena</header><text>If a person refuses to obey a subpoena issued under paragraph (1), the Commission may apply to a United States district court for an order requiring that person to appear before the Commission to give testimony, produce evidence, or both, relating to the matter under investigation. The application may be made within the judicial district where the hearing is conducted or where that person is found, resides, or transacts business. Any failure to obey the order of the court may be punished by the court as civil contempt.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C42E9E8D6F4431D8D33E235407FAEC6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Service of subpoenas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The subpoenas of the Commission shall be served in the manner provided for subpoenas issued by a United States district court under the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure for the United States district courts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD922E6F0D9AE4A50BF9F491CF099AD86"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All process of any court to which application is made under paragraph (2) may be served in the judicial district in which the person required to be served resides or may be found.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B0DC94EDBD7430A9D6FA58B69FE9E9E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Contracting</header><text>The Task Force may enter into contracts to enable it to carry out its duties.</text></subsection><subsection id="H052855183ADF4DA8B3934E594ABDCD1A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Task Force may accept, use, and dispose of donations of services or property.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2AC6BF91CE34EEF998DEA587CAF0C16"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Task Force may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as a department or agency of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB11D7BB883E848DA83D99370186E2313"><enum>6.</enum><header>Staff of Task Force</header><subsection id="H11F22184D4BA4263B0126987E1656219"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The chair of the Task Force, in consultation with the vice chair, in accordance with rules agreed upon by the Task Force, may appoint and fix the compensation of a staff director and such other personnel as may be necessary to enable the Task Force to carry out its functions, in accordance with the provisions of title 5, United States Code, except that no rate of pay fixed under this subsection may exceed the equivalent of that payable for a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA110483906E241DAA8E88A29D8DB841A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff of Federal agencies</header><text>Upon request of the chair of the Task Force, the head of any executive department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality of the Federal Government may detail, without reimbursement, any of its personnel to the Task Force to assist it in carrying out its duties under this Act. Any detail of an employee shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subsection><subsection id="H29895C2251EB4E1593B2DA1B1BA40BC9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultant services</header><text>The Task Force is authorized to procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, but at rates not to exceed the daily rate paid a person occupying a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD01D0BF7B7F847A9B73CAA9E55D46275"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act shall apply to the Task Force, including the staff of the Task Force.</text></section><section id="HF9F98DF1E93F43FE9471A544348E07EC"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report; termination</header><subsection id="H1328198D3F2D40C39467D34B88F4F601"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Final report</header><paragraph id="HF2822D04F7AD461EB28D824CA18501A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall, not later than 1 year after the date of its first meeting, submit to the individuals described in paragraph (2) a final report containing specific findings, conclusions, and recommendations required under this Act as have been agreed to by a majority of Task Force members. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF0D3CFEF80041ED845B4C53F10EA68D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individuals described in this paragraph are the President, the Attorney General, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, the majority leader of the Senate, and the minority leader of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H609C84A636784927A24741DAB4BA0247"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Classified and unclassified material</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report under this subsection shall be prepared—</text><subparagraph id="H43156D98525F489BA43AE56AC72475FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in an unclassified version; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC992D8D257146C9A8194460BF74BBF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a version which includes a classified annex. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C5EE5C409514A18916FA6FF87933783"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="H1707463F67EC4C129CD22EFF82248E7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force, and all the authorities of this Act, shall terminate on the date that is 30 days after the date of on which the Task Force submits the final report required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD485E656ED8E4E9EAB63AA23826BE7D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Records</header><text>Not later than the date of termination of the Task Force under paragraph (1), all records and papers of the Task Force shall be delivered to the Archivist of the United States for deposit in the National Archives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

