<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF489CD98D7E47388DE497E916524188" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8993 IH: Methane Emissions Mitigation Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8993</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for methane emission detection and mitigation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H74C41C43F331426C953DB5E3102F8DF5" style="OLC"><section id="H945BB7954AA645C88089F4793E1D9CB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Methane Emissions Mitigation Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEED80D78F1314CB6ABE0363668C95E18"><enum>2.</enum><header>Methane emission detection and mitigation</header><subsection id="HCF1A117BBEF742AF939A2B3F75B2E74B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle F of title IX of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16291">42 U.S.C. 16291 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7E041DEEC0E14B88906E8812C6EC8E0E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HC2D1381340A243F5B417E58A3F964124"><enum>969D.</enum><header>Methane leak detection and mitigation</header><subsection id="HF40F2BC5892247C38EABC881BA188185"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><paragraph id="H1CABB0AC810E40E39DCA7E5F51AF83D6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall carry out a program of methane emissions detection and mitigation research, development, and demonstration for technologies and methods that significantly detect, quantify, and mitigate methane emissions. In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE6A1148F2E30494A9731108463B922BD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enter into cooperative agreements with State or local governments or for-profit entities to provide technical assistance to—</text><clause id="HB211A85FFF0B41C0BA285949D2C268BB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prevent or respond to methane releases, including prediction, detection, mitigation, quantification, and identification of leaks, vents, and other outflows throughout the natural gas infrastructure (including natural gas storage, pipelines, and natural gas production sites); and</text></clause><clause id="HCDD942FB59E9498C90ECEAC3221A0D69" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect public health in the event of a major methane release;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB444DE69EC04FC099EA9BED8399AED0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote demonstration and adoption of effective methane emissions-reduction technologies in the private sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H900A0723D6A042399E27735E8C6ED520" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in coordination with representatives from private sector entities, State and local governments, and institutions of higher education, establish a publicly accessible resource for best practices in the design, construction, maintenance, performance, monitoring, and incident response for—</text><clause id="H8B7693FA2A18463F90C05540ECE9C7DA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pipeline systems, including compressor stations;</text></clause><clause id="HDE45FD409BBD4A7694BA9601A4712910" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>production wells;</text></clause><clause id="HA233627EC23E40C9A44E1930BEF72D1A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>storage facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="HF3D73169B4D34631AD975571FD0375B8" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other vulnerable infrastructure;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD99C007B93AC49368B06C2A25C470761" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in coordination with representatives from private sector entities, State and local governments, and institutions of higher education, establish a publicly accessible resource for best practices in evaluation and incorporation of emission reduction technologies, including—</text><clause id="HA00143788EEF4BF082346F075049E163" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>metrics for performance evaluation; and</text></clause><clause id="HBCB67F89CA964B93B64C1A0A985A6EA9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>principles for selection and integration that are best suited for the project or entity concerned;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB816E77218AC4C91BA5DA478695A477F" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>research technologies to more accurately quantify emissions, including—</text><clause id="HA7F77620254C430FA922331258195A47" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ability to accurately characterize and measure methane emissions through various atmospheric conditions such as wind, rain, fog, and dust;</text></clause><clause id="HBB0A1398E9394F1CBC45EE563471CEDF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements to data analytics and machine learning platforms; and</text></clause><clause id="H5C9ADE65177849B481CF1146713316C9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the ability to characterize temporal patterns in emissions, such as through continuous monitoring or multitiered system practices;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6CAE1304D1C4B529EC218EFF156EFC8" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>identify high-risk characteristics of pipelines, wells, storage facilities, and materials, geologic risk factors, or other key factors that increase the likelihood or intensity of methane emissions leaks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H040335D858844108BFE6D54152DB3633" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>identify methane mitigation methods and technologies in coal mines; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A18B108B68442FD9E39445CD0B89727" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>in collaboration with private sector entities and institutions of higher education, quantify and map significant geologic methane seeps and other sources of natural emissions across the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA33EA409CCF1410483635338333330AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><subparagraph id="H95481733F86C44F6920D43F4E7EA7197"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Historical data of methane emissions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ABB51B433774B19A3E59A6AF945F89C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Public health consequences.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B0DEB14B81F49F38C4C11BC9F287FB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Public safety.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H173B24A4BEF1485B8BF7B1F3A7161060"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Novel materials and designs for pipelines, compressor stations, components, and wells (including casing, cement, and wellhead).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EB25D3DC21F403E9CB86A6B55FA0579"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Regional geologic traits.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F2562214B24410190CA69F73AAED9C9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Induced and natural seismicity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24CFF56BEF6D46EBA45A382CB5CEE61B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methane leak detection consortium</header><paragraph id="H161AB4C07DAE43C48E93FCF70949E17E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish and operate a Methane Emissions Measurement and Mitigation Research Consortium (in this section referred to as the <quote>Consortium</quote>) for the purpose of supporting, to the maximum extent practicable, data sharing, research prioritization, and researching cooperative leak detection and repair strategies pertaining to methane emissions detection, quantification, and mitigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7754B0EB77EE4E1D94F9144A5E481EDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The members of the Consortium shall be representatives from relevant Federal agencies, National Laboratories, oil and gas operators and industry groups, vendors of methane detection and quantification technologies, institutions of higher education, community organizations, relevant nongovernmental organizations, and other appropriate entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F4BF40F5B5B40EE8E260A40E007BAEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Consortium shall develop and implement a multiyear plan that—</text><subparagraph id="HF97C9CB8C454418AB9F3B92CF297582F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies technical goals and milestones for the Consortium; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC6DAFDA781B4373AF82B5A88848F439"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitates data sharing for the purposes of—</text><clause id="H07DB5DA8CD014779B595533EDB4E5E1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>bettering the understanding of methane emissions from the oil and gas sector; </text></clause><clause id="HCE91D0BCE0894EE0B91028A35E50DA31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improving emissions detection, measurement, and mitigation capabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H61F32F6CD8984D689B82489C5A2870D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improving the understanding of methane quantification data analytics and machine learning platforms, including for calibration of measurements.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H269D575B6B9F4512B91AD0CB2B865899"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><subparagraph id="H82D16EEC95AD43F0962F77BA7976790F" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall report on the Consortium’s activities to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99372671BEF846ADBA2F7E554C98E8B4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report summarizing the activities, findings, and progress of the program. The report shall include—</text><clause id="HEE92D10F935347F091822FB2E17A4BFD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text> a review of LDAR technologies available to the oil and gas sector for the purpose of methane emissions measurement and mitigation;</text></clause><clause id="H3F5371F312684C6B9C337EBB45B9BEEA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a summary of research gaps and priorities related to methane emissions detection, measurement, and mitigation capabilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H63B5EF597DC94FE496F12928D44ECDDA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of the data sharing and cooperative activities that have been initiated pursuant to paragraph (3)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97EAB4A806CB435581403EE17EF53753" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which the report under subparagraph (B) is submitted and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report summarizing the activities, findings, and progress of the program. The report shall include—</text><clause id="HF5DF48272CFA46158D8374C44A523779" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an updated review of LDAR technologies available to oil and gas operators for the purpose of methane emissions measurement and mitigation;</text></clause><clause id="H90F81650BA0D4AD7AF21D3A15A348872" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the state of methane emissions detection and measurement capabilities;</text></clause><clause id="HA984CC7E031D4E2992F3B1142C58F931" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a summary of research priorities relating to methane emissions detection, measurement, and mitigation; and</text></clause><clause id="H26F6452AD52143EDB5E7E1E2CF078852" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an update on the data sharing and cooperative activities undertaken by members of the Consortium.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F4885F921AF43B2B58C4EB1E1D9FB4E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sunset; termination</header><subparagraph id="H160114A134C246CCB1D0795126C3AF6B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide support to the Consortium for a period of not more than ten years, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34F0DC83FDD2473F90F98BA31BB13EF7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Merit review</header><text>Not later than five years after the date on which the Consortium is established, the Secretary shall conduct a review to determine whether the Consortium has achieved the technical goals and milestones identified under paragraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H440F6A779E8248B690FD825192E787F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H9D24C409EEE0487DBB7BFDA856E773EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B81435280DB4FB498AE9BA532F96598"><enum>(B)</enum><header>LDAR</header><text>The term <quote>LDAR</quote> means a technology, program, or activity that is intended to monitor, detect, measure, or repair methane leaks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF75F9A0F04845CDBE7691C2090DAC19"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30A48439CFA9452CAC59AD56DDB06704"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section—</text><subparagraph id="H799902FB20B748E489F7676255D1598C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$33,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EE2D43E24304F1ABFDF1365765C0A6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$34,650,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57FC35012B194A61BB802E63F608FA32"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$36,382,500 for fiscal year 2025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4577AE06A8DC4B02A3586B3C660A90B7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$38,201,625 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00C4C3358234A0EA82FC87E26A8FB55"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$40,111,706 for fiscal year 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H00DCECF9BD224C7FA7370A4F694CEE6A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 is amended by adding at the end of the items relating to subtitle F of title IX of such Act the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF011983B9F354FE5B681EEAC55ACE3FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 969D. Methane leak detection and mitigation.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

