<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB4E7429D95884B62AF8B83932E52CD6D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8240 IH: Military Energy Security Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220628">June 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To combat military reliance on Russian energy.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D6F17E49C704B7A9DE59E238E418C8C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H45998E8FEAAF4778B1C771B2E3F00775" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Energy Security Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text> </section> <section id="HFBB6DD3860314F6D8F8E650108A58BB8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Combating military reliance on Russian energy</header> <subsection id="H9D7BA9D6B4924632B9400020F0004C9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text>
<paragraph id="H0E2E0FE7C9874A9BA8206D292E09B7DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reliance on Russian energy poses a critical challenge for national security activities in area of responsibility of the United States European Command; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E1F34DFCFA54FC5A1CC8B06530EB067"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in order to reduce the vulnerability of United States military facilities to disruptions caused by reliance on Russian energy, the Department of Defense should establish and implement plans to reduce reliance on Russian energy for all main operating bases in area of responsibility of the United States European Command.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H824A12DE05B049A6B81D95DB946E4186"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eliminating use of Russian energy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the goal of the Department of Defense to eliminate the use of Russian energy on each main operating base in the area of responsibility of the United States European Command by not later than five years after the date of the completion of an installation energy plan for such base, as required under this section. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H3552EB2B2E304E2CAE5A39A2641B6754"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Installation energy plans for main operating bases</header> <paragraph id="H6C8D16DF0FF54C82AF4519A9F40C1A80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Identification of installations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than June 1, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a list of main operating bases within the area of responsibility of the United States European Command ranked according to mission criticality and vulnerability to energy disruption.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H133922E992CE4AF29536F6E55708D142"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submittal of plans</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees—</text> <subparagraph id="HB040C419FF79463291B1983DFA6C6F23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an installation energy plan for each main operating base on the list submitted under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE93AD0853A554470A2ABC5C9143A8411"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the feasibility of reaching the goal for the elimination of the use of Russian energy pursuant to subsection (b) on that base, including—</text> <clause id="H96C4C80C4350477C930714B39D0D9330"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the steps that would be required to meet such goal; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H8D7B34BF8E7F4D2C9C70668286539CEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an analysis of the effects such steps would have on the national security of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H36083303543747E5BB65A5C7A1982304"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Content of plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each installation energy plan for a main operating base shall include each of the following with respect to that base:</text>
<paragraph id="HA97EDDB5633C427B9632200E5E4B20BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the energy resilience requirements, resiliency gaps, and energy-related cybersecurity requirements of the base, including with respect to operational technology, control systems, and facilities-related control systems.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DF9D334E16D46FDA9A0EF1AF8870A71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An identification of investments in technology required to improve energy resilience, reduce demand, strengthen energy conservation, and support mission readiness.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBAA2E93EDC7843F3B7DC5CF5C4E6F930"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of investments in infrastructure, including microgrids, required to strengthen energy resilience and mitigate risk due to grid disturbance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBC25976A00E4CB48814BF8F244025E1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations related to opportunities for the use of renewable energy, clean energy, nuclear energy, and energy storage projects to reduce dependence on natural gas.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3AD2B83663394655B104548267371408"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of how the requirements and recommendations included pursuant to paragraphs (2) through (4) interact with the energy policies of the country where the base is located, both at present and into the future.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1458BBF43D024DEDB4302CC718639D8D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation of plans</header> <paragraph id="H25F2275D494549708245581EEFA7E66E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deadline for implementation</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary submits an installation energy plan for a base under subsection (c)(2), the Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H835DA63371164C9F9723F41364DCA547"><enum>(A)</enum><text>begin implementing the plan; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H94E1295A1A084CEA905F86E7014B4BB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide to the congressional defense committees a briefing on the contents of the plan and the strategy of the Secretary for implementing the mitigation measures identified in the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H644F3B2355B74085B261362E141E266C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization of certain projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing an installation energy plan for a base under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize projects requested under section 2914 of title 10, United States Code, to mitigate assessed risks and improve energy resilience, energy security, and energy conservation at the base.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC6200A3050D41B0941B2C0BE340BDE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonapplication of certain other authorities</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 2914 of title 10, United States Code, shall not apply with respect to any project carried out pursuant to this section or pursuant to an installation energy plan for a base under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H555DBF73F108428D8783A1837AC72B0E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Policy for future bases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall establish a policy to ensure that any new military base in the area of responsibility of the United States European Command is established in a manner that proactively includes the consideration of energy security, energy resilience, and mitigation of risk due to energy disruption.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H94BDF5B94D8640F98CD28EF2CC0DE24B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual congressional briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall provide to the congressional defense committees annual briefings on the installation energy plans required under this section. Such briefings shall include an identification of each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H323DAC403F6E46D68B989E82DDFC0B49"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The actions each main operating base is taking to implement the installation energy plan for that base.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDABE3AF5A4BB4FA8A35B0D8E37E57FEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The progress that has been made toward reducing the reliance of United States bases on Russian energy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD723AE18D61748CBA1039EF0D3E37843"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The steps being taken and planned across the future-years defense program to meet the goal of eliminating reliance on Russian energy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE9B8F06818F640BDB8941FA3EC9A3084"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>congressional defense committees</term> means the Committees on Armed Services and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

