<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B0ACF906309473F91DE5849DD83A610" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9051 IH: Defending Memory Chip Supply Chains from the Chinese Communist Party Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9051</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on certain foreign flash memory integrated circuit companies that threaten the interests of the United States.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HBB5D6911ABBC4DE9B8FFFF701F20413C" style="OLC">
<section id="H35703DA8F0554DE583FF35D4EAB7670E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Memory Chip Supply Chains from the Chinese Communist Party Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD3BDB2AF728D4EABB4397D25F431D256"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions on certain foreign entities</header> <subsection id="HB78A66B64A154181BCFAA3E21F55E82C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> <paragraph id="H2F20DF53FEB64A8F84D4F9DAD67B0B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>On and after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall exercise all the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all significant transactions in property and interests in property of an entity described in subsection (b), if such property and interests in are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC0CF93C11EEB4DBD9AF6C2CB62CDB862"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of significance</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, in determining if transactions are significant, the President may consider the totality of the facts and circumstances, including the factors set forth in section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3597677B1F2046CB98E8B1437678318D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of this section, participation in an international standards-setting organization or in the activities of such an organization may not be construed to be transactions.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEDD18A72D8F6497EA706A159D7812477"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Entities affiliated with a country of concern described</header><text>An entity is described in this subsection if the entity is—</text> <paragraph id="H5E0F35E2AC4B48A5A54D2C80D81497A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Yangtze Memory Technologies Corporation (YMTC), any of its subsidiaries, or any company in which YMTC or its subsidiaries own at least 5 percent; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H250353D94D8D4A49B72CF9782AC9FE9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an entity—</text> <subparagraph id="H58724D7A3E8447D7AD8010F29273A32E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is engaged in the production of flash memory integrated circuits of at least 128 layers; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H10869196F5544D34AC542239F7D50B30"><enum>(B)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC87C642AE0E340CEBB505FEC66FBA12F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that receives or has received subsidies or investments from any national, provincial, county, municipal, or other government, quasi-government, or party body of a country of concern, including the Chinese Communist Party;</text></clause> <clause id="H2595BB6A71EC4D9685F63D1D69EDF51F" display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that has links to the sale, transfer, or research and development of technology for the Armed Forces of a country of concern, including the People’s Liberation Army;</text></clause>
<clause id="H679E425794F44103A4CFBFA1786CA61B" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that is directly or indirectly owned or controlled by the government or ruling party of a country of concern or by another entity described in this subsection;</text></clause> <clause id="H0B5C6F2F6FA64C03A3C17EF3F0FE1CA7" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">five percent or more of the outstanding voting stock or shares of which are owned, controlled, or held by the government or ruling party of a country of concern or by another entity described in this subsection;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF9992214048E45C29DB56BB7EC4C808E" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is subject to substantial influence from either a country of concern or another entity described in this subsection;</text></clause> <clause id="HADF9FED408C742E9BFB2DF556C09D8EC" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is domiciled in a country of concern and shares with another entity described in this subsection an employee in a position of material decisionmaking authority;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0284DF379F3D48D5ACA8215F29486663" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is part of another entity that is headquartered in a country of concern, including a subsidiary, a holding company, a contract affiliate, or a variable interest entity; or</text></clause> <clause id="HCB8871B287EA447AA479B0D3D920F005" indent="up1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is otherwise substantially influenced by a national of a country of concern or by another entity domiciled in the country of concern.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H9F277BE627B04A16AF6F812AB237223B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header>
<paragraph id="HF15675837B62422FBCED24056E970650"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7256836776ED4DB784CF704B9775A300"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header> <subparagraph id="HED61D04BB1F640B79EC59819629BEB86"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this section shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4D963F9B825B48C28DE782DD94E544E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H222B5B1333D94074A8CDFD38D2EF562F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person for renewable periods of not more than 30 days each if the President determines and reports to Congress that such a waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H7ED05AA681AD4DD6A9EBEFC8E4DC00DA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header>
<paragraph id="H084C163286BC47C5B25151836BA87286"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President shall exercise the authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to the extent necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31E3063B2D074F0A982D98F99752DF1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (a) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFC2675EEB313423081BAD759E6462931"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header>
<paragraph id="H703210CF7A854CC7B20038C818413207"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H19809854496E40D8AE65FAA24C80E6DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Country of concern</header><text>The term <term>country of concern</term>—</text>
<clause id="H546B5D70A1934CB8A88A17B1392C0C63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term <term>foreign adversary</term> in section 8(c)(2) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1607">47 U.S.C. 1607(c)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> <clause id="H7DE4BC69738A4E5EB7082161F8E4BCDB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes the People’s Republic of China, Russia, Iran, North Korea, Cuba, and Venezuela.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H175F1D8530454AF2AA122A52A137A691"><enum>(B)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> <clause id="HFCE42243841F4E6F8995EF70AAEABCEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HD6C7F1417AC0454895671B2F47AF5BA8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA394698CF2B745CB8FCEFD80F14A6F77"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Severability</header><text>If any provision of this Act or its application to any person or circumstance is held invalid, the invalidity does not affect other provisions or applications of this Act that can be given effect without the invalid provision or application, and to this end the provisions of this Act are severable.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


