<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE59F006E64D440E1A35C7FB85A329A06" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9616 IH: Preventing Child Sex Abuse Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9616</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect children against sexual abuse and exploitation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9ED3027E538848B68DAA2D8DD1B1E8E8" style="OLC"><section id="HF5A1A980558248D8BC502B38D40D0469" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Child Sex Abuse Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H62DDFED3DAAF4C6B8324E4A1FB74E153"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The sense of Congress is the following:</text><paragraph id="HC6F777E195BA420DAE912A797B338B9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The safety of children should be a top priority for public officials and communities in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B09FF4E1A34167BDA0CE34E7FD219F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Rape, Abuse &amp; Incest National Network, an individual in the United States is sexually assaulted every 68 seconds. And every 9 minutes, that victim is a child. Meanwhile, only 25 out of every 1,000 perpetrators will end up in prison.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B7EA450EC54618983BFB7BAB58E1C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The effects of child sexual abuse can be long-lasting and affect the victim’s mental health. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB16D215AD63A4E43BA3D329717E1691A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Victims are more likely than non-victims to experience the following mental health challenges:</text><subparagraph id="H138ABB7487E84312B217FE12EF9D0494"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Victims are about 4 times more likely to develop symptoms of drug abuse.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H955053E7556B4124942761685D104C2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Victims are about 4 times more likely to experience post-traumatic stress disorder as adults.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EA5B00E2AEA4F998518129A20EDEAA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Victims are about 3 times more likely to experience a major depressive episode as adults.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H503BB3533AFF48EB8DA0917118D28792"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The criminal justice system should and has acted as an important line of defense to protect children and hold perpetrators accountable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2EABE10398A45F5B0CB20E10B08800A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>However, the horrific crimes perpetuated by Larry Nassar demonstrate firsthand the loopholes that still exist in the criminal justice system. While Larry Nassar was found guilty of several State-level offenses, he was not charged federally for his illicit sexual contact with minors, despite crossing State and international borders to commit this conduct. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E1F2F06C94A4E8DAC2A7FBF6E9314A3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of Justice has also identified a growing trend of Americans who use charitable or missionary work in a foreign country as a cover for sexual abuse of children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAFEDB855A324A7E8E7762CF5C27FB6E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>It is the intent of Congress to prohibit Americans from engaging in sexual abuse or exploitation of minors under the guise of work, including volunteer work, with an organization that affects interstate or foreign commerce, such as an international charity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FD2882F194540DDB04803B7FB991BDE"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal law does not require that an abuser’s intention to engage in sexual abuse be a primary, significant, dominant, or motivating purpose of the travel. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FFFB8895C2E454298495901D801A8C9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Child sexual abuse does not require physical contact between the abuser and the child. This is especially true as perpetrators turn increasingly to internet platforms, online chat rooms, and webcams to commit child sexual abuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA99A9D04F988435685BD3B4DB3EE3F01"><enum>(11)</enum><text>However, a decision of the United States Court of Appeals for the Seventh Circuit found the use of a webcam to engage in sexually provocative activity with a minor did not qualify as <quote>sexual activity</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CFC44073106487DA160DCA40959C0A6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Congress can address this issue by amending the definition of the term <term>sexual activity</term> to clarify that it does not require interpersonal, physical contact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03C274ABC8BD4F40B4554182E8290204"><enum>(13)</enum><text>It is the duty of Congress to provide clearer guidance to ensure that those who commit crimes against children are prosecuted to the fullest extent of the law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEAA461EE65CF4454B5C4539246A10108"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interstate child sexual abuse</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2423 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2E1595FC56B54491877FEBEA793045D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), by striking <quote>with a motivating purpose of engaging in any illicit sexual conduct with another person</quote> and inserting <quote>with intent to engage in any illicit sexual conduct with another person</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8065CE3E38EE45F0890C4DD26F5270BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d), (e), (f), and (g) as subsections (e), (f), (g), and (i), respectively; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF63D4B430B240B18BC879AD38130DA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>with a motivating purpose of engaging in any illicit sexual conduct</quote> and inserting <quote>with intent to engage in any illicit sexual conduct</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E93AB2A824D455C9A13C15B0FD33304"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HACF9DA35E75C481DB26B2E8737296CC9"><subsection id="H4AE1A8A722F94DE08A02AE865295EBCC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As used in this section, the term <term>intent</term> shall be construed as any intention to engage in illicit sexual conduct at the time of the travel. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H0A7B2337830B43C1BA8BFD625A01CC1A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Abuse under the guise of charity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2423 of title 18, United States Code, as amended by section 3 of this Act, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDFDD1AAD94164999A4A56BEF881D59D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6CFF1C19D0E4A1C9D88635455F4532F"><subsection id="H673BB454D3364534963972E5D755FA64"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Illicit sexual conduct in connection with certain organizations</header><text>Any citizen of the United States or alien admitted for permanent residence who—</text><paragraph id="H817EDC3C11994D078EEA1F0F302833C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is an officer, director, employee, or agent of an organization that affects interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42E0D151BB7845C3B8A3CE4FC7441B99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>makes use of the mails or any means or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce through the connection or affiliation of the person with such organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A0F47CB889146A19A6C17457CD780E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>commits an act in furtherance of illicit sexual conduct through the connection or affiliation of the person with such organization, </text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be fined under this title, imprisoned for not more than 30 years, or both.</continuation-text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8E90F02F269400D8A6E2E29AF44D5F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (f), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>or (d)</quote> and inserting <quote>(d), or (e)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E5F4A78CB8B4A5A93F32A2A8A0B6D64" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (i), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>(f)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>(g)(2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA4368A18F95E4B96BA5FF600121CC913"><enum>5.</enum><header>Sexual activity with minors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2427 of title 18, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>does not require interpersonal physical contact, and</quote> before <quote>includes</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

