<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AA0CF64F1AF43508CC5A5459C741DD3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9463 IH: Satellite And Telecommunications Streamlining Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9463</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221208">December 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. Rodgers of Washington</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide authority for certain licenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9387F5FA327C4070B93C3D215C35C0F3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF347AEAD56E24B1EB854DE1862A8112E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Satellite And Telecommunications Streamlining Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAT Streamlining Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5EB6E05C3F9045EEB1E71A8CCC93BD87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority regarding certain licenses</header> <subsection id="H6999FB01DB8E481D95A54A73EF10A878"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Part I of title III of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/301">47 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H45EA6A16F2E14B4F89991F81D0B6C442" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4BB4A3D2AF684838A2A15C4E2F4A04E1"><enum>345.</enum><header>Radiofrequency licensing authority regarding certain operations</header> 
<subsection id="H2413E0238E224AB99615DE760B382EA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rules</header> 
<paragraph id="HE45FD0D0A05F439284A89FF79973A6CB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Commission shall issue rules to amend part 25, title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, to establish for each license granted under subsection (b) or any request for a grant of market access granted under subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC9D6909AFA4F417C99436CADAD991876" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in accordance with paragraph (2), specific, measurable, and technology-neutral performance objectives for space safety and orbital debris;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9DDBBD6F3D8E4749BC67BB8B9B2C2535" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specific modifications (or classes of modifications) to a license granted under subsection (b)(1) that warrant expedited treatment under subsection (g)(2);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBB0905AE83AC4A839ED3C92708E6648B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific actions taken by a licensee of a license granted under subsection (b)(1) or a grantee that has been granted market access under subsection (c)(1) that constitute a failure to coordinate in good faith; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H28FE50D81A1D44C9A41A3CC457E0E57E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a quantifiable level of protection required under subsection (h)(4); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7059AB3360074D40BC57CE898BD04D74" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manner in which an applicant shall notify the Commission of a request to submit a modification under subsection (g)(5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37938A589B334C1EB8307F311E1ABFCF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflict with interagency standard practices</header><text>In the rules issued pursuant to paragraph (1)(A), or any successor rule, the Commission may not establish performance objectives that conflict with any standard practice established in the Orbital Debris Mitigation Standard Practices adopted by the United States Government.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H602294D006624A7EBD6C0B9F1E5E6635"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application for license</header> <paragraph id="H3CF7F8BB24B94FC59D271E0CFCBE5AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>NGSO determination required</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 4(i), 303(r), and 303(y) and the authority of the Commission to require such other information under section 308(b) and consider such other matters under section 309(a), and except as provided in paragraph (5), not later than 1 year after the date on which a written application is submitted to the Commission, the Commission shall make a determination whether to grant such application for a license for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE681DD9EEA5047428BEE7D2142CA1CB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nongeostationary orbit space station or space-station constellation and an earth station or earth stations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56FB01A941704292B5CD7D34A41915F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nongeostationary orbit space station and the blanket-licensed earth stations that will operate with the nongeostationary orbit space station; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23FAAA920AD74BB0B7C1A36A79CBA420"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nongeostationary orbit space-station constellation and the blanket-licensed earth stations that will operate with the nongeostationary orbit space-station constellation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED16D9BBFA9741FFAA691037B6D0000B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>GSO determination required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which a written application is submitted to the Commission and except as provided in paragraph (5), the Commission shall make a determination whether to grant such application for a license for a geostationary orbit space station or space-station constellation and earth stations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F445553C71C463CAE429C129F68A185"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>In addition to the application requirements described in section 308(b), an application submitted under paragraph (1) or (2) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H1324071D6A3745F3A66A1261A45ADD23"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Performance metrics with respect to the frequencies and transmission power to be used.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF15E1343081D435AA9211D1A2CCF360C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of compliance by the applicant with the performance objectives and actions established under subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1) and, in the case of an application submitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection, subparagraphs (C) and (D) of subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H91A8061CDA83440DA35FED001D0A1170" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Term of initial license</header><text>The Commission shall grant a license for a term not to exceed 15 years for any application granted under this subsection.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37E3FA7E0B9E4B7EA3D0D0B990545776"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The deadline for the determination required in paragraphs (1) and (2) may be extended by the Commission for an application subject to review under section 310(d).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F9B08B6CC66430B83700413340EC9A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Timely grant of certain applications</header> <subparagraph id="H1D66A60BECD54192970FCB755EFB49FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grant of application required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Commission receives a written application for a license described in paragraph (1) that the Commission determines meets the additional criteria described in subparagraph (B), the Commission shall grant such application.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H270B4276E5C349A0BAAB3C3962D4773A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criteria described</header><text>The additional criteria described in this subparagraph are as follows:</text> <clause id="H1CF63D2DCBF54153954E9CC420D4429C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A limit on the number of space stations a constellation contains, as determined by the Commission.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H73823F025BB54EFCB8197C06D35EAB17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A limit on the total in-orbit lifetime for any individual space station, as determined by the Commission.</text></clause> <clause id="H12FE76A47C284E1191EDD22570F12BB3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For each space station, the following:</text> 
<subclause id="HB60FFE4EF6854E1194FBB6A6D0F4B253"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A limit on the orbital altitude at which the space station may operate, as determined by the Commission.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9BC9FFBE7D914C10814D217F8692DE73"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that the space station has a maneuverability capability and the ability to make collision avoidance and deorbit maneuvers, as determined by the Commission.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB75BB189148D4DF89EB5F3C7335EDE05"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that each space station is identifiable by a unique signal-based telemetry marker that meets requirements issued by the Commission.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1D8287BC585D4760BAB5A828FE1B335D"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>A requirement that the space station releases no operational debris.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8DEC3424F97E4C118A2AA66C224F82FC"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that the space station can be commanded by command originating from the ground to immediately cease transmissions and the applicant has the capability to eliminate harmful interference when required by the Commission.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H752E00E0DA8A481AB8D83755EE7BC8D8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A requirement that the operator has assessed and limited the probability of an accidental explosion, including an explosion that results from the conversion of energy sources on board any space station into energy that fragments the space station.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0AACFA76D853414898578E79602B0D12"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A limit on the probability of a collision between each space station and any other large object, as determined by the Commission.</text></clause> <clause id="H1EF2D0B30A3949F4A42377B9F18B1935"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that each space station is disposed of post-mission through atmospheric re-entry and the probability of human casualty from such re-entry meets requirements issued by the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5932AEF4BC63430195D05ABE3A1E164F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, the Commission shall—</text> <clause id="HDEEC200E89F047E4AC88B0D45BD2D81D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issue rules to implement this paragraph; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H31D45C5718974065A0E40BB03B90E8BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make the finding described in subparagraph (D).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CD62892CD4449E68C94140FF6334707"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Finding described</header><text>If the Commission finds that the rules of the Commission, as of the date of the enactment of this paragraph, satisfy the requirements in this paragraph, the Commission shall issue a public notice stating such finding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBAF91BF3E4D54BA18FD0B938C046B834"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application for grant of market access</header> 
<paragraph id="H25F34A75F3DF4A2D8D5F16E8933F9FDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding sections 4(i), 303(r), and 303(y) and the authority of the Commission to require such other information under section 308(b) and consider such other matters under section 309(a), the Commission shall make a determination whether to grant a written application submitted to the Commission for market access within the United States for—</text> <subparagraph id="H0AFDBA8CC35648A49B04026B03E8881F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nongeostationary orbit space station or space-station constellation and an earth station or earth stations;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC22BD53549F24E7E8B8329B3EFD06EFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nongeostationary orbit space station and the blanket-licensed earth stations that will operate with the nongeostationary orbit space station; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6CA5749889864C1B8A5AF6C35292324A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nongeostationary orbit space-station constellation and the blanket-licensed earth stations that will operate with the nongeostationary orbit space-station constellation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0118B0E64384415BB98E5B8188C347ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text>In addition to the application requirements described in section 308(b), an application submitted under this subsection shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H2E524F602F37429DABAB5A3E0EB99ECE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Performance metrics with respect to the frequencies and transmission power to be used.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA59F1DB3957E4153AC8E79245808C78A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of compliance by the applicant with the performance objectives and actions established under subparagraphs (A), (C), and (D) of subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6BE9F50099D44C8A537DA79D9812595" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term of initial grant of market access</header><text>The Commission shall grant a grant of market access for a term not to exceed 15 years for any application granted under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEA78B85869AE4DBCA6A0A9D082055583"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Earth station authorization</header> 
<paragraph id="HC16C113978FA44879B1B98223FAB3F24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text>Notwithstanding sections 4(i), 303(r), 303(y), and 309(a) and subsections (a) through (c) and (e) through (j) of this section, not later than 1 year after the date on which a written application is submitted to the Commission, the Commission shall make a determination whether to grant such application for authorization to use an earth station (including a gateway station) to receive a signal from—</text> <subparagraph id="H7DA0E42C1E5A45C697C4ADCBF242C951"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nongeostationary orbit satellite or nongeostationary orbit satellite system; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D1A3359F33947DAA1C8F9B0000DE15C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a geostationary orbit satellite or geostationary orbit satellite system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE655897D8CEA4249953E47817392A33E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deemed granted</header><text>If the Commission does not grant or deny a written application submitted under paragraph (1) within 60 days after the date on which the application is submitted to the Commission, except as provided in paragraph (3), the application shall be deemed granted on the date on which the Commission receives a written notice of the failure by the applicant. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7E8AA47C4CE47BCBCC3E403D212CC66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The deadline for the determination required in paragraph (1) may be extended by the Commission for an application subject to review under section 310(d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59481D510E77442D93D63118D9E069E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Determination of public interest, convenience, and necessity</header><text>Before making a determination to grant an application, renewal, or modification under subsection (b), (c), (d), (f), or (g) (as the case may be), the Commission shall determine if the license, grant, or authorization (as the case may be) serves the public interest, convenience, and necessity, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HACFD7C81A02442388B53CB41802DBCBB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a license or grant to which subsection (h)(4) applies, the license or grant does not exceed the quantifiable level of protection established in subsection (h)(4); and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H034A0DF8822F4CEBA31CAFCF33952373" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a license or grant that is required to protect radio astronomy observatories by the International Telecommunication Union, the application, renewal, or modification demonstrates that such protection will be provided.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4869DBA2FB54D088123560FFED6B00E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Renewal of license, grant of market access, or authorization</header> 
<paragraph id="HE1A0A8C59E2C4142A03677280EBD8AF5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 309(k)(2), the Commission shall grant a renewal for a license issued under subsection (b), a grant of market access under subsection (c), or an authorization granted under subsection (d), upon request by an applicant for a term not to exceed the length of the initial term beginning the day after the date on which the previous license, grant of market access, or authorization expires, if the Commission determines the requirements under subsection (e) and section 309(k) have been met.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8B4A1D8C2DE422A9E3886C9BFDD82AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Commission receives a request for renewal of a license issued under subsection (b), a grant of market access under subsection (c), or an authorization granted under subsection (d), the Commission shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF3B76EC663FE4683BF712E6179D35B14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>grant or deny such renewal; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59DC9F4842EE41CFB1C78ED62D50ACE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make the determination described in section 309(k)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5A0466691574A34AD51E2FD7D237BBB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Modification of license; grant of market access</header> 
<paragraph id="HD18F4489D4C74EE882EC7676269E07CF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Major modifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (2), (3), (5), and (6), and not later than 1 year after the date on which the Commission receives a request to modify an application granted under subsection (b)(1), the Commission shall grant the request if the Commission determines the modification meets the requirement of subsection (e). The Commission may grant a request to modify an application submitted under subsection (b)(2) or subsection (c) if the Commission determines the modification meets the requirement of subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74C2C0C77E4E4034BF17ACC630D36392" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expedited treatment for minor modifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraphs (3), (5), and (6), the Commission shall grant a request made by an applicant to modify an application granted under subsection (b)(1) not later than 90 days after the date on which the Commission receives the request to modify if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HECD6847DBB284F41B4DD9EA660BC61BA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the request does not exceed the quantifiable level of protection described in subsection (h)(4); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE147F1EE1E664E8AA965AF7C947DBB19" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the request is limited only to modifications, or a class of modifications, that—</text> 
<clause id="H1579250F7666489985B19CF9193596F1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>increase transmission capacity;</text></clause> <clause id="HCAF0C46E3DF74A638C74ACE5E3F242AB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve spectral efficiency, such as by improving compression technologies;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC149E9843C3141B09E56D412DAFFBF31" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improve the orbital variance efficiency of the constellation; or</text></clause> <clause id="HC36AB95D1F4C497E85FFF4A19B1B1F57" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>otherwise do not substantially modify the constellation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9BEC374DC4EE43DF840F007C1686BD05"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency modification</header><text>If the Commission finds that there are extraordinary circumstances requiring temporary operations in the public interest and that delay in the institution of such temporary operations would seriously prejudice the public interest, the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="HB47B08A98E5B4E77BB36585471374EFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may grant a license described in subsection (b), a grant of market access described in subsection (c), or an authorization described in subsection (d), a modification of such license, grant of market access, or authorization, or renewal of such license, grant of market access, or authorization for 180 days in a manner and upon the terms the Commission shall by rule prescribe in the case of an emergency found by the Commission involving—</text> 
<clause id="HAE6BC2C6432B48FE96BCFABB9B9E075A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>danger to life or property; or</text></clause> <clause id="H47C0376D4AD94F7FBF4E88FD6F5EDF0F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an action that is necessary for the national defense or security of the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3ECF2AA2DF74669B206D4A282077454"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include with a grant made under this paragraph a statement of the reasons of the Commission for making such grant;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H11A7B17DDB9F4A67A3119B9E0B141AAE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may extend a grant made under this paragraph for periods not to exceed 180 days; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE20AC9C7A4BA4BA2B5DDF4D0432BC62D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>shall give expeditious treatment to any timely filed petition to deny such application and to any petition for rehearing of such grant filed under section 405.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5B00D1A2068B442B9EC3AF70BD67A2E0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Paragraph (2) shall not apply to a request to modify a license for—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7AA5290DC3BD4D7E9A635BBDEA215CB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the addition of an ancillary terrestrial component; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A795D69D4DB4A46BF67E00C082A6202"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modifying the service offered under the initial license granted under subsection (b) between fixed and mobile service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1553C635CBD74DC2A443457F0F289D81"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Automatic grant of certain modifications</header><text>Upon notification to the Commission, the Commission may automatically grant a request to modify an application granted under subsection (b), (c), or (d) or a covered authorization, to replace one space station (or component of such space station) with a technically similar space station (or component of such space station) previously approved by the Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEBE6FD1D074342229F9D45F18DE10D23"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The deadlines under paragraphs (1) and (2) may be extended by the Commission for a request subject to review under section 310(d).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9ED59ACB947D431EA8FB521FE3943D3F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Shared spectrum; protection from harmful interference</header> 
<paragraph id="HAB5C079F9F924CA4A8C61115591A8F9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grandfathered treatment and sunset of certain authorizations</header><text>For the duration of the covered period—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C4A4AD135CB414582727A5E04E63F0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered authorization shall not be treated as being granted under subsection (b)(1) or subsection (c)(1) (as the case may be); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD02734FE36C4B8488CBD878EC5AD241"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Commission shall protect an entity with a covered authorization from harmful interference consistent with the terms of such protection afforded before the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H241123FBCDBD43B19C368B475D27CD9E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transitional rule</header><text>After the expiration of the covered period, an entity with a covered authorization may seek renewal for a license or grant of market access under subsection (f).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBCF7EDE20CD40F298BDEAE0A5A37604"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Good faith coordination of shared spectrum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date on which the rules issued pursuant to subsection (a) take effect, a licensee of a license granted under subsection (b)(1), a grantee of market access granted under subsection (c)(1), or an entity with a covered authorization, in a spectrum band with service rules that require such licensees or grantees to share spectrum, shall make a good faith effort to coordinate the use of spectrum with any other licensee or grantee authorized in the spectrum band in which another license was granted under subsection (b)(1), another grantee was granted under subsection (c)(1), or another entity was granted authorization to use spectrum in such band.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EF711E572B3411F945C3C0DFFDE250A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protection from harmful interference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the date on which the rules issued pursuant to subsection (a) take effect, for any spectrum band in which the Commission grants a license under subsection (b)(1) or a grant of market access under subsection (c)(1), the Commission shall establish a quantifiable level of protection that a licensee of a license granted under subsection (b)(1) or a grantee of market access granted under subsection (c)(1) shall afford to any other licensee or grantee authorized in the spectrum band in which another license was granted under subsection (b)(1), another grantee was granted under subsection (c)(1), or another entity was granted authorization to use spectrum in such band.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8CBB8ED5893B478A8D74BB2E221D8397"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration required</header><text>When establishing the quantifiable level of protection described in paragraph (4), the Commission shall ensure the benefit to improved coordination among licensees and grantees outweighs any costs associated with the implementation of such protection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA49793FCD22B4701BD0BCC5AAFCC5666"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Relation to ITU radio regulations</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to require the Commission to adopt rules regarding the use of spectrum that contravene a requirement by the radio regulations of the International Telecommunication Union.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7187F0A84D3472591942C273FFD2F63" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity with a covered authorization shall not be required to submit additional information in order to retain such authorization, nor shall paragraph (1) affect any obligation of such entity under applicable law or regulation until the end of the covered period. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCD35F29C28D2458089A390116BBDC8A1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>State preemption of market entry; rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of law, no State or local government shall have any authority to regulate the entry of or the rates charged by an applicant or licensee related to a license granted under subsection (b), an applicant or grantee related to a grant of market access granted under subsection (c), or an applicant or entity related to an authorization under subsection (d), except that this subsection shall not prohibit a State from regulating the other terms and conditions of such licensee, grantee, or entity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA9FF265523DE4C54ADFD208DF267FB53"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Regulatory restraint</header> 
<paragraph id="H6960B2ACEA244C1AA359F51782162D81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation of information provided</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the requirements described in section 307(c)(2), in performing any act, making any rule or regulation, or issuing any order necessary to carry out this section, the Commission—</text> <subparagraph id="HDEF82467610643E29C82768B0B7D3F25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall limit the information required to be furnished to the Commission;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2767FFCCDBDF4A68B34A11EF75BA23AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall demonstrate the Commission has taken every reasonable step to limit the information required to be furnished to the Commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6535FC94B7D847CE82DE8CEE2907F825"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may not request additional information regarding the performance objectives established in subsection (a)(1)(A) for any case in which an applicant has demonstrated compliance with such performance objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A341519ED994832A7DD0CF52BB31BEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for petition determination</header><text>If an applicant for a license or a licensee under subsection (b) files a petition under part 1, title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) relating to information required to be furnished to the Commission under this section, the Commission shall grant or deny the petition within 90 days after the date on which the petition is filed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H787612E784DD452E8AAD31DFEDA64F32" commented="no"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H72F024A69D6C4B248461D319AB184F3D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered application</header><text> The term <term>covered application</term> means an application for a license or grant of market access to operate a system described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (b)(1) or subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (c)(1) in a processing round established before December 31, 2022, that is pending on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DB2508A94714F33AA52343022B2B11D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered authorization</header><text>The term <term>covered authorization</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8971524FCD174A0D85BB90A432C74690" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a license or grant of market access granted by the Commission to operate a system described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (b)(1) or subparagraphs (A) through (C) of subsection (c)(1) in a processing round established before December 31, 2022, that has deployed a level of service commensurate with the terms of the license or grant of market access; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26C7A7F94D5D49CEABF1D974F7CD9CE1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a license or grant of market access granted by Commission approval of a covered application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBBFA09BA70C84608ABC24B79959CE91C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered period</header><text>The term <term>covered period</term> means, with respect to a covered authorization, the period of time that begins on the date of the enactment of this section and ends on the earliest of—</text> <subparagraph id="H1F563E1BBB894516898741C0330767AC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the covered authorization expires;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB67172F860BD455BA418540937967131" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date that is 15 years after such date of enactment; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CB4483782554A799D502FF4E4D9B956" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date on which the Commission grants a request to modify the covered authorization that would be a major modification under subsection (g) if the covered authorization were a license granted under subsection (b)(1) or a grant of market access granted under subsection (c)(1).</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H29055FF9ED2F4B3D8EFE5EC1BB2A71A5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Orbital variance efficiency</header><text>The term <term>orbital variance efficiency</term> means the mean of the distance between the actual altitude of each space station and the authorized altitude for each space station authorized under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HEE0ECA8992DF4A108E35E2A07B2D7C75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relation to other law amendments</header><text>The Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8C7E2E900EB0487AB819656547147AB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 309(j)(2)—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4101D97E1A04A679E5B7D20F42CF626" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, grants of market access, authorizations,</quote> after <quote>licenses</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF671FADA97394205AFFED06199185026"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0B1557383C448A3866C1C3A5F3270C3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD13AD966E219491AB9C20591ED3B2F84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block id="HB788474C9FD64BE18A7FFACD1E037799" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H83498EA273A14F4394E420A0505B0773"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for licenses, grants of market access, or authorizations granted under section 345; or</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H16A39F7DDDD54A0D949D8DFAAC3FD53B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 309(k)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7AF8697BA752413198952E9C0737BECE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Broadcast station renewal procedures</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Renewal procedures for certain authorizations</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7D679A10E46F43E58C26872F9A856035" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HF7D8A5DF454E4C75821870CF008C48F1" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<subclause id="HC627ABBAA3EC4C2DB16226B70CECA39E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, the licensee of a license granted under section 345(b), the grantee of a grant of market access granted under section 345(c), or an entity with authorization granted under section 345(d),</quote> after <quote>broadcast station</quote>; </text></subclause> <subclause id="H9DCDD1838FCB46159F8E83118507B4D1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, grant, or authorization</quote> after <quote>such license</quote>;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD561FDAB962C4708A01A0E1F3DAB56BA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking <quote>that station</quote> and inserting <quote>that licensee, grantee, or entity</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA6F7BB3066A04E93B423CAD200C3EA70" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, grant of market access, or authorization</quote> after <quote>its license</quote>; </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HF37CF8DB1EFA482B8BB0B50027C01799" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>the station</quote> and inserting <quote>in the case of a broadcast station, the station</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H599CADE2733E4DFA961DCFD5307497FE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA803EF4CFDC440EC9BB11662B57FAFF9" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H59F1DC5EE678497BB5B006C29E392596" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HAFA90BF613984A359801013DDDDABD65" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a licensee of a license granted under section 345(b), a grantee of a grant of market access granted under section 345(c), or an entity with authorization granted under section 345(d), the licensee, grantee, or entity has served the public interest, convenience, and necessity in accordance with section 345(e);</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H61CEAD6694954C95B0B7F071DD89595C" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (C), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>, grantee, or entity</quote> after <quote>licensee</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H35DBF4067E64465EBDD95C9497DDDA89" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (D), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>, grantee, or entity</quote> after <quote>licensee</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD7A14D27BA094C7E89925222F58752B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, or the licensee of a license granted under section 345(b), the grantee of a grant of market access under section 345(c), or an entity with authorization granted under section 345(d),</quote> after <quote>broadcast station</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF9D80C53835A4B91A58E8DA75BD98493"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<clause id="H16AEDB02451F4926AFD35FD7BBE3E7AF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>that a licensee</quote> and inserting <quote>that a broadcast station, a licensee of a license granted under section 345(b), a grantee of market access granted under section 345(c), or an entity with authorization granted under section 345(d)</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="HE4BCB0158397480F9273DB296EC5A464"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or 345</quote> after <quote>section 308</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H209FFC37E79E427295209ADBEEFE3D5C" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>or under section 345 specifying the information required by the Commission under section 345(b)(3), section 345(c)(2), or section 345(d)(1) (as the case may be) of the former licensee, grantee, or entity</quote> after <quote>former licensee</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C070F9E8F4B4238BADBBCEFC98640D5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 310(b), by inserting <quote>or license, grant of market access, or authorization granted under subsection (b), (c), or (d) of section 345</quote> after <quote>radio station license</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C98D8378B3B4F29A94F2D58FB894CFE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements in the amendments made by this section apply with respect to any application submitted under subsection (b), (c), or (d) of section 345 of the Communications Act of 1934 and any request for renewal or modification under such section, as added by subsection (a), on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

