<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H452E72ADB4754DA982332E06681D1C47" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6469 IH: Refund the Police Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6469</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220121">January 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize grants for States and units of local government to reverse law enforcement efforts that have been restricted, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6EA3D07839FF4616B27AC9E8DC798505" style="OLC"><section id="HEFA23917CAB74643BE6EF4FA7C0E7FFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Refund the Police Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H57A2E838C349419BA0C3008CFA93164B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to reverse restrictions on law enforcement</header><subsection id="H9B2C6255903B4363A5FD076DF3DBD08D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, is authorized to make grants to eligible States and units of local government for the purposes described in subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFD5B36E5FB04F5CAAC775CADA06E755"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>In order to be eligible for a grant under this section, a State or unit of local government shall meet each of the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="HCFC8714796944ECF9C841CCEA6D86A81" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Law enforcement policies</header><subparagraph id="H9B81BA5E3FD24C8483517963E48540CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State or unit of local government shall certify to the Attorney General that such State or unit of local government—</text><clause id="H65E1F9776181481AB4BF72BA36F03E35"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not have in effect any law requiring a heightened standard for use of force; and</text></clause><clause id="HABD9031DE309408E87B72AED2AE60C30" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has taken steps, in the previous year, to expand efforts to hire and retain law enforcement officers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H704020CC445F4CC4A1A9EFEA9AB3272B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Heightened use of force standards defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>heightened standard for use of force</quote>—</text><clause id="H90537B17CAA142FB960C494A259660C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>means a standard requiring law enforcement officers to use more than reasonable care in determining whether to use physical force against another person; and</text></clause><clause id="H41A79AD54C6B4D10A60B15BEDF253CDA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a standard requiring a law enforcement officer to leave an area instead of using force in any case in which there is no threat of imminent harm and no crime has been committed, is being committed, or is about to be committed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA87C1B95642745088034D4FAC790F585"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Drive-by shootings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or unit of local government shall certify to the Attorney General that such State or unit of local government has not taken steps in the previous year to eliminate drive-by shooting as a basis for murder in the first degree (as defined in section 1111(a) of title 18, United States Code).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0CDFFD4A0374C71BF89F7442903AD92"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, a State or unit of local government shall submit to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including the certification described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE1633E0B1EC45A9A9F9FD2AB7EDEFC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State or unit of local government that receives a grant under this section may use the grant for the purposes described under section 1701(b) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6EB7F2F6F1E41DBBCBE8848DB1E65B8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></subsection><subsection id="H70B82A57C487422F98B721BCB16B4E9A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <quote>State</quote> and <quote>unit of local government</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 901 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

