<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H76294312FB404269B2C0CFE288551E1D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7067 IH: Closing Loopholes in Russia Sanctions Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7067</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220311">March 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to the use of cryptocurrency to facilitate transactions by Russian persons subject to sanctions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF10686455FAD4584AEBC2EFA36D1A2DE" style="OLC"><section id="HF363D19700FC42CFADC72B1EAFBC993C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Closing Loopholes in Russia Sanctions Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H268B025AFF274D82B7567453CDC4A8D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act applies to any person engaged in the business of effecting transactions in digital assets for the account of others, including any communication protocol systems or other similar systems using decentralized finance technology or other similar technology to provide transactional services, including digital wallets, digital asset trading platforms, digital asset exchanges, and digital asset mining services.</text></section><section id="H7B582DF4D6D44D44B02106EF8360F0CF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4C61F9A5CC624D0DB514478BDBA041E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital assets</header><text>The term <quote>digital assets</quote> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HA4ADD20BDFEC472595B6DD0293CAA830"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any digital representation of value which is recorded on a cryptographically secured distributed ledger or any similar technology, as specified by the Secretary of the Treasury; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D32296CAECB4E1FAA9F6BDC950AB1B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>nonfungible tokens and other digital assets using blockchain or other similar technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBC9BA05EA24D48908F52BE01D14D2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital asset exchange</header><text>The term <quote>digital asset exchange</quote> or <quote>virtual currency exchange</quote> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HBC66D106293D445F8029CC40EB507AA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity such as a State-licensed money services business or money transmitting business, as defined in section 5330 of title 31, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H587E6507C2484E2ABA997E5FE7B2F51F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a financial institution that exchanges virtual currency or digital assets.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80E80B4F5AD84C7DBC24A3CE1D08D5E4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Digital asset wallets</header><text>The term <quote>digital asset wallets</quote> mean interfaces for storing and transferring digital assets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4C7C4CEDEE42AFB5E36FC43D66D4DB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H164EDAA142204BA28AA0F89584BB1872"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Hosted wallets</header><text>The term <quote>hosted wallet</quote> means a digital account hosted by a third-party financial institution that allows the account holder to store, send, and receive cryptocurrency and digital assets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4786554DDEE5409CB65D12A8A5DDEF9C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Unhosted wallets</header><text>The term <quote>unhosted wallets</quote> means a digital wallet that is not hosted by a third-party financial system, including software hosted on a computer, phone, or other device of a person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACAF4B804FF54717B4AB9036199A47B1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H29FC2117DF8F4798A7F4B4199E8370EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who is a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7A3137F78104DF69569361C54D8B8C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H131252A9893C42809BF5355FCEF13CEC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to the use of cryptocurrency to facilitate transactions by Russian persons subject to sanctions</header><subsection id="H78B9D6413445471E955C373392722189"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE02E6952AA084F9E8828DE335C83090D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign persons described</header><text>A foreign person described in this subsection is a foreign person—</text><paragraph id="H02A8ED4D33754AA980894F70D2DB67D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that operates a digital asset exchange or is otherwise a part of the digital asset industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0975643C854E4E25A311461FD329A934"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that facilitates, directly or indirectly, transactions for any person with respect to which sanctions have been imposed by the United States for actions relating to the Russian Federation, including transactions that facilitate the evasion of such sanctions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41FF995DF7C3428CA45C026D8C787A7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="HACCC7CDB884E456A903D95AD828C541E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59C53768E2414419B752B8329823B01C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H46444B43BEA94C379D9A01282DF2B87A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><paragraph id="H296D3A04D0D54D30A5306105185B2CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirement to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property under subsection (a) shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD0BC732613448E88401EEF26E090A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC584968EE9314B81AB5E1EC259F363E4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Virtual currency exchanges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No digital asset exchange that does business in the United States shall transact with, or fulfill transactions of, hosted wallets and unhosted wallets or cryptocurrency addresses that are known to be, or could reasonably be known to be, affiliated with persons headquartered in the Russian Federation.</text></section><section id="H6B88755332D240A5A2A6E2756D4631A7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transactions reports</header><subsection id="H63F26E1736DC4E039292E02466CFAB8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall require United States taxpayers holding greater than $10,000 in cryptocurrency in accounts outside of the United States to file a report described in section 1010.350 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, using the form described in that section, in accordance with section 5314 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD53DA8E7B69E4D57BFDED1748FCEB64C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall finalize rulemaking requiring banks and money service businesses to submit reports, keep records, and verify the identity of customers in relation to transactions involving convertible virtual currency or digital assets held in unhosted wallets.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7368B96759A84C59AFCB215B17BA61F6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of the Department of the Treasury in carrying out this Act, including any resources needed by the Department to improve implementation and progress in coordinating with governments of countries that are allies or partners of the United States.</text></section><section id="H61AA8A4759DB4A81B5A11AB1AFDA51DE"><enum>8.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Sections 4 and 5 shall cease to have effect on the date on which the President certifies to Congress that all sanctions imposed by the United States with respect to the Russian Federation have terminated.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

