<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H808817F95E1A4F9B9992528A677DD0CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 8409 IH: Countering Foreign Malign Influence Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8409</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220718">July 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make certain modifications relating to the Social Media Data and Threat Analysis Center for the purpose of improving cooperative actions to detect and counter foreign influence operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1895D3A956C84F2F8A05B927AC92491F" style="OLC"><section id="H20DCDC392F8740F7A16D08FBFFE0368F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Foreign Malign Influence Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H733AC23E84DF4D66A2C9A2A6A249D4BE" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifications to Social Media Data and Threat Analysis Center</header><subsection id="H55318060ADF04F828176EF1C938A84D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FFRDC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of subsection (c) of section 5323 of the Damon Paul Nelson and Matthew Young Pollard Intelligence Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 2018, 2019, and 2020 (division E of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3369">50 U.S.C. 3369</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>or a federally funded research and development center</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7DEB7E1C142240479E77BE71EAB93A25"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of such subsection is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB1BB9565075A4F0FB40FB5EF431CEF3B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H29F74A158D2043899487A1F7B6E84D95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HDA07CE4CE3E144CE8069F7473FDB07EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Acting as a convening and sponsoring authority for social media companies, other internet companies, third-party experts, nongovernmental organizations, data journalists, federally funded research and development centers, academic researchers, traditional media, and international counterparts, as appropriate, to collectively, cooperatively, and proactively identify, analyze, and counter the threats posed by internet-based foreign malign influence activities on social media platforms and other affected internet-based platforms.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79CB0AA96D7F432C93358EC775CE583F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Facilitating tactical and strategic analysis of internet-based foreign malign influence activities, within and across the individual social media platforms or other affected public-facing online platforms, including with respect to—</text><clause id="HDD65EDCBB6B0410A82A86C2F1965D00A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hacking and leaking campaigns;</text></clause><clause id="H1A2331D275DD4D7C8EF626615189CB0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinated inauthentic behavior;</text></clause><clause id="HF2FC8874D1D74D89993884689C20709B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>manipulation of social media algorithms or search engine results;</text></clause><clause id="H58BC1A2537E6483A800B870545F309FF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>machine-manipulated media;</text></clause><clause id="HEED9199DB19E4B9189E5D692AEE74ADF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>cut-out or proxy internet platforms, blogs, or similar properties;</text></clause><clause id="H087A87C14F0C4E1396590580E3E19C79" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>fake, deceptive, or inauthentic online profiles, including accounts that consist mainly of automated actions (commonly referred to as <quote>bots</quote>);</text></clause><clause id="HC72D7426F51A47DA9AAE193CD7F427C8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>disinformation campaigns; and</text></clause><clause id="H8CA17E222165454CAEB2B6EBB4EB87BA" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any other tactics assessed as supporting foreign malign influence through internet-based covert or undeclared means, and unlawful activities that fund or subsidize such operations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0570EC4768B4814B6AD2ECFDAB3290B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing processes and best practices for sharing relevant information, indicators, and findings about internet-based foreign malign influence activities among elements of the United States Government and the individual social media platforms and other public-facing internet-based platforms to inform threat analysis and provide timely warning of such foreign malign influence activities, working with the Office of the Director of National Intelligence as appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22555F46EBB74FDE8621D7E56E022D45"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Developing and making public criteria for identifying which stakeholders qualify for inclusion in the activities of the Center, and inviting entities that fit the criteria to join or otherwise participate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BBCD8C9F6A14B2B85D3DA4284FF59B2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determining jointly with social media companies and other public-facing internet-based platforms what categories of data and metadata related to indicators of internet-based foreign malign influence activities from their platforms and business operations will be made available for access and analysis by participants of the Center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFBE7AA03AD149C0BD583FCB6B732927"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing and making public the criteria and standards for data handling, data security, and data privacy that must be met for participants of the Center to access and analyze data relating to internet-based foreign malign influence activities within and across social media or other public-facing internet-based platforms, and to publish or otherwise use the results.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H202C666E765E406DB6D91374C80B5E8E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Developing and making public the ethical standards for—</text><clause id="H4E0B822428464D4295089C11B2042CB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>investigation of internet-based foreign malign influence activities;</text></clause><clause id="H4C294BD5BA6B4EA88059562E01949A41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of indicators, findings, or analyses relating to such activities;</text></clause><clause id="H93025674BF464C588E75ECB724C69547"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the protection of the privacy, civil liberties, and constitutionally protected activities of the customers and users of the social media platforms and public-facing internet-based platforms; and</text></clause><clause id="H9F7867ED6F1748BF88A97841CC7F9F80"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the protection the proprietary information of the social media companies and other affected internet-based platforms.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7C6FC21C34244109B4282D2D8AEB7C5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Developing technical, contractual, and procedural controls to prevent misuse of data, including any necessary auditing procedures, compliance checks, and review mechanisms.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FC0FD40146646078223011A4F79B500"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing and making public criteria and conditions under which social media platforms and other affected public-facing internet-based platforms shall proactively share with the appropriate elements of the United States Government data, metadata, or indicators pertaining to assessed internet-based foreign malign influence activities, including such criteria and conditions that address—</text><clause id="H4DC63252B2254013ADBEC990416F4252"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the timeliness and consistency with which social media platforms or other affected public-facing internet-based platforms shall share such data, metadata, or indicators (including with respect to real-time sharing);</text></clause><clause id="H340B2DF8C6AC443F9A0A6572D214463E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the categories of data, metadata, and indicators to be shared, including with respect to the activities specified in subparagraph (B); and</text></clause><clause id="HD892C04AE4254DAFBC743CAF330AB850"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the protection of the privacy, civil liberties, and constitutionally protected activities of users and customers of social media platforms and other public-facing internet-based platforms.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H358B28651D9E44599901B4DA9D6BCD75"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Hosting a searchable archive aggregating information related to foreign influence and disinformation operations to—</text><clause id="HDF4993999E8547C19D964E3E494A17D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>build a collective understanding of internet-based foreign malign influence activities; and</text></clause><clause id="H0886BBC410FB4213BFE977F9E84E740A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate future examination consistent with privacy and civil liberties protections for users and customers of social media platforms and other public-facing internet-based platforms.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AFE42CE3FD74765889C5C120466E382"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Developing data standards and protocols to harmonize and facilitate the timely sharing of information pursuant to this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

