<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFF810B4D403F4FD782A5AE1A1A17E864" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6464 IH: Hear our Heroes Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6464</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Vel&#225;zquez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to establish a presumption of service-connection for certain veterans with tinnitus or hearing loss, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4AF81EB52BF343699EDA32131C8A66E8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBCD005506FF64ABDB5EBC2E422C12559" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hear our Heroes Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA95D789C4CCE4C44A821242673678351" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Presumption of service-connection for hearing loss and tinnitus</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1112 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3791A894E92F465483BA8EABC383C8DC" style="USC">
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDAC69D357D064769817E34EF3EA3A0C0"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2827AFF38F7B40BAA84644F2F8321549"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1110 of this title, and subject to the provisions of section 1113 of this title, diagnosed hearing loss, tinnitus, or both of a veteran described in paragraph (2) shall be considered to have been incurred in or aggravated by the active military, naval, or air service of the veteran, notwithstanding that there is no record of evidence of such hearing loss or tinnitus, as the case may be, during the period of such service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC894B6D610C4E17B4BEB936D9715F18" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A veteran described in this paragraph is a veteran who while on active military, naval, or air service—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0334935420414760BF773064EBFFB471"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was assigned to a military occupational specialty or equivalent described in paragraph (3); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC47FC043EFA04F43845B0796604B5C0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>served in combat.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF7FBE92F6514DD6A14FA575B648BC7B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A military occupational specialty or equivalent referred to in paragraph (2)(A) is a military occupational specialty or equivalent in which individuals assigned to such military occupational specialty or equivalent in the active military, naval, or air service are or were likely to be exposed to a sufficiently high level of acoustic trauma as to result in permanent hearing loss, tinnitus, or both, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H7BFC178503D34D5C9016544B0120EFD3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modification to schedule for rates for disability compensation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Pursuant to section 1155 of title 38, United States Code, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall adjust the schedule of rating disabilities to establish a minimum disability rating for a veteran who requires a hearing aid because of a service-connected disability, including pursuant to section 1112(d) of such title, as amended by section 2.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

