<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7104F9EF54124801AEDFEF2D98EE9537" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8880 IH: Multilingual Financial Literacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8880</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Financial Literacy and Education Commission to carry out a study on the impact of language barriers to financial health, to require the website and toll-free telephone number of the Commission to be provided in the most commonly spoken languages in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H62EEC114769D44138EB49871057DFE40" style="OLC"><section id="H8EB35A6BF2374742BA5F4462C455982E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Multilingual Financial Literacy Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HDB1928A9498B444B932FD11E96B35DD2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on the impact of language barriers to financial health</header><subsection id="H389909835D0F43DDBBB2FE53A10B7C2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Financial Literacy and Education Commission shall carry out a study on the impact of language barriers to financial health, including access to financial literacy education and training, credit score outcomes, the cost of credit, and homebuying across groups with limited English proficiency.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFFD05478BC7F4D269B38AB44F2B8105E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the study required under subsection (a), the Financial Literacy and Education Commission shall consult with every agency represented on the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA026BA8BCFF94826966D51DAE5C94CAC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Financial Literacy and Education Commission shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate—</text><paragraph id="HFA84540DED22469D93C7D7263016BB2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">containing all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50759F44348D44DBB99686905B208BC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyzing the need for language accessibility across the financial services industry, including an identification of any industries in which information is provided solely in one language, highlighting any products, services, or other financial offerings with information which is limited in their availability beyond English.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAC6050D2BB59464B8BD8C337B4E8CDB4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Language access to Commission website and toll-free telephone number</header><subsection id="H7F54428B8629465E80C2EC7D9E5F9BA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 514 of the Financial Literacy and Education Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9703">20 U.S.C. 9703</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB9606D24E7A14002AA106EBF9EA66EB2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H75BD8AE4AA0740AD8AE598AB307B6B27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA92E6CAD26B94FAB8BCE191BA7D25187"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B21E18370CE499B8190E69A22AED83B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H88CD88A9D85E4DD488FCFC2790E852EB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD6C6C1B621544D3FA64D0CD2E6099D87"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be provided in at least 8 of the most commonly spoken languages in the United States, as determined by the Bureau of the Census.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1AE378968254479B6358D113B86F8F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD00A059158CC4413A311F36536D23E57" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HD2E734FBEDC94F939A60D4BE5EAEE629"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information on language resources from Federal agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The website established under paragraph (1) shall contain a separate website that provides—</text><subparagraph id="H52608E4097084FDA9C1E33B99A2CD4EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on which Federal agencies provide financial literacy and education resources in languages other than English, including which resources are available in which languages; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4DA293DD8E44BBEA10F53F196D2AF26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance on where individuals can find Federal agency resources in a particular language for various topic areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA13402D4C641E6BADF69EA97068E45"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Translation services provided by the Department of the Treasury</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the translation services necessary to comply with the language requirement under paragraph (2)(F).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA770A68C2B9E478A8276A1C648A94E4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The toll-free telephone number shall provide verbal assistance to members of the public in each of the 8 most commonly spoken languages in the United States, as determined by the Bureau of the Census. The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the staff necessary to comply with such language requirement.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4FA7A78EEE441B581C321187BEA0F57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66E19BBBA39F4F57A99DBCE7521FD7E9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HC4925762A9464AD1816EBF32259BEEC6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Language access to Federal agency information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall coordinate and promote efforts of Federal agencies to make all financial literacy and education resources of Federal agencies available in each of the 8 most commonly spoken languages in the United States, as determined by the Bureau of the Census.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3848356B3E6A43AA80B4E08298EC9C2B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The provisions of law added by this section shall apply after the end of the 1-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0628206448194E55AEF7E0CB670AD56C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Policy recommendations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 12-month period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Financial Literacy and Education Commission shall issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate containing—</text><paragraph id="H01A6C9DD72EF4A33AF7B6459CBA1A5EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">legislative and regulatory recommendations on how to address barriers to financial inclusion caused by language barriers, including financial literacy education and training and the role that emerging technology and financial products play in helping or harming communities with limited English proficiency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H663F795F571D4243AA4FDA2B6AA02D64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a summary of—</text><subparagraph id="HB52CA797814D433DB6AB6258B6ACC9F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the actions taken by the Commission to implement the amendments made by section 3; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B7C497D5565473A8CD69040ECBEFF30"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any actions taken by individual Federal agencies that are members of the Commission to make financial literacy and education resources of the agency available to the public in each of the 8 most commonly spoken languages in the United States, as determined by the Bureau of the Census; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE04732757624B15BD888778B5B141EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of the cost needed—</text><subparagraph id="H9E27CECA6657484783380E9F7D160CBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to implement the amendments made by section 3; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48CFC840EEDF4F20B94D704A0B5EA3CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for each Federal agency that is a member of the Commission to make financial literacy and education resources of the agency available to the public in each of the 8 most commonly spoken languages in the United States, as determined by the Bureau of the Census.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H9A5E89E857BD4428A7D6926E9E67E5DC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Annual report on financial literacy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 514(h)(2) of the Financial Literacy and Education Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/9703">20 U.S.C. 9703(h)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HADC5CFEE32E747EDA6061C40228D3D5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC20AF6CF358D4CFD82A4EDD37CFEE002"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (J) as subparagraph (O); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4A0EB874103461ABCF5D05CA58566D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (I) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF91F2643747B4612A56F72B9086BE577" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HB1489F13D0C645E1A12E9BFE6B902AAA"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the Commission’s efforts over the previous year to increase financial literacy across all member agencies of the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93B9C774A4E74B98A8CBE2C55CA48D50"><enum>(K)</enum><text>an analysis of where there are financial literacy needs across different groups, including information by age group, socioeconomic status, race, ethnicity, and language preference;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64048555C8D54730852A23AECEAAC834"><enum>(L)</enum><text>an analysis of limited access to credit and disparate credit scoring across different groups, including information by age group, gender, sexual orientation, socioeconomic status, race, ethnicity, and language preference;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB233124F5044CCE87F7B455D19CD01C"><enum>(M)</enum><text>an explanation of how a lack of financial literacy, systemic barriers, and other obstacles result in a wealth gap across different groups, including information by age group, gender, sexual orientation, socioeconomic status, race, ethnicity, and language preference;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C4141D2786A4A7281731086AB0686BA"><enum>(N)</enum><text>proposals and potential policy solutions for addressing barriers to financial literacy, disparate credit scoring, and the wealth gap; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

