<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H264F3B9FBA434B99965B68A37D527915"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9022 IH: Shifting Forward Vehicle Technologies Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9022</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support research, development, demonstration, and other activities to develop innovative vehicle technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id58007A3B99B549F7BFFDFD2DE14D4844" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Shifting Forward Vehicle Technologies Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idEE88926F9C15448B9026B45CDC52C0EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="idE46C8CC5A4AD4FF2B61C79CF56E9D344"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative fuel</header><text>The term <term>alternative fuel</term> means a fuel that results in a significant reduction in lifecycle greenhouse gas (GHG) and criteria air pollutant emissions compared to conventional fuel options.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id98A56AA34A384047AC598D12F5B17785"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extreme fast charging</header><text>The term <term>extreme fast charging</term> means recharging up to 80 percent of battery capacity in approximately 10 minutes or less.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEC32E00EAA9443F3A13D7CF9B2D1EF2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sustainable materials</header><text>The term <term>sustainable materials</term> means materials used throughout the consumer and industrial economy that can be produced in required volumes without depleting nonrenewable resources and without disrupting the established steady-state equilibrium of the environment and key natural resource systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3F841107C62E40A2896DA2C8A17B28A7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3A8E30FED4924ACCB5B058157EABD368"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id3809D162FF3F4D728BA6CB4A097B4CF2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting on the development of certain technologies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act and every two years thereafter through 2027, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing—</text><paragraph id="id735760F704A34E728F1CF937C556C8E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the activities undertaken pursuant to this Act, including—</text><subparagraph id="idC9F875ED800B4B4FB725D3C5558434BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the status of public-private partnerships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95D44DA189D048AD9368C8F9670FF5F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>progress of the programs under sections 4, 6, 8, and 12 in meeting goals and timelines; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4548AB5B7EBE418EB643CD542EBE9C4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a strategic plan for funding of activities across agencies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idB2E4ECD1ECB04F6096AFC8ECACC80E95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the technologies and knowledge developed and demonstrated as a result of such activities, with a particular emphasis on whether such technologies were successfully adopted for commercial applications, and if so, whether products relying on such technologies are manufactured in the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id8CFE491D54804AF6B13E3E6AF84BC923"><enum>4.</enum><header>Advanced vehicle research and development program</header><subsection id="id6874262360B841B19BA3B4C0A3D46390"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a research, development, and demonstration program of advanced vehicle technologies on more efficient, sustainable, and domestically available materials and manufacturing processes with the potential to—</text><paragraph id="id731DFBF2D6654823BCD12630658A2DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>substantially reduce or eliminate greenhouse gas emissions from the manufacture and use of passenger and commercial vehicles; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2CE8406A88954A538FE6BC0BA88866C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduce the cost of vehicle manufacturing and ownership.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF4CB30D73D6A4D23B247D3E46224A9BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program components</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall coordinate with the activities authorized under section 137 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17014">42 U.S.C. 17014</external-xref>; relating to research and development into integrating electric vehicles onto the electric grid) and subsection (q) of section 641 of the United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17231">42 U.S.C. 17231</external-xref>; enacted as subtitle D of title VI of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007; relating to the establishment of a critical material recycling and reuse research, development, and demonstration program), and with the heads of relevant Federal agencies to determine a comprehensive set of technical milestones for such activities and focus on research and development challenges across the vehicle supply chain including, to the maximum extent practicable, activities in the areas of—</text><paragraph id="id891066AED5C74445B3AE48FEB39F664A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>electrification of vehicle systems, including compact and efficient electric drivetrain systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id17FD5C56475A46E4A2C4AA22E1A71A38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>power electronics, electric machines, and electric machine drive systems, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id4F511A752CB644EDA6A6F164669C1F37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>electronic motors, including advanced inverters and motors that can be used for passenger vehicles and commercial vehicles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1A37DD1F02B744D1B9DFB70A2A02D3B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>magnetic materials, including permanent magnets with reduced or no critical materials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id8461D8036EAB4B12A915E0A91A32436E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving partial load efficiency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idAE3080926DD04FA2BE517531C28E6BD0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>design of power electronics and electric motor technologies that enable efficient recycling of critical materials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84E31ED67EBA4A3D8DBCBA35E0D2F72A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assessing potential impacts of various vehicle systems on electric propulsion performance, including potential impacts from AM/FM radio frequencies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id1CA29F2CDD0C4DBB8EFFE9D47232E29D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>vehicle batteries and relevant systems, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idE1C36328212F40B2AA7EF354FA95BDEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advanced batteries systems, ultracapacitors, and other competitive energy storage devices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id186468CDA0B44AB7A452C88A53E7E555"><enum>(B)</enum><text>common interconnection protocols, specifications, and architecture for both transportation and stationary battery applications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0CF0E478F1DA43839B42A5C99C0B8B35"><enum>(C)</enum><text>energy density and capacity, recharging robustness, extreme fast charging and wireless charging capabilities, and efficiencies to lower cost;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDBDD8613802345CAA212F6D0E9CC9BC5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lifetime improvement and reduction of potential lifecycle impacts from advanced batteries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB2035427479A4A4FA3A99FDD8FE7B5C9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>improving efficient use and reuse, substitution, and recycling of critical materials in vehicles, including rare earth elements and precious metals, at risk of supply disruption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1EEA900B0B354166AC32F6E212BD0CB6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advanced battery protection systems for safe handling of high voltage power and thermal management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1BA1F59E6D964CD3BAD0ED47E4FE2808"><enum>(G)</enum><text>technologies enabling flexible manufacturing facilities that can accommodate different vehicle battery chemistries and configurations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1530A36420C44D1785FF7BF4ACA6DC7E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>improving the efficiency and safety of the manufacturing of advanced batteries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id08115E221FCE47D39430ED108CBFE213"><enum>(4)</enum><text>vehicle components and systems, including manufacturing technologies and processes, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id85AC25654FDD421AB7624CDFC4A80EFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing or repurposing waste streams, reducing emissions, and energy intensity of vehicle, engine, and advanced battery manufacturing processes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBE3869CB9B9F4888A8051314657ECA5A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increasing the production rate and decreasing the cost of advanced battery and hydrogen fuel cell manufacturing, including purpose-built hydrogen fuel cell vehicles, hydrogen fueling infrastructure, and components;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0A27620019DA4F04BBBF11E1FB51BE75"><enum>(5)</enum><text>hybrid and alternative fuel vehicles and fuel pathways, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id290322BA27274A6DB04814110F5EBC42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>vehicle fuel cells and relevant systems, including power electronics systems to regulate fuel cell voltages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4F776DA5F9CD407AB303CB81E337F671"><enum>(B)</enum><text>synthetic fuels from recycled carbon dioxide and net-zero carbon liquid fuels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6F633775B21F42E29AAFC3FD60557248"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advanced biofuel technologies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idBC8C41CE631247E48F0EEB98873F05CC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>lubricants and accessory power loads for hybrid and electric vehicles aftertreatment technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3B2A59224783443EBEA7DA1B7DEEFF34"><enum>(7)</enum><text>vehicle weight reduction, which may include the development of—</text><subparagraph id="id2612A63DEC8E4769AAD9C564778B323B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>more sustainable and cost-effective lightweight materials; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id706611DD8D28445EACE5112374970A93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>higher efficiency manufacturing processes, such as additive manufacturing, to produce sustainable lightweight materials and fabricate, assemble, and use dissimilar materials, including—</text><clause id="idDA79577581AA4D688ED332EB8080BB60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lightweight systems which combine several existing vehicle components; and</text></clause><clause id="idB9CF887BAB674672BBB9DD5DD0B5811E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>voluntary, consensus-based standards for strategic lightweight materials;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id61F49BC4814B41F5962AEC019D80D84A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>improved vehicle recycling methods to increase the recycled material content of feedstocks used in raw material manufacturing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90B31D6A4B374681B3B8FB777C00FBF7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>vehicle propulsion systems, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="id3F29D59202134335A5880D80622E1255"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engine and component durability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1B61BF0918DA4205AADB14FFCDB65D74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engine down speeding;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4D7404F010414CCDBB45BE376279DFC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advanced internal combustion engines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCDD05901C38044F782F2F927B18F9870"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transmission gear and engine operation matching; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idACC23DE4A08848BC831A060ABA79A953"><enum>(E)</enum><text>advanced transmission technologies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id871931D1D7E4467FBBEF4B4DB6FD4710"><enum>(10)</enum><text>applying advanced computing resources to large, voluntarily provided industry datasets from providers and cities to support the development of predictive engineering, modeling, and simulation of components, vehicle, and transportation systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCD647D90ACA641709AEFFB81ED180B28"><enum>(11)</enum><text>leveraging the use of machine learning toward manufacturing and additive manufacturing optimization, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idBB825EECEF85442DAFA713AA39A0D78F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessing the efficiency and safety of manufacturing processes;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2A601BB31FD643C1BF2DCC954FE9FA80"><enum>(12)</enum><text>advanced computing systems, including energy efficient systems, technology, and networking for vehicular on-board, off-board, and edge computing applications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4A7FE4CBEF0E479FA11AE3974D97DC73"><enum>(13)</enum><text>assessing automation in both vehicle and infrastructure systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idEF6DACC5579147FC93B67B1B3FA14AAA"><enum>(14)</enum><text>infrastructure, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idF7384A360D5A454AA5E011EF421E8633"><enum>(A)</enum><text>refueling and charging infrastructure for alternative fueled and electric drive or plug-in electric hybrid vehicles, with consideration for the unique challenges facing urban and rural areas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD0EA95CD88A34B069735F3335D3938B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>extreme fast charging, including through wired and wireless charging systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id055478F51F1B4CC5B1B8D38B9CCEBB2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>integration, bidirectional capability, and operational optimization of vehicle electrification for light, medium, and heavy duty with the charging infrastructure and the electric grid; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2EB30A60EF964BCBA78EDC70DD9C115E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sensing, communications, and actuation technologies for vehicle, electric grid, and infrastructure, which may include—</text><clause id="idE5147257104048CDA94557CB0F62A0F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>communication, onboard sensing, and connectivity among vehicles, infrastructure, pedestrians, and the electrical grid;</text></clause><clause id="idD9524346307F420F8A2CCEEED4F676E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assessing the use of autonomous vehicles or connectivity to improve roadway throughput; and</text></clause><clause id="id2683A138701E468597881D93B6824EA5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>research autonomous refueling and charging technologies and infrastructure;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2F66BB308F1E4073B6D4C03207FB2174"><enum>(15)</enum><text>retrofitting advanced vehicle technologies to existing vehicles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94FF36DE5C9546AEB5C1D54F95271F7B"><enum>(16)</enum><text>informing and educating the public on the energy benefits of automation and connected vehicle technologies, connected infrastructure assets, and mobility applied sensors to build trust and acceptance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id939328D078E44D9DAD4AA2E1A13E438B"><enum>(17)</enum><text>reusing valuable components and materials, such as permanent magnets and other electric drive components for advanced vehicles; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idBEB77007825F4AD58D56DEA8BDFC93A8"><enum>(18)</enum><text>transportation system analysis to further understand the energy implications and opportunities of advanced mobility solutions, communication, and connectivity among vehicles, infrastructure, pedestrians, and the electrical grid.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id1FEF9FC2A3014335A3622DAAE6B034A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nonroad transportation environmental and technical assistance research</header><paragraph id="id5C895618F23E4B20BFA03FE335B8780C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in carrying out the program established under subsection (a), and in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall support research, development, and demonstration activities to address and reduce nonroad sector emissions from transportation fuels used in aviation, rail, and maritime technologies and other relevant technologies. Such activities may be carried out primarily by an Energy Innovation Hub established under section 206 of the Department of Energy Research Coordination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18632">42 U.S.C. 18632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id29772594FC1C43038DD7A2F72F5D50F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the research, development, and demonstration activities under paragraph (1) shall be to—</text><subparagraph id="id865A02155B534E3794A54B3B8D31DD15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify, study, evaluate, test, and demonstrate emerging transformational nonroad vehicle energy technologies and practices to improve environmental performance to meet Federal and international standards and guidelines, including reducing greenhouse gas emissions, water emissions, or other particulate or toxic emissions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2E525787BC2340038B32982E39F0D89A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advance research, development, and demonstration activities to—</text><clause id="id4243502962D54DD884028A7EAA0FFA10"><enum>(i)</enum><text>overcome barriers in transformational nonroad vehicle energy technologies, including alternative fuels such as hydrogen, components, and other energy technologies to improve total machine or system efficiency for nonroad mobile equipment; and</text></clause><clause id="id4270B3AD1E154CE9A55B32C20F6721BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>increase the fuel economy and use of alternative fuels and alternative energy;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id078ACCE35C7943319B203B69A57450B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support opportunities to transfer relevant research findings and technologies between the nonroad and on-highway equipment and vehicle sectors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id738C44C3422543899DA7DD4D874945A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>test relevant precommercial technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idF2A0CD7C512D45DD9B7C3A3C9056366A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary may coordinate the research, development, and demonstration activities under paragraph (1) with activities—</text><subparagraph id="id81F403AF330F4F12B7257A722FBB735B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that are associated with the development or approval of validation and testing regimes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE7AAEBF4D91547DE9254B2801C126D89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>related to certification or validation of emerging energy technologies or practices that demonstrate significant environmental or other benefits to domestic non-road transportation industries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id3FC4DCA4BEEC4A58B105680BAEF65480"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements, contracts, or other agreements with academic, public, private, and nongovernmental entities and facilities to carry out the activities under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id47DFF50215D144C6B5AFE55E722AAAF0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transformational nonroad vehicle technology defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>transformational nonroad vehicle technology</term> means an innovative technology that—</text><subparagraph id="id5FF0BA729FAF46DF837FAA65769DB026"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enables advanced nonroad transportation, nonroad transportation components, and related energy technologies that have the potential to produce significantly lower emissions and greater energy savings than current commercial technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC65671C4F4C24D7C8459B59C2A53D92B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enables improved or expanded supply and production of domestic emission reducing fuels and components; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idE29BA26333F0486383657D0F014998D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensures the long term, secure, and sustainable supply of critical materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id03900F4D41FF4AF8BF1279F58F94ECE0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standard of review</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically review activities carried out under this section to determine the achievement of technical milestones as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="idE7FCC9BC81C444F48B361776EF8B79E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technology testing and metrics</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary, in coordination with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall— </text><paragraph id="idF19FD3D5B188492A957C1D9F31A8081C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop voluntary, consensus-based standard testing procedures, methodologies, and best practices for evaluating the performance of advanced vehicle technologies, including heavy vehicle technologies under a range of representative duty cycles and operating conditions, including for electrified and hydrogen fuel cell systems; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7380F566AD6844049C4C2B2642EC8628"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluate advanced vehicle performance, including heavy vehicle and nonroad vehicle performance using work performance-based metrics.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id14102725B44B4E71A218BA0548521C4E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Advanced on-road vehicle security program</header><subsection id="id89918037E8054C4E919F7E379582545F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the program under section 4, the program authorized under section 137 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17014">42 U.S.C. 17014</external-xref>), and the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall establish a research and development program focused on the cybersecurity and physical security of interconnections between vehicles, vehicle energy storage systems, charging equipment, buildings, and the electric grid for plug-in electric vehicles, connected vehicles, autonomous, and other relevant vehicles, including the security impacts, efficiency, and safety of plug-in electric vehicles using alternating current charging, high-power direct current fast charging, and extreme fast charging.</text></subsection><subsection id="id1868B15F32E64A3EAA9FBC126D816F7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a 5- to 10-year impact assessment of emergent cybersecurity threats and vulnerabilities to the United States on-road transportation system and connected infrastructure by identifying—</text><paragraph id="idB2396A45BFD74A5CBFA90D8C7C6E1362"><enum>(1)</enum><text>areas of research with respect to which Federal cross-agency research coordination and cooperation may help address such threats and vulnerabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA29A5810B9FB43729E9D01E7C51C7A9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>current research and challenges associated with cyber-physical protection and resiliency of electric and connected and automated vehicle technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="idC04A1142E37F4E88A36909D1D848AE29"><enum>6.</enum><header>Vehicle energy storage system safety program</header><subsection id="idE1AB36A65B04486DA4446FBC5F1521B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In coordination with the program under section 4, the Secretary shall support a program of research, development, and demonstration of vehicle energy storage safety and reliability.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6EB1E3192AFF4A93A696F9FC6B330B19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall support activities to—</text><paragraph id="idF5EF69CF2C364F3F84E24CEAE3A3B077"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine the mechanisms that lead to vehicle energy storage system safety and reliability incidents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0E88C4D280B245F8A6D8A58561BE6BDB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop new materials to improve overall vehicle energy storage system safety and abuse tolerance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4E179B5E361B48F48BAB322977EAF1E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>perform abuse testing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id94A69CC103B04901835F9AFFE5208169"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advance and perform testing techniques;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id11FA66EB5739493485388E99BC5C5396"><enum>(5)</enum><text>demonstrate detailed failure analyses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idE17FCDA1E8C34D80A4FC54F3BFC89DF4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>mitigate vehicle energy storage cell and system failures, including hydrogen fuel storage tanks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5F54B59654654F028B310C0ECF006F66"><enum>(7)</enum><text>develop crush-induced battery safety protocols and technical standards to improve robustness.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8040B4A02DF843D8BF079E0CB2FF30CF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Advanced Vehicle Technologies Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="id5B35F12D89104A808B2B6BD2F4EACE95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish the Advanced Vehicle Technologies Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>advisory committee</quote>) to advise the Secretary on vehicle technology and mobility system research advancements. The advisory committee shall be composed of not fewer than 15 members, including representatives of research and academic institutions, environmental organizations, industry, and nongovernmental entities, including relevant labor organizations and associations representing automobile manufacturers, who are qualified to provide advice on the research, development, and demonstration activities under this Act (in this section referred to as the <quote>DOE Vehicle Program</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="id4DA7ACDDCF0F47E781DD91544D585157"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The advisory committee shall assess—</text><paragraph id="idCDAA2499472645BC98122DE901F786A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the current state of United States competitiveness in advancing vehicle technologies and mobility systems, including—</text><subparagraph id="id7135F8671D7E436E8ACFE949C871AD6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the scope and scale of United States investments in sustainable and advanced transportation research, development, and demonstration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id23A29A27A2B94548968FAB08102A65C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the scope and scale of research, development, and demonstration activities to lower vehicle and fuel lifecycle greenhouse gas emissions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8F1BA2BABC8C45EC978BE440FB5CCF60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>progress made in implementing the DOE Vehicle Program, including progress toward meeting the technical milestones as determined by the Secretary pursuant to section 4;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id595879C7ED004757B49533B0DE1AC723"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the balance of research and development activities and funding across the DOE Vehicle Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id77E7A89B246042EFA748B60409AF8039"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the management, coordination, implementation, and activities of the DOE Vehicle Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAE930136B59D47B9A6BD84F31D3596ED"><enum>(5)</enum><text>whether environmental, safety, security, and other appropriate issues are adequately addressed by the DOE Vehicle Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD9D77B0C0A1A4C21962151D02333E959"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other relevant topics as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id8F2B66BE70014098A9D66E18B0C3A1FC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act and not less frequently than once every three years thereafter, the advisory committee shall submit to the Secretary, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on—</text><paragraph id="id6D35884F74CB47648A14233F20205B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the findings of the advisory committee’s assessments under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id516412C3431C485188ED01BF8775E502"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the advisory committee’s recommendations for ways to improve or revise the DOE Vehicle Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC8CDDD69E9954C3B9BEEA670FB0D3A39"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application of Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>Section 14 of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the advisory committee.</text></subsection></section><section id="idB67D849BF2684BC39198F54B4092A31F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Medium- and heavy-duty commercial and transit vehicles program</header><subsection id="id2CA53559DA3F4B0F9F82A5045FCDFE29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with relevant research and development programs carried out by other relevant Federal agencies and appropriate industry stakeholders, including relevant labor organizations, shall carry out a program of research, development, and demonstration activities on advanced energy technologies for medium- to heavy-duty commercial, vocational, recreational, and transit vehicles, including, to the maximum extent practicable, activities in the areas of—</text><paragraph id="idF0DEE58845BD4F9794B1B167F5B41641"><enum>(1)</enum><text>vehicle engines, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="idAA7544818F774E14855E0ABF95D2DF5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engine efficiency, emission controls, and combustion research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id51353D53DA9A4AA886F58699E49A8163"><enum>(B)</enum><text>energy and space-efficient emissions control systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id863D713DACA443B8BA419CA7B4D2B40D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>engine idle and parasitic energy loss reduction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id0C3FF92C852A4EDAA87A14B6B51AE178"><enum>(D)</enum><text>advanced internal combustion engines; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id985765E193B940DA913FB786F3547AC7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>engine down speeding;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id80C37BAC878A4F548C47856ED362CD7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>electric drive trains, including—</text><subparagraph id="idBEB739AB0D9A4089AB6A782BA264C3AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>durable highly efficient power electronics and electric machinery research;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81EE9EAE54CB49B59A98B9C224459075"><enum>(B)</enum><text>partial load efficiency improvements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id26D1A21C1DCA467AA39D40D3D5527387"><enum>(C)</enum><text>control and coordination research for electric drive systems using multiple electric motors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1BB167E4C2D846A2B590379B20ED8D34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>regenerative braking to recoup braking energy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id84565A5895A0488AB13F1E71ADAB4862"><enum>(E)</enum><text>high fidelity modeling to accelerate design and adoption of electrified commercial vehicles;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id04CB2089279A451D8CDDCD2F6EC4E396"><enum>(3)</enum><text>friction and wear reduction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id10BFB3445D2B42ABB8512AF8B07821F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>improved aerodynamics and tire rolling resistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74C7B670813E4FA2884C666C98FAD17F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>advanced lightweighting materials and vehicle designs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7CCBE24F1CCD437299456672563D5046"><enum>(6)</enum><text>synthetic fuels from recycled CO<subscript>2</subscript> and other net-zero carbon liquid fuels;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9522D2EFA4FF44F38421126F2C419DA1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>vehicle batteries, including—</text><subparagraph id="idF078BB8A7F2D40BC92D60AE3BC6D7243"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complete vehicle and battery pack modeling, simulation, and testing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCF4C6E9328F041D08B1C26CEE8E0EAF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>thermal management of battery systems;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id2A172C5D20504CE884BA7657823D4742"><enum>(8)</enum><text>mild hybrid, heavy hybrid, plug-in hybrid, and electric platforms, and energy storage technologies, including—</text><subparagraph id="idEF3712E9BBBC49839C90E0968490B5BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and developing solutions for technical barriers to advance batteries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF78D8A40C37F437BB56D3A5EACB3AB52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>electric drive systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4F3D568375714AD28280F4C3BC9F2159"><enum>(C)</enum><text>charging and refueling systems for medium-duty goods and heavy-duty freight delivery vehicles;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id77063FA18F6A4559BE6340E43B159FB4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>vehicle components, including—</text><subparagraph id="id8A1F9E8B31C343AF99DD39AB435E8E91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transmission and drivetrain optimization, including compact and efficient electric drivetrain systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id1F9CE75D53A349E9BD244FEB39FAFA14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>waste heat recovery and conversion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id62F8A83667FF4B8C95839A244D188044"><enum>(C)</enum><text>electrification of steering systems, braking systems, and accessory loads;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id45521C56062341FDAA00EB1D3C44F9BB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>onboard sensing, computing, and communications technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF054B94AF0424F92A4BA845925E8C571"><enum>(E)</enum><text>advanced battery protection systems for safe handling of high voltage power;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idD35414BC9D4B4A118D80D1794D0C93FA"><enum>(10)</enum><text>relevant infrastructure, including bidirectional capability, beyond megawatt charging, and increasing load capacity per vehicle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70DB4271E6244642BBF4F9D4B0F2EE16"><enum>(11)</enum><text>recharging infrastructure and compressed natural gas infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id141F67DC679340F08C58FCF9746E1BF6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>hydrogen vehicle technologies, including—</text><subparagraph id="idCEF011C991EE413D9A4EE44E499CA4ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fuel cells;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id39BF856D9746435DA1615D4D5936D543"><enum>(B)</enum><text>hydrogen fueling infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC6D1EE9700FC4E4E938EFE2B6A4110B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development of medium and heavy-duty refueling equipment design and concepts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9B6367A7A8B04318833E1A28B3E19B43"><enum>(D)</enum><text>synthetic fuels;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCCB4FD33EDCE4014BFC65C7D1996986A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>onboard technologies for compressed and other advanced hydrogen storage systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3514E40B8A134716B04A56C20702E5F7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>advanced cooling technologies for fuel cell thermal management;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id63804D3DDF1B4BE18B860488D601C442"><enum>(13)</enum><text>retrofitting advanced energy technologies onto existing truck and bus fleets;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id833EE7752D4B4B1A82C5657F894670B7"><enum>(14)</enum><text>assessment of automated and connected vehicle technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6752B7E3215840CA9C7D5422277E30F3"><enum>(15)</enum><text>energy use strategies, including charging patterns that minimize impacts on the distribution grid and optimize the use of clean, low-cost generation resources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3076B20F721B4A4DBC41C409E7EDEE83"><enum>(16)</enum><text>integration of advanced systems onto a single truck and trailer platform or bus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id951C3B99E7994C47BBB9D24D5E0EA2D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Medium- and heavy-Duty systems research, development, and demonstration</header><paragraph id="id154CE909DF2340999C722BE5EDA83830"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award financial assistance for the research, development, and demonstration of the integration of multiple advanced energy technologies and advanced operational efficiency for medium- and heavy-duty platforms and trailers, including the integration of technologies specified in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFFFCA61B3C5C4AAD9D9BD11F9C66B13E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicant</header><text>Applicants applying for assistance under paragraph (1) may be comprised of truck and trailer manufacturers, engine and component manufacturers, hydrogen fuel cell and component manufacturers, public and private fleet owners and customers, university researchers, and other applicants determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id8EC9CC21F44C4E9B82AF31EEA6AB3118"><enum>9.</enum><header>Technical assistance to State, local, and Tribal governments</header><subsection id="idB651C57B899946A59B0843B632C87536"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may provide technical assistance to State, local, and Tribal governments or to a public-private partnership described in subsection (b) to assist with the commercial application of alternative fuels and alternative fuels vehicle technologies and infrastructure.</text></subsection><subsection id="idE829B418DDC7446F87034584DE0BA2B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public-Private partnership described</header><text>A public-private partnership described in this subsection is a public-private partnership comprised of State, local, or Tribal governments and nongovernmental entities, including industry partners.</text></subsection><subsection id="idCA865F9F715B4C30A5C45EC0522D4C20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>Technical assistance under this section may include—</text><paragraph id="id2448C3081A4443418D93D1EE00EFA9F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordination in the selection, location, and timing of alternative fuel recharging and refueling equipment and distribution infrastructure, including the identification of transportation corridors and specific alternative fuels that may be made available;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA044A2C8F67F43F99A26F5C7E7614541"><enum>(2)</enum><text>development of communication and other relevant protocols that integrate vehicle refueling and recharging into electric, hydrogen, biofuels, or other alternative fuel distribution systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA0694C10BE014CEB9B4B8255BF4C3F9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>development of procedures for the installation of alternative fuel distribution and recharging and refueling equipment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6FFB84F0A23045B9BB709F745109FD66"><enum>(4)</enum><text>education and outreach for the commercial application of alternative fuels; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC28C1A01C62940D6B8FD3031DE82DAE9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>analysis of nontechnical barriers to integration of alternative fuel vehicles into electric and natural gas utility distribution systems.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD08427A45BD74F7EA3A422F4D0D312D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="idCBF170221E384459AAE61064535A7CA0"><enum>10.</enum><header>Graduate Automotive Technology Education Centers of Research Excellence (GATE)</header><subsection id="id6B3FA10945E748688BCF66D3A66CCBE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to establish up to seven Graduate Automotive Technology Education Centers of Research Excellence (referred to in this section as <quote>Centers</quote>) at an institution of higher education or a consortium thereof, to provide future generations of engineers and scientists with knowledge and skills in advanced automotive energy technologies.</text></subsection><subsection id="idA48D55DEE8954898826EB23EA0F0AA17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>Each Center shall—</text><paragraph id="idEEE7394C1ECF4FB5ADE1FE98B57C91A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote the development of skilled engineering professionals who will overcome technical barriers and help commercialize the next generation of advanced automotive energy technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9FD3E4953E9D49839E29DBB6FF093E42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support graduate research and establish or expand course study and laboratory work; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA3010E34E5B84B10AC2B9FE92B264B75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>test energy technologies that represent the scale of technology development beyond laboratory testing, but not yet advanced to testing under operational conditions at commercial scale.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idBC8FE6434EF841D59D9F5B98DE971C26"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In awarding grants for the operation of the Centers under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that—</text><paragraph id="id045818D66E0B4FB4A5A30EA7313CE43F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the portfolio of Centers includes a diverse representation of geographical regions and resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB6289B4DBFFB47FBADEB0F98F974823E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each new Center demonstrates unique research capabilities, unique regional benefits, or new energy technology development opportunities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2E2231BA011041C391EF5C9FAFAF92CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>applicants are institutions of higher education with established expertise in engineering and design for advanced automotive energy technologies or are involved in partnerships with such institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idD69B45F0ACBE43859F5DB1640F565ADE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out subsection (c), the Secretary shall ensure that grants for the operation of the Centers under this section are awarded to two or more entities that represent a Historically Black College or University, minority-serving institution, or Tribal College or University as the primary awardees or as members of a consortium.</text></subsection><subsection id="id60118E8C56A0420EB07E0B0E590DAFDC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text>Each grant to operate a Center under this section shall be awarded for a term of not more than five years, subject to the availability of appropriations. The Secretary may renew such five-year terms only once without competition limits, subject to a merit review.</text></subsection><subsection id="id6A4113995A4C49728C52C5C12DE08C25"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Funds provided through a grant under this section may not be used for the construction of a physical building or facility to hold a Center unless the Secretary determines that such construction is necessary for reasons of safety or the use of relevant equipment.</text></subsection><subsection id="idF0F140EE008A457FB575DAD9D402C10C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Director may provide technical assistance to institutions of higher education receiving a grant under this section or entities seeking such a grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="id12C61B31D96A4BA3BB77FEC4CE3642AA"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $8,300,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="id3773F919CF42442CA6922F092FCADD5F"><enum>11.</enum><header>Request for information to assess research gaps in alternative fuel delivery, distribution, and transmission</header><subsection id="idA3E4E04942C14FD3A3368BBF1C022D84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall publish a request for information that shall be used by the Secretary to evaluate research, development, and demonstration activities to assess alternative fuel transmission and delivery technical barriers. The request shall identify research barriers associated to existing electric transmission and distribution systems to the distribution of alternative fuels and the deployment of alternative fuel recharging and refueling capability, at economically competitive costs of alternative fuel for consumers, including research to address—</text><paragraph id="id34266B3E3317493AAB8A8A468039EF5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>electric grid load management and applications that will allow bidirectional batteries in plug-in electric drive vehicles to be used for grid storage, ancillary services provision, and backup power;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id829F2CF9342946F69150A13CA987D8B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>integration of plug-in bidirectional electric drive vehicles with smart grid technology, including necessary equipment, and information technology systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8E5CABAE93FB482E8BBA43C7BE8D0590"><enum>(3)</enum><text>technical and economic barriers to delivery technologies for hydrogen and biofuels sufficient to support widespread consumer use; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0EB3A0866F0E48DA9060B5D5388897B2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other technical barriers to installing sufficient and regionally appropriate alternative fuel recharging and refueling infrastructure, including sufficiency and efficient use of zero-emissions generation and transmission capabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id560E8EBC31C247EE85B0B65814A6D51D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section in coordination with relevant industry, State, local, and Tribal government, and academic stockholders.</text></subsection><subsection id="idE993CB207C214B42A1A25FE7984C26E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report summarizing the findings under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="id99ACE1874C0F4B41B38C2B535CB1C999"><enum>12.</enum><header>Energy efficient mobility systems program</header><subsection id="idA3425B4874C844289E1226A1E098DB86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall support a program of research, development, and demonstration of advanced energy efficient mobility solutions that will address the potential energy impacts of advanced vehicle technologies throughout the transportation sector. Such program shall include the development of tools, techniques, processes, and capabilities to understand and identify essential components to improve the energy productivity of integrated mobility systems.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD111155D449A4A879EB33E7FD83A60A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall support activities to—</text><paragraph id="id23A727C081714821B92E1B35AD8A4353"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve the energy and mobility impacts of emerging and potentially disruptive technologies and services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7AB46A586F2A466B9245C5749AAF0AE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess automated vehicle computing loads and capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id10DE121F5A67469B8D141FAACE10A63D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve onboard sensing and external connectivity, including Vehicle-to-Vehicle, Vehicle-to-Infrastructure, and Vehicle-to-Everything;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id42FD238079B5425EB5DA8F6CA6148EA8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maximize vehicle energy efficiency for connected vehicles under real-world driving conditions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFE38798A7EFA462EA939354654FB8DF4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess methods to use autonomous vehicles or connectivity to improve roadway throughput;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9566BEF22BB04373B7BBDFC18B159CC9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>research advance autonomous refueling and charging technologies and infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2D604C20CC45488ABC2A73918435A6F6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>apply machine learning with high performance computing resources to large industry datasets from providers and cities to develop predictive capabilities for the transportation system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52B7728B283F4ACAA620E90601AFD8DB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>optimize systems for mobility, grid and buildings to support vehicle electrification and vehicle automation from light duty to heavy duty with grid stability, demand response, and reliability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF3BB239C98C84EBD920F7784F64A36E5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>carry out other innovative energy focused research and development areas as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id0CE6D424682C4F1CAB4A4E88E204C699"><enum>13.</enum><header>Coordination</header><subsection id="idB829C5D15DCF4C44ADE6EC98482C8011"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the activities under this Act, the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate research, development, and demonstration activities among—</text><paragraph id="id0D4398E2627A4E3A8E03A4179ACAA26C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relevant programs of the Department, including programs carried out by— </text><subparagraph id="id10A12AAEDADB4AAA9C47F3751BFB9C9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBBA93FCF0DEF4279B302773161D6EEF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Office of Science;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6386167C23AA44FE967F5D7AB8D4439D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of Electricity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idEDC3F436BD734E408F35167F59C40C46"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Office of Fossil Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBE9AC06AF94643BB8857AF81FE33A816"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id635FE114DFAC479A8A2AC2BDD45231DC"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idDCCABF90A6804D3A91DF9E11AF3F4044"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idFD8B34A8DA244C1B9DBF089233AB6B64"><enum>(H)</enum><text>other offices as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id82383AC267404D23824BF6B6E33E6EB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant technology research and development programs of other Federal agencies, including—</text><subparagraph id="id7911E12B50E64C40A9F13454767B26E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD94BAD7F348740B5AEB60243C342CA08"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards &amp; Technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idBF9F44FCC13343229DF7F54E9255EEB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id9754F04F03AB4528BCC08293E6A392FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id52880F2D54F940129C10DB1020DEC860"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other Federal agencies as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4EF45B4DF3D645EC89B6D99E41FCB815"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Intergovernmental coordination</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary shall seek opportunities to leverage resources and support initiatives of Federal, State, and local governments in developing advanced vehicle technologies, manufacturing, and infrastructure.</text></subsection></section><section id="id6D21FD1298C5497EAFDFFDF26586E4E8"><enum>14.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for research, development, and demonstration of alternative fuels, vehicle propulsion systems, vehicle components, and other related technologies in the United States, including activities authorized under this Act—</text><paragraph id="idB89DFE0EFE24477BBEBE143D59A33E56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2023, $530,000,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idD621659065F54A27827EBBB0DA1DDDEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2024, $556,500,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7C5375B2D1434585B3A765FD0576F374"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2025, $584,325,000;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id58BD917A2F7E491AA85EEB2576271F8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2026, $613,541,250; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id307F6CD338CC4C4BB9A2229715358F6D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2027, $644,218,312.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

