<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1C387FC7FCBF4D52A536EE9AE9BDDF78" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7696 IH: Clean Water Standards for PFAS 2.0 Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish effluent limitations guidelines and standards and water quality criteria for perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances under the Federal Water Pollution Control Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50151CCB4F8A4C60A453837373F2CB63" style="OLC"><section id="HDB0CBED1B0234D35A291B745F52E4A6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><subsection id="H16A4F249F0FB48B0BCB19D1A772388CD"><enum/><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Clean Water Standards for PFAS 2.0 Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HC9B169376D9C45739DBA02F27CCBF537"><enum>2.</enum><header>Clean Water Act effluent limitations guidelines and standards and water quality criteria for PFAS</header><subsection id="H57F98CABE5B741E884C170CD58A69CB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><paragraph id="HC1982CED06F84C599CAA119B9BD4D70A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Water quality criteria</header><text>Not later than the date that is 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register human health water quality criteria under section 304(a)(1) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1314">33 U.S.C. 1314(a)(1)</external-xref>) to address each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, and class of those substances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08CFF0B763104338A8B07A2205E1E908"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effluent limitations guidelines and standards for priority industry categories</header><text>Not later than the following dates, the Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register a final rule establishing effluent limitations guidelines and standards, in accordance with the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>), for each of the following industry categories for the discharge (including a discharge into a publicly owned treatment works) of each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, or class of those substances: </text><subparagraph id="HA0E30B8C17AF4223BB0E2B50B27C4DFD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>During calendar year 2024</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2024, for the following point source categories:</text><clause id="HFEB9891A56994A51944E7310BF4D0601"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Organic chemicals, plastics, and synthetic fibers, as identified in part 414 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="H63212FAD55B24761BBE01B04D939EFC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Electroplating, as identified in part 413 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="H7907F71D5CB94F76929B8745AA810CD7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Metal finishing, as identified in part 433 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7462F3C01FAE44869D1B88EB2FDEE421"><enum>(B)</enum><header>During calendar year 2025</header><text>Not later than June 30, 2025, for the following point source categories:</text><clause id="H7A642C53F9CA4043A497566EAC9DE5C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Textile mills, as identified in part 410 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="H6D6A11E26437460CAB0BDA52569D4DCB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Electrical and electronic components, as identified in part 469 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="HF509A9D3D681485FBF13473AAAA53E29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Landfills, as identified in part 445 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H340C69D819844D06BDCA0672EB1A4B46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>During calendar year 2026</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2026, for the following point source categories:</text><clause id="H63F7017603E34E16A25AEE55C4C64814"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Leather tanning and finishing, as identified in part 425 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="HD17DA46D0D2D4627AFF8B8A630F42ABA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Paint formulating, as identified in part 446 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></clause><clause id="H1C3665B1B6DE416EBA9B77B1DEE4EB90"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Plastics molding and forming, as identified in part 463 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4D9F059DF1042EB953DC5DC9FFF131A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional monitoring requirements</header><paragraph id="H34733A2EF8A14A5E8299B9F1EBA21F24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall require monitoring of the discharges (including discharges into a publicly owned treatment works) of each measurable perfluoroalkyl substance, polyfluoroalkyl substance, and class of those substances for the point source categories and entities described in paragraph (2). The monitoring requirements under this paragraph shall be included in any permits issued under section 402 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1342">33 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>) after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE25A001F896140EBA9876B3369FC903B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Categories described</header><text>The point source categories and entities referred to in paragraphs (1) and (3) are each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9D37154B928041A1ABA6BB0BDB223D79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Pulp, paper, and paperboard, as identified in part 430 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C1C12CA37AF4AA6B5FB98476F094852"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Airports (as defined in section 47102 of title 49, United States Code).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F2A4203890049558786D51C37ABE9A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination</header><subparagraph id="H8D31A672678F47E38344A9D3369152F7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2023, the Administrator shall make a determination—</text><clause id="H3108CE0DA35C489EB4E2F36284648E6B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to commence developing effluent limitations and standards for the point source categories and entities listed in paragraph (2); or </text></clause><clause id="H0984728D32F34CE7BAD1DD805EAF9EF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that effluent limitations and standards are not feasible for those point source categories and entities, including an explanation of the reasoning for this determination.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DEC8078B303424A9914E1F6EEB99634"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any effluent limitations and standards for the point source categories and entities listed in paragraph (2) shall be published in the Federal Register by not later than December 31, 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21E607A90FE74C999BC8E37937E5D71E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Administrator shall notify the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate of each publication made under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="H3823E8FBC99444059696F50E3D5DC84C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $12,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA5F3246EFF6A44AFBDDAEBC164639D09"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H455CA0878595465AA30C8F1F0DBB56B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE854B5A2DCE247E59884646CB6223DC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effluent limitation</header><text>The term <term>effluent limitation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67E1D05B67124402BB753C6B5EB9AC73"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Measurable</header><text>The term <term>measurable</term>, with respect to a chemical substance or class of chemical substances, means capable of being measured using test procedures established under section 304(h) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1314">33 U.S.C. 1314(h)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92D5547FC67E4294B905DDCDDDB808D4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Perfluoroalkyl substance</header><text>The term <term>perfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a chemical of which all of the carbon atoms are fully fluorinated carbon atoms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77258B5F67934118A1490F736E7CC560"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Polyfluoroalkyl substance</header><text>The term <term>polyfluoroalkyl substance</term> means a chemical containing at least 1 fully fluorinated carbon atom and at least 1 carbon atom that is not a fully fluorinated carbon atom. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42C5DE061FCC446BA4B1F57F8F33E2C1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment works</header><text>The term <term>treatment works</term> has the meaning given the term in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

