<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H96A0ECB27F4844AF88ADBE179CCFBF09" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9571 IH: To amend title II of the Public Health Services to provide clarity with respect to coverage of claims against health care practitioners providing health professional volunteer services at community health centers during declared emergencies.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9571</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title II of the Public Health Services to provide clarity with respect to coverage of claims against health care practitioners providing health professional volunteer services at community health centers during declared emergencies.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBE3EC144B4D84A279B1676F18E9A08F4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC015A1FF20C4FA79B22665830ABEE5C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Coverage of claims against practitioners providing health professional volunteer services at community health centers during declared emergencies</header> 
<subsection id="H14DCD1E5FFF64449B4E508339DB642D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 224(q)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/233">42 U.S.C. 233(q)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2DB6273146984658A8F40024F52509B7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H50ADF8BADBC34BA4A15DE865D4BDE586"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the process described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subparagraph (B), a health care practitioner who is a health professional volunteer sponsored by an entity described in subsection (g)(4) shall be deemed to be sponsored by another entity described in subsection (g)(4) if—</text> 
<clause id="H840526C399D24517BC76E4ACC84FC60D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such other entity seeks the assistance of such health professional volunteer for purposes of responding to a declared emergency;</text></clause> <clause id="H47205987819A447EA2909DEC0FE531F1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other entity submits a notification of such assistance to the Secretary not later than 15 days after the first day on which such volunteer is to begin service at such entity; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEE3F35EFCADC4400A72367C6EBF0B127"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>such volunteer is serving at such entity pursuant to such notification during a covered service period.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF968B56C08BA4A8CABCB150F6E72CAEE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>For purposes of subparagraph (E):</text> 
<clause id="H4B72DCA368BB466BB47F4BF46BA79CB8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered service period</quote> means the period—</text> <subclause id="HEB7BCBC8F2BE402BA73E2DC99AC8A6F1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>beginning on the later of—</text> 
<item id="H5AF7CAA1AB734B39BA3EB9A9F23FA9E3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the date on which the volunteer begins service at another entity described in subsection (g)(4); or</text></item> <item id="HCB484450A356483383DDBA97DFA5C2E0"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the first day of a declared emergency, as determined by the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration; and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1267375D3FC84B07AC7D34D61DC33894"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ending on the earlier of—</text> <item id="H35F1A2CAEB08421D8EB93F17768FFFE9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the date on which the declared emergency ends;</text></item> 
<item id="H21206FFBCEDE43ECA0BED67C8355DB2D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the date on which the provider stops volunteering at such other entity; or</text></item> <item id="H3C293391D71848A48380E3DEC2EFF565"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>90 days after the date determined under subclause (I).</text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFB832C84252643EDBC271F11672E00D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The term <quote>declared emergency</quote> means—</text> <subclause id="H2E087291494548A19044DD61D5F81101"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4C6EDC4B64B1403B9A4221BA73B24B0F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 319 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HBF99B6A1D96F42089CD2F96C3F72A32E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 224(q) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/233">42 U.S.C. 233(q)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H0CA323051B424421AF299E775319527D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph id="H9F9278F9F1504596B6F4ADA1576285F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>(or is deemed to be sponsoring a health care practitioner pursuant to paragraph (3)(E))</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C4CEFA161944ADD8188D531F601085C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>(and in the case of a health care practitioner providing services at another entity described in subsection (g)(4) pursuant to paragraph (3)(E), the State in which such other entity is located)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAABF8DDC7DD949C3A7BC7789C49CC404"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>With respect</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in subparagraph (E), with respect</quote>.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

