<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD097D067B2094A36861FF39C557899C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8575 IH: Funding Affordable Internet with Reliable Contributions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Communications Commission to conduct a study and submit to Congress a report examining the feasibility of funding the Universal Service Fund through contributions supplied by edge providers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA46E7E048DA343F8BAE6D575B81ACECD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H539FE9D963554A59909D0832599B82D6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Funding Affordable Internet with Reliable Contributions Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FAIR Contributions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD31E8F1C159E42C5A916AF1C677CD85E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and report on Universal Service Fund contributions</header> <subsection id="H4E199DF400904A2DAD92AC8E800DBD0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H7494BB8CD5F14F8FB5FA95ADAD8970FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E6648CC7A4943D7BBCACBAA9E762A7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0740062D59C84166A18C901EB6CBCA2F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCF96D7A61284228AD462C5EE1EEBD2D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6B620E17B3648C9937593DD47863776"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contribution</header><text>The term <term>contribution</term> means funds provided to the Universal Service Fund under section 254(d) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H55710EB4959F4EDBA6F6EDCA7964C36D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Edge provider</header><text>The term <term>edge provider</term> means a provider of online content or services, such as a search engine, a social media platform, a streaming service, an app store, a cloud computing service, or an e-commerce platform.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H066C1D4AA9EB40D686E8574A0858EE13"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Universal Service Fund</header><text>The term <term>Universal Service Fund</term> means the fund established pursuant to section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>) and administered by the Universal Service Administrative Company to support service to high-cost areas, schools and libraries, rural health care facilities, and the Lifeline program of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE8A5D526309D42849E0049DD9917AD22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and after issuing a notice of inquiry seeking public comment on the issues described in this subsection, the Commission shall conduct a study and submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report examining the feasibility of funding the Universal Service Fund through contributions supplied by edge providers, which shall include the consideration of comments on, and the findings of the Commission with respect to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBE3B06883E404CEF80C9C3799CE9AADC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the class of firms and services on which contributions could be assessed, including an inquiry into the specific sources of revenue potentially subject to contributions, such as digital advertising revenue and user fees; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32DFB9F0DB854BA7866783A052E29270"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the equity issues of the current contributions system, including the cost burden on consumers who traditionally purchase legacy telecommunications services; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0F770E1E460437BA296CAA893FDD0BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>equity issues of alternative contributions systems that would create new funding sources for the Universal Service Fund such as Federal appropriations or assessments on edge providers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43145E985E4F4BF0AEB58EE45120499B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether a particular contributions system results in progressive or regressive fees;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BAC3A06AA3A46629371F4FA66C4843C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the size of firms subject to contributions requirements;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F4716768FF341B09E4DD594BF7572C0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the broadband requirements, such as bandwidth and latency, of a particular online service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E920404BEEE42459FEB173F6E792DFE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>other Federal, State, and local taxes and fees that edge providers may already pay;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C6751A3789643819B1629F505CD11C0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>practical issues concerning the calculation of contributions, including which revenues should be subject to contributions, whether a flat or progressive rate is most appropriate, and the logistics of collection; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEFD7190118024786A125D09BB73AA2C6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the effect such a change would have on telecommunications bills of consumers, including low-income, elderly, and Tribal consumers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H048B3308F7E74CF6B5AB11A54FCE399A"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the effect such a change would have on the sustainability of the Universal Service Fund, and how to ensure that Universal Service Fund disbursements are consistent and predictable over time;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE4B474D210EF48448043BEA6E1C1B544"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the statutory authority the Commission would require to enact such a change and how such a change would interact with existing Federal and State law; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EC71F23BCEC4751A311B4BC4804FA05"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the continued necessity of the Universal Service Fund once advanced telecommunications capability is available to all people in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

