<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEEC1FB07C5784A9CA8CB16A68D1836C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9572 IH: Analyzing Kinetic Impact Projectiles Against Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9572</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into an arrangement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to conduct a comprehensive study on the health care impacts of the use of kinetic impact projectiles in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAF9C8ED9328444179C71017C0BC4E2F1" style="OLC"><section id="H228396E6699A4DD485ADF122A60FC02E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Analyzing Kinetic Impact Projectiles Against Americans Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HCF807A0FD00642C6892E8E4B21B02BFC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study on health care impacts of the use of kinetic impact projectiles in the United States</header><subsection id="HCE386ECE7AEC45B7A64AC9170ECA8733"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (or, if the National Academies decline to enter into such arrangement, another appropriate entity) under which, not later than 1 year after such date of enactment, the National Academies (or other appropriate entity) will complete a comprehensive study on the health care impacts of the use of kinetic impact projectiles in the United States. </text></subsection><subsection id="H9A6CED4883FA4C20BAC88E629D63E4D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required analysis</header><text>The study conducted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include an analysis of each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HA99F00C2F8BA49BDBBEE59A9C9487457"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The frequency and severity of injuries and health impacts caused by the use of kinetic impact projectiles on individuals domestically.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76F72BCD54114A3DB5425512404B26FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The settings related to the use of kinetic impact projectiles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AD4385861674AA7A9837B8A7B8F0EE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A statistical review of the frequency of use of kinetic impact projectiles by law enforcement entities domestically. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30A77F51AAA94F889950D5FB2EAF0F5C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A demographic and racial breakdown of individuals who have been impacted by kinetic impact projectile-caused injuries domestically.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34967EEF164A4C88BDA7032C96CB528A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A statistical review of the site and morbidity of injuries caused by kinetic impact projectiles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5329CDADAEDF40B3B2284760B7BBF94D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A review of treatments for kinetic impact projectile-caused injuries and the efficacy of such treatments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6E3FDA3AFFA438FBA876EF1A376A7AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The arrangement under subsection (a) shall provide for the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (or other appropriate entity), not later than 6 months after the completion of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a), and annually thereafter—</text><paragraph id="H03E95CFEE8DC41A9A4AB6E732DCA237D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to submit to the relevant congressional committees of jurisdiction, including the Committees on Appropriations, Energy and Commerce, and the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Appropriations; Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions; and the Judiciary of the Senate, a report that contains—</text><subparagraph id="H5AE1B12FA0AA4A6D82D0DBF277D451F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the analysis conducted under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F226F4FAB494D92916E21F7579948E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations, regarding the effects of the use of kinetic impact projectiles in the United States, to—</text><clause id="HFE79C8A3AEB740D5AE41F1CB4939FC60"><enum>(i)</enum><text>implement changes governmentwide;</text></clause><clause id="H45266776C60041BE87E8A90985BFBD8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish guidelines and best practices for the use of kinetic impact projectiles; and</text></clause><clause id="H3F79C5C66A5647A0BF4437C1C39112D3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improve the oversight of Federal procurement and funding for kinetic impact projectiles; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D9B2E1AF34D4F6E89793A2A42A19DF5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to make such report publicly available on the internet.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5EC75700E0B84337ACF0D45BD5E3C982"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>kinetic impact projectile</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H0915B034A091415787FF33BCE3A8C609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a rubber or plastic bullet, bean bag round, sponge round, pellet round, or wooden dowel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09BABF0BC877451185272402F77E11F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other projectile-delivered impact munition determined to be subject to the study under this section by the Secretary of Health and Human Services in consultation with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (or other appropriate entity).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF743FCF40ED424EA5829C4CECF045B9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $2,000,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

