<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89007D1365634390A7BBDCDCF38F9276" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7760 IH: Strengthening Our Health Security Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7760</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220512">May 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a procedure for terminating a determination by the Secretary of Health and Human Services to suspend the introduction of persons into the United States from designated places, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD24781E2F187403988795C3BCCA3797C" style="OLC"><section id="H78344BF058A9459AA3AFFEBE5C9834B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Our Health Security Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCFCE6254E0BB45CE8E102628B4063F74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of suspension of persons from designated places related to the COVID–19 pandemic</header><subsection id="H55A2164661134AF5AF6F28E5B8E75CA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An order of suspension issued under section 362 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/265">42 U.S.C. 265</external-xref>) as a result of the public health emergency declaration under section 319 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>) with respect to COVID–19 (including any renewal of such declaration) shall not be lifted earlier than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary of Health and Human Services provides written notification to the appropriate committees of Congress that such public health emergency declaration has been terminated.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAAC6D918833B4B1693120BE2465930E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures during 60-Day termination window</header><paragraph id="H1974D2ECF4CD41A4B96D0A0B3EA312DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a written notification is provided under subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a plan to address any possible influx of persons related to the termination of such order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24175E4A62E848C5A9E7FA008DDCF8E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall develop the plan required by paragraph (1) in consultation with—</text><subparagraph id="H6874BFEB50504798B0917B4C7B5CEEC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BD4B75C24A848BB9BFF99AE54FECCD2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Federal agency, State, local, or Tribal government, and nongovernmental organization that, as determined by the Secretary, has a role in managing outcomes associated with the termination of such order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C399C2878AD40FFA357D738F19E1AA6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The plan required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB815288E208E402FA8291C4B42938405"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The process for screening persons referred to in paragraph (1) for COVID–19 and other communicable diseases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD49BDDA5DC0748AE8FFDFF016A17330D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the Federal Government’s capacity for testing such persons for COVID–19 and other communicable diseases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE879459D7534C70840EF021F071685C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the protocols to prevent the spread of, and to treat, communicable diseases (other than COVID–19) in connection with an influx of persons described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25FECB0A3A254D9BBFA93A01901ADD69"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of the protocols to be implemented to protect Federal employees working with or near such persons from potential exposure to COVID–19 and other communicable diseases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFC6313E7D3B433886C25031247E723E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The process for screening such persons for controlled substances, including fentanyl, being imported illicitly.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H641F00D8D3784D9A8B3F5AF3382C45C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A specification of how long, and with respect to how many such persons, the Federal Government has the capacity to carry out the activities referred to in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA978323D72384E588CA5A966616FCCC8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A specification of the circumstances under which a request will be submitted for additional such capacity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E699F518CCB435FB0A56E55F5010864"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Failure to submit</header><text>If a plan under paragraph (1) is not submitted to the appropriate committees of Congress within the 30-day period described in such paragraph—</text><subparagraph id="H11F9FC52B56A40C9B1430EB070A067BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 7 days after the expiration of such 30-day period, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress, in writing, of the status of preparing such a plan and the timing for submission as required under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H712F69593A794FC7802518EE77780224"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the termination of an order of suspension pursuant to such plan shall be delayed until a date that is at least 30 days after the date on which such plan is submitted to such committees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

