<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" bill-type="olc" dms-id="A1" public-private="public"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 9353 IH: Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9353</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221122">November 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Klamath Basin Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2000 to provide the Secretary of the Interior with certain authorities with respect to projects affecting the Klamath Basin watershed, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="H813276FB54004342B631574034C833D6"><section section-type="section-one" id="H91379EEB3BD14CD6B73E92A765049332"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H820687F1F05543589634CC08C35290D9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Klamath project water and power</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D1A6805BF7548EDAEC32FF27D105535"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Addressing water, power, and facilities management for irrigation</header><text>Section 4 of the Klamath Basin Water Supply Enhancement Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/498">Public Law 106–498</external-xref>; 114 Stat. 2221; 132 Stat. 3886; 134 Stat. 976) is amended—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id5C87165D04E24568ACDD7734A8570412"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4A119C207B5749CE9D4EA74529065E1E"><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id4B01F21F2F39478B8A846BEA7AC7B5D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to appropriations and required environmental reviews, the Secretary is authorized to carry out activities, including entering into a contract or making financial assistance available through cooperative agreements or other methods, to plan, implement, and administer programs, including conservation and efficiency measures, land idling, and use of groundwater, to align water supplies and demand for irrigation water users associated with the Klamath Project, with a primary emphasis on programs developed or endorsed by local entities composed of representatives of those water users.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="idB479243CC15F4C6681C895D4FBEBB5B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBCFBFB70972941C28B92A494E07B4EC4"><paragraph id="H5C162F8F6DDA481DBCCDE0078B1BCC77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><subparagraph id="H49196FA867CD49789999F7A433B3EC6A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement Support Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall, through 1 or more cooperative agreements, financial assistance agreements, or other methods, implement, or support the implementation of, the recommendations identified in the report described in paragraph (1) that the Secretary determines would lead to bringing the net delivered power cost for covered power use to an amount that is the same as, or less than, the power cost benchmark, subject to the availability of appropriations, on the fastest timeline practicable, with respect to near- and long-term actions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA49FC471A3DE4A80AA78FE9030626745"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The implementation of recommendations under subparagraph (A) shall be carried out in accordance with—</text><clause id="HA491EAE1A49E487490C18012124EA2AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the report submitted under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="HDD99945C6F294835923D97EF377552A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any reports submitted under paragraph (3).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC39EB955FE847E59C81F4D2B324F764"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional reports</header><text>Not later than April 30, 2025, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to each committee described in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) a report that describes—</text><subparagraph id="H7056829B01764ADF8A830EF95346120D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any progress toward meeting the requirements of this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3898F6C2365549F4ACE4B5EAD18688FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any modifications or updates to the actions recommended under paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC14780E38E114DDEA2FAFBE96372655A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H90601A2521B34ACCA7F513770FB25E78"><subsection id="HB5D99F3459FE4293A273CE1A50107143"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restoration Activities</header><text>The Secretary may—</text><paragraph id="id1BC91F41FC6B469593F4BB44F3EEFDFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>plan, design, construct, operate, and maintain projects in the Klamath Basin watershed, including—</text><subparagraph id="H94AAC26EF50B487FB85835CDD222D3C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilities to reduce fish entrainment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H139675B60B8D47B183C5C3E6EB2D5A9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>projects that reduce or avoid impacts on aquatic resources of facilities involved in the storage or diversion of water for irrigation in the Klamath Project service area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47F9550E6B784467A17710BEFAE58E04"><enum>(C)</enum><text>projects that restore habitats in the Klamath Basin watershed, including Tribal fishery resources held in trust;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id152175ED01F84719AD61CA0E71ADF524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>undertake studies, including feasibility studies, and improvements that the Secretary determines to be necessary to implement this subsection;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id687119691E9C4826AF5AB6ECBE029983"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in implementing this subsection, enter into contracts, memoranda of understanding, financial assistance agreements, cost-sharing agreements, or other appropriate agreements with—</text><subparagraph id="idBF2EF91F1A804176AD97069EF1AB5C5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State, Tribal, and local governmental agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id5822DE13AB284A5B8D5BBFF8E370AAB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>private parties; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9DE09802EA1F49BF9E228D7D7DECC0C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>accept and expend non-Federal funds in order to facilitate implementation of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF36C75AAFB0F4A70A8D7E59EB5F6D6F7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of activities under subsections (b) and (d) shall include, as applicable—</text><paragraph id="HEEFFA168B2394656BB340317E487D3D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the short-term and long-term reduction and resolution of conflicts relating to water in the Klamath Basin watershed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF3DDAB692A42408DD5F1A48286721B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compatibility and utility for protecting natural resources throughout the Klamath Basin watershed, including the protection, preservation, and restoration of Klamath River Tribal fishery resources, particularly through collaboratively developed agreements.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA9E71C8F4634A8C8A0E3A2121ED4519"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Pumping Plant D</header><text>The Secretary may enter into 1 or more agreements with the Tulelake Irrigation District to reimburse the Tulelake Irrigation District for not more than 69 percent of the cost incurred by the Tulelake Irrigation District for the operation and maintenance of Pumping Plant D, subject to the condition that the cost results in benefits to the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H144BA3B6DA28499198631B12CEF59411"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Keno and Link river dams</header><text>The Secretary shall comply with the terms of the agreement entitled <quote>2016 Klamath Power and Facilities Agreement</quote>, including Attachment A to the agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD952F526A2554DBAA9828689119279A0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Replacement of C Canal flume</header><paragraph id="idBE4BFDC6B26F48EBBAF0A1DA511E7214"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The replacement of the C Canal flume within the Klamath Project shall be considered to be, and shall receive the treatment authorized for, qualified emergency extraordinary operation and maintenance work in accordance with Federal reclamation law (the Act of June 17, 1902 (32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093), and Acts supplemental to and amendatory of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/371">43 U.S.C. 371 et seq.</external-xref>)). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id228D92FED0C54494AB8F39EB1A4C5CA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contract</header><subparagraph id="idF875927102D14480A3A743F31ABBAA0B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of receipt of a request from the Klamath Irrigation District to enter into a contract with the Klamath Irrigation District to amend the contract numbered 16–WC–20–4838, the Secretary shall enter into a contract with the Klamath Irrigation District providing that—</text><clause id="id7B9EC3256B8042B594B20F1809D4F043"><enum>(i)</enum><text>35 percent of the total repayment obligation under the contract entered into under this subparagraph is nonreimbursable to the United States; and </text></clause><clause id="idF21EE5781AA5493586D57808B52C1419"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>65 percent of the total repayment obligation under the contract entered into under this subparagraph shall be repaid to the United States over a period of 50 years. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id3F15E46388CE42FD9D2264893B2EC80F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>Although the Secretary shall not condition the agreement to the contract entered into under subparagraph (A) on any other term, the contract may include other terms that are not less favorable to the contractor than contract numbered 16–WC–20–4838.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5BDCB79E32C46059CA957EEFE20C149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration; effect</header><paragraph id="H8931A369D2104AF797F25CF947E20CFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>In implementing the amendments made by this section, the Secretary of the Interior shall comply with—</text><subparagraph id="HCB3BBE7E2700403F8C4E0B5C3D886949"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92831C97016F4ED5881C9F1875A1297E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA67C139A7F494B9F97915C17A943B508"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all other applicable laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79C198DE82FD4592BEC97F647C4ECF0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>None of the amendments made by this section—</text><subparagraph id="HB03F422140C84271923C201B0A0CE2F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modify any authority or obligation of the United States with respect to any Tribal trust or treaty obligation of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAA69F908CF6410EB1EAA049A3AEF7BC"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="id61A95F632A9C4DB2ADDE51EA41D42603"><enum>(i)</enum><text>create or determine any water right; or</text></clause><clause id="idD0721E3E6B3A4B7399E99F9CBDFC8489" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>affect any water right or water right claim in existence on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05CE56B14C534EB7A06B4B17A3A1F693"><enum>(C)</enum><text>authorize the use of Federal funds for the physical deconstruction of the Iron Gate, Copco 1, Copco 2, or John C. Boyle Dam located on the Klamath River in the States of California and Oregon.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

