<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H360892F73DC740FB8907D05370757AD2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7819 IH: Accountability for Online Firearms Marketplaces Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7819</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220518">May 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Decency Act to remove immunity for online firearms marketplaces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB4A59E63AA2048B18F8F05ED4D6EA427" style="OLC"><section id="H6EB8A550971342BEA72CEBD87BDB808D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accountability for Online Firearms Marketplaces Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H82066D35CFC14D62A2F5AC17C9D92FC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF6F06DB212C344F790AF5E3AB730E332"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The core purpose of section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>Communications Decency Act</quote>) (referred to in this section as <quote>Section 230</quote>) is to provide a specific protection for online platforms acting as Good Samaritans to stop online abuse. Specifically, Section 230 states that providers of interactive computer services will not be treated as publishers or speakers of user-generated content. In turn, the provision entrusted providers to act as Good Samaritans police their platforms by blocking and screening offensive content.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4BD66753F3C45F390C33959DFF5BA69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 230 bars actions that hold providers liable as publishers of third-party content, but the statute is irrelevant to claims unrelated to such publications. If a claim does not treat the defendant as a publisher, Section 230 should not apply.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A485AB38A6E46409F54BF834F88546E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>However, courts have interpreted Section 230 as providing sweeping immunity for a broad array of providers, including providers alleged to have facilitated violations of criminal laws online. This interpretation is overly broad and discourages the self-policing that Section 230 intended to incentivize.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFEB358ABDFC4CFDB25B25F5C55859F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In Daniel v. Armslist, the Wisconsin Supreme Court read Section 230 to bar claims against an online firearms marketplace. The court’s decision swept so broadly as to cover websites designed to encourage and facilitate firearms trafficking in violation of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/44">chapter 44</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H447FDA26EC2D427DB75936A4A71FD910"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Online firearms marketplaces have made it increasingly easy for people who are prohibited from gun ownership to purchase guns online. Online firearms marketplaces facilitate such sales because while Federal law requires licensed gun dealers to perform background checks on prospective buyers, it does not require unlicensed sellers to do so. For more than a decade, online firearms marketplaces have exploited this legal loophole by allowing unlicensed sellers to sell guns directly to people prohibited from gun ownership.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1338A53DB1D8445AB48FE4CE6322B773"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Every year, unlicensed sellers post more than 1,000,000 advertisements on online firearms marketplaces in States that do not legally require a background check. Individuals with criminal histories and other prohibited purchasers rely on these postings to evade basic background check laws and procure firearms. One study found that nearly 1 in 9 prospective gun buyers who respond to advertisements from unlicensed sellers on a major online firearms marketplace would not pass a background check, which is a rate that is 7 times higher than the denial rate in contexts where background checks are required. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6251B93FC79A4FA9B01DEF150E54AD77"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress did not intend for Section 230 to bar otherwise valid claims against online firearms marketplaces for their own design of a website that encourages and contributes to its users circumventing Federal laws, including Federal gun laws. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H334C71D5A8C744299560B55B70FF28A3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protection of victims of gun violence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7A1B19F65F1440208FACF5D40976C430"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HCE4235EFCEFC44CFA46EAAFBBD60F758"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>No provider</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided in paragraph (3), no provider</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B7182A2884E445196ED538F13CA1DBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H77739683E6154AA585477FA903154467"><paragraph id="H3BD0289F72FB4E65B78860BA7D7AA7DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of publisher or speaker does not apply to online firearms marketplace</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to an online firearms marketplace, for purposes of any claim in an action brought against the online firearms marketplace in its capacity as an online firearms marketplace.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB80EFF9031CB4A9B8B4F3645C4CE6640"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (f), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F31BF9B9ADD45BD8CD6DC0E5E37B44D"><paragraph id="HDFCE629A70FF41E0BACCC04EF8B3914E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Online firearms marketplace</header><text>The term <term>online firearms marketplace</term> means an interactive computer service that—</text><subparagraph id="HE331E91217B14472B3C589B3ECA6A9C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>facilitates transactions related to firearms, firearms accessories, firearms equipment, and other firearms-related materials; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF0EC5BCDCEB4F4A8F0EE75C47338765"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advertises or makes available any posting or listing of any statement by a transferor or by a transferee that could be reasonably inferred to propose the transfer of a firearm; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3356C80DD05A4881A05CD6BE29F8D92C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>makes digital instructions in the form of Computer Aided Design files or other code that can automatically program a 3-dimensional printer or similar device to produce a firearm or complete a firearm from an unfinished frame or receiver, </text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">regardless of whether such transactions or other activities violate the terms of service of the interactive computer service. </continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DAA35F8DA554041B7C41D37F98B6256"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text> The term <term>firearm</term> has the meaning given the term in section 921(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill>


