<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4EA51A8785E94755B8A446381FE69FC7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7923 IH: Investor Justice Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7923</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220531">May 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish a grant program to fund qualified investor advocacy clinics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H599A7633DE81469FA468EF0313FC9D6A" style="OLC"><section id="H7CCBE33D2A564F8A93A48B3E7D635475" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investor Justice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H75ECE3BFECE34DEE8F652BC990A1B7B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to qualified investor advocacy clinics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(g) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78d">15 U.S.C. 78d(g)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H2BDE2BEBF40D4CB69E90494B117ED590" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H779FF808EE884D98B250EDBEC1C121FB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Grants to qualified investor advocacy clinics</header><subparagraph id="HBC80245337AE4CABAA1C4FE00FADB2EF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>The Commission, acting through the Investor Advocate, may make grants, on a competitive basis, to qualified investor advocacy clinics in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADDAE76F314848498D83F06EFEA2202A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under subparagraph (A), a qualified investor advocacy clinic shall submit to the Commission an application at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Commission may require, including information with respect to—</text><clause id="HD21AABAF90DA47C683209D2F1282C81E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of investors in the geographical area served by the clinic;</text></clause><clause id="HB13B2F42EB7947C68997DCA193434713"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other similar entities serving the same population;</text></clause><clause id="HC478F5D5E5C2436AAF2449A110E91B45"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the quality of the program offered by the clinic, including—</text><subclause id="HD299C483AFD7406BAFDD48A9E6DB4E68"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the qualifications of the administrators and qualified representatives of the clinic; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9FC315300F9640828F9039A5BD805E99"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the record of the clinic, if any, in providing legal and educational services to investors with low dollar value claims in arbitrations and mediations; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC76ABE8612174DDDB3550E5911BB4234"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>funding sources available to the clinic, including—</text><subclause id="H200E0325A1104FAC90D43F828116A675"><enum>(I)</enum><text>amounts received from other grants and contributions; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5B0677B66E0841298FD890EE6AF1F401"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the endowment and resources of any institution sponsoring the clinic.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5A124B3A63F48B9949D361E48819105"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Grant uses</header><text>A qualified investor advocacy clinic awarded a grant under subparagraph (A) may only use grant funds for the development, expansion, or continuation of the qualified investor advocacy clinic.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F35767F5446426F9E520F712D5114E0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Detail of executive agency employees</header><text>Upon the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that Federal agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its functions under this section. The detail of any such personnel shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04CBA590FDF14796B511E01E7A45EE0D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text>A qualified investor advocacy clinic awarded a grant under subparagraph (A) shall submit to the Commission a detailed accounting of the use of grant funds at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Commission may require.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC459B77D127640C994D1B52AC4333CBC"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Limitations</header><clause id="H19316C75D04A4C078044F0B0AC4C6540"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Aggregate limitation</header><text>The aggregate amount of grants made under subparagraph (A) during a fiscal year may not exceed $5,000,000 (as such amount is annually adjusted by the Investor Advocate to reflect the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor).</text></clause><clause id="H5BF9CC5805304BBE9E8930B3F7813289"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Single clinic limitation</header><text>In making grants under subparagraph (A), the Commission may not award, during a fiscal year, more than $150,000 (as such amount is annually adjusted to reflect the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor) to any single qualified investor advocacy clinic.</text></clause><clause id="H69C14039F9084514BE34203380F90B2D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of activities carried out using grant funds made available under subparagraph (A) may not exceed 50 percent.</text></clause><clause id="HF932849241AF401EBBDE879EFC5E9D87"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Multi-year grants</header><subclause id="H91DCFD17B0BD4D8A9E40DD612953D701"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In making grants under subparagraph (A), the Commission may award multi-year grants.</text></subclause><subclause id="H85871EDD40964F0F8670C1F03AA56854"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Multi-year grants awarded under this clause may not be made for a period exceeding three years.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E06D6A828E40DEADE46A62D92091B5"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5596FB7559064DFAA44CD2B518AC03A2"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="H17E72D0501E84AA0AACEBBD193A8FDDC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Qualified investor advocacy clinic</header><text>The term <quote>qualified investor advocacy clinic</quote> means an entity—</text><subclause id="H0F90544657E44398B2A0167A4A9D2D65"><enum>(I)</enum><text>that provides or will provide free representation to investors with claims of less than $100,000 (as such amount is annually adjusted by the Investor Advocate to reflect the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor) in securities arbitrations and mediations before a registered national securities association (with exceptions to the requirements of this subclause authorized to be made by the Investor Advocate on a case-by-case basis); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H860FA9F34B1D4D8BAA6C30A7D946F78B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that is or will be sponsored, offered, or run by—</text><item id="H3D52BF53735546479CC3819A5345B52B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a clinical program at or partnering with an American Bar Association accredited law school; or</text></item><item id="H825266CB526A4EE59FA1981551922A94"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HEB40C37BD36742C5B58079D2E53864BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Qualified representative</header><text>The term <quote>qualified representative</quote> means any individual authorized to represent investors before a registered national securities association.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

