<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H568CC11E9E204FFC88A3333C4CB51D27" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8833 IH: Making Communities Stronger through the Community Reinvestment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8833</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220915">September 15, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000187">Ms. Waters</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 to improve the assessment process for financial institutions under that Act, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3892DCAEF0CA4CF690497EA4B0AB0F0E" style="OLC">
<section id="HBF1B575CE809477DA38D1FE1D8828F59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Making Communities Stronger through the Community Reinvestment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA8692C4EA62642BCACAC6503CDB92A12"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that Senator William Proxmire, who authored the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 legislation, testified when discussing its purpose: <quote>By redlining . . . I am talking about the fact that banks and savings and loans will take their deposits from a community and instead of reinvesting them in that community, they will actually or figuratively draw a red line on a map around the areas of their city, sometimes in the inner city, sometimes in the older neighborhoods, sometimes ethnic and sometimes black, but often encompassing a great area of their neighborhood.</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H7AB79A0F12FF467281FB0BCFE581D1C6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessment of community service</header>
<subsection id="HC6B4AD07055645CBAC0D13A59D637932"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 804 of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2903">12 U.S.C. 2903</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6B1104C8DB0743FDA6EC0251883C5534" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H852F7875AB1B426DB06E6848985774A7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment of community service</header> <paragraph id="HDE63C48EE6E449CEA04ED7041EE7818B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In assessing and taking into account, under subsection (a), any community service or charity work performed by the executives, board members, and employees of a financial institution, the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency may not give any credit for such service or work unless—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0B2DE3D11BD64197AC98901385EE8A7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the executives, board members, and employees performing such service or work were acting as representatives of the financial institution at the time the service or work were performed;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0DA307477D2428B86366FDBB34BF277"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a financial institution with total consolidated assets of at least $2,000,000,000, the financial institution—</text>
<clause id="HE24B8AEC871C4642A913701969C9A2BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collects and maintains relevant information with respect to the community service and charity work of the financial institution, in a format prescribed by the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC8CC4990BB9745E6B7B81D700E9E6677"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reports such information on an annual basis to the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA7B1A8B11C874209B6B3D031B4B30914"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial institution demonstrates the impact of the community service or charity work on low- and moderate-income neighborhoods, including whether the community service or charity work—</text> <clause id="H16EDF569B36549D1888839DE16A07F1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves persistent poverty counties;</text></clause>
<clause id="HAB179D905266468495B82D8BBBEB71E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serves geographic areas with low levels of community development financing;</text></clause> <clause id="H793EBA357F724599AAF64CA6676C4F9D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supports a minority depository institution, women’s depository institution, low-income credit union, or a community development financial institution certified by the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA96453A1610F4D24B01A279E2FFF06F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>serves low-income individuals and families;</text></clause> <clause id="H31FE8B03AE4A4056803B2CA86386BEF3"><enum>(v)</enum><text>supports small businesses or small farms with gross annual revenues of $250,000 or less;</text></clause>
<clause id="H081641D20BA7460E8472F549764A2042"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>directly facilitates the acquisition, construction, development, preservation, or improvement of affordable housing in high opportunity areas;</text></clause> <clause id="H59084E20F1824885B03A5CEEC743A592"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>benefits Native communities, such as—</text>
<subclause id="HE0BFB17FE6414FF0B2188A3FEDBC43BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revitalization activities in Native Land Areas;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H989B30A3519448FF88537BFECF51CBD2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>essential community facilities in Native Land Areas;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HEEE8C433CD5548C8A1627FE736C54D17"><enum>(III)</enum><text>essential community infrastructure in Native Land Areas; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3EC992B8DE534F3793336B8F898148C2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>disaster preparedness and climate resiliency activities in Native Land Areas;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H7C35A120B4B74B1BA7B18B67DB189DD8" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reflects a high degree of engagement with community partners, and are highly responsive to the needs of low-income communities;</text></clause> <clause id="H075FA39BF8924942BDEF0D33195E5DE8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>result in a new community development financing product or service that addresses community development needs for low- or moderate-income individuals and families; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H03A44FE63E8F4C31BFD369D143875B01"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serves limited English proficient communities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF94BFDC68D34E588DFA5A159D0FA18C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text>
<subparagraph id="H8F48FA66386E42FDB63366060C812226"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Community development financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>community development financial institution</quote> has the meaning given that term under section 103 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H464E839ECB1143509CC786B8BF5CC629"><enum>(B)</enum><header>High opportunity area</header><text>The term <quote>high opportunity area</quote> means an area—</text>
<clause id="HEC98664F68924426AC57C7A436E9BCC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designated by—</text> <subclause id="H918585CA17D04B2585ED55BB800D4991"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development as a Difficult Development Area; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB03DEBFEC2CB41CA84F6763E4D5AAFE7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State or local qualified allocation plan as a high opportunity area; and </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H06214EB852C54614BFA5D181FDC9182F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with a poverty rate below—</text>
<subclause id="H44321EE98F464284A66644DC7539B07E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>10 percent, with respect to a metropolitan area; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB27689710C9D4C199AF20178A07359D4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>15 percent, with respect to an area that is not a metropolitan area.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8BAA38756F3C4AC5BD15440AE186AC20"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Native Land Area</header><text>The term <quote>Native Land Area</quote> means—</text> <clause id="HD205A0E23B744567BEC14E5B15D9E8E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all land within the limits of any Indian reservation under the jurisdiction of the Federal Government, as described in section 1151(a) of title 18, United States Code;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBD14025EFCB94E36827E3AEC708F2059"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all dependent Indian communities within the borders of the United States whether within the original or subsequently acquired territory thereof, and whether within or without the limits of a State, as described in section 1151(b) of title 18, United States Code;</text></clause> <clause id="H06488F1832D147F0A988B93D27FEDA40"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all Indian allotments, the Indian titles to which have not been extinguished, including rights-of-way running through the same, as defined in section 1151(c) of title 18, United States Code;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDA6F4951722145F99BF3C51AEE354988"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any land held in trust by the United States for Native Americans, as described in section 3765(1)(A) of title 38, United States Code;</text></clause> <clause id="HACE1E53F2F9F40F09AD9E9A8D8F5D8E5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reservations established by a State government for a Tribe or Tribes recognized by the State;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9909E4C327854E6BAC441F88D37AD1D8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Alaska Native village as defined in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H6CFCFB9A13F74E05AFBA9E60CBE00549"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>lands that have the status of Hawaiian Home Lands as defined in section 204 of the Hawaiian Homes Commission Act, 1920 (42 Stat. 108);</text></clause>
<clause id="H318447E2822A473E9A51FE9FD9702C2A"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">areas defined by the Bureau of the Census as Alaska Native Village Statistical Areas, Oklahoma Tribal Statistical Areas, Tribal-Designated Statistical Areas, or American Indian Joint-Use Areas; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBBFE5ED0402B4100AAFC0A1FCD269FE0"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">land areas of State-recognized Indian tribes and heritage groups that are defined and recognized by individual States and included in the annual Boundary and Annexation Survey of the Bureau of the Census.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H441A3E834AF34E22BA290B3D486D0FDA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Persistent poverty county</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Term <quote>persistent poverty county</quote> means a county that has had poverty rates of 20 percent or more for the past 30 years, as measured by the most recent decennial censuses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HE58E429414724953B85C1B7070077555"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 804(e) of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977, as added by subsection (a), shall take effect after the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H8D560B712D8C4D1DAF5E576896DD7B56"><enum>4.</enum><header>Treatment of illegal and discriminatory activity</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 804 of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2903">12 U.S.C. 2903</external-xref>), as amended by section 3, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3422ECA10A01459AAF5E8CF6F5498D4A" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H85CC7A9167A34DF186F8DAC7033588AF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Treatment of illegal or discriminatory activity</header> <paragraph id="HABFCDA07E03048AAB34577354F62FCCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In assessing and taking into account, under subsection (a), the record of a financial institution, the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall give negative credit for any activity of the financial institution, a subsidiary of the financial institution, or an entity partnering with the financial institution or subsidiary that includes evidence of an illegal or discriminatory practice, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9133DA19AC934186808A82D80EF45197"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activity that harms, including by displacing, residents of low- and moderate-income neighborhoods;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF8A0899C4B44393B522CC19FFC4B0D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any violation of Federal law, regardless of whether the violation is credit-related or not, including any violation of section 987(b) of title 10, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Military Lending Act</quote>), the Servicemembers Civil Relief Act, or prohibitions against unfair, deceptive, or abusive acts or practices;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D7C650C961D41E3900035BC3E6AB83B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any violation of State law; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H525BF38CD74347B6AB36B9964C2F1415"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any evidence of discriminatory practices obtained by—</text>
<clause id="H164CA927023348E9AFE1FA8DD93D8109"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection as a part of the Bureau’s regular supervision of the financial institution, subsidiary, or entity; and</text></clause> <clause id="H78826B9004654163B9D2888E26F4B6E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE8E3CD71D7734DC1A144FD187860873D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the treatment of any illegal or discriminatory activity described under paragraph (1), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall consider—</text> <subparagraph id="HF02861050A2E4BA986A02C1DBE0195FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the root cause of the activity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEF81946FF5A341359640ACE09853EAF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the severity of the harm to individuals and communities as a result of the activity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61F1E4B55DD04DA5AFA0DAEC79146371"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the duration of time of the activity; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H60749A6A0F4A4B3DBD04346027640DAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the pervasiveness of the activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0907C19672145589756A904685FD536"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment on tests and overall assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, in performing an assessment of a financial institution under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency uses separate tests or other evaluations as part of the calculation of the overall assessment, the agency shall give negative credit on both the overall assessment and any applicable test or evaluation.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HED64944086364CAB99868CE11BC942BF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Community Advisory Committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 804 of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2903">12 U.S.C. 2903</external-xref>), as amended by section 4, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H93988395222C44F0AF9DE477D9B28F6F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H2ED9B0D0A22B41F4A62DB3E779D8D7EE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Community Advisory Committees</header> <paragraph id="HA3B6A9C454CD448DA2C2E9711B0C0FD9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each financial institution shall form a separate Community Advisory Committee (which shall be composed of a diverse set of consumer, housing, community development, and other stakeholder groups representing the applicable metropolitan statistical area) in each of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HBE5ABDBA0C234077A725AEB0EE1EBCF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a financial institution with consolidated assets equal to or greater than $2,000,000,000, each metropolitan statistical area where the financial institution or any subsidiaries of the financial institution have a branch or other facility (including an automated teller machine) and each metropolitan statistical area where the financial institution has a substantial number of customers who maintain deposit accounts with the financial institution.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4BF89ACE27F643A28EA789B416144907" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a financial institution with consolidated assets of less than $2,000,000,000, each State where the financial institution or any subsidiaries of the financial institution are located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9D4BC91DE68A43C3A760F699D450C8AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Quarterly consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The executives of a financial institution shall meet with all the financial institution’s Community Advisory Committees on a quarterly basis—</text> <subparagraph id="H8C2DC895CD014389A37E57736540AD88"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to discuss the financial institution’s current work to meet the credit and deposit needs of low- and moderate-income individuals and underserved communities, persons with disabilities, LGBTQ+ communities, and Chinese, Asian Indian, Filipino, Japanese, Korean, Vietnamese, Pakistani, Cambodian, Hmong, Laotian, Thai, Taiwanese, Burmese, Bangladeshi, Nepalese, Indonesian, Malaysian, Hispanic or Latino, Black or African American, American Indian and Alaska Native, Native Hawaiian, Samoan, Chamorro, Tongan, iTaukei, Marshallese, and Other Pacific Islander communities, as applicable to the financial institution’s geographic areas;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA51F65350F5B4F88973B3E5B426B5F2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a financial institution with consolidated assets equal to or greater than $2,000,000,000, to assist the executives in developing and updating a plan for how the institution will work to meet the credit needs of the institution’s entire community, including low- and moderate-income neighborhoods; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H514EB2350AA7472EABD150DC606C50DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to discuss the institution’s data (which shall be disaggregated by Chinese, Asian Indian, Filipino, Japanese, Korean, Vietnamese, Pakistani, Cambodian, Hmong, Laotian, Thai, Taiwanese, Burmese, Bangladeshi, Nepalese, Indonesian, Malaysian, Hispanic or Latino, Black or African American, American Indian and Alaska Native, and Native Hawaiian, Samoan, Chamorro, Tongan, iTaukei, Marshallese and Other Pacific Islander communities, as applicable to the financial institution’s geographic areas) on—</text>
<clause id="HAB639C91C1844768A99B76B8BF5068C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mortgage lending and lending to small businesses and small farms;</text></clause> <clause id="H03B654B4B39B440ABBE8E1CF2009FD83"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>retail products and services;</text></clause>
<clause id="H3C51BE1086334F75BFA786DFB1AEB29F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>community development services; and</text></clause> <clause id="H44C7B8FEEBCD4F47B1896A449495C731"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community development financing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H02D1A23F243A4C16945A4DA7A010060F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specific consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the quarterly consultations required under paragraph (2), the executives of a financial institution with consolidated assets of more than $2,000,000,000 shall meet with the Community Advisory Committee before—</text> <subparagraph id="H669E3CBEA456468FB8B62587363C0CE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial institution applies for a merger or acquisition;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H995ACE3B80E745BD9B4D776E7A0B8680"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the financial institution, or any subsidiary of the financial institution, applies for deposit insurance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7C64878ECD3404C8AD878129C11CD7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the financial institution applies to open a new branch or to relocate an existing branch; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0587DF6F212C49598EAEE144331D3A78"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the financial institution provides notice that it would close a branch or other facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HF2DCD5E0CDF84E5682B9173BB1DFD31C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Consideration of lending in partnership with non-depository lenders</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 804 of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2903">12 U.S.C. 2903</external-xref>), as amended by section 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H52E195181E7A4FAD9ABEABBAA8619634">
<subsection id="H0C86E29213AF40F1A9FF20EC63116A8E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Consideration of lending in partnership with non-Depository lenders</header>
<paragraph id="HBA172D54396447FEBE9270B6FE240BFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of assessing a financial institution under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall evaluate the financial institution’s performance in originating small farm loans, consumer loans (including residential mortgages, unsecured installment loans, advances, and lines of credit), and loans for small businesses (including unsecured installment loans, advances, and lines of credit) in partnership with one or more non-depository lenders.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6A9DCC6B37343FFAE85B0BDE907EE98"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affordability and sustainability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making the evaluation described under paragraph (1), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall consider the affordability and sustainability of the loan originations made in partnership with one or more non-depository lenders.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H141100600507402DAAA35F18313A4293"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="H2570B8D162454FBBAC2446808E496E62"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Non-depository lender</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>non-depository lender</quote> means a lender that is not an insured depository institution (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8AC1D1A876574E8FA00A77B3C696A8D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>small business</quote> means a small business concern (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)), except such term shall not include any small business concern with gross annual revenue of greater than $5,000,000 for the preceding fiscal year. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBAEA1AF319AB449097D0F07F895AA14B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small farm loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>small farm loan</quote> means a loan—</text>
<clause id="HEC908DE120F4469F8B424C23E4BE3A32" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>originated in an amount of $500,000 or less; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF96292FF43A64823B905DEBFF4D03347" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is reported as a—</text>
<subclause id="H52DB79552F8B4A6995C9AE6E88D472DC" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>loan to finance agricultural production and other loan to farmers; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H85B951E400BC46138F7874A90B4CF676" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>loan secured by farmland.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HEED68B04B11F4F15ABF672EFD3B62F97"><enum>7.</enum><header>Consideration of small home mortgage lending</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 804 of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2903">12 U.S.C. 2903</external-xref>), as amended by section 6, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE6A7C5D8E0CD42DDB9F4FF99D3B2A1FF" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H5C94E98461E448F3847E63060C07BBBF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consideration of small home mortgage lending</header> <paragraph id="HCAE16266842A40998BF662EA58AA864D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As part of assessing a financial institution under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall evaluate the financial institution’s performance in facilitating home mortgage lending targeted to low- and moderate-income borrowers in a safe and sound manner, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H49D7A5841CCB46478F739B887645107F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>small-dollar, first-lien mortgages of $100,000 or less in value that facilitate a home purchase or help a borrower to refinance an existing mortgage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC29E0DCC059F4EF6B541ED9C778E7544"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mortgages of any size originated in cooperation with a minority depository institution, women’s depository institution, low-income credit union, or a community development financial institution certified by the Secretary of the Treasury (as defined under section 103 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAD20ACC7D7447BEABA6409E00F34574"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data collection and reporting by large financial institutions</header>
<subparagraph id="H0C79C9C7B24C41DEA3CE4711D5E79BF5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each large financial institution shall collect, maintain, and report to the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency—</text> <clause id="HA7EF28A770DE4025BBABC613BA663F06"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mortgage loan data needed to calculate retail lending volume and distribution metrics;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF933FED053414DD282AA367BE1AE21F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information related to demographics of borrowers, including the income, gender identity, sexual orientation, race, and ethnicity of mortgage applicants;</text></clause> <clause id="HC5AC88CC7ED2432CB6B6CC8164745639"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of mortgage loans originated with a value of $100,000 or less, as well as the demographics of borrowers, including income, gender, race, and ethnicity; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HAADD550008E8474F8341C69AD2A151F5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the financial institution has a special purpose credit program that focuses on borrowers from Hispanic or Latino, Black or African American, Chinese, Asian Indian, Filipino, Japanese, Korean, Vietnamese, Pakistani, Cambodian, Hmong, Laotian, Thai, Taiwanese, Burmese, Bangladeshi, Nepalese, Indonesian, Malaysian, American Indian and Alaska Native, Native Hawaiian, Samoan, Chamorro, Tongan, iTaukei, Marshallese, and Other Pacific Islander communities, all mortgage loans originated by the financial institution under such program that are made for the purpose of a home purchase or to refinance a mortgage loan made for the purpose of a home purchase.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14E012513D2F41F294EE7CF26BE5867E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Template</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate Federal financial supervisory agencies shall, jointly, issue rules to establish a template that large financial institutions shall use to collect information required to be collected under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8895BF7EF33C4AB9AE0601AD051F0A89"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional consideration of small dollar mortgages by small and intermediate financial institutions</header>
<subparagraph id="H2A3A8EFD55D045F0A40B37CFACF6EC5E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of assessing a small or intermediate financial institution under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency shall, at the request of the financial institution, provide additional consideration of any mortgages extended by the financial institution that are small-dollar mortgages of $100,000 or less in value that facilitate a home purchase or help a borrower to refinance an existing mortgage.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40553CB2E96D491C82BC6752C315E09F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rating adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency planned to assign a rating under section 807(b)(2) to a small or intermediate financial institution of <quote>Satisfactory record of meeting community credit needs</quote>, the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency may, after the additional consideration described under subparagraph (A), change such rating to <quote>Outstanding record of meeting community credit needs</quote>, if the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agency determines such change is appropriate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8074695A470040BA8E0C24AC692422AB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall, jointly, define the terms <quote>large financial institution</quote> and <quote>small or intermediate financial institution</quote> for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HC4C0ECA30EA24FEAA52F762ED4EB021A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Study on discrimination and disparities in access to credit</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2901">12 U.S.C. 2901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HABDC832711F74881813A86DBBA3671CC" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="H0E7176B197CD47B4B7154D775852554D"><enum>810.</enum><header>Study on discrimination and disparities in access to credit</header>
<subsection id="HE0F7F545428E4D8DA3336386C1ABF318"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this section, and every 2 years thereafter, the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agencies shall, jointly, and in consultation with such other Federal or State agencies as the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agencies determine appropriate, complete an interagency statistical study to identify metropolitan areas and rural counties that either experience ongoing discrimination or exhibit significant racial disparities in access to credit for any racial or ethnic group.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H64AF880DD268486989AFF9DB241E3E97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out each study required under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agencies shall make use of—</text>
<paragraph id="H890CBA802360491DB80D67004E2D304A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>data obtained under the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BDE86F8152E4366AD926729F8E0000B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>data obtained under section 704B of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H624C64A63DDF40F8A863390A5341A15C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>available State data; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB43281D88DD1481793DA392F37E519F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information contained in public litigation against regulated financial institutions for redlining or lending discrimination (including litigation initiated by the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Department of Housing and Urban Affairs, the Department of Justice, or by private parties).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H366805125798440E84C3E3296AA27F90"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the completion of each study required under subsection (a), the appropriate Federal financial supervisory agencies shall, jointly, issue a report to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, containing—</text> <paragraph id="H2278EA22BA2047EC88CFBB259BD19464"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all findings and determinations made in carrying out the study; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6492CE56649743F08C1784F5C869DDE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy recommendations to remedy the discrimination and disparities identified in the study.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

