<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" bill-type="appropriations" dms-id="ID34BAC14540CB4BC4ADFBFC96EE9D188A" public-private="public"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8257 RH: Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2023</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 304</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8257</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–396]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</sponsor>, from the <committee-name committee-id="AP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, reported the following bill; which was committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">Making appropriations for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body changed="not-changed" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" id="ID3F54C6107CE743A8878D0BC760C31247" style="traditional-inline"> 
<section display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="ID79993566F894480FBAE9AE6C63CC75EA" section-type="undesignated-section"> <text>That the following sums are appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, for the Department of Homeland Security for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, and for other purposes, namely:</text> </section> <title id="HA7D846B1C23C4766915D072D6F15B16C" level-type="subsequent" style="traditional-inline"> <enum>I</enum> <header display-inline="no-display-inline">Departmental management, intelligence, situational awareness, and oversight</header> <appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="H24B7AC78712249E6BE98D6D508ADB495"> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Office of the secretary and executive management</header> </appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small commented="no" id="H397D19AA58EB48FA870DBD9216CEBDD6"> <header>Operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Secretary and for executive management for operations and support, $346,717,000; of which $28,570,000 shall be for the Office of the Ombudsman for Immigration Detention, of which $5,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $30,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H37DE9CED80FF4165B26A32032680A9D8"><header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Secretary and for executive management for procurement, construction, and improvements, $8,048,000, which shall remain available until September 30, 2025. </text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="HD8C28D5127F445988DCBAA40F9BCD0E1"><header>Federal assistance</header></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H638B06FA00614261B152EB970351F6B2"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Secretary and for executive management for Federal assistance through grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other activities, $40,000,000, which shall be transferred to <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, of which $20,000,000 shall be for targeted violence and terrorism prevention grants and of which $20,000,000 shall be for the Alternatives to Detention Case Management program, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate commented="no" id="HEC4E848DE58D45519FFF5F2690A1ECFB"> <header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Management directorate</header> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="H579626B655A34EC9887847972E201A35"> <header>Operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Management Directorate for operations and support, including vehicle fleet modernization, $1,787,000,000, of which $76,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H6E23D26DD8824A43B5B1824A916508CA"> <header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Management Directorate for procurement, construction, and improvements, $597,378,000, of which $182,378,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2025, and of which $415,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2027.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="HA63687F382F54882A5A545A63FB1CF95"><header>Federal Protective Service</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The revenues and collections of security fees credited to this account shall be available until expended for necessary expenses related to the protection of federally owned and leased buildings and for the operations of the Federal Protective Service.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H427FBB39F9F44EACB7D7E364B6E4738B"><header>Intelligence, analysis, and situational awareness</header></appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="H5A912B291B4B45F7ABCC11928257CED6"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of Intelligence and Analysis and the Office of Homeland Security Situational Awareness for operations and support, $341,159,000, of which $119,792,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $3,825 shall be for official reception and representation expenses and not to exceed $2,000,000 is available for facility needs associated with secure space at fusion centers, including improvements to buildings.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="H70AB92914735436BABB73977C2928AC4"> <header>Office of the inspector general</header> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="H50EB8CEF06BF4772B229460792D44133"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Office of the Inspector General for operations and support, $218,379,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $300,000 may be used for certain confidential operational expenses, including the payment of informants, to be expended at the direction of the Inspector General.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="HA9375AB41E4C4B1493BC122A7721784C"> <header>Administrative provisions</header><subheader>(including transfer of funds)</subheader> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<section id="HD94254E228554C1FA267B8B1D85DA889"><enum>101.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE503598C6C0945FFBA85961CF3133E30"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report not later than October 15, 2023, to the Inspector General of the Department of Homeland Security listing all grants and contracts awarded by any means other than full and open competition during fiscal years 2022 or 2023.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H724E91B24C3847B9B44B296C35DE9B9A"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Inspector General shall review the report required by subsection (a) to assess departmental compliance with applicable laws and regulations and report the results of that review to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than February 15, 2024.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD8C890EFF2614DB784A46445BBBCF5C5"><enum>102.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the last day of each month, the Chief Financial Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a monthly budget and staffing report that includes total obligations of the Department for that month and for the fiscal year at the appropriation and program, project, and activity levels, by the source year of the appropriation.</text></section> <section id="H18E1BF6D967D4F92A8A15ED7B620DA7A"><enum>103.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall require that all contracts of the Department of Homeland Security that provide award fees link such fees to successful acquisition outcomes, which shall be specified in terms of cost, schedule, and performance.</text></section> 
<section id="H86BB61277D20425CA946D015F6DF9CB7"><enum>104.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF068B9E8E4D14D39875DCC5BB3A6624C"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives of any proposed transfers of funds available under section 9705(g)(4)(B) of title 31, United States Code, from the Department of the Treasury Forfeiture Fund to any agency within the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2CB2B04991C34591B666C87FC386D31B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds identified for such a transfer may be obligated until the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified of the proposed transfer.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8ED39B38B3AD472AA21385ABDBC17668"><enum>105.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All official costs associated with the use of Government aircraft by Department of Homeland Security personnel to support official travel of the Secretary and the Deputy Secretary shall be paid from amounts made available for the Office of the Secretary.</text></section> <section id="HE6CB3610621A462EBF270560668BA3F9"><enum>106.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD790DD7AFC90475C9308E1EB282C6ECF"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Management shall brief the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 30 days after the end of each fiscal quarter on all Level 1 and Level 2 acquisition programs on the Master Acquisition Oversight list between Acquisition Decision Event 1 and Full Operational Capability, including programs that have been removed from such list during the preceding quarter.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCCF28006D9524E348E73F1AD08C1BAA5"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For each such program, the briefing described in subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HAA32A034B2874E6C941E831998A27D21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the purpose of the program, including the capabilities being acquired and the component(s) sponsoring the acquisition;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2DC7A8D9E2F144789A90D95B220A3676"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the total number of units, as appropriate, to be acquired annually until procurement is complete under the current acquisition program baseline;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CDB9EAB00464916BEAC6202FFD86D1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Acquisition Review Board status, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF899B4A52A8E43259B72C4FE4083BB25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the current acquisition phase by increment, as applicable;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98E07C0CFA6F4EE19F1AFA927FD01276"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of the most recent review; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H176334F7B6D04D3A81D57C9D9EAC865D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the program has been paused or is in breach status;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A89EBA84EDB48339B21B9992D419553"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a comparison between the initial Department-approved acquisition program baseline cost, schedule, and performance thresholds and objectives and the program's current such thresholds and objectives, if applicable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E53C92AC1374F1F82F8C372D1D00D35"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the lifecycle cost estimate, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H9669EEA180FE418E91186DBB99433792"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the confidence level for the estimate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H170E061D2C924E3690B7DA8C686155E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the fiscal years included in the estimate; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEAFB40115704A20BCC32417B60BE6A3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a breakout of the estimate for the prior five years, the current year, and the budget year;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF68340A16004750BABEB69FF320FE51"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a breakout of the estimate by appropriation account or other funding source; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03F4662EC4154650B46CDC2DD76AC611"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of and rationale for any changes to the estimate as compared to the previously approved baseline, as applicable, and during the prior fiscal year;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7B9B23238054AD7A779E4524651B8D8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a summary of the findings of any independent verification and validation of the items to be acquired or an explanation for why no such verification and validation has been performed;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C162009D91B4797A667375D21079CA5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a table displaying the obligation of all program funds by prior fiscal year, the estimated obligation of funds for the current fiscal year, and an estimate for the planned carryover of funds into the subsequent fiscal year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E47D3E0471D456C90DAD386CCEB588F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a listing of prime contractors and major subcontractors; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCABA14F57BD74C6392B11A567D3FD8C1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>narrative descriptions of risks to cost, schedule, or performance that could result in a program breach if not successfully mitigated.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2AE66062EE0A4F838AE6204FD77A9F33"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Under Secretary for Management shall submit each approved Acquisition Decision Memorandum for programs described in this section to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than five business days after the date of approval of such memorandum by the Under Secretary for Management or the designee of the Under Secretary.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFDB805FB08994B74B9C4F3BD7B0DA733"><enum>107.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5294C935F8C540DA9F3F5A51D15E0496"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security in this Act or prior appropriations Acts may be obligated for any new pilot or demonstration program unless the component or office carrying out such pilot or program has documented the information described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1332BF3EA9B422CA99C397812000943"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Prior to the obligation of any such funds made available for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for a new operational pilot or demonstration program, the Under Secretary for Management shall provide a report to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives on the information described in subsection (c).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3BDAF91DD013449DBDB93321783FCE39"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The information required under subsections (a) and (b) for a new pilot or program shall include the following—</text> 
<paragraph id="H76E33D51A09D43DE934F409F83FDC3E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documented objectives that are well-defined and measurable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H049D6914A2F64CA0987D23CC4A73421C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment methodology that details—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3E38E2714F43452B9FAFF4BC08AF2DE1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the type and source of assessment data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EED4D9148F142F79F0E53BDEB48B66A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the methods for and frequency of collecting such data; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25AC05C079BB4626A0BA2497BACB2A56"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such data will be analyzed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H99C9FF87D7ED46A4A68FCCC95AC36F2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> an implementation plan, including milestones, a cost estimate, and schedule, including an end date.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H770547398E324A26B59265DD9B5C5F8F"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of completion of a pilot or program described in subsection (e), the Under Secretary for Management shall provide a report to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives detailing lessons learned, actual costs, any planned expansion or continuation of the pilot or program, and any planned transition of such pilot or program into an enduring program or operation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA216AF44460E4178A4735D8D619540CA"><enum>(e)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, a pilot or demonstration program is a policy implementation, study, demonstration, experimental program, or trial that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9E3A3B45F0304DC4A0E2714826FFA26F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a small-scale, short-term experiment conducted in order to evaluate feasibility, duration, costs, or adverse events, and improve upon the design of an effort prior to implementation of a larger scale effort; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB340A5FA740145A2834ED503C528D30A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>uses more than 5 full-time equivalents or obligates more than $1,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="H25FE7ACD5CDB4C2CBBA8853D36A21C7F" changed="not-changed"><enum>108.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount made available by section 4005 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>), $14,000,000 shall be transferred to <quote>Office of Inspector General—Operations and Support</quote> for oversight of the use of funds made available under such section 4005.</text> </section> </title> <title id="H89091290E5724BC2906D946C93613125"> <enum>II</enum> <header display-inline="no-display-inline">Security, enforcement, and investigations</header> <appropriations-intermediate id="H406D3D12A2E24C28B6EFFC8811BC350E"> <header>U.S. customs and border protection</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="HC1D0B2C6F5894E09A10D7FE8ABF52BB5"><header>Operations and support</header> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="HC652EB6DC6F24D4793AE0E09BD7D8CBF"> <header>(including transfer of funds)</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Customs and Border Protection for operations and support, including the transportation of unaccompanied alien minors; the provision of air and marine support to Federal, State, local, and international agencies in the enforcement or administration of laws enforced by the Department of Homeland Security; at the discretion of the Secretary of Homeland Security, the provision of such support to Federal, State, and local agencies in other law enforcement and emergency humanitarian efforts; the purchase and lease of up to 7,500 (6,500 for replacement only) police-type vehicles; the purchase, maintenance, or operation of marine vessels, aircraft, and unmanned aerial systems; and contracting with individuals for personal services abroad; $14,690,501,000; of which $3,274,000 shall be derived from the Harbor Maintenance Trust Fund for administrative expenses related to the collection of the Harbor Maintenance Fee pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9505">section 9505(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9505">26 U.S.C. 9505(c)(3)</external-xref>) and notwithstanding section 1511(e)(1) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/551">6 U.S.C. 551(e)(1)</external-xref>); of which $200,000,000 shall be available until September 30, 2024; and of which such sums as become available in the Customs User Fee Account, except sums subject to section 13031(f)(3) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(f)(3)</external-xref>), shall be derived from that account: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $34,425 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $150,000 shall be available for payment for rental space in connection with preclearance operations: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,000,000 shall be for awards of compensation to informants, to be accounted for solely under the certificate of the Secretary of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $5,000,000 may be transferred to the Bureau of Indian Affairs for the maintenance and repair of roads on Native American reservations used by the U.S. Border Patrol.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H236DAA32891F4B4ABE49A75FE00E6611"> <header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Customs and Border Protection for procurement, construction, and improvements, including procurement of marine vessels, aircraft, and unmanned aerial systems, $547,539,000, of which $402,180,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2025; and of which $145,359,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2027.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-intermediate id="H2798B040609A41838B885BDDE326718E"> <header> U.S. immigration and customs enforcement</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <appropriations-small id="H937259F931214E43B79118386F291EF5"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for operations and support, including the purchase and lease of up to 3,790 (2,350 for replacement only) police-type vehicles; overseas vetted units; and maintenance, minor construction, and minor leasehold improvements at owned and leased facilities; $8,298,567,000; of which not less than $6,000,000 shall remain available until expended for efforts to enforce laws against forced child labor; of which $46,696,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024; of which not less than $1,500,000 is for paid apprenticeships for participants in the Human Exploitation Rescue Operative Child-Rescue Corps; of which not less than $15,000,000 shall be available for investigation of intellectual property rights violations, including operation of the National Intellectual Property Rights Coordination Center; of which not less than $13,500,000 shall be used for providing financial assistance for operational, administrative, salary reimbursement, and technology costs associated with participation of Federal, State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers on the Homeland Security Investigations Border Enforcement Security Task Force; and of which $3,923,433,000 shall be for enforcement, detention, and removal operations, including support for joint processing centers and transportation of unaccompanied alien minors: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $11,475 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $10,000,000 shall be available until expended for conducting special operations under section 3131 of the Customs Enforcement Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2081">19 U.S.C. 2081</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,000,000 shall be for awards of compensation to informants, to be accounted for solely under the certificate of the Secretary of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $11,216,000 shall be available to fund or reimburse other Federal agencies for the costs associated with the care, maintenance, and repatriation of smuggled aliens unlawfully present in the United States: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That of the amounts made available under this heading for Executive Leadership and Oversight, $5,000,000 shall not be available for obligation until the reports directed under this heading in the explanatory statements accompanying Public Laws 116–6, 116–93, and 117–103 have been submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the amount made available under this heading for Executive Leadership and Oversight shall be reduced each month by $25,000 for each day after the required date that the briefing described in section 219 has not been provided to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives. </text></appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H01B88A2D7E4D4EA1BB5A49D2912E31A7"> <header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for procurement, construction, and improvements, $97,762,000, of which $22,997,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2025, and of which $74,765,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2027.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-intermediate id="HDBB1675285724C939BB3C5244442C2D8"> <header>Transportation security administration</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <appropriations-small id="H980232AE7942446F880FA6400E46F112"> <header>Operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Transportation Security Administration for operations and support, $9,244,863,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $7,650 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That security service fees authorized under section 44940 of title 49, United States Code, shall be credited to this appropriation as offsetting collections and shall be available only for aviation security: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the sum appropriated under this heading from the general fund shall be reduced on a dollar-for-dollar basis as such offsetting collections are received during fiscal year 2023 so as to result in a final fiscal year appropriation from the general fund estimated at not more than $6,754,863,000.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H4B30ADEA30314EA395939BD14A8EEB49"> <header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Transportation Security Administration for procurement, construction, and improvements, $141,689,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="HDEFC875C497B4770A7C00BB76568CED0"> <header>Research and development</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Transportation Security Administration for research and development, $33,532,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="H631E5C0A12594617958DD09AE72AE01A"><header>Coast Guard</header></appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="H453F29DAF07A442D80607A3A57356C0E"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Coast Guard for operations and support including the Coast Guard Reserve; purchase or lease of not to exceed 25 passenger motor vehicles, which shall be for replacement only; purchase or lease of small boats for contingent and emergent requirements (at a unit cost of not more than $700,000) and repairs and service-life replacements, not to exceed a total of $31,000,000; purchase, lease, or improvements of boats necessary for overseas deployments and activities; payments pursuant to section 156 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/97/377">Public Law 97–377</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/402">42 U.S.C. 402</external-xref> note; 96 Stat. 1920); and recreation and welfare; $9,751,469,000, of which $530,000,000 shall be for defense-related activities; of which $24,500,000 shall be derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to carry out the purposes of section 1012(a)(5) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2712">33 U.S.C. 2712(a)(5)</external-xref>); of which $6,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2025; of which $28,386,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2027, for environmental compliance and restoration; and of which $70,000,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024, which shall only be available for vessel depot level maintenance: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $23,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H9C0FF94036A74953858CBE52F76D68D2"> <header>Procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Coast Guard for procurement, construction, and improvements, including aids to navigation, shore facilities (including facilities at Department of Defense installations used by the Coast Guard), and vessels and aircraft, including equipment related thereto, $2,301,050,000, to remain available until September 30, 2027; of which $20,000,000 shall be derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to carry out the purposes of section 1012(a)(5) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2712">33 U.S.C. 2712(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="H7E20CEF8F0E0415D870A32D16A80445F"> <header>research and development</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Coast Guard for research and development; and for maintenance, rehabilitation, lease, and operation of facilities and equipment; $7,476,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025, of which $500,000 shall be derived from the Oil Spill Liability Trust Fund to carry out the purposes of section 1012(a)(5) of the Oil Pollution Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2712">33 U.S.C. 2712(a)(5)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That there may be credited to and used for the purposes of this appropriation funds received from State and local governments, other public authorities, private sources, and foreign countries for expenses incurred for research, development, testing, and evaluation.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="HFBF4FC889C7747ACAED7B17FA5F6EF4A"> <header>retired pay</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For retired pay, including the payment of obligations otherwise chargeable to lapsed appropriations for this purpose, payments under the Retired Serviceman's Family Protection and Survivor Benefits Plans, payment for career status bonuses, payment of continuation pay under section 356 of title 37, United States Code, concurrent receipts, combat-related special compensation, and payments for medical care of retired personnel and their dependents under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, $2,044,414,000, to remain available until expended.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-intermediate id="H50393E44C36E432287E272A09EF9A7EA"> <header>United states secret service</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <appropriations-small id="HA14A1CC1B09141658EFD9E4B506E28BD"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Secret Service for operations and support, including purchase of not to exceed 652 vehicles for police-type use; hire of passenger motor vehicles; purchase of motorcycles made in the United States; hire of aircraft; rental of buildings in the District of Columbia; fencing, lighting, guard booths, and other facilities on private or other property not in Government ownership or control, as may be necessary to perform protective functions; conduct of and participation in firearms matches; presentation of awards; conduct of behavioral research in support of protective intelligence and operations; payment in advance for commercial accommodations as may be necessary to perform protective functions; and payment, without regard to section 5702 of title 5, United States Code, of subsistence expenses of employees who are on protective missions, whether at or away from their duty stations; $2,645,596,000; of which $52,296,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024, and of which $6,000,000 shall be for a grant for activities related to investigations of missing and exploited children; and of which up to $17,000,000 may be for calendar year 2022 premium pay in excess of the annual equivalent of the limitation on the rate of pay contained in section 5547(a) of title 5, United States Code, pursuant to section 2 of the Overtime Pay for Protective Services Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/5547">5 U.S.C. 5547</external-xref> note), as last amended by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/269">Public Law 116–269</external-xref>: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $19,125 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $100,000 shall be to provide technical assistance and equipment to foreign law enforcement organizations in criminal investigations within the jurisdiction of the United States Secret Service.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H4F5B1296C9714F1384875A6EA209B99E"> <header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Secret Service for procurement, construction, and improvements, $77,888,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="HF89B7F2E52DE4591BFCA0CF8D15A6A36"> <header>research and development</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the United States Secret Service for research and development, $4,025,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="H924CB4B402BB473A8F2CAA7FD3DFE6D3"> <header>Administrative provisions</header></appropriations-intermediate><appropriations-small id="H7C5E4C5A08124FDBA12FFB46757C6E2B"><header>(including transfer of funds)</header> </appropriations-small> 
<section id="H61E4835B62C8440286914D5DA211D813"><enum>201.</enum><text>Section 201 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2018 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>), related to overtime compensation limitations, shall apply with respect to funds made available in this Act in the same manner as such section applied to funds made available in that Act, except that <quote>fiscal year 2023</quote> shall be substituted for <quote>fiscal year 2018</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5C66DB270D074643823C0862951E2361"><enum>202.</enum><text>Funding made available under the headings <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Operations and Support</quote> and <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> shall be available for customs expenses when necessary to maintain operations and prevent adverse personnel actions in Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands, in addition to funding provided by sections 740 and 1406i of title 48, United States Code.</text></section> 
<section id="H0132F13032F04B088024341B87970789"><enum>203.</enum><text>As authorized by section 601(b) of the United States-Colombia Trade Promotion Agreement Implementation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/42">Public Law 112–42</external-xref>), fees collected from passengers arriving from Canada, Mexico, or an adjacent island pursuant to section 13031(a)(5) of the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/58c">19 U.S.C. 58c(a)(5)</external-xref>) shall be available until expended.</text></section> <section id="H5B3AFD6E7F08445BBA2D3062DDD3ED6F"><enum>204.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H23C1A9D946344E8992FA98168D5E5541"><enum>(a)</enum><text>For an additional amount for <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Operations and Support</quote>, $31,000,000, to remain available until expended, to be reduced by amounts collected and credited to this appropriation in fiscal year 2023 from amounts authorized to be collected by section 286(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(i)</external-xref>), section 10412 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8311">7 U.S.C. 8311</external-xref>), and section 817 of the Trade Facilitation and Trade Enforcement Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/25">Public Law 114–25</external-xref>), or other such authorizing language.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H86CAB42EED864E44B2845A440AB8D585"><enum>(b)</enum><text>To the extent that amounts realized from such collections exceed $31,000,000, those amounts in excess of $31,000,000 shall be credited to this appropriation, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H677AC49A50874031A3348274A7E85D78"><enum>205.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act for U.S. Customs and Border Protection may be used to prevent an individual not in the business of importing a prescription drug (within the meaning of section 801(g) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act) from importing a prescription drug from Canada that complies with the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That this section shall apply only to individuals transporting on their person a personal-use quantity of the prescription drug, not to exceed a 90-day supply: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the prescription drug may not be—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDC7A98AE5DE54EFBA40054D97E00FF79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a controlled substance, as defined in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H072DFF67EEF843B89B1CFF77B85DE22D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a biological product, as defined in section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFCB44FE717A64B52B67984C30F647E22"><enum>206.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAE4B78EF99FC43F58957D26D13201E6A"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, none of the funds provided in this or any other Act shall be used to approve a waiver of the navigation and vessel-inspection laws pursuant to section 501(b) of title 46, United States Code, for the transportation of crude oil distributed from and to the Strategic Petroleum Reserve until the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretaries of the Departments of Energy and Transportation and representatives from the United States flag maritime industry, takes adequate measures to ensure the use of United States flag vessels.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3F536394753D4126A7AA65823DF8A1D9"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives within 2 business days of any request for waivers of navigation and vessel-inspection laws pursuant to section 501(b) of title 46, United States Code, with respect to such transportation, and the disposition of such requests.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDF740A4A33F248659A36F996FE1CF67E"><enum>207.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H395C87EC73D64746A7173408D47E1D62"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall not—</text> <paragraph id="HAE00F4BFDBCD4696937E5958055473B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish, collect, or otherwise impose any new border crossing fee on individuals crossing the Southern border or the Northern border at a land port of entry; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93345DB361FA4C738E2B4A5CA414936B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct any study relating to the imposition of a border crossing fee.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB2CC4501C8F745C997F5E06135C83806"><enum>(b)</enum><text>In this section, the term <term>border crossing fee</term> means a fee that every pedestrian, cyclist, and driver and passenger of a private motor vehicle is required to pay for the privilege of crossing the Southern border or the Northern border at a land port of entry.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H83C26F34C52640EBA57D0706B8418EFB"><enum>208.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H96749BE9BE114010BDA6E4B1E243B196"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit an expenditure plan for any amounts made available for <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> in this Act and prior Acts to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA2EAC5AAD1224E64B6AC7F47622ADED8"><enum>(b)</enum><text>No such amounts may be obligated prior to the submission of such plan.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HD080F0224FEF4FB189D9FFEF4B9A218C"><enum>209.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Federal funds may not be made available for the construction of fencing—</text> <paragraph id="H2A8490DA17FF4A73A9C2065788E18B4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within the Santa Ana Wildlife Refuge;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0096DEC6164540319B02CDADEA6C086C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within the Bentsen-Rio Grande Valley State Park;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD85A3AA9FAEF4A1FA6EBD18806C8AA32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>within La Lomita Historical park;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3962C2B42A44944B9B4AAB6ED7E1514"><enum>(4)</enum><text>within the National Butterfly Center;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H149F2E7C124D468F85C3633BC093D07C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>within or east of the Vista del Mar Ranch tract of the Lower Rio Grande Valley National Wildlife Refuge;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E1488713FAA480AA764A1A0A24BA20A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within any cemetery designated as a historic cemetery under State law or regulation; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7D68489FCD6463FABFEB30245B57C83"><enum>(7)</enum><text>within the San Ygnacio Bird Sanctuary &amp; Riverfront; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEDD4B1F25954FF895BAF98F1220D890"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within the Salineño Wildlife Preserve.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF11D72E8A61B4E0FBFF2C99CD78F21B0"><enum>210.</enum> <subsection id="H78EF9CE661714358BF0E5F27FB294AF1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balances of amounts specified in paragraphs (1) through (5) of section 230(a) of division F of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>), section 230(a)(1) of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</external-xref>), section 209(a)(1) of division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/93">Public Law 116–93</external-xref>), and section 210 of division F of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) shall, in addition to the purposes for which they were originally appropriated, be available for—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3355BA5A07164BA781164EBBB93F03D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the construction and improvement of roads along the southwest border;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD96D7D04ED2949D493745B431AAC9F3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>control of vegetation along the southwest border that creates obstacles to the detection of illegal entry;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF30ECC019C4477193666A6C1EF8EF77"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remediation and environmental mitigation, including scientific studies, related to border barrier construction, including barrier construction undertaken by the Department of Defense; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H663B288472E941A5A2BF178984DA8393"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the acquisition and deployment of border security technology at and between ports of entry along the southwest border.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H972EA3A9EE5D4F078958243B938684BB"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts repurposed by this section shall be in addition to any other amounts made available for such purposes.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD8238356F18B4EEF8421F718737434D8"><enum>211.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may transfer up to $100,000,000 in unobligated balances available from prior appropriations Acts under the heading <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> to the Department of the Interior (including any agency or bureau within the Department of the Interior) or the Forest Service within the Department of Agriculture for the execution of environmental and other mitigation projects or activities, including the acquisition of land and scientific studies, related to the construction of border barriers on the southwest border during fiscal years 2017 through 2021 by U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Department of Defense. </text> </section> 
<section id="HEA50B46EBA6A499FBBEEFDFBDA145D50" commented="no" changed="not-changed"><enum>212.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 230(b) of division F of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>), section 230(b) of division A of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</external-xref>), section 209(b) of division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/93">Public Law 116–93</external-xref>) (including with respect to section 210 of division F of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>)) shall no longer apply.</text></section> <section id="HA3D3B03B5CC540A8B380E4512DD60F64"><enum>213.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided under the heading <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support</quote> may be used to continue a delegation of law enforcement authority authorized under section 287(g) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1357">8 U.S.C. 1357(g)</external-xref>) if the Department of Homeland Security Inspector General determines that the terms of the agreement governing the delegation of authority have been materially violated.</text></section> 
<section id="HDC18964315FD406DA352C34AB85374E2"><enum>214.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBAD000C7A2904749A4A8527A11A03FEB"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds provided under the heading <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support</quote> may be used to continue any contract for the provision of detention services if the two most recent overall performance evaluations received by the contracted facility are less than <quote>adequate</quote> or the equivalent median score in any subsequent performance evaluation system.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H38BF0B0ACBAF4F56B58C7CB99F51742C"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The performance evaluations referenced in subsection (a) shall be conducted by the U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement Office of Professional Responsibility.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3608F106110E4C339A8989B09D269C2F"><enum>215.</enum><text>Without regard to the limitation as to time and condition of section 503(d) of this Act, the Secretary may reprogram within and transfer funds to <quote>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support</quote> as necessary to ensure the detention of aliens prioritized for removal.</text></section> <section id="H0EF1EEBEC8504A0499DF20D17F4C5C2E"><enum>216.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reports required to be submitted by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, related to immigration enforcement, under section 216 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2021 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>), and section 218 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020 (division D of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) shall continue to be submitted semimonthly and each matter required to be included in each such report by such section 216 shall apply in the same manner and to the same extent.</text></section> 
<section id="H6C7AAFFC659B4BFCBD59E820654A255E"><enum>217.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used to place in detention, remove, refer for a decision whether to initiate removal proceedings, or initiate removal proceedings against any individual— </text> <paragraph id="H2AC4EF9247A9444183358CEAAD15F669"><enum>(1)</enum><text>based on information provided to a Federal employee or contractor related to facilitating the sponsorship of an unaccompanied alien child (as defined in section 462(g) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279(g)</external-xref>)) or the reunification of such child with a family member; or </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD24E44A2DC0A4107867BBA270B7E4925"><enum>(2)</enum><text>based on information gathered in therapy sessions conducted while in the care of the Office of Refugee Resettlement of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text> </paragraph></section> <section id="HF2A1FE27CB14485B9C2FB610CA8DD110"><enum>218.</enum><text>The terms and conditions of section 217 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2020 (division D of Public Law 116—93), related to reporting on the U.S. Customs and Immigration Enforcement 287(g) program, shall apply to this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H83CED26BCC624E84B6291325BCC21625"><enum>219.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 30 calendar days after the date of enactment of this Act and not later than the 21st day of each month thereafter, the Director of Immigration and Customs Enforcement (or the Director’s designee) shall provide a briefing to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives on obligations and on-board staffing levels at both the account and the program, project, and activity level for the prior two fiscal years and the current fiscal year, to-date, and projected obligations and staffing levels by month for the remainder of the current fiscal year. </text></section> <section id="H703630809C0C4C048D2E02C45B3B0140"><enum>220.</enum> <subsection id="H10F8BCCB48344942A4C81D764AC36633" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided under the heading “U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement—Operations and Support” may be used to engage in civil immigration enforcement activities, such as arrests, expulsions, custodial detentions, removals, or referrals, processing, or issuance of charging documents, using Homeland Security Investigations personnel, resources, or capabilities, absent probable cause that the individual facing such enforcement action has committed a criminal offense, excluding state, local, or Federal offenses for which an essential element was the noncitizen's immigration status.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFFA4D7469C334637A81E90F292E4D4EE"><enum>(b)</enum><text>For the purposes of this section, criminal offenses for which an essential element was the noncitizen’s immigration status includes, but is not limited to, offenses identified in sections 264, 266(a), 266(b), 275, or 276 of the Immigration and Nationality Act and state and local offenses for which an essential element was the noncitizen’s immigration status.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7D754384BA9B438383B2D2241CA1058A" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>221.</enum> <subsection id="H40074097422444D9A8720A28927F9BAD" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used for the purposes of section 6(d) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/81/626">Public Law 81–626</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1555">8 U.S.C. 1555(d)</external-xref>). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC252FB83F614FCFAB6B07E1AB7F38DD"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply if the rate described such section for work performed is not less than the rates established under paragraph (1) of section 6703 of title 41, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4F7A524044824CA3B46A3CB80B9D26CD"><enum>222.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the United States House of Representatives and the United States Senate, including the leadership; the heads of Federal agencies and commissions, including the Secretary, Deputy Secretary, Under Secretaries, and Assistant Secretaries of the Department of Homeland Security; the United States Attorney General, Deputy Attorney General, Assistant Attorneys General, and the United States Attorneys; and senior members of the Executive Office of the President, including the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall not be exempt from Federal passenger and baggage screening.</text></section> 
<section id="H876C1E926A9841BAB56706148D6F4DF6"><enum>223.</enum><text>Any award by the Transportation Security Administration to deploy explosives detection systems shall be based on risk, the airport's current reliance on other screening solutions, lobby congestion resulting in increased security concerns, high injury rates, airport readiness, and increased cost effectiveness.</text></section> <section id="H70E0C1812D894CE38D17568D6CC7A23E"><enum>224.</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 44923 of title 49, United States Code, for fiscal year 2023, any funds in the Aviation Security Capital Fund established by section 44923(h) of title 49, United States Code, may be used for the procurement and installation of explosives detection systems or for the issuance of other transaction agreements for the purpose of funding projects described in section 44923(a) of such title.</text></section> 
<section id="HF653C1A90ECA42989D4A71A61496A640"><enum>225.</enum><text>Not later than 45 days after the submission of the President's budget proposal, the Administrator of the Transportation Security Administration shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations and Homeland Security in the House of Representatives a single report that fulfills the following requirements:</text> <paragraph id="H0E84AE1295BC4F8489BE09490A84677D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a Capital Investment Plan, both constrained and unconstrained, that includes a plan for continuous and sustained capital investment in new, and the replacement of aged, transportation security equipment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9224884CD7A47E0B5BA3940188FE1DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the 5-year technology investment plan as required by section 1611 of title XVI of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as amended by section 3 of the Transportation Security Acquisition Reform Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/245">Public Law 113–245</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82C9FB49F9D048DDA2A22DF8D81A437F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Advanced Integrated Passenger Screening Technologies report as required by the Senate Report accompanying the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2019 (Senate Report 115–283).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H080062991F064BD28B4DFCBAE4F1154D" changed="not-changed"><enum>226.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 225 of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/6">Public Law 116–6</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/44901">49 U.S.C. 44901</external-xref> note), relating to a pilot program for screening outside of an existing primary passenger terminal screening area, is amended in subsection (e) by striking <quote>2023</quote> and inserting <quote>2025</quote>. </text></section> <section id="HCC753B11824F437897338D5840F2FBE7"><enum>227.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7F6BB385BE0D4FF087DBFA0AAFBC905F"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds made available by this Act under the heading <quote>Coast Guard—Operations and Support</quote> shall be for expenses incurred for recreational vessels under section 12114 of title 46, United States Code, except to the extent fees are collected from owners of yachts and credited to the appropriation made available by this Act under the heading <quote>Coast Guard—Operations and Support</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H481BF501D2384669A0B1DC3B0925ADE0"><enum>(b)</enum><text>To the extent such fees are insufficient to pay expenses of recreational vessel documentation under such section 12114, and there is a backlog of recreational vessel applications, personnel performing non-recreational vessel documentation functions under subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/121">chapter 121</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, may perform documentation under section 12114.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HD91197AAF739465EB11FBE43A6855598"><enum>228.</enum><text>Without regard to the limitation as to time and condition of section 503(d) of this Act, after June 30, in accordance with the notification requirement described in subsection (b) of such section, up to the following amounts may be reprogrammed within <quote>Coast Guard—Operations and Support</quote>—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBAF79B1402474F3898231183420D9C15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$10,000,000 to or from the <quote>Military Personnel</quote> funding category; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCEEA691D5134755812963BBD9554CE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$10,000,000 between the <quote>Field Operations</quote> funding subcategories.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC5B8BE8E353C4CDCBE370621CF696779"><enum>229.</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Commandant of the Coast Guard shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a future-years capital investment plan as described in the second proviso under the heading <quote>Coast Guard—Acquisition, Construction, and Improvements</quote> in the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/4">Public Law 114–4</external-xref>), which shall be subject to the requirements in the third and fourth provisos under such heading.</text></section> <section id="H77968C4239934F218FD249AFDEB8E5B8"><enum>230.</enum><text>Of the funds made available for defense-related activities under the heading <quote>Coast Guard—Operations and Support</quote>, up to $190,000,000 that are used for enduring overseas missions in support of the global fight against terrorism may be reallocated by program, project, and activity, notwithstanding section 503 of this Act.</text></section> 
<section id="H31012077C2454F23B475F7355F4A19BD"><enum>231.</enum><text>Amounts deposited into the Coast Guard Housing Fund in fiscal year 2023 shall be available until expended to carry out the purposes of section 2946 of title 14, United States Code, and shall be in addition to funds otherwise available for such purposes.</text></section> <section id="H3356CA729CBE4472A985673C11A89730"><enum>232.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE6A376A6ECE5407082054FC093BF1770"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 2110 of title 46, United States Code, none of the funds made available in this Act may be used to charge a fee for an inspection of a towing vessel, as defined in 46 CFR Section 136.110, that utilizes the Towing Safety Management System option for a Certificate of Inspection issued under subchapter M of title 46, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB69A3A59C73840578736EAAB5F896268"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply after the date the Commandant of the Coast Guard makes a determination under section 815(a) of the Frank LoBiondo Coast Guard Authorization Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/282">Public Law 115–282</external-xref>) and, as necessary based on such determination, carries out the requirements of subsection 815(b) of such Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H217D5CB50EC9466E902F0E04AD57560F"><enum>233.</enum><text>The United States Secret Service is authorized to obligate funds in anticipation of reimbursements from executive agencies, as defined in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, for personnel receiving training sponsored by the James J. Rowley Training Center, except that total obligations at the end of the fiscal year shall not exceed total budgetary resources available under the heading <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote> at the end of the fiscal year.</text></section> 
<section id="HF4AC770AADAB43FAB5D4134F0704564C"><enum>234.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE9E97A431B534A8CA5DD23084EC0B578"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the United States Secret Service by this Act or by previous appropriations Acts may be made available for the protection of the head of a Federal agency other than the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H59CEF00D2D534652B2BDAA627BCED05C"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Director of the United States Secret Service may enter into agreements to provide such protection on a fully reimbursable basis.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1E30F4900C264A6EAC80D9E94B43A423"><enum>235.</enum><text>For purposes of section 503(a)(3) of this Act, up to $15,000,000 may be reprogrammed within <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5E80AA52B5BD4F65B9C10FCC84350E55"><enum>236.</enum><text>Funding made available in this Act for <quote>United States Secret Service—Operations and Support</quote> is available for travel of United States Secret Service employees on protective missions without regard to the limitations on such expenditures in this or any other Act if the Director of the United States Secret Service or a designee notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives 10 or more days in advance, or as early as practicable, prior to such expenditures.</text></section> 
<section id="H95B9EDDCFE20450189D092030D4975AC"><enum>237. </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to any legal limitations on continued detention, none of the funds made available by this Act may be used to release removable aliens into the United States until the Secretary of Homeland Security has determined whether that person is included in the terrorist screening database and whether the National Crime Information Center includes any active wants or warrants in the jurisdiction where such alien is to be released.</text></section> <section id="H9385115F788C4421B2CE8B6365F5886A"><enum>238.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to pay the salaries or expenses of personnel to process aliens encountered at the United States border under the immigration laws (as such term is defined in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>)), if such alien would have been processed under section 362 and section 365 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 265 and 268) as of January 19, 2021, until 180 days after date on which the public health emergency relating to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 pandemic, declared under section 319 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>) on January 31, 2020, and any continuation of such declaration (including the continuation described in Proclamation 9994 on February 24, 2021) has been terminated.</text></section> </title> 
<title id="H150283C0E38046999EFCCE3E89CAC5D6" style="appropriations"> <enum>III</enum> <header display-inline="no-display-inline">Protection, preparedness, response, and recovery</header> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="HFAF247F9E7CC43DA988E88B8BF3F0323"> <header>Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency</header> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="HA61FFD6BA45246AC9C6BC26EB55D083F"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency for operations and support, $2,373,213,000, of which $28,293,000, shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $5,500 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H7921D229F0D642F197438AC70021AEC3"> <header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency for procurement, construction, and improvements, $547,148,000, of which $520,048,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2025, and of which $27,100,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2027.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="H137C19583D5C463CBF9B37903B5E6FC2"> <header>research and development</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency for research and development, $7,431,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text></appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="HEB2701D4009746D99EAD190E7C323266"> <header>Federal emergency management agency</header> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="HA355F59A3E8D434CA620EDF482AE298B"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for operations and support, $1,414,461,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,250 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H3EEBE63B649C4EC5B7D4BEEF24820F1A"> <header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for procurement, construction, and improvements, $203,730,000, of which $126,425,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2025, and of which $77,305,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2027.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="HC7A18D79D75F4E4A824C50C78C2867BE"><header>Federal assistance</header> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="H3F88083CB62B4C2A9C9313A697530846"> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For activities of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for Federal assistance through grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other activities, $4,051,619,000, which shall be allocated as follows:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA49108704C3947B9A8D7A7343FA60C97"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$520,000,000 for the State Homeland Security Grant Program under section 2004 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/605">6 U.S.C. 605</external-xref>), of which $90,000,000 shall be for Operation Stonegarden, $15,000,000 shall be for Tribal Homeland Security Grants under section 2005 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/606">6 U.S.C. 606</external-xref>). <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That notwithstanding subsection (c)(4) of such section 2004, for fiscal year 2023, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico shall make available to local and tribal governments amounts provided to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico under this paragraph in accordance with subsection (c)(1) of such section 2004.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7AA2B1D5CFA24FCDA1371582B9ECB708"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$615,000,000 for the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/604">6 U.S.C. 604</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA005878CB434460A8E4E60D147A9959D" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$360,000,000 for the Nonprofit Security Grant Program under sections 2003 and 2004 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (6 U.S.C. 604 and 605), of which $180,000,000 is for eligible recipients located in high-risk urban areas that receive funding under section 2003 of such Act and $180,000,000 is for eligible recipients that are located outside such areas: <italic>Provided</italic>, That eligible recipients are those described in section 2009(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609a">6 U.S.C. 609a(b)</external-xref>) or are an otherwise eligible recipient at risk of a terrorist or other extremist attack.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92952D26C39E4C29B5BFF10631BCFB18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$105,000,000 for Public Transportation Security Assistance, Railroad Security Assistance, and Over-the-Road Bus Security Assistance under sections 1406, 1513, and 1532 of the Implementing Recommendations of the 9/11 Commission Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1135">6 U.S.C. 1135</external-xref>, 1163, and 1182), of which $10,000,000 shall be for Amtrak security and $2,000,000 shall be for Over-the-Road Bus Security: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such public transportation security assistance shall be provided directly to public transportation agencies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC6ACC545B1244DEBD6762123A7FDD2F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for Port Security Grants in accordance with section 70107 of title 46, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC49B63E2A5944F278040981536E2442A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>$740,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024, of which $370,000,000 shall be for Assistance to Firefighter Grants and $370,000,000 shall be for Staffing for Adequate Fire and Emergency Response Grants under sections 33 and 34 respectively of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (15 U.S.C. 2229 and 2229a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H933324BAA6494EC7A5BF9DA6C3E77711"><enum>(7)</enum><text>$370,000,000 for emergency management performance grants under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121</external-xref>), the Earthquake Hazards Reduction Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7701">42 U.S.C. 7701</external-xref>), section 762 of title 6, United States Code, and Reorganization Plan No. 3 of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78FDCEA212254F70AD23C0CC535A118A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>$350,000,000 for necessary expenses for Flood Hazard Mapping and Risk Analysis, in addition to and to supplement any other sums appropriated under the National Flood Insurance Fund, and such additional sums as may be provided by States or other political subdivisions for cost-shared mapping activities under section 1360(f)(2) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4101">42 U.S.C. 4101(f)(2)</external-xref>), to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0400989FF094348BD527F195B29C366"><enum>(9)</enum><text>$12,000,000 for Regional Catastrophic Preparedness Grants.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H088380F36B9042E280ED8985D912901F"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$280,000,000 for the emergency food and shelter program under title III of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11331">42 U.S.C. 11331</external-xref>), to remain available until September 30, 2024, of which $150,000,000 is for the purposes of providing humanitarian relief to families and individuals encountered by the Department of Homeland Security: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed 3.5 percent shall be for total administrative costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39CC5AD19D274492BA6A04BDD893A0B3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>$40,000,000 for the Next Generation Warning System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H465B67B421364272A7AA0C95D6C9AF09"><enum>(12) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$247,500,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024, for the purposes, and in the amounts, specified in the table entitled <quote>Community Project Funding</quote> under this heading in the report accompanying this Act, in addition to amounts otherwise made available for such purposes; of which $51,856,713 is for emergency operations center grants under section 614 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5196c">42 U.S.C. 5196c</external-xref>); of which $173,118,908 is for pre-disaster mitigation grants under section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133(e)</external-xref>, notwithstanding subsections (f), (g), and (l) of that section (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133(f)</external-xref>, (g), and (l)); and of which up to $22,524,379 is for management and administration costs of recipients. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3676B61D8004F3EB8D7F7A33CD46929"><enum>(13)</enum><text>$312,119,000 to sustain current operations for training, exercises, technical assistance, and other programs.</text></paragraph></appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="H2F638FC183FD4537BB62AD5FF06E1D9A"> <header>Disaster relief fund</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses in carrying out the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>), $19,945,000,000 to remain available until expended, shall be for major disasters declared pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) and is designated by the Congress as being for disaster relief pursuant to section 1(f) of H. Res. 1151 (117th Congress), as engrossed in the House of Representatives on June 8, 2022. </text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H130BBA43E0044FF28A8A99DAB076E1CA"> <header>National flood insurance fund</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For activities under the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4001">42 U.S.C. 4001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Biggert-Waters Flood Insurance Reform Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/141">Public Law 112–141</external-xref>, 126 Stat. 916), and the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/89">Public Law 113–89</external-xref>; 128 Stat. 1020), $225,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024, which shall be derived from offsetting amounts collected under section 1308(d) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(d)</external-xref>); of which $18,500,000 shall be available for mission support associated with flood management; and of which $206,500,000 shall be available for flood plain management and flood mapping: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That any additional fees collected pursuant to section 1308(d) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015(d)</external-xref>) shall be credited as offsetting collections to this account, to be available for flood plain management and flood mapping: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That in fiscal year 2023, no funds shall be available from the National Flood Insurance Fund under section 1310 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4017">42 U.S.C. 4017</external-xref>) in excess of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5313F6DA90DA4A71BF0331A5310B2667"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$233,700,000 for operating expenses and salaries and expenses associated with flood insurance operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8753B7A0C754E839F89B3CDCD17CA93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$960,647,000 for commissions and taxes of agents;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAC469F56E9D54C3581C88D65F1F63D4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such sums as are necessary for interest on Treasury borrowings; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1BE95FF0E1247EB88FC351D53FCE477"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$175,000,000, which shall remain available until expended, for flood mitigation actions and for flood mitigation assistance under section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>), notwithstanding sections 1366(e) and 1310(a)(7) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(e)</external-xref>, 4017):</text></paragraph> <continuation-text continuation-text-level="appropriations-small"> 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the amounts collected under section 102 of the Flood Disaster Protection Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a</external-xref>) and section 1366(e) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(e)</external-xref>), shall be deposited in the National Flood Insurance Fund to supplement other amounts specified as available for section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, notwithstanding section 102(f)(8), section 1366(e) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, and paragraphs (1) through (3) of section 1367(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4012a">42 U.S.C. 4012a(f)(8)</external-xref>, 4104c(e), 4104d(b)(1)–(3)): 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That total administrative costs shall not exceed 4 percent of the total appropriation: 
<proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That up to $5,000,000 is available to carry out section 24 of the Homeowner Flood Insurance Affordability Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4033">42 U.S.C. 4033</external-xref>).</continuation-text></appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="HA7014FFC5FCA45A0B3509750A4B48663"> <header>Administrative provisions</header> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<section id="H7E05D2715B0A478BBF2947C9101B4C8E"><enum>301.</enum> 
<subsection id="HB0B00213422C4EEA99A6636646B0ABB8" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Notwithstanding section 2008(a)(12) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/609">6 U.S.C. 609(a)(12)</external-xref>) or any other provision of law, not more than 5 percent of the amount of a grant made available in paragraphs (1) through (5) under <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, may be used by the recipient for expenses directly related to administration of the grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1B49B2E84F084C6DBCDA12152AE28BD1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority provided in subsection (a) shall also apply to a state recipient for the administration of a grant under paragraph (3) under such heading for the Nonprofit Security Grant Program.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H738E6CFEDAFC436A82C7A94F2620CBCC"><enum>302.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clauses (i) through (v) of section 204(e)(1)(A) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/605">6 U.S.C. 605(e)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref> through (v)), for fiscal year 2023, the meaning of <quote>total funds appropriated for grants under this section and section 2003</quote> shall not include any funds appropriated for the Nonprofit Security Grant Program under paragraph (3) under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>. </text> </section> <section id="HF5FB6B5792364832B332ADC7B59AE83E"><enum>303.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applications for grants under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for paragraphs (1) through (4), shall be made available to eligible applicants not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, eligible applicants shall submit applications not later than 80 days after the grant announcement, and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall act within 65 days after the receipt of an application.</text></section> 
<section id="HB8AEC7BF659145CB8516A7AFB621A460"><enum>304.</enum> 
<subsection id="H34125D2E57794242892283E8B3EADB28" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>Under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for grants under paragraphs (1) through (5) and (9), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall brief the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives 5 full business days in advance of announcing publicly the intention of making an award.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFCC65399316E4E7CB63B88F5F9FCED86"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any such public announcement is made before 5 full business days have elapsed following such briefing, $1,000,000 of amounts appropriated by this Act for “Federal Emergency Management Agency—Operations and Support” shall be rescinded. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H142AC07E9579490FA3D786CE7FBF4A17"><enum>305.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for grants under paragraphs (1) and (2), the installation of communications towers is not considered construction of a building or other physical facility.</text></section> <section id="H7C75331B63B1491E88D1012E63FB29D3"><enum>306.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reporting requirements in paragraphs (1) and (2) under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Disaster Relief Fund</quote> in the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/4">Public Law 114–4</external-xref>), related to reporting on the Disaster Relief Fund, shall be applied in fiscal year 2023 with respect to budget year 2024 and current fiscal year 2023, respectively—</text> 
<paragraph id="H023612A2656B4A39AF5A4FFEA2DC7FB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by substituting <quote>fiscal year 2024</quote> for <quote>fiscal year 2016</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0383394B55D41B4B30634AD584DA5AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by inserting <quote>business</quote> after <quote>fifth</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC89A8495ACC2468B8DE7A15A2AEF7BED"><enum>307.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for Staffing for Adequate Fire and Emergency Response grants, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may grant waivers from the requirements in subsections (a)(1)(A), (a)(1)(B), (a)(1)(E), (c)(1), (c)(2), and (c)(4) of section 34 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2229a">15 U.S.C. 2229a</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="HE60EA180291A41F39DACB8C02273CB14"><enum>308.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFF0618C6CDD64858A434B31827A88D3D"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggregate charges assessed during fiscal year 2023, as authorized in title III of the Departments of Veterans Affairs and Housing and Urban Development, and Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5196e">42 U.S.C. 5196e</external-xref>), shall not be less than 100 percent of the amounts anticipated by the Department of Homeland Security to be necessary for its Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program for the next fiscal year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3E1AAB6F93340B8BE71D64DDD117A91"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The methodology for assessment and collection of fees shall be fair and equitable and shall reflect costs of providing such services, including administrative costs of collecting such fees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFBDD2F7210E8472BBDFE11D11CAA295A"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Such fees shall be deposited in a Radiological Emergency Preparedness Program account as offsetting collections and will become available for authorized purposes on October 1, 2023, and remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H409B9C29717F44C98A02455DABA9653C"><enum>309.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants under the heading <quote>Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance</quote>, for Assistance to Firefighter Grants, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may waive subsection (k) of section 33 of the Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2229">15 U.S.C. 2229</external-xref>).</text></section> </title> <title id="H10C9B3C5101140238C7C4C4DE374C86A"> <enum>IV</enum> <header display-inline="no-display-inline">Research, development, training, and services</header> <appropriations-intermediate id="H7576B864AA2E4B6082DB8424E9433A71"> <header> U.S. citizenship and immigration services</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <appropriations-small id="HF196538D8C814DA8BB08EB6316CA4046"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for operations and support, including for the E-Verify Program, application processing, the reduction of backlogs within asylum, field, and service center offices, and for the Refugee, Asylum, and International Operations Programs, $653,293,000: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That such amounts shall be in addition to any other amounts made available for such purposes, and shall not be construed to require any reduction of any fee described in section 286(m) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1356">8 U.S.C. 1356(m)</external-xref>): <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,500 shall be for official reception and representation expenses: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That, notwithstanding any other provision of law, not to exceed $20,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024, shall be for implementation of the Deferred Action for Childhood Arrivals Program of the Secretary of Homeland Security, established pursuant to the memorandum from the Secretary of Homeland Security entitled ‘Exercising Prosecutorial Discretion with Respect to Individuals Who Came to the United States as Children’, dated June 15, 2012, including for the processing of applications for such program and for work authorization under such program.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small commented="no" id="H738A02FD559F47C3960D64F0A34E86E2"><header>Federal assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services for Federal assistance for the Citizenship and Integration Grant Program, $30,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text></appropriations-small><appropriations-intermediate id="H6077AA5B139A49C88EDDBAA89A561651"> <header>Federal law enforcement training centers</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <appropriations-small id="H78247CF5F7F24D899D945394E151C0BE"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers for operations and support, including the purchase of not to exceed 117 vehicles for police-type use and hire of passenger motor vehicles, and services as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, $355,247,000, of which $66,665,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso>Provided</proviso>, That not to exceed $7,180 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="H44926F8B6CAC4172B0CE62F7AD6F0EE7"> <header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers for procurement, construction, and improvements, $41,300,000, to remain available until September 30, 2027, for acquisition of necessary additional real property and facilities, construction and ongoing maintenance, facility improvements and related expenses of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-intermediate id="HBA8130D2908F476D968A5EE4C4B1D572"> <header>Science and technology directorate</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <appropriations-small id="H6135A1885273499680AA8B8893E31222"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Science and Technology Directorate for operations and support, including the purchase or lease of not to exceed 5 vehicles, $369,107,000, of which $215,397,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $10,000 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small><appropriations-small id="H0031E12F1754450BADD3E713C17DFAD1"><header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Science and Technology Directorate for procurement, construction, and improvements, $63,716,000, to remain available until September 30, 2027.</text></appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="H3697F1F0393B433F9E587FFEF5855322"> <header>research and development</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Science and Technology Directorate for research and development, $530,954,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-intermediate id="H60945449DC3642559FDBC20A7BC2B370"> <header>Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office</header> </appropriations-intermediate> 
<appropriations-small id="H3FEEA13A01F64B6FB2B8EB8CD40181E2"> <header>operations and support</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office for operations and support, $151,970,000, of which $50,446,000 shall remain available until September 30, 2024: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That not to exceed $2,250 shall be for official reception and representation expenses.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="HE9C408838A29452AA347A3D5AF6AE2B0"> <header>procurement, construction, and improvements</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office for procurement, construction, and improvements, $55,304,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-small id="H5CCF4B3595BA492F9C1899231427FFF9"> <header>research and development</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office for research and development, $82,515,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025.</text> </appropriations-small> 
<appropriations-small id="HE097D2E726A04D8D89E817EB85E62570"> <header>federal assistance</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">For necessary expenses of the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office for Federal assistance through grants, contracts, cooperative agreements, and other activities, $139,183,000, to remain available until September 30, 2025.</text> </appropriations-small> <appropriations-intermediate id="HB714FE90518C4670974E3CA9FEA04D0B"> <header>Administrative provisions</header> </appropriations-intermediate> <section id="HD914879D17A548969305D86AC33E6DC0"><enum>401.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8692E4E7ADC845578C0E2950A13B0A31"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, funds otherwise made available to U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services may be used to acquire, operate, equip, and dispose of up to 5 vehicles, for replacement only, for areas where the Administrator of General Services does not provide vehicles for lease.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6FEBB1AB5434C0E8DA22F8CCEE1BB15"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services may authorize employees who are assigned to those areas to use such vehicles to travel between the employees' residences and places of employment.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HEBC2FB2EB4804A68926B24862102211C"><enum>402.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated by this Act may be used to process or approve a competition under Office of Management and Budget Circular A–76 for services provided by employees (including employees serving on a temporary or term basis) of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services of the Department of Homeland Security who are known as Immigration Information Officers, Immigration Service Analysts, Contact Representatives, Investigative Assistants, or Immigration Services Officers.</text></section> 
<section id="H8DDE68D779B34C21BC458982C6B45AEF"><enum>403.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any Federal funds made available to U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services may be used for the collection and use of biometrics taken at a U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services Application Support Center that is overseen virtually by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services personnel using appropriate technology.</text></section> <section id="H5E7FF33C3ECB42678BB3B282C87B74D0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>404.</enum> <subsection id="HB57AF344A1C14813BD814FA968D1D135" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text> The numerical limitations in sections 201, 202, and 203 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>, 1152, and 1153) shall not apply during fiscal year 2023 or during any subsequent fiscal year to an alien described in section 101(a)(27)(J) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)(J)</external-xref>) for whom a petition for classification under section 203(b)(4) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>) was filed before October 1, 2023.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6E2FEA1067B14EA9B39FDAC473D7269E"><enum>(b)</enum><text>This section shall take effect on June 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3D2CC54C798D4D49BE8CF681023C78C9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>405.</enum> <subsection id="H9D28898E285C415A94852D343FA5277F" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum> <paragraph id="HD6B9BA0836094C5C9443C817A2BF20A7" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning in fiscal year 2023, the number of family-sponsored immigrant visas that may be issued under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) shall be increased by the number computed under paragraph (2). Section 202(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152(a)(2)</external-xref>) shall not apply to the additional family-sponsored immigrant visas made available under this paragraph.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CD5C7B0253947B5A0887C6F35CD5144" indent="up2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number computed under this paragraph is the difference, if any, between—</text> <subparagraph id="HCEDF3E2491E7430DA96A3AEFC840FA85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the difference, if any, between—</text> 
<clause id="H837DCFE0DC5D4639835621308FC19754"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of visas that were originally made available to family-sponsored immigrants under section 201(c)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(c)(1)</external-xref>) for fiscal years 1992 through 2021, reduced by any unused visas made available to such immigrants in such fiscal years under section 201(c)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(c)(3)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> <clause id="HFD393C7EFBF14600BE695522CAE3AF3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of visas described in clause (i) that were issued under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>), or, in accordance with section 201(d)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(d)(2)(C)</external-xref>), under section 203(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0757109C4B6249D3AA2ADE45944B9D3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of visas resulting from the calculation under subparagraph (A) issued under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) after fiscal year 2022.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H202DA7B5650D4825BE3B9DA6E6BA4466"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of family-sponsored immigrant visas computed under paragraph (2) that may be issued under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>) shall be allotted between the family-sponsored categories at the start of every fiscal year as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9F084C21A5AF4D3884E2419754D0CE09"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10.4 percent to family-sponsored immigrants under section 203(a)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)(1)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraph (E);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H89E6C55D7DC54204953333CEBC50F60C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>38.9 percent to family-sponsored immigrants under section 203(a)(2)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H597194AAC6124128AC7FD7D767A91876"><enum>(C)</enum><text>11.6 percent to family-sponsored immigrants under section 203(a)(2)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) and (B);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB07E48DD8DA94F3095915A859080582C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>10.4 percent to family-sponsored immigrants under section 203(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)(3)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) through (C); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6632F33E9BE942D48B47C49DCAD29BCA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">28.7 percent to family-sponsored immigrants under section 203(a)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)(4)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC2106A3AD2ED493A96004F0677A79D6D"><enum>(b)</enum> <paragraph id="HAF0D3C43FBE942C8B4716F54EBFCC8B3" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning in fiscal year 2023, the number of employment-based immigrant visas that may be issued under section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>) shall be increased by the number computed under paragraph (2). Section 202(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1152">8 U.S.C. 1152(a)(2)</external-xref>) shall not apply to the additional employment-based immigrant visas made available under this paragraph.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3361AA6AC49F4CEA927023016D3B1F9A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number computed under this paragraph is the difference, if any, between—</text> <subparagraph id="H6293E19BA6E546B8A89F2860A66C0A63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the difference, if any, between—</text> 
<clause id="HF7075981FFCB41F2B83EBEFA66FD6162"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of visas that were originally made available to employment-based immigrants under section 201(d)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(d)(1)</external-xref>) for fiscal years 1992 through 2022, reduced by any unused visas made available to such immigrants in such fiscal years under section 201(d)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(d)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></clause> <clause id="HD9F4B8F672DD403D868EC5412CD61523"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of visas described in clause (i) that were issued under section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>), or, in accordance with section 201(c)(3)(C) of the immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(c)(3)(C)</external-xref>), under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(a)</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAE5649B729141B992347AD7FC8D5591"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of visas resulting from the calculation under subparagraph (A) issued under section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>) after fiscal year 2022.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2A8B88746EF4C29B426934146557B56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of employment-based immigrant visas computed under paragraph (2) that may be issued under section 203(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)</external-xref>) shall be allotted between the employment-based categories at the start of every fiscal year as follows:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE89FFEC66C1D472FBD1251B24737896F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">28.6 percent to employment-based immigrants under section 203(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(1)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraph (F);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H57CB6164E0704CDA952A9C6DEEDFF06F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>28.6 percent to employment-based immigrants under section 203(b)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(2)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7E5943031964F7F8B42FE4C5D6CA011"><enum>(C)</enum><text>21.5 percent to employment-based immigrants under section 203(b)(3)(A)(i) and (ii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(3)(A)(i)</external-xref> and (ii)), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) and (B);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EDA9BCEC61D4F85923AE291AF279CFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>7.1 percent to employment-based immigrants under section 203(b)(3)(A)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(3)(A)(iii)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) through (C);</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H873E52CF970541E8A91CC7C2E254D374"><enum>(E)</enum><text>7.1 percent to employment-based immigrants under section 203(b)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) through (D); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65E17F4D658448788594963F07AE6068"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">7.1 percent to employment-based immigrants under section 203(b)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(5)</external-xref>), plus any visa available under this paragraph not required for subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4EB992969228410C97FCE03F2D64BFC6"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Section 201(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H2E7A3DB490D44F0AAA95244983D7B8F3" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H6456D7F58B514D5EA243C4F012B3E3EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Worldwide Level of Family-Sponsored Immigrants</header><text>The worldwide level of family-sponsored immigrants under this subsection for a fiscal year is equal to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB0E827F17C974AF7A49D2004C00B1689"><enum>(1)</enum><text>226,000, plus</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB419E70348EA4C648C177470747FE265"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the difference (if any) between the maximum number of visas which may be issued under section 203(a) (relating to family-sponsored immigrants) during the previous fiscal year and the number of aliens who were issued immigrant visas or who otherwise acquired the status of aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence under that section during that year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H136BC75C9A844DA29E211D4C49BF30B4"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Section 201(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H728D15C5FAA948FB824BC4E908C991A4"> <subsection id="HBA76F68A117D4424A53AFDDA2D42292A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Worldwide Level of Employment-Based Immigrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The worldwide level of employment-based immigrants under this subsection for a fiscal year is equal to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4367DDB36F304152928E1689580FEE5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>140,000, plus</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2CAB5F5593F4DDCAD179C774E2B2B47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the difference (if any) between the maximum number of visas which may be issued under section 203(b) (relating to employment-based immigrants) during the previous fiscal year and the number of aliens who were issued immigrant visas or who otherwise acquired the status of aliens lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence under that section during that year.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H9E353C00949C4D008465AD8B71A05B5A" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>406.</enum> 
<subsection id="HAA6A377D42D24475B2291D9EDC64DAC1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 204(a)(1)(I)(ii)(II) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(I)(ii)(II)</external-xref>), and subject to subsection (d) of this section, an immigrant visa for those selected in accordance with section 203(e)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(e)(2)</external-xref>) in any of fiscal years 2017, 2018, 2019, 2020, or 2021 shall remain available to such alien if the alien was refused a visa, prevented from seeking admission, or denied admission to the United States solely because of—</text> <paragraph id="H2110B73395454DA998F3C9C72A00C305" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13769 (82 Fed. Reg. 8977; relating to <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into The United States</quote>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24576058011C4276903D33C3A2536216" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Executive Order 13780 (82 Fed. Reg. 13209; relating <quote>Protecting the Nation from Foreign Terrorist Entry into the United States</quote>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9FAC3D9AFA3C4810AAF0EF5574457051" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Proclamation 9645 (82 Fed. Reg. 45161; relating to <quote>Enhancing Vetting Capabilities and Processes for Detecting Attempted Entry into the United States by Terrorists or Other Public-Safety Threats</quote>); or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5C4C3CDC55794ADF91FD294613ECA886" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Proclamation 9983 (85 Fed. Reg. 6699; relating to <quote>Improving Enhanced Vetting Capabilities and Processes for Detecting Attempted Entry into the United States by Terrorists or Other Public-Safety Threats</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDBDFC63ACCD340B9BBBF16AEB2F7B134"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary of State shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H214EEB5F00A84900A4234E973B27FB85"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide written notice, consistent with subsection (c), to each alien described in subsection (a) (and such alien’s representative, if applicable) of the alien’s continuing eligibility to apply for a visa under section 203(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03C3EA94480A49CAA17453B516B4DA19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish on the Department of State website, information and procedures implementing this section. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD68979F4BC6D412CBAA6D2261AC02BBC"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The notice described in subsection (b)(1) shall include procedures for the alien to inform the Secretary of State of the alien’s intent to proceed with or abandon the application, and shall include an advisal that such application shall be deemed abandoned if the alien fails to notify the Secretary of the alien’s intent to proceed within one year after the date on which the notice was issued.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEEE8DA87B7B84B2C8032DBCF253E63AA"><enum>(d)</enum><text>An alien described in subsection (a) shall remain eligible to receive a visa described in such subsection until the earliest of the date that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H73A66091C5004ED29CC7D97A3980C533"><enum>(1)</enum><text> the alien—</text> <subparagraph id="H9402DEC44AB4482BA81EF0DB10F505C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text> notifies the Secretary of the alien’s intent to abandon the application; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H20498D4D8AE244F2AC3A2B219487FC7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fails to respond to the notice described in subsection (b)(1); or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0354A7403E6E49BC878E19509A382C4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of State makes a final determination of the alien’s ineligibility for such visa under section 203(c)(2), 204(a)(1)(I)(iii), or 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(c)(2)</external-xref>, 1154(a)(1)(I)(iii), or 1182(a)).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H71A960CB314448D48D7BC45ACF2D3054"><enum>(e)</enum><text>A determination of whether an alien is the child of a visa recipient described in subsection (a), pursuant to section 203(d) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(d)</external-xref>) shall be made using the age of the child when an applicant was initially selected for a visa in accordance with section 203(e)(2) of such Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H0C3EF4EDD88F47EB85FCD493B728B72E"><enum>407.</enum> <subsection id="HE7B778599619460583DBAE50E8879914" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the numerical limitation set forth in section 214(g)(1)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>), the Secretary of Homeland Security, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor and upon the determination that the needs of American businesses cannot be satisfied in fiscal year 2023 with United States workers who are willing, qualified, and able to perform temporary nonagricultural labor, may increase the total number of aliens who may receive a visa under section 101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(b)</external-xref>) in such fiscal year above such limitation by not more than the highest number of H–2B nonimmigrants who participated in the H–2B returning worker program in any fiscal year in which returning workers were exempt from such numerical limitation.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43E7FF98C0AE42AE823F79117ED851B1"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue guidance implementing this section not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H713EB50720404F6982441C4A17463694"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such guidance may be published on the internet website of the Department of Homeland Security, and shall be effective immediately upon such publication.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFB4AE84AE1864BDE87769D85CAC894AB"><enum>408.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fiscal year 2023, nonimmigrants shall be admitted to the United States under section 101(a)(l5)(H)(ii)(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(H)(ii)(a)</external-xref>) to perform agricultural labor or services, without regard to whether such labor is, or services are, of a temporary or seasonal nature.</text></section> <section id="H85BEBFA4E1734AB88B20B413BFA0A4B5"><enum>409.</enum> <subsection id="H39CB5F3128134BFFBFCE5324A781D18A" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum></enum><text>The Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers is authorized to distribute funds to Federal law enforcement agencies for expenses incurred participating in training accreditation.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC9DF14461EE64F34BBC7D4543D884997"><enum>410.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Law Enforcement Training Accreditation Board, including representatives from the Federal law enforcement community and non-Federal accreditation experts involved in law enforcement training, shall lead the Federal law enforcement training accreditation process to continue the implementation of measuring and assessing the quality and effectiveness of Federal law enforcement training programs, facilities, and instructors.</text></section> <section id="HB3EBFEE4FED34AAA84D886FF66B64A2F"><enum>411.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB16E39747BD84D92B4D75FDA046E7912"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers may accept transfers to its <quote>Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> account from Government agencies requesting the construction of special use facilities, as authorized by the Economy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1535">31 U.S.C. 1535(b)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52223377D6B74E718BAE1F9433AC279F"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers shall maintain administrative control and ownership upon completion of such facilities.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4A35E7CD01F1408F836680458CEDE8EB"><enum>412.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The functions of the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers instructor staff shall be classified as inherently governmental for purposes of the Federal Activities Inventory Reform Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/501">31 U.S.C. 501</external-xref> note).</text></section> </title> 
<title id="H2DC190EC93A04673BA9110B355CC0B82" changed="not-changed"> <enum>V</enum> <header display-inline="no-display-inline">General provisions</header> 
<appropriations-small id="HB0AC7A3A786D46F2B128B1741F27ECB9"> <header>(including transfers and rescissions of funds)</header> </appropriations-small> 
<section id="H5DB2394F73354C92B4055031DB3845EE"><enum>501.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein.</text></section> <section id="HD3F74709A27F4216B0CBD5177E5554DF"><enum>502.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the requirements of section 503 of this Act, the unexpended balances of prior appropriations provided for activities in this Act may be transferred to appropriation accounts for such activities established pursuant to this Act, may be merged with funds in the applicable established accounts, and thereafter may be accounted for as one fund for the same time period as originally enacted.</text></section> 
<section id="HBF4C9FDD80D44D8AB34B3474A1BCD920"><enum>503.</enum> 
<subsection id="H8339D17DA78442A18DA829B4A0B70588" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text> None of the funds provided to the Department of Homeland Security by this Act, by prior Acts, or from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived from the collection of fees available to the components funded by this Act, shall be available for obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds that—</text> <paragraph id="H185EF2CAEA344F79B2BF28EDBA6E87F5" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creates a new program, project, or activity; </text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07EAF6C8E51845248A7C3C92998D4611" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eliminates a program, project, or activity; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3F9718C4B294A2F9F88507B01127705" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>augments funding for any program, project, or activity in excess of $5,000,000 or 10 percent, whichever is less; or </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AF438534B9C4031B96401F94899FC1E" indent="up1"><enum>(4) </enum><text>reduces funding for any program, project, or activity, or numbers of personnel, by 10 percent or more.</text> <subparagraph id="HF7B2FA58711B4EF48C4768C368C36296"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply if the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified at least 15 days in advance of such reprogramming by the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA42B57740A794594AD6C76F71440D69F"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Up to 5 percent of any appropriation made available to the Department of Homeland Security by this Act or provided by previous appropriations Acts may be transferred between appropriations to address exigent requirements or circumstances if the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified at least 30 days in advance of such transfer, except that—</text> <clause id="HAF58227B96D74938A5B74742A1943407"><enum>(1)</enum><text>no such appropriation shall be augmented by more than 10 percent by such transfers unless otherwise specifically provided in this Act; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="HF9261B45BE3549E499D85183ABC98540"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no funding may be transferred from an appropriation that is designated by the Congress as being for— </text> <subclause id="HBC554C974360447E8A58FC7F6FB22462"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget; or </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H61C7083559744BB19C8A390A53DBAEA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disaster relief pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget. </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HCA689C31760A4F5788EC86F6CA049CE7" indent="up1"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsections (b) and (c), no funds shall be obligated for any purpose described in subsection (a) and no funds shall be transferred between appropriations based upon an initial notification provided after June 30, except—</text> 
<subclause id="HF52835989C9A47DFB3A15F8AA8E05A3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as otherwise provided in this Act; or </text></subclause> <subclause id="H8674F5F4854D4DD1916EF4478B3989E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>when the Under Secretary for Management provides a written justification and certifies in writing to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives that such action is necessary due to extraordinary circumstances that imminently threaten the safety of human life or the protection of property. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1FEE33E981484AF5B40EB884D713731D" indent="up1"><enum>(e)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subsection (c), the Secretary of Homeland Security may transfer to the fund established by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note, up to $20,000,000 from appropriations available to the Department of Homeland Security if the Secretary notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives at least 5 days in advance of such transfer. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H7599CD29AFFD4B95A47CA931C86925C1" indent="up1"><enum>(f)</enum><text>For purposes of this section— </text> 
<paragraph id="H44786726D7E44E159B31E6624E3D59FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>program, project, or activity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H145FE5CF277D44CDBEBFBD9A0154CC4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text> each item listed under an appropriation account or fee funded program account for which an amount is specified in the detailed funding table located at the end of the explanatory statement accompanying the applicable appropriations Act;</text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1FB4FDA1F6D840DDA741A0B03F2A6205"><enum>(B)</enum><text>each item for which the explanatory statement accompanying the applicable appropriations Act specifies a funding amount, except for references to increases or reductions below the budget request; or </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FC9EBAE6C064826B515EBF8642B0B68"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of subsection (a)(1), any allowable use of funds that is not within the scope of an item described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of this paragraph, except for such accounts or programs for which there are no such items; </text> 
<clause id="H46E1440B5AB24F76A05E32B32F98B6B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>reprogramming of funds</quote> means a reduction to or augmentation of a funding amount specified in the explanatory statement accompanying the applicable appropriations Act for a program, project, or activity; and </text></clause> <clause id="H7EF784AB7C9D4ED59CB249528A0FC670"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>exigent requirements or circumstances</quote> means those requirements or circumstances for which an inability to increase budgetary resources through a transfer of funds during the current fiscal year would result in a significant increase in costs to the Federal government in the current or a subsequent fiscal year or would seriously compromise needed departmental capabilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
<section id="H5D7680F723764BF3923753AA2152E1F2"><enum>504.</enum> 
<subsection id="H380D8F9AB6B147318320AAF4C8C71BE1" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds provided by this Act, by prior Acts, or from any accounts in the Treasury of the United States derived from the collection of fees available to the components funded by this Act, shall be available for an obligation that contracts out any function presently performed by Federal personnel or any new function proposed to be performed by Federal personnel in the President’s budget, submitted pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, and accompanying justification materials for the fiscal year funded by this Act or prior Department of Homeland Security appropriations Acts. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H474BA2D9B5AF4F1389D7648BA96AB627"><enum>(b)</enum><text>None of the funds provided by this Act or prior Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Acts for “Procurement, Construction, and Improvements” may be available for an obligation for any purpose that was not— </text> 
<paragraph id="H046D469D6E6C4E9496B83973BE6FAC4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proposed in the President’s budget, submitted pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, and accompanying justification materials, for the applicable fiscal year; or </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H119764D0978244A5913E68D262BD3DF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>explicitly described in the applicable appropriations Act or the explanatory statement accompanying such Act. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H38BD0C34A0DE479482A70DFE5116DFF2"><enum>(c)</enum><text>None of the funds provided by this Act or prior Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Acts for “Operations and Support” may be available for an obligation to establish or eliminate any office or other functional unit affecting more than 10 full-time personnel equivalents unless such establishment or elimination was— </text> <paragraph id="HB961DD58F4D94204A3ABAB28F0307649"><enum>(1)</enum><text>proposed in the President’s budget, submitted pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, and accompanying justification materials, for the applicable fiscal year; or </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H200822DF7EBA41A0B8CBC9D5058B60F1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>explicitly described in the applicable appropriations Act or the explanatory statement accompanying such Act. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9DA7F36241A74069BA4F6B71714C8A0D"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Subsections (a), (b), and (c) shall not apply if the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives are notified at least 15 days in advance of such obligation by the Under Secretary for Management of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HAEC9CF4ACAB84C80AA589A4C31F0CB34"><enum>505.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB54170DF3DA24B8CA4170F6D09AC5F22"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise specifically provided by law, not to exceed 50 percent of unobligated balances remaining available at the end of fiscal year 2023, as recorded in the financial records at the time of a reprogramming notification, but not later than June 30, 2024, from appropriations for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> for fiscal year 2023 in this Act shall remain available through September 30, 2024, in the account and for the purposes for which the appropriations were provided.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H71CA5FAC2B24426095EA3050F6002076"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the obligation of such funds, a notification shall be submitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives in accordance with section 503 of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H450424D13B6243D7A1B7EFFB5B1C7643" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>506.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD4B10BBA2658491D90C91FF3BB56837F"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 504 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2017 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>), related to the operations of a working capital fund, shall apply with respect to funds made available in this Act in the same manner as such section applied to funds made available in that Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC28F3E8EB5564C79845024EA9653FC26"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds from such working capital fund may be obligated and expended in anticipation of reimbursements from components of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB31AB56549BF45E6906601C47AEC1186"><enum>507.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H793CAF235FDC4ADEB4814C6C2676DB27"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available by this Act for intelligence activities are deemed to be specifically authorized by the Congress for purposes of section 504 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/414">50 U.S.C. 414</external-xref>) during fiscal year 2023 until the enactment of an Act authorizing intelligence activities for fiscal year 2023.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H32C374C42E3346C9A182118F8D81C042"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts described in subsection (a) made available for <quote>Intelligence, Analysis, and Situational Awareness—Operations and Support</quote> that exceed the amounts in such authorization for such account shall be transferred to and merged with amounts made available under the heading <quote>Management Directorate—Operations and Support</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52250F45D2C543E3B41F1251BDBEF803"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prior to the obligation of any funds transferred under subsection (b), the Management Directorate shall brief the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives on a plan for the use of such funds.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF2E323772D4843B9B1D3C57695C256C0"><enum>508.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H098D8634273E419D9525EB55133DDCBA"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, or the designee of the Secretary, shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives at least 3 full business days in advance of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA366BC1BB7A64CA89485947DBAE34309"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making or awarding a grant allocation or grant in excess of $1,000,000;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63B1FDE0DA994CC1AB68B19F7E0D0CBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making or awarding a contract, other transaction agreement, or task or delivery order on a Department of Homeland Security multiple award contract, or to issue a letter of intent totaling in excess of $4,000,000;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2B9745962604FA68FE2FE6C5901B3F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">awarding a task or delivery order requiring an obligation of funds in an amount greater than $10,000,000 from multi-year Department of Homeland Security funds;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FDB913A19E14C4298B5506952C87322"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making a sole-source grant award; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78A1848A61FF45DFBC099BEE65B748B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">announcing publicly the intention to make or award items under paragraph (1), (2), (3), or (4), including a contract covered by the Federal Acquisition Regulation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7BDB58E96C1241B2AB136C070595BB08"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that compliance with this section would pose a substantial risk to human life, health, or safety, an award may be made without notification, and the Secretary shall notify the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives not later than 5 full business days after such an award is made or letter issued.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF7DA2320FF584EF6B26004B561B639FF"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notification under this section—</text> <paragraph id="HB1F89E7CC41F4D8A8D0260AAD16937A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not involve funds that are not available for obligation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF762CF6D205430291DE0F24B335DD71"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall include the amount of the award; the fiscal year for which the funds for the award were appropriated; the type of contract; and the account from which the funds are being drawn.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB75B5546315942B88FAFF1F1CEDD2A2F"><enum>509.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no agency shall purchase, construct, or lease any additional facilities, except within or contiguous to existing locations, to be used for the purpose of conducting Federal law enforcement training without advance notification to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, except that the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers is authorized to obtain the temporary use of additional facilities by lease, contract, or other agreement for training that cannot be accommodated in existing Centers' facilities.</text></section> 
<section id="HE24B1AF8D7E149C4B1B8AB0440C5965E"><enum>510.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used for expenses for any construction, repair, alteration, or acquisition project for which a prospectus otherwise required under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, has not been approved, except that necessary funds may be expended for each project for required expenses for the development of a proposed prospectus.</text></section> <section id="H3BE8136CE73A43B981121739334FC31A"><enum>511.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be available to pay the salary of any employee serving as a contracting officer's representative, or anyone acting in a similar capacity, who has not received contracting officer's representative training. </text></section> 
<section id="HFBD730CB9EC64169A3FD5ACDDC0BD6D7"><enum>512.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H06B0D54509CE482DB1BE98DDDB9EE3F3"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used in contravention of the applicable provisions of the Buy American Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD576546D7773435482232F1D6EFD90F5"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), the term <term>Buy American Act</term> means <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/41/83">chapter 83</external-xref> of title 41, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC5F2B39D564F45BAAA1B5DA8EA8A1737"><enum>513.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to amend the oath of allegiance required by section 337 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1448">8 U.S.C. 1448</external-xref>).</text></section> <section id="H5134F5B23EBB42FE8819C36DB0752247"><enum>514.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided or otherwise made available in this Act shall be available to carry out section 872 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/452">6 U.S.C. 452</external-xref>) unless explicitly authorized by the Congress.</text></section> 
<section id="H61E55D44422F4F8CB5C2B4EE92CDF01C"><enum>515.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used for planning, testing, piloting, or developing a national identification card.</text></section> <section id="HB8912F0488AF4D6997E82EA0B8CFB526"><enum>516.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any official that is required by this Act to report or to certify to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives may not delegate such authority to perform that act unless specifically authorized herein.</text></section> 
<section id="HEFAD681148D14FE4A233CE751B4CC799"><enum>517.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used for first-class travel by the employees of agencies funded by this Act in contravention of sections 301–10.122 through 301–10.124 of title 41, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></section> <section id="HE378F1E0692B43B49069EE0681DE5656"><enum>518.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, none of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available by this Act may be used to pay award or incentive fees for contractor performance that has been judged to be below satisfactory performance or performance that does not meet the basic requirements of a contract.</text></section> 
<section id="H112CB58C10484BE4BAA613A13996FC4F"><enum>519.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H41883677B71B485A8E2B0280B6584876"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to maintain or establish a computer network unless such network blocks the viewing, downloading, and exchanging of pornography.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFCFCCA971F3744928655B27C15C82CFD"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subsection (a) shall limit the use of funds necessary for any Federal, State, tribal, territorial, or local law enforcement agency or any other entity carrying out criminal investigations, prosecution, or adjudication activities.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H418637D4B80641D789573C7539C50AB0"><enum>520.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used by a Federal law enforcement officer to facilitate the transfer of an operable firearm to an individual if the Federal law enforcement officer knows or suspects that the individual is an agent of a drug cartel unless law enforcement personnel of the United States continuously monitor or control the firearm at all times.</text></section> <section id="HF84AF50B849348C089CFF2AD6AD6A7B5"><enum>521.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC5A101DB2F5749E58951E16B7F986CE6"><enum>(a)</enum><text>None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to pay for the travel to or attendance of more than 50 employees of a single component of the Department of Homeland Security, who are stationed in the United States, at a single international conference unless the Secretary of Homeland Security, or a designee, determines that such attendance is in the national interest and notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives within at least 10 days of that determination and the basis for that determination.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9E91E8B6FFEB41CE82C25EAF1C45294A"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section the term <term>international conference</term> shall mean a conference occurring outside of the United States attended by representatives of the United States Government and of foreign governments, international organizations, or nongovernmental organizations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD2E1F45105694FA68046279640393438"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total cost to the Department of Homeland Security of any such conference shall not exceed $500,000.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD76B343ED0D049BEA81C14A6D2DB19DF"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Employees who attend a conference virtually without travel away from their permanent duty station within the United States shall not be counted for purposes of this section, and the prohibition contained in this section shall not apply to payments for the costs of attendance for such employees.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HAB599BC04E8F4A83B4CBBE4D74420981"><enum>522.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available in this Act may be used to reimburse any Federal department or agency for its participation in a National Special Security Event.</text></section> 
<section id="H350B964B783E4CE692CFBACED4819DE7"><enum>523.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9BF70FD167B8418FB0873064496188E6"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security by this or any other Act may be obligated for the implementation of any structural pay reform or the introduction of any new position classification that will affect more than 100 full-time positions or costs more than $5,000,000 in a single year before the end of the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security submits to Congress a notification that includes—</text> <paragraph id="HCC3DE71817384933AE44C22977E0A399"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of full-time positions affected by such change;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF67CC5CDB446441A99655E273006E83E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funding required for such change for the current fiscal year and through the Future Years Homeland Security Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE98A8BF6808D48E4A54E7D33B332AB7F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">justification for such change; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B70FD445C4E42C48FA5E736AA93C84D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a structural pay reform, an analysis of compensation alternatives to such change that were considered by the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3F4EFA0F7AF4141B87EAD2743062017"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply to such change if—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9BCAD15E74864AC69763BA08B79005DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it was proposed in the President’s budget proposal for the fiscal year funded by this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6584B6E18EF46E29916198678B14CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funds for such change have not been explicitly denied or restricted in this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H799F6CE4D24C406E8BE46BA5944677F1"><enum>524.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H07EE233B6E2C4CA2A79DAE163F48A577"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any agency receiving funds made available in this Act shall, subject to subsections (b) and (c), post on the public website of that agency any report required to be submitted by the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives in this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC38CE863463141128689A34879FA686E"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply to a report if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA85A1CD08BF44F108254A3311BD3A73C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public posting of the report compromises homeland or national security; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEEF3ED2BB8BA4D7CBD16ACDEF18B661C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the report contains proprietary information.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC60B9C71356643D6B5F3E9304E3A50F6"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the agency posting such report shall do so only after such report has been made available to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives for not less than 45 days except as otherwise specified in law.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H21862C2874B847CB9AFDA0311BB8985B"><enum>525.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBE70B22310A145C2B9FFFFF76BCD1751"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funding provided in this Act for <quote>Operations and Support</quote> may be used for minor procurement, construction, and improvements.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H556C900768E94A63B7D18F18051B88F9"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a), <quote>minor</quote> refers to end items with a unit cost of $250,000 or less for personal property, and $2,000,000 or less for real property.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE1F7F183EA634E1A909A064163135C6D"><enum>526.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority provided by section 532 of the Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/141">Public Law 115–141</external-xref>) regarding primary and secondary schooling of dependents shall continue in effect during fiscal year 2023.</text></section> 
<section id="H984B39AB2C0D48CFADDD37FCE37AF012"><enum>527.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H359EAB5653D04AADB36CE492D97AFBDF"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 831 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/391">6 U.S.C. 391</external-xref>) shall be applied—</text> <paragraph id="HBE4275A272B54BCE8846E1EA5C4521C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by substituting <quote>September 30, 2023,</quote> for <quote>September 30, 2017,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B2959BFB9C047D9B0749FF27DD39EE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(1), by substituting <quote>September 30, 2023,</quote> for <quote>September 30, 2017</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9A01B807B26440FAB1540468F0B8470F"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, under the authority of section 831 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/391">6 U.S.C. 391(a)</external-xref>), may carry out prototype projects under section 2371b of title 10, United States Code, and the Secretary shall perform the functions of the Secretary of Defense as prescribed.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE991858973E2459BBF2690A4C6893530"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security under section 831 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/391">6 U.S.C. 391(d)</external-xref>) may use the definition of nontraditional government contractor as defined in section 2371b(e) of title 10, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6D67D5C9211241C5966798BB4AC07574"><enum>528.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6C29DE2987C24967BDA4F39196006C92"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Homeland Security by this Act may be used to prevent any of the following persons from entering, for the purpose of conducting oversight, any facility operated by or for the Department of Homeland Security used to detain or otherwise house aliens, or to make any temporary modification at any such facility that in any way alters what is observed by a visiting Member of Congress or such designated employee, compared to what would be observed in the absence of such modification:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB4FB9F11BE8B4C228046D485CF0036D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member of Congress.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBF3A13D30EC4DDEBA128F3CD7C895F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee of the United States House of Representatives or the United States Senate designated by such a Member for the purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2A098257C42040A6A9A82EBDE59AA46C"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to require a Member of Congress to provide prior notice of the intent to enter a facility described in subsection (a) for the purpose of conducting oversight.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8963C33C5B0E4CBF8B5D69B02380377C"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to individuals described in subsection (a)(2), the Department of Homeland Security may require that a request be made at least 24 hours in advance of an intent to enter a facility described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCF4DDC0807634A629B8AC513C71272DE"><enum>529.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H19F3E9D1D20949D8A9F3AF3069AA435C"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), none of the funds made available in this Act may be used to place restraints on a woman in the custody of the Department of Homeland Security (including during transport, in a detention facility, or at an outside medical facility) who is pregnant or in post-delivery recuperation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H871E2C5513D94EE29C663BAA4948B0B6"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a pregnant woman if—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC6962E08AAF3492E945A264523A76E5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an appropriate official of the Department of Homeland Security makes an individualized determination that the woman—</text> <subparagraph id="H04CA48ECCD684B5789A8DE9580DC47D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a serious flight risk, and such risk cannot be prevented by other means; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC0EBC8E7DFFB443C8433E67240B5BAB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">poses an immediate and serious threat to harm herself or others that cannot be prevented by other means; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A528E3F60CE4209AA6DCCF99BEC0E15"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a medical professional responsible for the care of the pregnant woman determines that the use of therapeutic restraints is appropriate for the medical safety of the woman.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA8DF121F82284699B275225C8A3CD0E0"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a pregnant woman is restrained pursuant to subsection (b), only the safest and least restrictive restraints, as determined by the appropriate medical professional treating the woman, may be used. In no case may restraints be used on a woman who is in active labor or delivery, and in no case may a pregnant woman be restrained in a face-down position with four-point restraints, on her back, or in a restraint belt that constricts the area of the pregnancy. A pregnant woman who is immobilized by restraints shall be positioned, to the maximum extent feasible, on her left side.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H73015F73257941D7B2E454B06EA3EDCC"><enum>530.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE158A6C86C8748A2B5A8B9EC8F19BA8E"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to destroy any document, recording, or other record pertaining to any—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB13EA2215342496BA036FEA18D2346C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">death of,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11C2C139770846BF95ED3D9A8EC0AD42"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">potential sexual assault or abuse perpetrated against, or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H098BC848761442D8BEC307300CE81F76"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allegation of abuse, criminal activity, or disruption committed by</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="section">an individual held in the custody of the Department of Homeland Security.</continuation-text></subsection> <subsection id="H517C879E3EFC4C38B746EA7A79A35F6B"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The records referred to in subsection (a) shall be made available, in accordance with applicable laws and regulations, and Federal rules governing disclosure in litigation, to an individual who has been charged with a crime, been placed into segregation, or otherwise punished as a result of an allegation described in paragraph (3), upon the request of such individual.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBC7177DDB98349CE881E723B2CDE915C"><enum>531.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 519 of division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>, regarding a prohibition on funding for any position designated as a Principal Federal Official, shall apply with respect to any Federal funds in the same manner as such section applied to funds made available in that Act.</text></section> <section id="HC1ECDDA2063E41DAB78A33FF5684FB0B"><enum>532.</enum> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE3AC2F0E143049058CFAEA4393400D89"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after the date on which the budget of the President for a fiscal year is submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code, the Under Secretary for Management of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report on the unfunded priorities, for the Department of Homeland Security and separately for each departmental component, for which discretionary funding would be classified as budget function 050.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5249C5DD4854F76870C04E2EE99F436"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under this section shall specify, for each such unfunded priority—</text> <paragraph id="H13629B9E29714030B14EDF023ED34174"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary description, including the objectives to be achieved if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09F8A47B25EB49A1BBC3CFC7FE8DC6D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the description, including the objectives to be achieved if such priority is funded (whether in whole or in part);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E865CB5CE2A4B868F4F687F612F0877"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account information, including the following (as applicable):</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39E42FF3A8F0453E95348B95542F91C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">appropriation account; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50E535798A454EE6A53AC3EC27CD0AA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">program, project, or activity name; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1599F5165D00407C89BBED9497633A66"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the additional number of full-time or part-time positions to be funded as part of such priority.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEC5B074C965245658F6F2971690BDCEA"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>unfunded priority</term>, in the case of a fiscal year, means a requirement that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H653532CEC6B44D20B214526EC64C190E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not funded in the budget referred to in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27B62FB69D4F432081AD5EBC46A393E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is necessary to fulfill a requirement associated with an operational or contingency plan for the Department; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0474FD1836214AC09BDFEC492DFC4F2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would have been recommended for funding through the budget referred to in subsection (a) if—</text> <subparagraph id="H6996B8E0389C4369B87908F0A564E618"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">additional resources had been available for the budget to fund the requirement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1D448383BCB64D42AFBD20B2D8BB8418"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirement has emerged since the budget was formulated; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC35AFDF210C843F7974DDF5E8F1C7246"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the requirement is necessary to sustain prior-year investments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HEF606270FE4047AD9D6E061E2706AADE"><enum>533.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDDF807BE5FF94559B63B867A73F58864"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after a determination is made by the President to evaluate and initiate protection under any authority for a former or retired Government official or employee, or for an individual who, during the duration of the directed protection, will become a former or retired Government official or employee (referred to in this section as a <quote>covered individual</quote>), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a notification to congressional leadership and the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committees on the Judiciary of the Senate and the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives (referred to in this section as the <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9A4201D5A8746D484B31256EAEB5E21"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such notification may be submitted in classified form, if necessary, and in consultation with the Director of National Intelligence or the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, as appropriate, and shall include the threat assessment, scope of the protection, and the anticipated cost and duration of such protection.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE77EAB6167764DB5A2E50F75A0CF5AFF"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days before extending, or 30 days before terminating, protection for a covered individual, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a notification regarding the extension or termination and any change to the threat assessment to the congressional leadership and the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7BEECD979CAC4F53AE881F9B65B01934"><enum>(d)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 45 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and quarterly thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the congressional leadership and the appropriate congressional committees, which may be submitted in classified form, if necessary, detailing each covered individual, and the scope and associated cost of protection.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF00D7B2A81BA473E93973E62012F4635"><enum>534.</enum> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H24924F2A93844925AB7F0CD2266424D5"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided to the Department of Homeland Security in this or any prior Act may be used by an agency to submit an initial project proposal to the Technology Modernization Fund (as authorized by section 1078 of subtitle G of Title X of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/91">Public Law 115–91</external-xref>)) unless, concurrent with the submission of an initial project proposal to the Technology Modernization Board, the head of the agency—</text> <paragraph id="HE66BE0FC5F5C4CA4B246DD3D60048443"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notifies the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives of the proposed submission of the project proposal;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56A943A1F19748A3A04E02C3584A972C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submits to the Committees on Appropriations a copy of the project proposal; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H178C73F3BE6946FBA4BE1E098BB4C111"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a detailed analysis of how the proposed project funding would supplement or supplant funding requested as part of the Department's most recent budget submission.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H17733D598DE44845B70D36614A45E93A"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds provided to the Department of Homeland Security by the Technology Modernization Fund shall be available for obligation until 15 days after a report on such funds has been transmitted to the Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H714DAD528DCB4A01AB5E8AC3001197F1"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report described in subsection (b) shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H883D9FBBD06943E9AB23AE4CBCA4464B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the full project proposal submitted to and approved by the Fund’s Technology Modernization Board;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9FF1B1874B24B38BD2A098D64E98A89"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the finalized interagency agreement between the Department and the Fund including the project’s deliverables and repayment terms, as applicable;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE477A8D54B4E426F9D4D2D75155FB50A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed analysis of how the project will supplement or supplant existing funding available to the Department for similar activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB62CED0ADF1C4B10823FA70E669E44E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for how the Department will repay the Fund, including specific planned funding sources, as applicable; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3991E0EFD11E470F8BDFDFE01A2B1929"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other information as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H893BE2A2BBE648C6A0728EC7286D1389"><enum>535.</enum> <subsection id="H77FBDB7E23FD42748ABEA89E22263FD7" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an additional amount for border management requirements of the U.S. Border Patrol, non-detention border management requirements of U.S. Customs and Immigration Enforcement, and the emergency food and shelter program for the purposes of providing shelter and other services to families and individuals encountered by the Department of Homeland Security, in addition to amounts otherwise made available for such purposes, $200,000,000. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7211A6A951BB4BD3A63248CA8706724B"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The amount made available by subsection (a) may be transferred by the Secretary of Homeland Security between appropriations for the same purposes, notwithstanding section 503(c) of this Act. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H2ADF35DA8C3641D7A36304374AEFA841"><enum>(c)</enum><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary for Management shall provide an expenditure plan for the use of the funds made available in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB4E1060F64CB41FEAF910E036135A058" changed="not-changed"><enum>536.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be used by the Department of Homeland Security to deny any benefit application for admission, or protection available to an individual under the Immigration and Nationality Act (8 U.S.C. 1101 et. seq.) on the sole basis of any event, conduct, finding, admission, history of substance use disorder, arrest, or juvenile adjudication related to cannabis possession, consumption, or use, or to a conviction solely based on such possession, consumption, or use.</text></section> <section id="H3ED2E0071FA6476C842A7738DC2D0EE2"><enum>537. </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds made available to the Department of Homeland Security may be used to enter into a procurement contract, memorandum of understanding, or cooperative agreement with, or make a grant to, or provide a loan or guarantee to, any entity identified under Section 1260H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>) or any subsidiary of such entity.</text></section> 
<section id="HBF66E458288C42508DCF8ACE1F9513ED"><enum>538.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 205 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5135">42 U.S.C. 5135</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H048E81124869465F919DCC33137C699E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H04FF2F22322845B5AA2AE76AF3B30E4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H2785897F8A674EE4807E3F1E3E4D99CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (C);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H75FAA136A66F4B11B789D954AC59363B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at the end of subparagraph (A), by adding <quote>and</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC5420B759B7A41FDBC0EE01BF9B9395F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at the end of subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H352E26DBE320459EA176DEB9E02E9CF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(D), by striking <quote>local governments, insular areas, and Indian tribal governments</quote> and inserting <quote>local governments and Tribal governments</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39B0E3F4765140CBB851A4320D95FDDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60E243A55B6C4DFAA010E42A7DC9FC8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (m)—</text> <subparagraph id="HB176CEBF016A4E12A50E9EFB64AF71AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H07A88B391CA4423CB7761B23F9586952" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H89D7713E1C044653A9275706EEF306F1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible Entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term ‘eligible entity’ means a State or an Indian tribal government that has received a major disaster declaration pursuant to section 401.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD5DD5BBD1CD4C7280B8006B2D88C7CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking paragraphs (5) and (10); </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4D9ABD01EC84FF78D53913D7BD254DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (6) through (9) as paragraphs (5) through (8), respectively; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCCBA135075B4F9DA167EEB22576EC9D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (11) as paragraph (9).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5C2F38313D14473A8FF1763A7E438E1D"><enum>539.</enum> 
<subsection id="H2F46789236714000BC9CB52138D6D3AE" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The remaining unobligated balances of funds from amounts provided under the heading “Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance’’ in division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref> for the project identified as the ‘‘Vermilion Safe Room’’ in the table entitled ‘‘Homeland Incorporation of Community Project Funding Items/Congressionally Directed Spending Items’’ under the heading ‘‘Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance’’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 in the matter preceding division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref> are hereby rescinded. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HE4D33EFFF9774375947CC920B64C47E3"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for an additional amount for fiscal year 2022 for "Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance", $3,000,000, to remain available until September 30, 2024, for an Emergency Operations Center grant under section 614 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5196c">42 U.S.C. 5196c</external-xref>) for the project identified as the ‘‘Vermilion Safe Room’’ in the table entitled ‘‘Homeland Incorporation of Community Project Funding Items/Congressionally Directed Spending Items’’ under the heading ‘‘Federal Emergency Management Agency—Federal Assistance’’ in the explanatory statement described in section 4 in the matter preceding division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00F62AF0255D4E7F9F620808E0CD8FDE"><enum>(c)</enum><text>—</text> <paragraph id="HB743665A45294D52B21B2906FA93EE1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Subject to paragraph (2), this section shall become effective immediately upon enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5244E0AD83F94C54A57391BAED28189B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If this Act is enacted after September 30, 2022, this section shall be applied as if it were in effect on September 30, 2022.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> <appropriations-small id="H0288CC5398FC450C900FB6F81B4E3277"><header>(rescissions of funds)</header></appropriations-small> <section id="H84910871D0C748959FBFDD0369C7AFC6"><enum>540.</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds appropriated to the Department of Homeland Security, the following funds are hereby rescinded from the following accounts and programs in the specified amounts: Provided, That no amounts may be rescinded from amounts that were designated by the Congress as an emergency requirement pursuant to a concurrent resolution on the budget or the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0D04791F3B734960A6EFCEA41D0B6003"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$30,000,000 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref> under the heading <quote>U.S. Customs and Border Protection—Procurement, Construction, and Improvements</quote> .</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B185C62A30747D8AFA3AE894036C8A4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$100,097,000 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref> under the heading <quote>Transportation Security Administration—Operations and Support</quote>. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H626804D555324148961C002B162C1882"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$87,619,000 from <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref> under the heading <quote>U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services—Operations Support</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><appropriations-small id="H9F56BA7A8041464AB2BFFB6647FE739A"><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Appropriations Act, 2023</short-title></quote>. </text></appropriations-small> </title> </legis-body> <endorsement> <action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date> <action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc> </endorsement> </bill> 

