<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD331737C4B7748158133E99E6135AEB9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8426 IH: Nogales Wastewater Improvement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8426</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220719">July 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the assumption of full ownership and control of the International Outfall Interceptor in Nogales, Arizona, by the International Boundary and Water Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAE22DCE9092F4BF988358A29369CF1A1" style="OLC"><section id="H8E3A19A727894BA19A4CD6FDC48DD2DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Nogales Wastewater Improvement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5B177A4094624A4FB0877888721D9EE2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to the Act of July 27, 1953</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The first section of the Act of July 27, 1953 (67 Stat. 195, chapter 242; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/277d-10">22 U.S.C. 277d–10</external-xref>), is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>: <proviso><italic>Provided further</italic></proviso>, That the equitable portion of the Nogales sanitation project for the city of Nogales, Arizona, shall be limited to the costs directly associated with the treatment and conveyance of the wastewater of the city and, to the extent practicable, shall not include any costs directly associated with the quality or quantity of wastewater originating in Mexico.</quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H48F9486ADAFE4DDFAE053969D3DF292D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Nogales sanitation project</header><subsection id="H19CBEAFC686542BDBAD72C6E9424BABC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H56B6CB7040624F9EAE9FF58455FC07CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>City</header><text>The term <term>City</term> means the City of Nogales, Arizona.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA21A0D0A2D4C49668B4FF40492F6B858"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the United States Section of the International Border and Water Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3350C2CF40614676B615A4CCB07C7BE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>International Outfall Interceptor</header><text>The term <term>International Outfall Interceptor</term> means the pipeline that conveys wastewater from the United States-Mexico border to the Nogales International Wastewater Treatment Plant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H431E9DE718E245D5973640418A91C8CC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nogales International Wastewater Treatment Plant</header><text>The term <term>Nogales International Wastewater Treatment Plant</term> means the wastewater treatment plant that—</text><subparagraph id="H702E683A412B4A279CAD3B10E0AF47E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is operated by the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25A967D2928C4C3691B36E24C8C1C95B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is located in Rio Rico, Santa Cruz County, Arizona, after manhole 99; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD5D974947834663BB3496DF44C82D7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>treats sewage and wastewater originating from—</text><clause id="H379803EB024F4B1AB4D0F6B1D0CFA8D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Nogales, Sonora, Mexico; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B0CFF79C16F40D8A49AF10DBCD7E062"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nogales, Arizona.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8680DF5C0EC642179F22AD00DE39786A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ownership and control</header><paragraph id="H9B8D102184E54DE7B9C09AC08BF29A9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2) and in accordance with authority under the Act of July 27, 1953 (67 Stat. 195, chapter 242; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/277d-10">22 U.S.C. 277d–10 et seq.</external-xref>), on transfer by donation from the City of the current stake of the City in the International Outfall Interceptor to the Commission, the Commission shall enter into such agreements as are necessary to assume full ownership and control over the International Outfall Interceptor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AC08646AFBD4900BEE91EEBBE070DC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agreements required</header><text>The Commission shall assume full ownership and control over the International Outfall Interceptor under paragraph (1) after all applicable governing bodies in the State of Arizona, including the City, have—</text><subparagraph id="H8D239FF4ECBD4F0A9D7986CFC459B6E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>signed memoranda of understanding granting to the Commission access to existing easements for a right of entry to the International Outfall Interceptor for the life of the International Outfall Interceptor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14030A1FFF374195A7458A84C768D756"><enum>(B)</enum><text>entered into an agreement with respect to the flows entering the International Outfall Interceptor that are controlled by the City; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65C7B1E95161437A8CC0791A11BDC227"><enum>(C)</enum><text>agreed to work in good faith to expeditiously enter into such other agreements as are necessary for the Commission to operate and maintain the International Outfall Interceptor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1896B4F39484C129E29DF4AAFABDBAF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Operations and maintenance</header><paragraph id="H3AE4F27ADF504E16B024F07FA619534F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date on which the Commission assumes full ownership and control of the International Outfall Interceptor under subsection (b)(1), but subject to subsection (e), the Commission shall be responsible for the operations and maintenance of the International Outfall Interceptor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83C503194BF349FD8F3055AA3E6C3AF8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission to carry out this subsection, to remain available until expended—</text><subparagraph id="H6C43E50FC2684CC7AD0F8B9744A5F736"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$4,400,000 for fiscal year 2023; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0E23AB519FE42B09DE4C89A9659FD6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than $2,500,000 for fiscal year 2024 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83783E6510D44D7286DD03265BF92428"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Debris screen</header><paragraph id="H81592448763F44CF895CEC38E825EA80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Debris screen required</header><subparagraph id="H5AB51D4B3C274CEC8222D531CC00681E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall construct, operate, and maintain a debris screen at Manhole One of the International Outfall Interceptor for intercepting debris and drug bundles coming to the United States from Nogales, Sonora, Mexico.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20F6CA0A4DA940CA821CC81258F48108"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In constructing and operating the debris screen under subparagraph (A), the Commission and the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall coordinate—</text><clause id="HEF41A4C74C3C47DCBFA15690ADDE2D2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the removal of drug bundles and other illicit goods caught in the debris screen; and</text></clause><clause id="HAF27836EF023442B9BE1663089A4C101"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other operations at the International Outfall Interceptor that require coordination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5277114C168C4C70ADFEFDCDF38161C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission, to remain available until expended—</text><subparagraph id="HF50631A8CB6C4B6CBA01F01129BDEB54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$11,900,000 for fiscal year 2023 for construction of the debris screen described in paragraph (1)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67187E49B79F46E79D917B8D16F853D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$2,200,000 for fiscal year 2024 and each fiscal year thereafter for the operations and maintenance of the debris screen described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A520052B00B46B5A1A93B3B7147BCF6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation of claims</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/171">Chapter 171</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1346">section 1346(b)</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Tort Claims Act</quote>), shall not apply to any claim arising from the activities of the Commission in carrying out this section, including any claim arising from damages that result from overflow of the International Outfall Interceptor due to excess inflow to the International Outfall Interceptor originating from Nogales, Sonora, Mexico. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

