<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDFF64E5A32884D4EACF1F99405B76129" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7989 IH: Protecting Infants from Formula Shortages Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7989</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220608">June 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to prevent food shortages, including shortages of infant formula and certain medical foods.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC0EF699073CD4E2DB79A89F158123833" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDAE2E26A0408461C88087E4FCDD3BE3F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Infants from Formula Shortages Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE12EFAB8249A41CBBA5160E3FB5F0877"><enum>2.</enum><header>Discontinuance or interruption in the production of essential sources of nutrition</header> <subsection id="H555057A7E2B94BDCA9869450A359180F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Discontinuance or interruption in the production of essential food</header><text>The Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act is amended by inserting after section 412 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/350a">21 U.S.C. 350a</external-xref>) the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8DB5E48D405947F59902693C56A8C682">
<section id="H5AA6100FA95E45A5AFD3179325BFB75A"><enum>412A.</enum><header>Discontinuance or interruption in the production of food, including infant formula and certain medical foods for inborn errors of metabolism</header>
<subsection id="HCEF0FE3E935240549D3CAF1ACF36B88D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A manufacturer of an essential source of nutrition shall notify the Secretary, in accordance with subsection (b), of a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of such food or an interruption of the manufacture of an essential source of nutrition or any other circumstance that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of such food in the United States, and the reasons for such discontinuance or interruption.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBB3229E624CD4F818F7059857976A652"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (g), a notice required under subsection (a) shall be submitted to the Secretary—</text>
<paragraph id="H9A5DD65937D04583BA3F5715077D0241"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least 6 months prior to the date of the discontinuance or interruption; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H089BCAAAFC7B41D685D38BE716B0ACB4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if compliance with paragraph (1) is not possible, as soon as practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H24753F789A9E4307849FB9BBE6B277C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall distribute, to the Secretary of Agriculture and to appropriate organizations, as determined by the Secretary, through such means as the Secretary determines appropriate, information on the discontinuance or interruption of the manufacture of an essential source of nutrition, or other circumstance, reported under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE0776B3CE6CD4F8D8F25AE1201856885"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text>Nothing in this section authorizes the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code, or section 1905 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2BDE027855EF43FEAA2EEE2000F4B2EA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Failure To meet requirements</header><text>If a person fails to submit information required under subsection (a) in accordance with subsection (b)—</text> <paragraph id="H783CCF7379AC465F9C8F14450756A95C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary shall issue to such person a letter that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H72485DE2DD594CF3B33571641DDC2CE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>informs such person of the failure to comply;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB32406241534B6E864AA10566213709"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes the basis for noncompliance; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3083BFEDAFF14B2BAB2C5EA80B81CE38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requires the person to comply not later than 30 calendar days after the date on which the letter was issued;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC671744A3CA40C0B0FD817209551E60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 calendar days after the issuance of a letter under paragraph (1), the person who receives such letter shall submit to the Secretary a written response to such letter that provides the information required under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8B2127BC3DE482480E8410917D984D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 45 calendar days after the issuance of a letter under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make such letter and any response to such letter under paragraph (2) available to the public on the website of the Food and Drug Administration, with appropriate redactions made to protect information described in subsection (d), except that, if the Secretary determines that the letter under paragraph (1) was issued in error or, after review of such response, the person had a reasonable basis for not notifying as required under subsection (a), the requirements of this paragraph shall not apply.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7DC8220C46E745C1A20B7FDB1725EE53"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header> <paragraph id="HEB076505A55B4E2BB4422718DA754F10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Protecting Infants from Formula Shortages Act of 2022</short-title>, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations regarding the requirements under this section. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0211B6F11D4A45138904370E18268304"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Such regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="H99D6D878635345B2A54A1B9AF40C6B72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include a list of each category of food for which a manufacturer is required to notify the Secretary in accordance with subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89BCDCCFB4DF4255943D4CB0D2D29B27"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may—</text> <clause id="H55AB01331AA444698D3C8BBE5A72A47E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designate foods not otherwise defined as an essential source of nutrition, giving special consideration to foods—</text>
<subclause id="H732987E3B1A84E57BAAC7E9F7691036B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>upon which individuals with certain diseases or conditions may be particularly reliant; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB423C1C724EA404183D9052EB1068407"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that are administered under medical supervision;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H7CC4F88155424D07B93C6BBA3E1B086E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>designate additional categories of foods for which the Secretary determines notification described in subsection (a) is appropriate during a public health emergency declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB74F02E8DA01464C85CF007EEAD48520"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prescribe additional conditions on the timing and manner of such notifications as are reasonable and appropriate during such a public health emergency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H714B3C9B1059406299378C2030752A25"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Order</header><text>During a public health emergency declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act, the Secretary may order any manufacturer of an essential source of nutrition to provide notification required by this section. Such order may—</text> <paragraph id="HE3F41BCB6A834C8F914D7764188A780C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>impose additional conditions on the timing and manner of notification as are reasonable and appropriate in light of the circumstances of the public health emergency; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6B547D8B72E245ACB89319640466C476"><enum>(2)</enum><text>designate additional categories of food for which the Secretary determines notification is appropriate during the public health emergency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3208F0F446354ACA9AF12F49DB872750"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Risk management plans</header><text>Each manufacturer of an essential source of nutrition shall develop, maintain, and, as appropriate, implement a redundancy risk management plan that identifies and evaluates risks to the supply of the food, as applicable, for each establishment in which such food is manufactured. A risk management plan under this subsection—</text>
<paragraph id="HD7C234EDEC454C018374B3224AF918EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may identify and evaluate risks to the supply of more than one food, or food category, manufactured at the same establishment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H851FE13A1CE8486389AB84398C9707B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be subject to inspection and copying by the Secretary pursuant to section 704 or at the request of the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H8B82F438278C4EC3994AA73CF81D6955"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4AF1259A0DEC40EDA2F54181EA9F67EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Essential source of nutrition</header><text>The term <term>essential source of nutrition</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="HDA5405CBD3614744AECF53D04854B540"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an infant formula;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7CB9B6C82B96453A992D997DF44041C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a food that—</text>
<clause id="H696F6CB7439F44EBB16C838CC232C3F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the definition of <quote>medical food</quote> in section 5(b) of the Orphan Drug Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9A6D96EFD77A491F8625D550D47549D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is intended for use by individuals with—</text>
<subclause id="H2686E600F30748EE8D271790FEB2D94B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>certain inborn errors of metabolism; or </text></subclause> <subclause id="HE6342E0CA1A9491DB4CC1034001F03F7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other conditions requiring a medical food, as determined by the Secretary in guidance issued under subsection (f); or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFF15662162FD418B94DA39DD48C93F60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a food so designated pursuant to subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H868CA70846ED4C92A0AFF4BB24E989C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Meaningful disruption</header><text>The term <term>meaningful disruption</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAA3B078FD0CB44FAAF4CCE2288CE8B33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a change in production that is reasonably likely to lead to a reduction in the supply of an essential source of nutrition by a manufacturer that is more than negligible and affects the ability of the manufacturer to fulfill contractual obligations or meet expected demand for its product; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55B44DEE50F448FFA9BF148EDE2C3042"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include interruptions in manufacturing due to matters such as routine maintenance or insignificant changes in manufacturing so long as the manufacturer expects to resume operations in a short period of time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H5ED6613325EC4C97987020C99875A598"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text>Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BCA091DDF8A4CFCA03D39B52556C10A"> <subsection id="H79B74A74FE4B41F6B2C9E4226EEB43D0"><enum>(fff)</enum><text>The failure to provide information as required under section 412A after receipt of a letter from the Secretary under subsection (e) of such section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
<section id="H89D1CC83F49A4E5CBBB03C14785E2DDA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Remote records assessment for essential sources of nutrition</header>
<subsection id="H2C466F698FE749E0987A1E9739AAEACA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Factory inspection</header><text>Section 704(a)(4)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/374">21 U.S.C. 374(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended in the first sentence by inserting <quote>or the manufacturing, processing, packing, or holding of an essential source of nutrition (as defined in section 412A)</quote> after <quote>processing of a drug</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF21E93ED891A4FC4B2A6E7BD0B1DA600"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall promulgate regulations describing circumstances in which the Secretary may issue requests for records or other information in advance of, or in lieu of, an inspection pursuant to section 704(a)(4)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as amended by subsection (a), processes for responding to such requests electronically or in physical form, and factors the Secretary may consider in evaluating whether such records are provided within a reasonable timeframe, within reasonable limits, and in a reasonable manner, accounting for resource and other limitations that may exist, including for small businesses. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

