<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4BF093C645C044529E6FAB6E3604461A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7866 IH: Giving Disadvantaged Businesses Opportunities for Success Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7866</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, and the Small Business Act to direct the Department of Transportation and the Small Business Administration to strengthen and advance certain disadvantaged businesses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H82AE6D27A3FB45578BE1E2EF112F6442" style="OLC"><section id="H4E4D8D7DA6E04D34A29FCF2F7D806B68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Giving Disadvantaged Businesses Opportunities for Success Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H270A0F8556F54301A6C7FCDC8C71F6C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H4E4D8D7DA6E04D34A29FCF2F7D806B68" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H270A0F8556F54301A6C7FCDC8C71F6C3" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7E1AEB719B904910A8C8AAA4BBDE006A" level="section">Sec. 3. Congressional findings on the importance of disadvantaged businesses.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBF3D32DB0E1C46139E3D422B61A0C182" level="section">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFF24C63BAC9E423CB34C5824053D4BD6" level="section">Sec. 5. Severability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3A91F1B499624F8893C4FF31CA8E4B2E" level="title">Title I—Department of Transportation</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFD54EF7D50484965BCDB7BA2873E5574" level="section">Sec. 101. Inflation adjustment to Department of Transportation net worth caps.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBC91B69D597444FE94AAAD6DFD2A6174" level="section">Sec. 102. Update to Department of Transportation Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE size standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H38ECC72EE909415FA881B518B24EE4DF" level="section">Sec. 103. Department of Transportation annual gross receipts timeline.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H76E0033F866643C0A6D88C48D2E1653C" level="section">Sec. 104. Definition of assets under Department of Transportation personal net worth test.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE8FCE81B64344161BF58FE31273A8746" level="section">Sec. 105. Additional funding for Department of Transportation minority resource center.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF0E01D38F8D6414A96719FD5825C8AC3" level="section">Sec. 106. Improvements to Department of Transportation Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE mentor-protégé programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9E0209970CA843DB808476184B97AC36" level="section">Sec. 107. Department of Transportation Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE certification universal recognition.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H31FBAAFD2B6E47F885498153628D1BF0" level="section">Sec. 108. Incentives for excellence in Disadvantaged Business Enterprise programs and ACDBE programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEC0A4B1143764B15902E37D44A7A6DC9" level="section">Sec. 109. Reporting requirements and standards for waivers and exemptions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H61E990B14F024CC79E41AE2E53541367" level="section">Sec. 110. Advisory committee on disadvantaged business enterprises and ACDBEs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H676E6D2D89B742A8914ECA755C8C0EED" level="title">Title II—Small Business Administration</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HACCADBA1E8A44C789C00474EC6923030" level="section">Sec. 201. Update to small business concern disadvantaged business net worth caps.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9C7B4F5C13194FE9A9D68E0F1819059F" level="section">Sec. 202. Update to certain size standards under the Small Business Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB2204BCF771F4CA1882A6A8103043B50" level="section">Sec. 203. Annual gross receipts timeline under the Small Business Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDED0B51284B3493F99976BE5CE74A584" level="section">Sec. 204. Definition of assets under the Small Business Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB49C1AA8CA3645C2AD963A0CE337B2FE" level="section">Sec. 205. Small business development center partnerships with the Department of Transportation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA2AD4FB789C24A29A6D5586FC66A08B8" level="section">Sec. 206. Small business development center partnerships with nonprofits.</toc-entry></toc></section><section id="H7E1AEB719B904910A8C8AAA4BBDE006A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional findings on the importance of disadvantaged businesses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7FC967E6D7C645CC8E4BCA1BBFF83BD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While significant progress has occurred due to the establishment of the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program of the Department of Transportation under section 11101(e) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), the ACDBE program of the Department of Transportation under part 23 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, and the Section 8(a) Business Development Program of the Small Business Administration (established under section 8(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637</external-xref>)), discrimination and related barriers continue to pose significant obstacles for minority- and women-owned businesses seeking to do business in federally assisted transportation markets across the United States and through procurement contracts of Federal agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H271299FB2C054CB4B670F8CDF10ED827"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The continuing barriers described in paragraph (1) merit the continuation of the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program, the ACDBE program, and the Section 8(a) Business Development Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BDDFA518B49466A975145FDB7D9AE6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Congress has received and reviewed testimony and documentation of race and gender discrimination from numerous sources, including congressional hearings and roundtables, scientific reports, reports issued by public and private agencies, news stories, reports of discrimination by organizations and individuals, and discrimination lawsuits, which show that race- and gender-neutral efforts alone are insufficient to address the problem.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H859045EB637942EC818D9E807C97D437"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Some examples of the sources described in paragraph (3) include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H112B1C4D08DC41C18AF076AC3B8D029F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The hearing of the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives held on September 23, 2020, titled <quote>Driving Equity: The U.S. Department of Transportation’s Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Program</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB78EBFAB0B51463A9B5A5DEDFE0622A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The hearing of the Subcommittee on Contracting and Infrastructure of the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives held on March 2, 2022, titled <quote>The 8(a) Program: Overview and Next Steps to Promote Small Business Success</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93BDEE929D054639A1713660A6DC74A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The 2017 Disparity Study of the Illinois Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44C9F28A014C44FC9365822B86FA6F08"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The 2018 Disparity Study of the City of Denver.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FE1953DD1F744E0B459831D4CA676F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The testimony and documentation described in paragraphs (3) and (4) demonstrate that discrimination across the United States poses a barrier to full and fair participation of women business owners and minority business owners in federally assisted transportation markets and through procurement contracts of Federal agencies and has impacted the development of such businesses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H177C2FC50DF44A64AED9FBC6E9AC032E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The testimony and documentation described in paragraphs (3) and (4) provide a strong basis that there is a compelling need for the continuation of Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program, the ACDBE program, and the Section 8(a) Business Development Program to address race and gender discrimination in federally assisted transportation markets and through procurement contracts of Federal agencies.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBF3D32DB0E1C46139E3D422B61A0C182" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H1AD9FFD31EE84D968A862116BB7CFE2A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE996752C4EB84E3FACC3351577662610" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Airport concession disadvantaged business enterprise</header><text>The terms <term>Airport Concession Disadvantaged Business Enterprise (ACDBE)</term> and <term>ACDBE</term> have the meaning given the term <term>Airport Concession Disadvantaged Business Enterprise (ACDBE)</term> in part 23.3 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95C5B5103D2E4F6C8A8BF95AAE4E190F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Concerned operating administration</header><text>The term <term>concerned operating administration</term> has the meaning given such term in part 26.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB37934800BBE4F1FB9EA3FB586EE210F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disadvantaged Business Enterprise</header><text>The term <term>Disadvantaged Business Enterprise</term> has the meaning given such term in part 26.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70A0386B923B43E3A671BE3B4ABB6B36"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Advisory Committee</header><text>The term <term>Disadvantaged Business Enterprise Advisory Committee</term> means the committee established in section 110 of this Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF456D1E333A84C2C9B2463C1F1360EEE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Prime contractor</header><text>The term <term>prime contractor</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8701(5) of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83C32CAF09064E308D9E56C81185FFCE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Recipient</header><text>The term <term>recipient</term> has the meaning given such term in parts 23.3 and 26.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9940292E04B47A5B30A3EE85733056D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43466A14305E40D2B3296DBF82FEDC56"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Small business development center</header><text>The term <term>small business development center</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD213CB22C981494F9334A606317FD4CD" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Small business transportation resource center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business transportation resource center</term> means an entity funded by the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department of Transportation that provides an array of technical assistance to build the capacity of small disadvantaged transportation businesses.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFF24C63BAC9E423CB34C5824053D4BD6" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, an amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision or amendment to any person or circumstance is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the amendments made by this Act, and the application of such remainder to any person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section><title id="H3A91F1B499624F8893C4FF31CA8E4B2E"><enum>I</enum><header>Department of Transportation</header><section id="HFD54EF7D50484965BCDB7BA2873E5574" commented="no"><enum>101.</enum><header>Inflation adjustment to Department of Transportation net worth caps</header><subsection id="HE65FF8AF1CAE4514A98323AAB30090C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to increase the personal net worth cap contained in parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to account for any inflation that has occurred since the net worth cap under such parts was increased in the rule submitted by the Department of Transportation issued on January 28, 2011, titled <quote>Disadvantaged Business Enterprise: Program Improvements</quote> (76 Fed. Reg. 5083).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCDD2417325D44B39BA92B0EE35B55CF2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Parameters</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H7F6959739050458C8A1DC98523933239"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">use the consumer price index published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics as the inflation metric; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C2E0938FB1C4797AEF34E8B833575A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for any inflation that occurred in the time period between the final effective date of the rule submitted by the Department of Transportation issued on January 28, 2011, titled <quote>Disadvantaged Business Enterprise: Program Improvements</quote> (76 Fed. Reg. 5083) and the final effective date of any rule issued pursuant to subsection (a). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H672E53F5665541A9896E7EC113F888C7" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional inflation adjustments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update parts 23 and 26 of title 49, United States Code, to establish an interval in accordance with this section to make additional adjustments, after the adjustment under subsection (a), to the net worth caps for determining social and economic disadvantage for inflation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCBCFA03F637E4ECEBCD499ABDAD18461" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The interval for adjusting the net worth caps described in subsection (c) shall be the same annual interval that the Administrator adjusts the net worth caps for the Small Business Administration under section 201(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H79662E18BF3844E29C2FE7CAC3C749B0" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>First additional adjustment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The first additional inflation adjustment under subsection (c) shall occur at the same time the Administrator carries out the first adjustment under section 201(b)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC8FAFEA8CED5425F95AD58BEF8D4A937" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Metric</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use the same inflation metric under subsection (c) that the Administrator chooses under section 201(b).</text></subsection></section><section id="HBC91B69D597444FE94AAAD6DFD2A6174" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header>Update to Department of Transportation Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE size standards</header><subsection id="H907C2D9FEF904DDA8E86C3ABA7241835"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Highways and transit small business concern definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11101(e)(2)(A) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA0F1685FC7F54DE7BD43F5F4BF3F4BC6"><subparagraph id="HA2C56DBE0E1946CEA569272510B432A2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small business concern</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H28ED02AA05BE46F9BFC5A5174F73D08D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Aviation small business concern definition</header><text>Section 47113(a)(1) of title 49, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9EF72FEE5DA04E1B8B0E22AE998BBFDF"><paragraph id="H769955BC91CC4366938A3FD0E3D51A2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text><quote>small business concern</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF91DD9ECCC1A4985BA9E527520B0B69E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue or amend such rules as are necessary to carry out the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H38ECC72EE909415FA881B518B24EE4DF"><enum>103.</enum><header>Department of Transportation annual gross receipts timeline</header><subsection id="H213DB946E5024A4B88122023ED60F8BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>FHWA and FTA gross receipts timeline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 11101(e)(2)(A)(ii) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>during the proceeding 3 fiscal years</quote> and inserting <quote>during the proceeding 7 fiscal years</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFE76ABC76EDA4AFC801A65CA6B22F4E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FAA gross receipts timeline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update the gross receipts timeline contained in part 23.33 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, from 3 years to 7 years for the purposes of a firm being certified as an ACDBE. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7EDDE55B250B4D4E8B5D450278AC257C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment in subsection (a) shall be treated as if such amended was included on the date of enactment of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD05C30EB003B4427B4A13851E01FE768" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out the amendment made by this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H76E0033F866643C0A6D88C48D2E1653C"><enum>104.</enum><header>Definition of assets under Department of Transportation personal net worth test</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update the assets excluded in the personal net worth test contained in parts 23.3 and 26.67 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to match the assets excluded in the computation of net worth under Section 8(a)(6)(E) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(a)(6)(E)</external-xref>), as amended by section 204 of this Act.</text></section><section id="HE8FCE81B64344161BF58FE31273A8746"><enum>105.</enum><header>Additional funding for Department of Transportation minority resource center</header><subsection id="HF0F4AC7E8D45482FABE4B30D35532B59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvements to minority resource center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 332 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H578F1D0A653849ABB55F4AE7A1D49AE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H11DE713AE66E4274A0885582B53072AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (6) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB77385D30E544318BDC0572C68DEA0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (7) as paragraph (8); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B9FE38D0E364E3BA9153A078A89C1F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (6) the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCF76303593E84F4FAB9D6C70EAB59E42" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H78CB633AFF624D34AE8DA9CA1434B617"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a goal of having a small business transportation resource center in every State; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H104962AEE1954CBF8A79A2FD258F1C3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e)(2) by striking <quote>such sums as may be necessary for fiscal years 2005 through 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>$25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5EE8123C4A8543029FF96D03AB7E70B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funding</header><text>The Secretary shall use any additional funding appropriated under section 332 of title 49, United States Code, to—</text><paragraph id="H4D509317449F44999C92CB2B567452DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish additional small business transportation resource centers with the goal of having 1 in each State; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA94F9616907F41C8939D46C1C80BD8A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide additional funding to existing small business transportation resource centers to augment the activities of the center so the center can reach more disadvantaged businesses.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF0E01D38F8D6414A96719FD5825C8AC3" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>106.</enum><header>Improvements to Department of Transportation Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE mentor-protégé programs</header><subsection id="HDCFE8BC20EB0408B864AE671F58CC6C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update parts 23 and 26.35 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation) to require covered large recipients with Disadvantaged Business Enterprise programs or ACDBE programs to have a mentor-protégé program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0BF41CE7C27F4748B7AA234487FF92BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quality control standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue or update regulations regarding minimum quality standards or certain items that shall be included in mentor-protégé programs in order for such programs to qualify under subsection (a), including—</text><paragraph id="HA648FB0915CD44EE8690A052568BC9AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that any mentor-protégé program results in the increase or success of a protégé in—</text><subparagraph id="HE438DD83D9344A7B8E33F59D853DE7BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>capital base, including—</text><clause id="H418EED262BF2423392197A3CBBEE7D6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>working capital;</text></clause><clause id="H39C2A8AD302E481C8A89540467ACF9FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">depreciated value of equipment owned or leased;</text></clause><clause id="H829979743B0148CE92B0DE6415582CC9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>payroll;</text></clause><clause id="H3505BD677B7C45DDA2B32DBACFE7A7C7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>overhead;</text></clause><clause id="H92DD69CD63574D55998C62D2D274CDDD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>material expensed;</text></clause><clause id="HC7B56A1EFC6C41388D027746C0D99FCC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>overhead expensed;</text></clause><clause id="H037FDC9CEAF74205A7504918B04DEC48"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>net profit; and</text></clause><clause id="HE17209CA6E4144DD89FE90117679A137"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>available credit;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H094956B6F62246B8BBFF8695E4FECA3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bonding limits, by job and in the aggregate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC7F05EB35F34D89A9ADBD24A510F673"><enum>(C)</enum><text>value of current and future work;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09C80AA8CB6C4CA89E79BD526ACABDBA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>success in getting profitable work outside any government or other procurement program for small, minority, women, or disadvantaged business enterprises;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA46DBDA99F2E4B12A5AABC87BEE5A2D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>retention of reliable and productive employees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FA677F5A7CC4484B23703435C241C08"><enum>(F)</enum><text>customer loyalty resulting in repeat business; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1C64ABBDAA7460A97703F26F8E285AB"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other area determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF701975136E741C2B232D1A0914E3868"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that any mentorship-protégé program demonstrates overall success in—</text><subparagraph id="H7DCFD785859C4604946238E503C987D3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">higher than average survival rate for protégés;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE25CC5656CC645638D09FB646FBCC8B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continuous improvement in the financial strength and bonding capacity of protégés;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD279B2652F774D0794FA7E381D0B8CEE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consistent success in meeting the objectives included in each protégé's individual business plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31BC65171CC546688928DD5849707C0C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a high rate of successful transition out of the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA43276CC38FD4CA484AA597E6092DDE9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other area determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B961EEBF53A40E8B626B7550B3A0CB9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Auditing</header><paragraph id="HFC903591F0F347F0B6BDF5A76071552B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically audit the mentor-protégé programs of recipients to ensure such programs are meeting the quality control standards set under subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8ADDC9041F4D92B09F1E40A3CB176F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>The findings of the audits under paragraph (1) shall inform any updates to the quality control standards that the Secretary issues under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49903CF0CA7842B48F8F0BA28403C2C3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to make clear that a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program of a covered large recipient is not in compliance with this section unless such recipient’s Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program has the required mentor-protégé program and such program complies with all requirements or regulations established by the concerned operating administration or Secretary, including any quality control standards established under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H677AE5FC0D624224B7F0CE4C5875A7E6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, of which—</text><paragraph id="H09BF52528D3741C691B858DF38BB4B52"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000,000 for each fiscal year shall be for the Secretary to carry out the quality control, auditing, and compliance activities required under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D6DCE876C334D2ABF19957F34F81D03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$7,000,000 for each fiscal year shall be for the Secretary to assist recipients with setting up, improving, and carrying out mentor-protégé programs. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74D6378F9C604610825D7CFCF4C7633D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered large recipients defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered large recipients</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HA9702E1059714884B1250AF82646A37F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State department of Transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB5AF1E8F8C4F8DB1D14C2CF37476C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>large public transportation and regional transportation agencies, as defined by the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C25B0ED5C24488FBBE3C49B7BF86091"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any recipient of airport funds authorized under section 47101 of title 49, United States Code, that operates a large hub airport (as such term is defined in section 47102(11) of title 49, United States Code); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6FD4632ED33402D80AF6D3C74FA8110"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recipients that are similar in size and purpose to recipients described in paragraphs (1) through (3), as determined by the Secretary. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9E0209970CA843DB808476184B97AC36"><enum>107.</enum><header>Department of Transportation Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE certification universal recognition</header><subsection id="H2027C4844CDC4D98BDA3838C53D57F6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Universal certification recognition</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, (or a successor regulation) to require States and recipients to recognize a certification issued by another State to a business recognizing such business as a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or an ACDBE without further procedures.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7EE7CAB6865D4CB7A7D38B5790191290"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification criteria</header><text>In certifying a business as a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or an ACDBE, a State shall meet any requirements that the Secretary establishes under section 11101(e)(5) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC0CB5D22AA5D4BC4BA5FF39A4B7EFA0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Secretary authority</header><text>The Secretary shall have the authority to regulate certain items or issue standards that any recipient’s Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program shall meet as part of universal certification recognition under this section, including—</text><paragraph id="HFE3ACD242A404DCAAB320A6185A3D0E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the transportation contracts that a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE shall have access to bid on once such business obtains Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE certification;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7EC8DB87A604B3AA8CDCCCC2E43B952"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any differences in the way a State a recipient treats a home state Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE versus an out of State Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC39744F592294B138D0045D8A2323425"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to a State or recipient’s resources and information that an out of State Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE has access to once such business obtains a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE certification; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85249AA325F0407ABBBE324D961634A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any other area the Secretary determines necessary to ensure the success of universal certification recognition.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF749329DB0B7492A8978D464C0932B09"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Auditing</header><paragraph id="HC7048F0199B74EF5954B83859011AF44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically audit States and recipients to ensure that such States are recognizing a certification issued by another State to a business recognizing such business as a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE without further procedures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3E5207D8F654AF1A8B8BE8FAE3F9528"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>The findings of the audits under paragraph (1) shall inform any updates to the regulations that the Secretary issues under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA5F058E17A9A41E6A202DE5B19CABD82"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to make clear that a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program of a recipient is not in compliance with this section unless said recipient’s Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program recognizes a certification issued by another State to a business recognizing such business as a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE without further procedures and meets any standards established by the Secretary under subsection (c).</text></subsection></section><section id="H31FBAAFD2B6E47F885498153628D1BF0"><enum>108.</enum><header>Incentives for excellence in Disadvantaged Business Enterprise programs and ACDBE programs</header><subsection id="HC30754AC55804DA1AB407B50FBF9643E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of excellence awards</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an awards program that recognizes recipients that have excellent Disadvantaged Business Enterprise programs or ACDBE programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H03419B0CD1264A399D03E7DC28FB7634"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual awards</header><text>The Secretary shall on an annual basis review recipients’ Disadvantaged Business Enterprise programs or ACDBE programs and recognize certain recipients that have excellent Disadvantaged Business Enterprise programs or ACDBE programs through the awards program under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A0B3237F98547B6BCBCD1FDD5601417"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for awards</header><text>In carrying out the awards program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consider the following criteria:</text><paragraph id="HCA216149B14041EEB5687F383717773C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>How high the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE participation goal of the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program is. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H393C65CD260549D5927339C816FA2A98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The success of the recipient in meeting and exceeding participation goals described in paragraph (1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11CB1901EE1B4190836E6A4241E7C6E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>How much successful growth a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE in the program has. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53DC8D2DB237469080C1061A303CF1F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To what extent and how well a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program welcomes new Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF2A26613A4C44E98A4C1713080C74EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>How well a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program assists all socially and economically disadvantaged individuals in overcoming barriers to participation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1395D4AF985411EA6B7081642F7249F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The existence of and the quality of a mentor-protégé program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEB9D5B6E06E46A8AD7C00499083F01A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other criteria the Secretary determines is integral to an excellent Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB6D0D7F91EC4520ABD58FE52E5866EC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Adjusting criteria</header><text>The Secretary may adjust the criteria under subsection (c) to account for a recipient’s size, type of business, geographic location, or any other characteristic the Secretary determines necessary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE26338AF04044A1FA29CB3CBD02A3F9F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Discretionary grant preference</header><text>The Secretary shall provide preferences for discretionary grant funding awards to recipients that are recognized under subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA570AFBFAD424C47BB878500DA32965B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notice of funding opportunities</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law or regulation, the Secretary shall ensure that any notice of funding opportunity or availability for discretionary grant funding issued by the Secretary contains the preferences under subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="H88DF85CDDDAF40B8BB3C31E33668B4C3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Timing of requirement</header><text>Subsection (f) shall apply to any notice of funding opportunity or availability issued after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H86B189A0EFCE48458E2A11AE96EC2AE8"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Additional incentives</header><text>In addition to the grant preferences under subsection (e), the Secretary may provide additional incentives to recipients that are recognized under subsections (a) and (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DD5B9C2A7294A38B465CBE683EE51D2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HDE36A34387F14048B2EE915B8056FFB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make available on the Department of Transportation’s website a list of recipients being recognized for excellent Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE programs under subsection subsections (a) and (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B3365A42444304A17E172356793A0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include a rationale for why the Secretary is recognizing the recipients described in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22AB837A209744D883CACF46EFB3F947"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide information regarding the recipients’ Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE programs, including a link to the recipients’ program website; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE1E5098A914FE9B10DE356888DF43D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>annually update the information required under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA97C922D62CA4D7A91DEA78DE5070505"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to carry out this section $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEC0A4B1143764B15902E37D44A7A6DC9"><enum>109.</enum><header>Reporting requirements and standards for waivers and exemptions</header><subsection id="H01CA5A52FCE14DD0A99898F80CAE2317"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall update parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to require each concerned operating administration or model agency to annually report to the Secretary any waiver or exemption such administration or agency grants to a recipient from any requirement under parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3328EB8DAF9B40C79717ECD04F6B4EF0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reports under subsection (a) shall contain the following information:</text><paragraph id="HA34F7C88502D4C2AB72C42DAE88D3C41"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The name of the recipient granted the waiver or exemption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H790FB8F2585E42E29E245B7DB0CB7176"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The name of the concerned operating administration or model agency that granted the waiver or exemption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A7272AE91E44F38A0AF8458C52E157"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any provision that the recipient received a waiver or exemption from.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A32444601BD490FB77BCF838811CE5C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The reason the concerned operating administration or model agency granted the waiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71BC6C12762347D1AFE39726BA860FC6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the conditions in the recipient’s jurisdiction that made the situation appropriate to grant the recipient’s program proposal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAAAC55F45FD4EB897C64272B11A1409"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The duration of the waiver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06C477595F3243E7A60473BEB666D577"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The public participation a recipient conducted in developing such recipient’s request, including any consultations with the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H941E1600D7184DE4906E1E8A5877FF43"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Any other information the Secretary determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD9CE7A9110845219E4C199E315190A6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Posting on website</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which a report is required to be filed under subsection (a), the Secretary shall in a full-text searchable, sortable, and downloadable format for access by the public—</text><paragraph id="HB401AD487E85452FB44C1B3A407D0C57"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the reports submitted to the Secretary under subsection (a) available on the website of the Department of Transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AB3581F5AC428EB867D0E356167E63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>report the total number of waivers or exemptions that a concerned operating administration or model agency granted that year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E8036BA94364D34A0BB054ADFFB1C0F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>report the total number of waivers or exemptions that a recipient applied for or was granted that year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07722A98B5B843F5AA1F072F2D85F9F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standards for granting waivers</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as may be necessary to update regulations regarding the standards for granting waivers or exemptions to a recipient from any requirement under parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, in order to minimize the improper granting of such waivers or exemptions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H583C8CF0F8EA4786B51226C835DD76D7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out subsection (d), the Secretary shall consider—</text><paragraph id="H63F6561268AD42F9B0226162BDB97F0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>creating a uniform list of reasons for granting waivers or exemptions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27C305F131B54A77ADA6316C60766F3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>creating a uniform list of conditions in jurisdictions that are appropriate for granting waivers or exemptions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9945A679BC0C4CF79720203CA6C2A877"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limiting the number of waivers or exemptions a recipient can receive;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2F947CD00DF433C9A634F25ABA94787"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requiring a recipient to conduct more public hearings and consultations with the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE communities before a proposal for a waiver or exemption can be granted; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2B0EEE338D548F5B00F61789B195A14"><enum>(5)</enum><text>increasing the level of standard for which a recipient’s proposal must meet before concerned operating administration or model agency will grant a waiver or exemption to a recipient.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2630520B7BFD48E3B57BCEE703831274"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Auditing</header><paragraph id="HB8E70BC1C96342B4AEF7A7EE06F42AA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall periodically audit concerned operating administrations or model agencies to ensure that such administrations or agencies are minimizing the improper granting of waivers or exemptions to a recipient from any requirement under parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A4B36FF4B034C61A59F4C5DC7E978B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of information</header><text>The findings of the audits under paragraph (1) shall inform any updates to the regulations that the Secretary issues or updates under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC52CA9C1EDC94BFD8B848B3176281355"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="H61E990B14F024CC79E41AE2E53541367"><enum>110.</enum><header>Advisory committee on disadvantaged business enterprises and ACDBEs</header><subsection id="H959EA5EEA506461B851CE71492A53A85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disadvantaged business enterprise and ACDBE advisory committee</header><paragraph id="H8B0F41A8CFEB49E98E1ECD8FF6680509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise and ACDBE Advisory Committee (in this section referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D59EE93429F477A8405D22A2EB9F2CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Committee shall be to provide a forum for stakeholders to discuss and make policy recommendations to Congress with respect to advancing the success of Disadvantage Business Enterprises and ACDBEs in the transportation, infrastructure, construction, and building industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD4615F55F724B63ACD313243A239270"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><subparagraph id="H88B7418590024FFE9A2C5595642FC999"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Voting members</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of the following voting members:</text><clause id="HA42CF8E1EAE94D1F8265779A750D152C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary or the Secretary’s designee.</text></clause><clause id="H7933A6C4C13A4A2989DB2FE058B5D03D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Administrator or the Administrator’s designee.</text></clause><clause id="HD8F13ABE79BE4F7E8AF0057E3E198F4D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A representative of State governments.</text></clause><clause id="H91CA91AB4A92492DAD53F7019C749700"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A representative of local governments.</text></clause><clause id="HDAB1F8C9B6E9430EAA2F0CEA748AB6EA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A representative of county governments.</text></clause><clause id="H5F99EF8E205C4140989693D0C199DB38"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A representative of State Departments of Transportation.</text></clause><clause id="H144F03C540944C6FB30E8FF668F4DE68"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A representative of transit agencies.</text></clause><clause id="H63F9F855FA8741CB974E07AA3748F27E"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A representative of airports.</text></clause><clause id="H3045CE4C7D5A482D82EAD2220691585B"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A representative from the Conference of Minority Transportation Officials.</text></clause><clause id="H87DC3698E3D948D49EF2AFCCBA2B682F"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Two individuals who have experience advocating for Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs.</text></clause><clause id="HC784C9743E9D433FA1CA15FF5504397A"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Two or more representatives from Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs owned by persons of color.</text></clause><clause id="HFB0DD3147A2B46ECA83EC49795616BFF"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Two or more representatives from Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs owned by women.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49899663CB6B427993857F3C234B0CC7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appointing authority</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint all members of the Committee, except for the Administrator, who shall have a self-executing appointment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7F4020487D74C298D8CF175891E219B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Appointment replacement</header><text>The Secretary shall promptly appoint a replacement for any member whose term has expired or who has resigned from the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EEF8A76D5A142A58B0E2F0BF29A90C3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Term length</header><clause id="H7C11B5085C634E3E94CE8759E8740DFB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member, except for the Secretary or the Administrator, shall serve for an initial term of 4 years on the Committee.</text></clause><clause id="H8D172C41D25A44BDA9228C5A528C01ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reappointment</header><text>A member whose term has expired may be reappointed to the Committee for subsequent terms.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H444DAFEB075641FA914217A8E1259426"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Service continuation</header><text>A member whose term has expired may continue to serve until the Secretary has appointed a replacement member. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H327B35BA4EEF4555822967C5F25CE857"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Non-voting members</header><text>The Secretary may allow additional interested stakeholders to attend and participate in the activities of the Committee as non-voting members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98790577A6524D8A9446E7CCFFE4B8C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Committee shall meet not less frequently than—</text><subparagraph id="HB68A2B19D2394E0FA89BFB163914CD6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>4 times per year until the report under paragraph (5) is submitted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6EBF34BC11946828C374E98310CE79E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>2 times per year after such report is submitted. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H067BE5F471EA4A24980094F522FCF7DB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><subparagraph id="HAF2FD7B38BD64F0CA816E33D38877820"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the establishment of the Committee, the Committee shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report that contains recommendations, supported by at least a majority of all voting members. Such report shall include recommendations regarding—</text><clause id="H2CA0494DF5174D9A964C8C3798562107"><enum>(i)</enum><text>policy or regulatory changes to help increase the success of Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs in the transportation construction and building industries;</text></clause><clause id="H34C3A0AFC8304CD488755E9FF1852910"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy or regulatory changes to help increase the number of prime contractors that are Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs;</text></clause><clause id="H68A57DDBA021482186EC03AD8A1E8F74"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy or regulatory changes to address the penalization that occurs when businesses owned by women or persons of color become too large to qualify as Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs;</text></clause><clause id="H28BE25C27C26430EB0588349FF5F6F77"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>policy or regulatory changes to address the structural and legacy barriers faced by women and persons of color in attempting to enter or succeed in the transportation, construction, and building industries; </text></clause><clause id="HDEC133F58D0545C2842D5CDE5E0C90D8"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy or regulatory changes to increase the access of Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs to financial capital and other necessary ancillary services to succeed; and</text></clause><clause id="H9EFFE7EB53934AC483AA73A80F3B4FC0" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ways to make existing Federal technical assistance programs such as small business transportation resource centers, small business development centers, minority business development centers, and procurement technical assistance centers work better and reach more Disadvantaged Business Enterprises and ACDBEs. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADAA046DDE364791BA7715588B83EF53"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Dissenting views</header><text>The report in subparagraph (A) shall include a section allowing any dissenting views and the dissent’s rationale from the majority’s recommendations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5740DB5AB779487496BCCE45A5983337"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional reports</header><text>After the submission of the report under paragraph (5), the Committee shall, from time to time at an appropriate time determined by the Committee, submit to the Secretary and Congress subsequent reports that are consistent with the duties of the Committee described in paragraph (2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D59404355524F7D8E2199255AF0164E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Committee shall serve without compensation, but may be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBCA7CDB06FC434E997C2CD6B5B1407C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Support</header><text>The Secretary shall use the resources of the Department of Transportation and the Office of the Secretary to provide support to the Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0735AACAFCDE4B88BEE33665312B9071"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Committee shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date on which the Committee is established under subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="H5937A778616B4275BB50DF0D75C96A9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall have the authority to issue or modify any regulations necessary to carry out subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H081763F4AE2442CB843EE69786F26B84"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Sections 100501, 100502, and 100503 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) are repealed. </text></subsection></section></title><title id="H676E6D2D89B742A8914ECA755C8C0EED"><enum>II</enum><header>Small Business Administration</header><section id="HACCADBA1E8A44C789C00474EC6923030"><enum>201.</enum><header>Update to small business concern disadvantaged business net worth caps</header><subsection id="H28E9A7B400E047D193AE2AE24CCBD6DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall update part 124 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations, with respect to the maximum net worth of an individual claiming economic disadvantage to be equal to the net worth cap established by the Secretary of Transportation under section 101.</text></subsection><subsection id="H46BF8F16AF88475097DF0C06A629ADCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment</header><paragraph id="H5E23E2D6BB4E4BD0BE76DEB2921378AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interval</header><text>On the first January 1 that is 2 years after the date the Administrator makes the update described in subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall adjust the maximum net worth described in subsection (a) for inflation using a metric developed by the Administrator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3AD3CBB723C4E6F9EA402CBBC109D7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Metric</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the metric described in paragraph (1) to account for inflation, the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="HD62FEDC56C9D43F3BF621B994A98A471"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider using the Consumer Price Index published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics in such metric;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3195503FD157468CBEDA02E06ABF5EDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solicit and consider the recommendations of the Secretary of Transportation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H886A5877FB6049559D9F379900DF8BEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>solicit and consider public comment on the appropriate metric to use and whether such metric should take into account regional variations in maximum net worth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6611DE8E59534AA28CAA9F827C7D09A7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final rule on inflation metric</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Administrator solicits public comment pursuant to paragraph (2), the Administrator shall issue a final rule describing the metric developed under this paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05FE6B752FCC495B8464FF6AB7197839"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on net worth variation</header><paragraph id="H77284FD603B241EF9C0A7832D740409E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report examining the feasibility of, and the benefits and drawbacks of adjusting the maximum net worth under subsection (a) for regional variations in maximum net worth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D32B89CC465420DA6D8A27937489A92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report requirements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall contain—</text><subparagraph id="H407F2220777B4A1F8D1375CAF1518D50"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the feasibility of measuring regional variations in maximum net worth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3C2001AEE6A441C9F9B6305696A6604"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an examination of possible methods to measure regional variations in maximum net worth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7107AB4BA98430A90DE1C8EB8D8B073"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an examination of the efforts of other Federal agencies to develop metrics on a regional basis and whether such efforts could be applicable measuring regional variations in maximum net worth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H309DB19EEC2B4CC8924DD9F954FD0C1C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benefits and costs of measuring regional variations in maximum net worth; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B32029CBBD649A8B3E9F2BD8A921C70"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a recommendation on whether or not the Small Business Administration should measure regional variations in maximum net worth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03C76A98825241D589E3A17CAF9DB7B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the report required under this paragraph, the Administrator shall consult with interested persons, including—</text><subparagraph id="HFE976901384441AC9E6C20D9494EF41C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns (as defined in section 8(a)(4)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC501E65906C54946A9845FB8E81D5673"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of concern that would that would qualify as a socially and economically disadvantaged small business concern but for the maximum net worth established in part 124 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BDCA8DF800F4307970A0A1C561A71EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD345E04DC2F544B6A6475E01BC83447D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>State or local chambers of commerce or equivalent organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49135D7643C4408E8A797B91C34040F6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">groups representing or advocating for owners of socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9C7B4F5C13194FE9A9D68E0F1819059F"><enum>202.</enum><header>Update to certain size standards under the Small Business Act</header><subsection id="H00A08FA14763481E90D188506AD3904A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Certain size standards review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall conduct a detailed review of the size standards for small business concerns established under section 3(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)</external-xref>) and part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulation (or a successor regulation), including a review of the the size standards methodology contained in <quote>Small Business Size Standards: Revised Size Standards Methodology</quote> (84 Fed. Reg. 14587 (April 11, 2019)), for concerns assigned a North American Industry Classification System code beginning with 23 or 48 and make the appropriate adjustments to the size standards for such concerns. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2F0D8AB7ABB24C7B8C68E6564BE8EABF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the review described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall consult with interested persons, including—</text><paragraph id="H3244765FCC8741039E08AA2BDD7C0549"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns (as defined in section 8(a)(4)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>)) assigned a North American Industry Classification System code beginning with 23 or 48;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8EC3B12B31411B8421295791B43260"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">owners of concerns in the industries assigned a North American Industry Classification System code beginning with 23 or 48 that would qualify as a socially and economically disadvantaged small business concern but for the size standards established in part 121 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC43C2830561D4D74901D93A75B4D3A83"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Transportation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152BDBE4D4BB4966A4294D9486D49BB8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>groups representing or advocating for owners of socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns in the industries covered by subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4160BEDBFEE419B9A274D23A40E4429"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">groups representing construction businesses and transportation and warehousing businesses; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99D165530D3E44C6BA2E3B6468AA3C99"><enum>(6)</enum><text>State or local chambers of commerce or equivalent organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BD9DB21118D4D2C97A3B43F17405F24"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In making an adjustment described in subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H28075938D38F49B8BBBAD655DBFD1D7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>presume that market conditions have changed as a result of the increase in infrastructure spending in the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B90F77105524F57931867436D5E5E67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the size standards described in subsection (a) are increased by an amount equal to at least 150 percent of such size standards that are in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, unless the Administrator determines that such action would jeopardize Federal assistance provided to owners of socially and economically disadvantaged small business concerns.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56A3AA57C72E4E09B0FB7371C2C2A243" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Administrator makes an adjustment under subsection (a), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives, make publicly available, a report on the review, including—</text><paragraph id="H90BDCB0465694E0BBD1533841A5DC4F4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on the factors evaluated for each review conducted under subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8DAD1E8D2784C458F063DFCEDEC2976" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any adjustment made to each size standard that was reviewed pursuant to subsection (a), including any revisions made to size standard methodology pursuant to subsection (a), and the rationale for that adjustment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5347C65A0846FBBF62C92CB105A86A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Administrator makes a determination to not increase a size standard by an amount equal to at least 150 percent of such size standards that are in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act (as described in subsection (c)(2)), an explanation of the rationale for such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB2204BCF771F4CA1882A6A8103043B50"><enum>203.</enum><header>Annual gross receipts timeline under the Small Business Act</header><subsection id="H0A789BBF05034CD0AE1BF66B1D1E0C98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Gross receipts timeline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(a)(2)(C)(ii)(II) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632(a)(2)(C)(ii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>5 years</quote> and inserting <quote>7 years</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H07BF141F50064F399C94CB2AB16AEFEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue or amend such rules as are necessary to carry out the amendment made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="HDED0B51284B3493F99976BE5CE74A584"><enum>204.</enum><header>Definition of assets under the Small Business Act</header><subsection id="H6A65B08F93494ADCBB5DE59A185FE8E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of assets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8(a)(6)(E) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(a)(6)(E)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCDF229016AB843299BD0F7B0C7E1DA2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51D5AE9902B14CD5B94A958AD41EA524"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding the following new clauses:</text><quoted-block id="HD8F6582A5AFE4D77AD832FF58107D4D8" style="OLC"><clause id="H9699C46EE63A40FCBBAD61B6D4DE0A90"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>retirement savings accounts of disadvantaged owners;</text></clause><clause id="HC3716C0D5DFB439983D7731EEDBED575"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>investments in real estate other than primary personal residences of disadvantaged owners; and</text></clause><clause id="H2A87E6E47B5B4344AA2E49DA96E355C8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>equity in businesses that are not certified under this subsection of disadvantaged owners.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA092AA7C1F24C64BA8C878E7FE68023"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue or amend such rules as are necessary to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="HB49C1AA8CA3645C2AD963A0CE337B2FE"><enum>205.</enum><header>Small business development center partnerships with the Department of Transportation</header><subsection id="H6D791346D5844E2DB085CB527C993293"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21(c)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1273B6AFC450471CB56719CE5208CDE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (T), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27168FDEE864B2C8223F6F7599E4E30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (v) of the first subparagraph (U) (relating to succession planning), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CCFD8972BF44BBA88FA29881DC90FEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in second subparagraph (U) (relating to training on domestic and international intellectual property protections)—</text><subparagraph id="HA4A6111322224F299C65C25B0075DE69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(II), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90FAD14932B74DB7916DDCBEC5605EDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating such subparagraph as subparagraph (V); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4A5BB6156BB4A419F5D498CC065215A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H836B1A6985C44C0BA49CE8A4FF7B995E" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HCB62951E178D480693452D3941BF2876"><enum>(W)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuant to a cooperative agreement entered into under section 205 of the Giving Disadvantaged Businesses Opportunities for Success Act, providing assistance to Disadvantaged Business Enterprises (as such term is defined in part 26.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations), Airport Concession Disadvantaged Business Enterprises (as such term is defined in part 23.3 of such title 49), and small business concerns in starting or expanding businesses in Federally assisted surface transportation markets and obtaining the necessary capital, financial, and business expertise operate such business.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F7044024FAC4302BA473102F1EE651F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperative agreement</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Administrator shall enter into a cooperative agreement to allow Disadvantaged Business Enterprises and ACDBEs to have access to small business development centers in the State in which a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise or ACDBE, respectively, has its principal place of business.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1B6B6AAABDC40CCB89A034B077F2AB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Terms of agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and Administrator shall determine the terms and conditions of the cooperative agreement required by subsection (a), which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HC8E04316F20042248DCCE3DDB99720B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ways in which small business development centers and small business transportation resource centers of the Department of Transportation will formally partner to carry out the cooperative agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA53B56C9BF124BB8BA5FE7DDBCF03244"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A process by which the Secretary may provide assistance and expertise, including resources controlled by the Secretary and small business transportation resource centers, to small business development centers to carry out the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H133F6206DC174D11B4189FB1EE18B68D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Access for Disadvantaged Business Enterprises to the following assistance from small business development centers:</text><subparagraph id="H15FBD0FEFAC24D08BD23C4C0C4712D0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Estimating.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB72C7798240A423896D01CFBD00ECC2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Bonding and insurance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5EB55B872C94E16A1D16F332E83FF82"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Cash flow management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H488BF377DE9C46F58A2C3FBADD55C1A0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Project management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H087977D55BC04DB08A4ADC0A08C1AD6C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Assistance with pre-qualification applications to be eligible to bid on contracts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31E0FFFE841D4B99BDFD17F4EBDDAEB0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Post contract award management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EEEDD43D0AC4D66BE6D703254D8E08C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other area determined necessary by the Administrator and Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16404E7318174B75BAC65509A99F04B4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Methods to encourage collaboration between small business development centers and nonprofit organizations with relevant transportation construction or Disadvantaged Business Enterprises expertise.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9A13767160A467FA3401C5105603327" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>DBE and ACDBE programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall require each recipient with a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program certified by the Secretary under section 11101(e)(5)(A) of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>) or part 23 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to—</text><paragraph id="HF959A308C04447CC81498B2EF7C3C21A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>educate Disadvantaged Business Enterprises or ACDBEs about available assistance from small business development centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EE2F7F301FA4AD48EB39842F83845F8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon request by the Administrator or a small business development center, provide assistance and expertise to small business development centers located in the same State as the recipient.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H021DDEAE5C82444B84C92E9BD89E8849"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Status updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and Administrator shall provide updates to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate on the status of the cooperative agreement required under subsection (b) every 6 months beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which such agreement is finalized.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3AFCF658310F46A0A8A9BE3F025A795B" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the requirements under this section, the Secretary shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update parts 23 and 26 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to clarify that a Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program is not in compliance with this section unless the Disadvantaged Business Enterprise program or ACDBE program of such recipient has complied with the requirements in subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H08C3D7D7B0124C02A319A5E9B4BEBD91"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated, for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to carry out the activities under the cooperative agreement required under subsection (b)—</text><paragraph id="H3A15DE84220A400D86BE8DD92213916F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3551879AA5D4FB99EA25618FE8108A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA2AD4FB789C24A29A6D5586FC66A08B8"><enum>206.</enum><header>Small business development center partnerships with nonprofits</header><subsection id="H8A284E2FA9ED4E7B8CBF8E0A0787812D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonprofit eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 21(a)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF2209DDC0F214018A2452B4106E66014"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by inserting <quote>(including nonprofit organizations)</quote> after <quote>private partnerships</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8355E56DBB294691BF22EF8E93E3253D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block id="H77BD725813674C74904910429BF1E02A" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H5F6660E3874045CFB96487451270B3AC" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each small business development center shall develop and implement a process under which a nonprofit organization may apply at least once every 2 years to partner with such small business development center to provide services, expertise, or resources to enhance and expand the services of such small business development center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84AFE95DA7B54EADAEE571C2471FF394" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A small business development center may make a subgrant or subaward of any Federal funds awarded to such small business development center to a partner nonprofit organization (as described in subparagraph (D)) to carry out activities of the small business development center.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C97845E4A5E40FDBADB48C1267045D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue or amend such rules as are necessary to carry out the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

