<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC46BBC155FA942DFB5B58FB0384DF8C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8120 IH: Expanding Trade Sanctions on Russia Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8120</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation of certain products of the Russian Federation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9220110BF43C44CEB6E5CC50B9CDF5BF" style="OLC"><section id="H70EAC7C4F5F341AB8DB6E81E8C724CC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Trade Sanctions on Russia Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5C3FF7FF2EA04D838708DCCAB839E354"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on importation of certain products of the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="HE822AC6A17B24F44869BD301350C20EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H35D45C465B6B4D66B1E0D38A8B6EA05C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Effective beginning on the date that is 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, all products of the Russian Federation described in paragraph (2) shall be banned from importation into the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H878B6E3943654CF7917A46C3E7E508B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Products described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The products described in this paragraph are products classifiable under headings 2304.00, 2844.20, 4412.33, 7106.91, 7110.11, 7110.21, 7110.29, 7110.31, 7115.90, 7201.10, 7202.21, 7202.49, 7203.10, 7207.12, 7224.90, 7304.29, 7408.11, 7502.10, 7503.00, 7601.10, 7601.20, 7605.11, 7801.10, 8108.90, 8412.10, and 9306.30 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89AF4E184A754A10BA5D28DA425E05A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="H5801C7E25E62468383523B0C14A473A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President is authorized to waive the prohibition under subsection (a)(1) with respect to one or more of the products of the Russian Federation described in subsection (a)(2) if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification that such waiver is in the national interest of the United States and includes in such certification a description of the product or products to which the waiver is proposed to apply. Such waiver shall take effect beginning on the date that is 90 calendar days after the date of submission of such certification, unless there is enacted into law during such 90-day period a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E9E21572103482B9730F9FC2D1D233F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prior justification</header><text>The President shall, not later than 15 calendar days before submitting a certification described in paragraph (1), submit to the appropriate congressional committees a justification for the waiver proposed under such paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H277AB11F8A504252B9B5CFF1866CCC66"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="H68A23293B6C94FAFBAB0E79AC4EAC3E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President is authorized to terminate the prohibition on importation of certain products of the Russian Federation under subsection (a)(1) if the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification under paragraph (2). Such termination shall take effect beginning on the date that is 90 calendar days after the date of submission of such certification, unless there is enacted into law during such 90-day period a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H177434D8FC7A479B9DD0EE7697A2D6AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>A certification under this paragraph is a certification in writing that Russia—</text><subparagraph id="H439B1C40C673416DB74359B7ECF7C4A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has reached an agreement to withdraw Russian Forces and cease military hostilities in Ukraine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE7EE8F8BC68471E8B7337EE67373843"><enum>(B)</enum><text>poses no immediate military threat of aggression to any North Atlantic Treaty Organization member; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H069794A32B8343308A5D690170F56216"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recognizes the right of the Ukrainian people to independently and freely choose their own government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8B66456479674194BE60FF10D1C5F95F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99CA80E52CE9447298CD801C9C8CF392"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="HE5D6DC6B8BF34734ACEC0858B82C065A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subsection (b), the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution—</text><clause id="HCF43B9362223426AABC5D83C932E3766" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that does not have a preamble;</text></clause><clause id="H826DFC60BB694E8795CE4E38F7BD627B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>Joint resolution disapproving the President’s certification under section 2(b) of the Expanding Trade Sanctions on Russia Act.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H44EB1FFBD8EA483891472FEF93EB793D" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the certification of the President under section 2(b) of the Expanding Trade Sanctions on Russia Act, submitted to Congress on ___ </quote>, the blank space being filled in with the appropriate date; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47625A226B924DC0AB57D30C382F0C20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subsection (c), the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution—</text><clause id="H0FA756C38AE04709ADDC81EEFA9FB5CB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that does not have a preamble;</text></clause><clause id="H2F6CA54D1FA54E37BE645BA437592699" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>Joint resolution disapproving the President’s certification under section 2(c) of the Expanding Trade Sanctions on Russia Act.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H56757E0D7EEE4B0EADE94A29FDAB805A" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the certification of the President under section 2(c) of the Expanding Trade Sanctions on Russia Act, submitted to Congress on ___ </quote>, the blank space being filled in with the appropriate date.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5C54D816C2B64B63B4488FDEE96C2C43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction in the House of Representatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of 5 legislative days beginning on the date that a certification under subsection (b) or (c) is submitted to Congress, a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the House of Representatives by the majority leader or the minority leader.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5E6E8B5F74354E52AAE2CBB7DF27709E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Introduction in the Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of 5 days on which the Senate is in session beginning on the date that a certification under subsection (b) or (c) is submitted to Congress, a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the Senate by the majority leader (or the majority leader’s designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader’s designee). </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBB2F2AC363AF4967B667B7A1568761EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Floor consideration in the House of Representatives</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H32BF94D2C03B4E79B6B0A91C3E01D744"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a committee of the House to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported such joint resolution within 10 legislative days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration thereof. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H85BE66ED89BC44F0B7BCCDBA6FE542E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after each committee to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred reports it to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on a joint resolution with regard to the same certification. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H382422CE313149DDB3F8AA69C53FD142"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H67939605F6614766A602B92A811AF084"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC57DB30966EA4097AF7DEE52E867CAE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEA455832D57F47AFAABFDC3F84872DBE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the Committee on Finance has not reported such joint resolution of disapproval within 10 days on which the Senate is in session after the date of referral of such joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of such joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1EEFAEF5AFFC449EA607F483BA9AE9E8"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Finance reports the joint resolution of disapproval to the Senate or has been discharged from its consideration (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) shall be waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution of disapproval is agreed to, the joint resolution shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE6914384EAF948E7B4A352504635B653"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>Debate on the joint resolution of disapproval, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees. A motion to further limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution of disapproval is not in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HEDDEF129ECC64F97B6DC067E41BC6F5B"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage shall occur immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the joint resolution of disapproval and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate, if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC85FF0A972C449C6BB609BEAE85CA2ED"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rules of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to the joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC7243C0964E8491D83CC7114A8F976CD"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to the joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with such joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3DE78A501AF84046B1C25298C66FE86C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Procedures in the Senate</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the following procedures shall apply in the Senate to a joint resolution of disapproval:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3A916A4D0F094B78870BEFAA2B9ACB56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a joint resolution of disapproval that has passed the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be referred to the Committee on Finance for consideration in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1473C4A0B48E4D7781A1832EBBD637F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a joint resolution of disapproval was introduced in the Senate before receipt of a joint resolution of disapproval that has passed the House of Representatives, the joint resolution from the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be placed on the calendar. If this subparagraph applies, the procedures in the Senate with respect to a joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate that contains the identical matter as the joint resolution of disapproval that passed the House of Representatives shall be the same as if no joint resolution of disapproval had been received from the House of Representatives, except that the vote on passage in the Senate shall be on the joint resolution of disapproval that passed the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB2566E2BFE0D496CB7A18C59A404BA96"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rules of the House of Representatives and the Senate</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H219F9852949E479086ACBD3F200C39D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution of disapproval, and supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1DB688D7CD4421F9D8534B37B0554C2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED66602CD86E4F3FBB52AD47B1D7E4E0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</text><paragraph id="H61298E89691D465D920C8AF119810A18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66D11457F864430894C7880C7FA04933"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

