<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H53495E79DE734D2AB3F76010D01CB966" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2187 RH: Truck Parking Safety Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 448</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2187</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–622]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210326">March 26, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221213">December 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000615">Mr. Pence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000825">Ms. Wexton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221213">December 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 26, 2021</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 23, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Transportation to set aside certain funds to provide parking for commercial motor vehicles on the Federal-aid highway system, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HA0B0430C7C55431EBA54B78D01336699"><section id="H14F16216386A4E01BB443737038C22CC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Truck Parking Safety Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1974B9E95C6A436DB8DBB8F85681FB29"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that it should be a national priority to address the shortage of parking for commercial motor vehicles on the Federal-aid highway system to improve highway safety.</text></section><section id="H0647F654A8A24C438EC7F3A544A1E682"><enum>3.</enum><header>Parking for commercial motor vehicles</header><subsection id="HE02763378A7D4886A6DFFB38CEEB8C46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">Chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB576C9C5C6DE47C3B4DD421919F39C92" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><section id="H42805FC4B7234CACAFD7F5EE2BB0785A"><enum>177.</enum><header>Parking for commercial motor vehicles</header><subsection id="H4D721FD7E4154F64868B4251E14C96D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text>Subject to the availability of funds, the Secretary shall make grants under this section, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for projects to provide parking for commercial motor vehicles and improve the safety of commercial motor vehicle operators.</text></subsection><subsection id="H441092372DFC4FD69473DAB14FFEF817"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H65CF53E3BF114B8AB7E7D334B4E4BDED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application contents</header><text>An application submitted under subsection (b) shall contain—</text><paragraph id="H5DE41C3837474302935EF9C9C1C3E6CA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the proposed project; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB73B0E135C44AD997DF32BD776739E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other information that the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0B2B8F2A9FB478EA58641E96FA832F0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The following entities shall be eligible to receive amounts under this section:</text><paragraph id="H069A16D893AD4FE2915C36C5A3C853FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F002674E91B4FE08AFE0233537AAB53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A metropolitan planning organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47F71AA002A742F99C1E771B4B48A3E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A unit of local government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96545D9FB0F7439D8BD15C28FBB3D3E9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A political subdivision of a State or local government carrying out responsibilities relating to commercial motor vehicle parking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49CCF1E0F3164BB28C60615900E83A85"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A Tribal government or a consortium of Tribal governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70AD43DF024A4337B76EDF0B13399564"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A multistate or multijurisdictional group of entities described in paragraphs (1) through (5).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF842D4ECCC774FBCA5D8F73D4099171C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Private sector participation</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may partner with a private entity to carry out an eligible project under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H74F3970DCDB245709A3F00309A0116D9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><paragraph id="H346B26CE31D5494DBFB08853D79C8E8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An entity may use a grant awarded under this section for a project described in paragraph (2) that is on—</text><subparagraph id="HAC9A3D584EC142EAA3EF4FB9CF688071"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Federal-aid highway; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A7DD601F207411FAE2321FCE271DFA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a facility with reasonable access to—</text><clause id="H0C958995A3F542CD8F62B781E5A1DCC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal-aid highway; or</text></clause><clause id="HA6FE4DBB2BDC4CF9A32177C604B298D9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a freight facility.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B741DFAAB314E79BD4DBC1C51D9791E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projects described</header><text>A project described in this paragraph is a project to—</text><subparagraph id="H40A768F4EB884BD29AF09CC69D4E71C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>construct safety rest areas (as such term is defined in section 120(c)) that include parking for commercial motor vehicles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02BA4DEE724C478891A3ABD0DDED0AFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>construct additional commercial motor vehicle parking capacity—</text><clause id="H014DCBB041054E45BDEB0628F1A5577D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>adjacent to private commercial truck stops and travel plazas;</text></clause><clause id="H7178DBED780B4DDE92CA238E91FAD336"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within the boundaries of, or adjacent to, a publicly owned freight facility, including a port terminal operated by a public authority; and</text></clause><clause id="H4C4367B76A3643738557B08C3E0E462B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at existing facilities, including inspection and weigh stations and park-and-ride locations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4D7DBC8A7D2463B94E7CBE8A723364F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>open existing weigh stations, safety rest areas, and park-and-ride facilities to commercial motor vehicle parking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7AA2C4FA6EE4EC480A9FFEAF6DBD50C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>construct or make capital improvements to existing public commercial motor vehicle parking facilities to expand parking utilization and availability, including at seasonal facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC09F48DE0E464F318235425180478031"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identify, promote, and manage the availability of publicly and privately provided commercial motor vehicle parking, such as through the use of intelligent transportation systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3168AB5B1264A35B013FB504A783478"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improve the safety of commercial motor vehicle operators at parking facilities as part of a project described in subparagraphs (A) through (D); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE8272F3F88D493FA02F8218F67F8FD5"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve a parking facility, including through truck stop electrification systems, as defined in section 101(a), and other improvements determined appropriate by the Secretary, as part of a project described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0BE90DD2C834C5689A6931B98E70218"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Publicly accessible parking</header><text>Commercial motor vehicle parking constructed or opened with a grant under this section shall be open and accessible to all commercial motor vehicle operators.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74AF0EB8723E4C36A69DD049772CF01F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H4BB66C687D0A4998809B47F5708B8ED4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity may use a grant under this section for—</text><subparagraph id="H098180E0372542CF9D159148CCF93ED7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development phase activities, including planning, feasibility analysis, benefit-cost analysis, environmental review, preliminary engineering and design work, and other preconstruction activities necessary to advance a project under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H072DAB3DB15F465F8B785A2EFF48E36F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>construction and operational improvements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCBE13975E114C7E86FE208221FF449C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subparagraph id="H359555857D28489A995C3EE4ADAE48B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity may use not more than 25 percent of the amount of a grant under this section for activities described in paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A0E1D5E3373478DBFF9AFBC3F52EE25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Existing facilities</header><text>Not more than 10 percent of the amounts available for each fiscal year for grants under the program may be used for projects described under subsection (f)(2)(E) that solely identify, promote, and manage the availability of existing commercial motor vehicle parking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC213838496BC4A52AC891D29B8A61714"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><text>In making grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall give priority to applications that demonstrate—</text><paragraph id="HBFD1308218E74810B906903403D9A221"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a shortage of commercial motor vehicle parking capacity in the corridor in which the project is located;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF351630A5C4E32886DC3E6178B235B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consultation with motor carriers, commercial motor vehicle operators, public safety officials, and private providers of commercial motor vehicle parking;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC309EC3522DA44ACB238E04635B859C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that the project will likely—</text><subparagraph id="H811B17B80D27405A8D4287551500E5CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increase the availability or utilization of commercial motor vehicle parking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07C3BAB9256A43E89CF0347218BD98F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate the efficient movement of freight; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1935FF41C34A45518281FAB12C967EC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve highway safety, traffic congestion, and air quality; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79195B96AC3940958EBC803F3D1B93B7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the ability to provide for the maintenance and operation of the facility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H263277DBE37E4E6DB832A621E89C27BA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Notwithstanding section 120, the Federal share for a project carried out under this subsection shall be up to 100 percent.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0DB25124EAD849E59AFBF54B429D9233"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Treatment of projects</header><paragraph id="H0663A11539F6448E94461A82FC8946A8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, projects funded under this section shall be treated as projects on a Federal-aid highway under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA973D390039D48B3AEB68AC04158400B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of availability</header><text>Funds appropriated for projects under this section shall remain available for a period of 3 years after the last day of the fiscal year in which the funds are made available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB354F43AD3FE44E3BD375A602ADDA6CC"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Prohibition on charging fees</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall agree that no fees will be charged to a commercial motor vehicle to access parking constructed, opened, or improved with a grant under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H68EFBAFEBE2E4671AAAE704821BE8859"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Notification of congress</header><text>Not less than 3 business days before making a grant for a project under this section, the Secretary shall notify, in writing, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate of the intention to award such a grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF286DFD38AE74573B4891A7891EC6E79"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Survey and comparative assessment</header><paragraph id="H530AD38AECEF49BCBC836C064F157A1D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this subsection, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate State motor carrier safety personnel, motor carriers, State departments of transportation, and private providers of commercial motor vehicle parking shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Environment and Public Works of the Senate a report that—</text><subparagraph id="H2B57A125C75449C08AA57F161BE572FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluates the availability of adequate parking and rest facilities, taking into account both private and public facilities, for commercial motor vehicles engaged in interstate transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE669B36D2E034990A2FF09E39132D2C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluates the effectiveness of the projects funded under this section in improving access to commercial motor vehicle parking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H051C849361894F2AA333C8B1255E04C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluates the ability of entities receiving a grant under this section to sustain the operation of parking facilities constructed with funds provided under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9599306561FC464887A78931D8A7E97A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reports on the progress being made to provide adequate commercial motor vehicle parking facilities in the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4212D84E629849AE9F85AD9B7190D146"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Results</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report and subsequent updated reports under paragraph (1) available to the public on the website of the Department of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC372E95EE142349E3C4786F317D8B7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alignment of reports</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall consider the results of the commercial motor vehicle parking facilities assessments of the States under section 70202 of title 49 and seek to align the contents of the report and reporting deadlines under paragraph (1) with the requirements of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4E6E5DB833D466DB9E110112239DB05"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Commercial motor vehicle defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>commercial motor vehicle</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 31132 of title 49.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9C1BA81B045846FFBED698C9FBD8A571"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item relating to section 176 the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFAC08F88A0D443B7B87B06B62841F35F" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><toc-entry level="section">177. Parking for commercial motor vehicles. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H9DB410612BEC476A9492B9B369C392B4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated out of the general fund of the Treasury for projects for commercial vehicle parking under section 177 of title 23, United States Code (as added by this Act)—</text><paragraph id="H15E4BE754A304E2EABCE61EA08BE4820"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$175,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H035BCA4D931C4E149F4EBADD7261E823"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$185,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64267CF9AD814B109EF55FDF2B5D576A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$195,000,000 for fiscal year 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C0F69762BE94C8A8C8C8F1E27BE1B33"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H34F43E2D96B54E26B1F22F74D3DAD63A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds made available to carry out the Truck Parking Safety Improvement Act, or the amendments made by such Act, may be used for electric vehicle or electric truck charging.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221213">December 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

