<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HFAE440B189DE400AA34F976E874D8621" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4673 : Ensuring Veterans’ Smooth Transition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 4673</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to provide for the automatic enrollment of eligible veterans in patient enrollment system of Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4D00AD5CA7874F6EBA004C1C326EE484" style="OLC"><section id="H27D02E8009454CC8913CC4AC76BB2955" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Veterans’ Smooth Transition Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EVEST Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H92631997E2294227AF1619F4CB36DF63" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Automatic enrollment of eligible veterans in patient enrollment system of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="H722B396FEFE84613816A2EC9A47771EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H5756614919AC42BB92AB4F7EBB0B3A3F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA95D6986EF334506872CD3E40CEE3FAC"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H308C135323964A74A6A70C65F2E6236C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary shall enroll each veteran described in subsection (a) in the patient enrollment system under this section by not later than 60 days after receiving the information described in paragraph (3) with respect to the veteran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2839EDB5C6AA4D2BAD75BB2E6EF25FE3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)(A)</enum><text>Not later than 60 days after enrolling a veteran under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall provide to the veteran—</text><subparagraph id="H57EC19D0FB9C4FE79F32A49ED15EBF4D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>notice of the veteran’s enrollment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5C40DE8C28E43F4885D224619799F09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>instructions for how the veteran may opt out of such enrollment, at the election of the veteran; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54AF020F5CE146F99DB2883CAE3854B3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>instructions for how the veteran may elect to enroll at a later date.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DF606886485422995829F7442046A71" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall consider using, to the extent practical, mass texting capabilities through mobile telephones.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B98214C9EB645A88715320DA3D3E5B6" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any notice or instructions required to be provided under this paragraph shall be provided in the form of a physical copy delivered by mail and, to the extent practical, in the form of an electronic copy delivered by electronic mail.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FCC293760B9434DA74C8999E8B5BD17" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The information described in this paragraph is the appropriate information concerning eligibility for enrollment in the patient enrollment system under this section, as provided by the Defense Manpower Data Center of the Department of Defense, or such successor entity of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H972C7D97F54D402EA850E35EC84632E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall apply to a veteran who is discharged or separated from the Armed Forces on or after the date that is 90 days before the date of the enactment of this Act and with respect to whom the Secretary receives the information described in paragraph (3) of such subsection on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9AC972D3E7D94F80935A62A8F63CCE99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Electronic certificates of eligibility for Department of Veterans Affairs patient enrollment system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than August 1, 2022, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall ensure that any veteran who is eligible for automatic enrollment in the patient enrollment system under subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), is able to access—</text><paragraph id="H4461E0BAEA1D414AAB4909EDB781724C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an electronic version of the certificate of eligibility showing the veteran’s eligibility for such enrollment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF65FD7E04414E5098974DBFB487F1E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an electronic mechanism by which the veteran may opt out of such enrollment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2AD7B612A9AA47F2AAE6915E9278BEC0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Provision of notice and information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The notice and instructions required to be provided under subsection (d)(2) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall be provided in accordance with the established procedures of the Department of Veterans Affairs with respect to the provision of similar types of notices and instructions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E437BE9A1924347A24D66D68B3F4A10"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report on automatic enrollment</header><paragraph id="H06B9A79E9603423BA83F7B1EB305677C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the first veteran is enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs under subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the enrollment process under such subsection. Such report shall include each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6CB861745ABB497380B17F5636D7096D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A discussion of any anticipated challenges that occurred in implementing such subsection, the strategies used to address such challenges, and the effectiveness of such strategies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADBF127C76BC47A0A8B53F06B1FE9AAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A discussion of any unanticipated challenges that occurred in implementing such subsection, the strategies used to address such challenges, and the effectiveness of such strategies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H432AAE6121934F1B9055FD5692F8D7CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any additional information the Secretary determines appropriate, including information that may be useful to other Federal departments and agencies considering the implementation of similar automatic enrollment programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H168A5A4C23BA419980BBFF2D7BBB02F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF76034BD6887409DA825A88934DEB954"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO report on notice of automatic enrollment in patient enrollment system of Department of Veterans Affairs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing the results of a study to determine the best methods for the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to provide notice under paragraph (2) of subsection (d) of section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 2. In making such determination, the Comptroller General shall consider needs of veterans based on—</text><paragraph id="H551E2DD5B3A24715865AAB8539DAE1A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>age;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H630E596F01B24BD1929212D43B604857"><enum>(2)</enum><text>residence in urban areas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F703209B9B042C4AE7D8CE508695101"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">residence in rural areas.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220120" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives January 20, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

