<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3E7C52855FDA4DA6A7B471D9F554133A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7451 IH: Revitalizing Small and Local Businesses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7451</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a competitive grant program to provide assistance to support small businesses and business district revitalization in low-income, rural, and minority communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDD37A23B274145E58A6464EAE38DA692" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D1C03F29E19407E84B171920FBEC30C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revitalizing Small and Local Businesses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF050C389A028473F9397744F3A03C337"><enum>2.</enum><header>Revitalizing business districts program</header> <subsection id="HB0B8773D2ED54FAABECEA655E3750EF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Title II of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3141">42 U.S.C. 3141 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H6926868E856F4A66B3718D143BBE7781" style="OLC">
<section id="HF06213F09C114130841EF6FEB6EEB8E4"><enum>219.</enum><header>Revitalizing business districts program</header>
<subsection id="H4B669BB79FAD4C3BBD3EA6C9D90CCC88"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1E6A20AC87424776B8B9151619ADB17E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>national nonprofit organization</term> means a nonprofit organization that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1223F25D5C0E431AB3D760C9C5F99FEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operates, including through affiliates, membership networks or partnerships with third party entities, in each geographic area served by a regional office of the Economic Development Administration; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5719FF036AAA42A09D7AB3DE6EA23848"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has experience and expertise in providing technical assistance and capacity building programs in support of community-based organizations that focus on revitalizing business districts and commercial corridors, including through support of underserved small businesses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C263A3077544280AD4EEE4F3CB081C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <quote>nonprofit organization</quote> means an organization that is—</text> <subparagraph id="H39155B29AC8F451BBA6BBEFBDD2EFD1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>described in paragraph (3), (4), (5), or (6) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H34D7C91349DF4CD481460C9000358109"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC553C1CCFE3446A09A114931390BCA73"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a national program under which the Secretary shall award grants on a competitive basis to national nonprofit organizations to carry out place-based programs, in partnership with locally-based nonprofit or public community and economic development partners, to provide specialized technical assistance, capacity building, and related services that support small businesses and business district revitalization in low-income, rural, and minority communities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2581F7EB97D94A93A8FCB110043157D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish reasonable caps on administrative costs and activities necessary for awardees to implement activities funded under the program established under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCC4015FEDE7644C2AA0DBD5B7EC430F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A national nonprofit organization seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Applications shall include a strategy for distributions of grant funds to local business district organizations or similar place-based business or economic development organizations.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H11CDB3D68AD549B09A508D5890F0DF5A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In order to receive a grant under this section, a national nonprofit organization shall demonstrate a track record of supporting local business district organizations or similar place-based business or economic development organizations and serving disadvantaged businesses or communities that are socially and economically disadvantaged, including rural communities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFCA201E4366F4464B9932ABB775A5414"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>Notwithstanding section 206 in selecting grant recipients under this section, the Secretary shall ensure a broad geographic distribution of award activities, and give priority to an applicant—</text>
<paragraph id="HD970D9A2FC8046A6AD3D003F1D30C659"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that would serve communities that are socially and economically disadvantaged, including rural communities; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF06CAF3FDA734093BEED43F25A4974EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that has the demonstrated capacity to serve multiple States or multiple geographies within a State.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H03984317F8F04C8DB83260158D936A06"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Awardees must submit to the Secretary (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may prescribe, but no more frequently than annually) a report specifying—</text> <paragraph id="H7D6336066B44498E821483A0BD8F6908"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the names and addresses of the local business development or economic development organizations funded by the awardee;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCFAFFBEA07F4497FAB4D70C443407650"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of funds, both by the awardee and by each funded entity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A0B600D4A884D8F937089A3563F16E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the total number of small businesses receiving direct or indirect assistance through the funding and the number of employees at those business;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD238BD0CD11D41D3B023BD4C103ABC74"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the total number of such small businesses that qualify as disadvantaged businesses or are in communities that are socially or economically disadvantaged, including rural communities, and the number of employees at such businesses; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87B48C2331584D07A4E3C71C901A3CAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H326CF11F540D40AC8F82B0B0BF987997"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out this section through the headquarters office of the Economic Development Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEFC95A5D80994AF8BE8920F871CA68A7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Federal share</header> <paragraph id="HAF7EFD49167043DD8B56C8D8B438C559"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3) and notwithstanding section 204 or any other provision of law, the Federal share of the cost of a project carried out with assistance under this section shall be not more than 80 percent.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5EE946DB56A84D7D8875DFFBAB4EC0AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of other Federal funds</header><text>A grant recipient may use other Federal funds provided to the grant recipient to increase the Federal share under paragraph (1) up to 100 percent, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA5BEC94A11949E9BD4C12F2A4E8068D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may increase the Federal share under paragraph (1) up to 100 percent if the Secretary determines that the grant recipient is unable to pay, or would experience significant financial hardship if required to pay, the non-Federal share.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0000E2ADB1844403B8F1C1D5F8C18651"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out this section for a fiscal year, the Secretary may use not more than 2 percent for the administrative costs of carrying out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H19BFE1F8E71648D89A966CFBAC3EF6B3"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Out of any unobligated funds provided to the Economic Development Administration, the Secretary may expend up to $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, to remain available until expended, to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HA0E2DCD23E3E49889F98434CDA8062A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct expenditure or redistribution by recipient</header><text>Section 217(a) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3154c">42 U.S.C. 3154c(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or 207</quote> and inserting <quote>207, or 219</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE2AE9B9844644254BE92091F1F321AB0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3121">42 U.S.C. 3121</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 218 the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H816BE2A79CE8405F904BD3D70758A15F" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 219. Revitalizing business districts program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

