<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCF8DD4C185F24A849207EA1119CB2161" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8459 IH: Russian Property Theft and Occupation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8459</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to foreign persons that engage in certain transactions with Ukrainian property.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5BD67A34DFF04DFBA1A181DB510F94D7" style="OLC"><section id="HEAA7C05550364178ACFC8BFC20B54DA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Russian Property Theft and Occupation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB196818844354E13ABDC67F53B4D440E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sanctions with respect to foreign persons that engage in certain transactions with Ukrainian property</header><subsection id="HFC6BDB40978D4C289D2F5D830E2DC1EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="H8302C3C20AD94168B81C7EEE5606CAFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to a foreign person if the President determines that the foreign person, on or after such date of enactment, knowingly engages in an activity described in paragraph (2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C87CF7BB5024EF8BC37F99116E3F40E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Activities described</header><text>A foreign person—</text><subparagraph id="HE4EE3CFFF884401AA557A947BAE92288"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under the direct or indirect control of, or acting for or on behalf of, the Government of the Russian Federation that is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in, or attempted to engage in, the seizure, confiscation, theft, expropriation, or appropriation of property for personal gain or political purposes in Ukraine; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB35828FDBA894E528B10AA96A6BE5C0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that knowingly provides significant financial, material, or technological support to, or knowingly engages in a transaction with, a foreign person described in subparagraph (A); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C230B371C044DA8ADD272E251067605"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that is a leader, official, senior executive officer, or member of the board of directors of an entity the President determines operates in illegally occupied areas in Ukraine. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43FCC7BC6A2C4B09A491152EC7BDC1E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="H24E2B2583D2140549B0E4228ADFFFF8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions to be imposed with respect to a foreign person described in subsection (a) are the following: </text><subparagraph id="H3AF1321856754D188CCDB8FD9BF86416"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF69C42AD79AC4138A16C86C81794C3DA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><clause id="H308EE566429F478986A3B7BF10A02526"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is—</text><subclause id="H40E8A5AE323548F9862DAF7CB7BFE80C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States; </text></subclause><subclause id="HF5FBAA7023F6489982BDB37A66F29BC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and </text></subclause><subclause id="H3F9B24029B7147AF893C549DAD57E5AE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H795688BBDE264E438A55EE8D0F9B11AD"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subclause id="H8990F76CEE1940539D74BE264C2809CB"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued. </text></subclause><subclause id="H1CC6423CBBC04BB6B96697AE298A4C4C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall—</text><item id="H7859CC20FBDA473A830FC5B4E2646406"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and </text></item><item id="HE33B399071E84969B4637A25139FE44C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession. </text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H461A30B8A0924D42B11F445C9E4E4D66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out paragraph (1)(A) to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C62906BAB4E45C785D9FD9DD4F69907"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</text><subparagraph id="H6291C5CDCC8B49D5B3F31BDF36D9FE7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB169C701C95549F0AEFD4CBEEA685EF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEFF91A75A787409EB4BB30C2636FBF1B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that identifies, for the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and ending on the date of the report, foreign persons that have engaged in the activity described in paragraphs (2)(A), (2)(B), and (2)(C) of subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="HFBC9DF4CF3924E5F88685FEC1CB49C1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional requests</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request from the chairman or ranking member of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a person meets the criteria of a person described in subsection (a) the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H044D18A7C02A405B92212A1F64838DE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine if the person meets such criteria; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ADBD52E6369401081C96154496BE799"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a classified or unclassified report to such chairman or ranking member, as the case may be, that submitted the request with respect to that determination that includes a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions with respect to such person. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B9BFA7A9DA545048991D5B709871E0E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President—</text><paragraph id="H08E2F7B3508C4EDABE68B31767E444A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that the waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H510B533A3B954193A5527EA4BEAF2C53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the waiver and the reasons for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4888D536839C40D4BC555DBE72D45D77"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</text><paragraph id="H2053C3CBBC3745A4801A2C1934517A7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A53CD86BEA1409ABCF832F5D0628C2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

