<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE05CDD01AAD544699AD1E44EAED3B0FC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8910 IH: Behavioral Health Integration Awareness Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8910</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220920">September 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001195">Mr. Smith of Missouri</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000465">Mr. Ferguson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide outreach and reporting on certain behavioral health integration services furnished under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD91F46AC55C9492F945D74A0D30F807D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2DD44C2DEDAC45438A418508B90AB4A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Behavioral Health Integration Awareness Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HF3228B51DD2C4812825D7DE6223976A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provider outreach and reporting on certain behavioral health integration services</header> <subsection id="H5D766380BEA642DF870B52CB94404338"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct outreach to physicians and appropriate non-physician practitioners participating under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to behavioral health integration services described by any of HCPCS codes 99492 through 99494 or 99484 (or any successor code). Such outreach shall include a comprehensive, one-time education initiative to inform such physicians and practitioners of the inclusion of such services as a covered benefit under the Medicare program, including describing the requirements to bill for such codes and the requirements for beneficiary eligibility for such services.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H211F4E47521E4C19A6DC37D4FDEA074C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header> 
<paragraph id="HA8B2CCBEAD034B5A9B6F51F6BEF4E98F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Provider outreach</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the completion of the education initiative described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the outreach conducted under such subsection. Such report shall include a description of the methods used for such outreach.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H58803888A6EE46B98A03717821A3ABA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Utilization rates</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the completion of the education initiative described in subsection (a), and two years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the number of Medicare beneficiaries (including those accessing services in rural and underserved areas) who, during the preceding year, were furnished services described in subsection (a) for which payment was made under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

