<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB7A98BCF44C41609937B4E4A278089B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6580 IH: Algorithmic Accountability Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6580</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Trade Commission to require impact assessments of automated decision systems and augmented critical decision processes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F258876BD864D549584AC9FE9F6105D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HCA55A553BB9F443184CEB27DCEBD847D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Algorithmic Accountability Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2EDCDC8659CC445CAAF84460567BA874"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4677046F6BD64FA5A1BB55601F0BB493"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Augmented critical decision process</header><text>The term <term>augmented critical decision process</term> means a process, procedure, or other activity that employs an automated decision system to make a critical decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7015EEB684124090B209B82C9255CF74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Automated decision system</header><text>The term <term>automated decision system</term> means any system, software, or process (including one derived from machine learning, statistics, or other data processing or artificial intelligence techniques and excluding passive computing infrastructure) that uses computation, the result of which serves as a basis for a decision or judgment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70554D8A8B3942319AA32D8997E6DDFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Biometrics</header><text>The term <term>biometrics</term> means any information that represents a biological, physiological, or behavioral attribute or feature of a consumer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA217E43DA214466E8D71BF942B195FE9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The term <term>Chair</term> means the Chair of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12C50579530C45C8BD9884E9F369F991"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E20098735D5401C89D8525D818153F1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consumer</header><text>The term <term>consumer</term> means an individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H021376C17C2F4CBAA1BF57ACBECF8895"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><subparagraph id="H3E503F153D6543179F1887F16F277EF1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered entity</term> means any person, partnership, or corporation over which the Commission has jurisdiction under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>)—</text><clause id="H2533DBCFF0564E8C8F7BAC3259304671"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that deploys any augmented critical decision process; and</text><subclause id="HAA31BC64F6B042389C0CB2FC216C0BC7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>had greater than $50,000,000 in average annual gross receipts or is deemed to have greater than $250,000,000 in equity value for the 3-taxable-year period (or for the period during which the person, partnership, or corporation has been in existence, if such period is less than 3 years) preceding the most recent fiscal year, as determined in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/448">section 448(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986;</text></subclause><subclause id="H071F9CDCFCA4419A8A0C2C941129F47F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>possesses, manages, modifies, handles, analyzes, controls, or otherwise uses identifying information about more than 1,000,000 consumers, households, or consumer devices for the purpose of developing or deploying any automated decision system or augmented critical decision process; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H9AF8CEB0F03A4416AC5FF263719B4ECA"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is substantially owned, operated, or controlled by a person, partnership, or corporation that meets the requirements under subclause (I) or (II);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBD942075805A46EBBE1E620DAAA486CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that—</text><subclause id="HAC59D2579CC6433EAE1DB8EA1C8CA358"><enum>(I)</enum><text>had greater than $5,000,000 in average annual gross receipts or is deemed to have greater than $25,000,000 in equity value for the 3-taxable-year period (or for the period during which the person, partnership, or corporation has been in existence, if such period is less than 3 years) preceding the most recent fiscal year, as determined in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/448">section 448(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and </text></subclause><subclause id="H6B4C67C2E7084AAA94D87B4BA52BD894"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deploys any automated decision system that is developed for implementation or use, or that the person, partnership, or corporation reasonably expects to be implemented or used, in an augmented critical decision process by any person, partnership, or corporation if such person, partnership, or corporation meets the requirements described in clause (i); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8D87D1D4ABCB4764980617E3216317C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that met the criteria described in clause (i) or (ii) within the previous 3 years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05982283A2404856A1B5F20937CA9814"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><text>For purposes of applying this paragraph in any fiscal year after the first fiscal year that begins on or after the date of enactment of this Act, each of the dollar amounts specified in subparagraph (A) shall be increased by the percentage increase (if any) in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (U.S. city average) from such first fiscal year that begins after such date of enactment to the fiscal year involved. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD31F5218FAF444494DBB65FDD333B13"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Critical decision</header><text>The term <term>critical decision</term> means a decision or judgment that has any legal, material, or similarly significant effect on a consumer's life relating to access to or the cost, terms, or availability of—</text><subparagraph id="H401EC7A4E9714F728035036769304D8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>education and vocational training, including assessment, accreditation, or certification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD520E354464484E9BC4E730D08D6F19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employment, workers management, or self-employment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08CB950DF88F4534AE27FD7E83E94129"><enum>(C)</enum><text>essential utilities, such as electricity, heat, water, internet or telecommunications access, or transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8617B1271E204D6D94ED85F1DA2CA28F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>family planning, including adoption services or reproductive services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45D28DAD42B24AF8BD09DADF1BE35820"><enum>(E)</enum><text>financial services, including any financial service provided by a mortgage company, mortgage broker, or creditor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11C075C416A54EEDB03355FF0607CE59"><enum>(F)</enum><text>healthcare, including mental healthcare, dental, or vision;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07EC14EE6F7E4C72AFECFB9CEDDEF28F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>housing or lodging, including any rental or short-term housing or lodging;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8037C0F29BC84F8FAD3FFFCB4D2DB6A2"><enum>(H)</enum><text>legal services, including private arbitration or mediation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14BBF7F81D454BB38B9BF28AC5035C4E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other service, program, or opportunity decisions about which have a comparably legal, material, or similarly significant effect on a consumer's life as determined by the Commission through rulemaking.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H31AC4963DD90494084A09B48AA0422FE"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Deploy</header><text>The term <term>deploy</term> means to implement, use, or make available for sale, license, or other commercial relationship.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA41EB468ED81479DB0D56E82DEB0B7CA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Develop</header><text>The term <term>develop</term> means to design, code, produce, customize, or otherwise create or modify.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28EF5EE5DE8A494EB520C2B389B12B44"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Identifying information</header><text>The term <term>identifying information</term> means any information, regardless of how the information is collected, inferred, predicted, or obtained that identifies or represents a consumer, household, or consumer device through data elements or attributes, such as name, postal address, telephone number, biometrics, email address, internet protocol address, social security number, or any other identifying number, identifier, or code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E91B1C998FE40CBA6E0441F8A46E0B0"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Impact assessment</header><text>The term <term>impact assessment</term> means the ongoing study and evaluation of an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process and its impact on consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H370BA7138CEC42BE83949A361D29A8E0"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Passive computing infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>passive computing infrastructure</term> means any intermediary technology that does not influence or determine the outcome of a decision, including—</text><subparagraph id="H235FB0C63780450E85B61A3B71EC9FCF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>web hosting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA1589804259453DA30D5A0F1E85237E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>domain registration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0D8C28C9A06441596F1DBE47BF18917"><enum>(C)</enum><text>networking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6928139BB27B4FEF9ED1160A3FE191F0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>caching;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE2539948B2A421DA7161238F4DC741D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>data storage; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4752D480F53C428B87DC5AFD5627CE80"><enum>(F)</enum><text>cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H614AD202A03C42409D3DC3FC08F729BD"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6790E3000AC34068B6B1B41BF2DA0FDB"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Summary report</header><text>The term <term>summary report</term> means documentation of a subset of information required to be addressed by the impact assessment as described in this Act or determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA07161193AEA4EEAA033C8E83BBB7BBA"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Third-party decision recipient</header><text>The term <term>third-party decision recipient</term> means any person, partnership, or corporation (beyond the consumer and the covered entity) that receives a copy of or has access to the results of any decision or judgment that results from a covered entity's deployment of an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H89F1D86816FE4FD3A9A02122AAE30D29"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assessing the impact of automated decision systems and augmented critical decision processes</header><subsection id="H85073C351AC5462A973805D324B7F4A4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acts prohibited</header><paragraph id="H0EE6791E37AE4419A91D0A176341D06E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It is unlawful for—</text><subparagraph id="H270D3978062145B9859B55993165C45B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any covered entity to violate a regulation promulgated under subsection (b); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64E72EFF251F4F8D8C0CC67257D51816"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person to knowingly provide substantial assistance to any covered entity in violating subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EAB981D44DB478384BAF749E9E054F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preemption of private contracts</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any covered entity to commit the acts prohibited in paragraph (1), regardless of specific agreements between entities or consumers. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H531B52453DFC41F7AA58D45BA6C4CB99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H53D9541B4AEB474AA920BA50AA230152"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and other relevant stakeholders, including standards bodies, private industry, academia, technology experts, and advocates for civil rights, consumers, and impacted communities, promulgate regulations, in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, that— </text><subparagraph id="H405E6258A8EF4376A7CDFAA602C8A482"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require each covered entity to perform impact assessment of any—</text><clause id="HD13CE57ACD6E44D585ABBFE4F38D0625"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deployed automated decision system that was developed for implementation or use, or that the covered entity reasonably expects to be implemented or used, in an augmented critical decision process by any person, partnership, or corporation that meets the requirements described in section 2(7)(A)(i); and</text></clause><clause id="HCB3E9541ED174B6E969CD93B62CE90C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>augmented critical decision process, both prior to and after deployment by the covered entity;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2911368282BA43E892A3A31C7B65586D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require each covered entity to maintain documentation of any impact assessment performed under subparagraph (A), including the applicable information described in section 4(a) for 3 years longer than the duration of time for which the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process is deployed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBB6572FEB19458F86EBE18B5E6720C7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require each person, partnership, or corporation that meets the requirements described in section 2(7)(A)(i) to disclose their status as a covered entity to any person, partnership, or corporation that sells, licenses, or otherwise provides through a commercial relationship any automated decision system deployed by the covered entity in an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69E1DE162DA844499D5720425FFFDC11"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require each covered entity to submit to the Commission, on an annual basis, a summary report for ongoing impact assessment of any deployed automated decision system or augmented critical decision process; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD39FD6083BC84CF982CD73E7DB29A60A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>require each covered entity to submit an initial summary report to the Commission for any new automated decision system or augmented critical decision process prior to its deployment by the covered entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB3CAA2041B24A67A73EABB4CC9911A4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>allow any person, partnership, or corporation over which the Commission has jurisdiction under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) that deploys any automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, but is not a covered entity, to submit to the Commission a summary report for any impact assessment performed with respect to such system or process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27CF0BC7D25F43C594B538320778D462"><enum>(G)</enum><text>require each covered entity, in performing the impact assessment described in subparagraph (A), to the extent possible, to meaningfully consult (including through participatory design, independent auditing, or soliciting or incorporating feedback) with relevant internal stakeholders (such as employees, ethics teams, and responsible technology teams) and independent external stakeholders (such as representatives of and advocates for impacted groups, civil society and advocates, and technology experts) as frequently as necessary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74CE8895E1DB4167B39D2933809863BF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>require each covered entity to attempt to eliminate or mitigate, in a timely manner, any impact made by an augmented critical decision process that demonstrates a likely material negative impact that has legal or similarly significant effects on a consumer's life;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBADE1DF7C811419DA3B91F438A8BDFB8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>establish definitions for—</text><clause id="HB47B771D42724A518D57DDD8AFBB00A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>what constitutes <quote>access to or the cost, terms, or availability of</quote> with respect to a critical decision;</text></clause><clause id="H5252753AE5254DE4B6583E7224BFC340"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what constitutes <quote>possession</quote>, <quote>management</quote>, <quote>modification</quote>, and <quote>control</quote> with respect to identifying information;</text></clause><clause id="H177417A2A86A4885B5F1FC8F64FC8764"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the different categories of third-party decision recipients that a covered entity must document under section 5(1)(H); and</text></clause><clause id="H22B086A662E845E49FA4C67434A1D8BC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any of the services, programs, or opportunities described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) of section 2(8) for the purpose of informing consumers, covered entities, and regulators, as the Commission deems necessary;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E6F313EB17F47C586D3620B06C06EC4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>establish guidelines for any person, partnership, or corporation to calculate the number of consumers, households, or consumer devices for which the person, partnership, or corporation possesses, manages, modifies, or controls identifying information for the purpose of determining covered entity status; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58D275977BB24959AABAAE80018A37C9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>establish guidelines for a covered entity to prioritize different automated decision systems and augmented critical decision processes deployed by the covered entity for performing impact assessment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC47F45188E7046148636D8FDA8B1F905"><enum>(L)</enum><text>establish a required format for any summary report, as described in subparagraphs (D), (E), and (F), to ensure that such reports are submitted in an accessible and machine-readable format.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDEC278DAD7D47BDAAC737CC788B4BE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In promulgating the regulations under paragraph (1), the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="H13D378BB38BC473092C30AA34441A215"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall take into consideration—</text><clause id="HC016D7ACE2EC45E0AD6A9500960F31D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that certain assessment or documentation of an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process may only be possible at particular stages of the development and deployment of such system or process or may be limited or not possible based on the availability of certain types of information or data or the nature of the relationship between the covered entity and consumers; </text></clause><clause id="H98E7536EB1D341DA9B571CC6CA9D903A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the duration of time between summary report submissions and the timeliness of the reported information;</text></clause><clause id="H7E047811E537442188CDDFBD5132224B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the administrative burden placed on the Commission and the covered entity;</text></clause><clause id="HA213942974A04C6A9601DA957234349C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the benefits of standardizing and structuring summary reports for comparative analysis compared with the benefits of less-structured narrative reports to provide detail and flexibility in reporting;</text></clause><clause id="HA390F611486D472CB4A45A71748F9A75"><enum>(v)</enum><text>that summary reports submitted by different covered entities may contain different fields according to the requirements established by the Commission, and the Commission may allow or require submission of incomplete reports;</text></clause><clause id="H3B2313A3553B4456B68898120135941C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>that existing data privacy and other regulations may inhibit a covered entity from storing or sharing certain information; and</text></clause><clause id="H039041FA9DE14FD381069F0CF17708E8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>that a covered entity may require information from other persons, partnerships, or corporations that develop any automated decision system deployed in an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process by the covered entity for the purpose of performing impact assessment; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE62FEEB5DF294BDB91139C3FDD6E287B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may develop specific requirements for impact assessments and summary reports for particular—</text><clause id="HD9EFE78FA15E4CA09D0FAC7271F817AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>categories of critical decisions, as described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) of section 2(8) or any subcategory developed by the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="H72B8BA7335EA459B8557586317FF8A31"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>stages of development and deployment of an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11CB7457B9104D7BB8A72B7F8085A2FA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The regulations described in paragraph (1) shall take effect on the date that is 2 years after such regulations are promulgated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEDC062ED4D2944FA843FCD19CEAA7738"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements for covered entity impact assessment</header><subsection id="HA5C3A810FD7C40A5B9CDA407CFFCB0CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for impact assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In performing any impact assessment required under section 3(b)(1) for an automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, a covered entity shall do the following, to the extent possible, as applicable to such covered entity as determined by the Commission:</text><paragraph id="HB3DD24F8C7EE4B7E834E081D9EC07A10"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the case of a new augmented critical decision process, evaluate any previously existing critical decision-making process used for the same critical decision prior to the deployment of the new augmented critical decision process, along with any related documentation or information, such as—</text><subparagraph id="H904337EAA4DE4D2FA85654D2AEC0B9F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the baseline process being enhanced or replaced by the augmented critical decision process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9C43DC1B571418CBF776BD2FD7C56C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any known harm, shortcoming, failure case, or material negative impact on consumers of the previously existing process used to make the critical decision;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AE59F917E8C4723B6561F6BDB7AB0C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the intended benefits of and need for the augmented critical decision process; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE944F2F2877D4B2D9ECC311285734331"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the intended purpose of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB813536C1CFE4E67B0A6B072745FE479"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identify and describe any consultation with relevant stakeholders as required by section 3(b)(1)(G), including by documenting—</text><subparagraph id="H024BD4DD92C941AD9F2CF2DA41573367"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the points of contact for the stakeholders who were consulted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1D963DFCB394C3F90ED77DBD8DDC34E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of any such consultation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25939A3D6075408DAEADEA91D6944A27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information about the terms and process of the consultation, such as—</text><clause id="H953EF03FE60D453B8A6BA9EB644A8D74"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the existence and nature of any legal or financial agreement between the stakeholders and the covered entity;</text></clause><clause id="H9844D1DB361047EDB3C3ED67529133BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any data, system, design, scenario, or other document or material the stakeholder interacted with; and</text></clause><clause id="H61A1AB7CCF70462E94BAE73BC1F244AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any recommendations made by the stakeholders that were used to modify the development or deployment of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, as well as any recommendations not used and the rationale for such nonuse.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD22783ED8FC42EEA479DAD09123DE61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In accordance with any relevant National Institute of Standards and Technology or other Federal Government best practices and standards, perform ongoing testing and evaluation of the privacy risks and privacy-enhancing measures of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, such as—</text><subparagraph id="H787630491A004BCB814B22DB869B7ADA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assessing and documenting the data minimization practices of such system or process and the duration for which the relevant identifying information and any resulting critical decision is stored;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A23DDC1A93E494C8108BD6445DBD1C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessing the information security measures in place with respect to such system or process, including any use of privacy-enhancing technology such as federated learning, differential privacy, secure multi-party computation, de-identification, or secure data enclaves based on the level of risk; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C3F8696905D4A64ADA9F33A4A2DE38A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assessing and documenting the current and potential future or downstream positive and negative impacts of such system or process on the privacy, safety, or security of consumers and their identifying information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF7E9AAE2B894E71B3015D0454785ED6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Perform ongoing testing and evaluation of the current and historical performance of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process using measures such as benchmarking datasets, representative examples from the covered entity’s historical data, and other standards, including by documenting—</text><subparagraph id="H8E482854001240E6A643F0C907E028F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of what is deemed successful performance and the methods and technical and business metrics used by the covered entity to assess performance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD35C38B7CA954D0590A66AF45A5050CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of the performance of such system or process under test conditions or an explanation of why such performance testing was not conducted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7867289CE1A54689843DDECDFD433138"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a review of the performance of such system or process under deployed conditions or an explanation of why performance was not reviewed under deployed conditions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B038BD3E42B479186CB5AF6C42ECEFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a comparison of the performance of such system or process under deployed conditions to test conditions or an explanation of why such a comparison was not possible;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC934236B676440718C75B255A6115A92"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an evaluation of any differential performance associated with consumers' race, color, sex, gender, age, disability, religion, family status, socioeconomic status, or veteran status, and any other characteristics the Commission deems appropriate (including any combination of such characteristics) for which the covered entity has information, including a description of the methodology for such evaluation and information about and documentation of the methods used to identify such characteristics in the data (such as through the use of proxy data, including zip codes); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H587651B9258A4C928477663B01B68533"><enum>(F)</enum><text>if any subpopulations were used for testing and evaluation, a description of which subpopulations were used and how and why such subpopulations were determined to be of relevance for the testing and evaluation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99C5D86EB6D54AAAB166D1562BFFAB55"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Support and perform ongoing training and education for all relevant employees, contractors, or other agents regarding any documented material negative impacts on consumers from similar automated decision systems or augmented critical decision processes and any improved methods of developing or performing an impact assessment for such system or process based on industry best practices and relevant proposals and publications from experts, such as advocates, journalists, and academics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA16A4C4D7FDB46409DDBDCF9E58EB7DE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Assess the need for and possible development of any guard rail for or limitation on certain uses or applications of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, including whether such uses or applications ought to be prohibited or otherwise limited through any terms of use, licensing agreement, or other legal agreement between entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BBE72B6C04E483FA0CD0032AFB1465A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Maintain and keep updated documentation of any data or other input information used to develop, test, maintain, or update the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB3EC3C5128EC4410B0856954C989F017"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how and when such data or other input information was sourced and, if applicable, licensed, including information such as—</text><clause id="HEB2AD29E5D5842A6AF1327D6D6A80320"><enum>(i)</enum><text>metadata and information about the structure and type of data or other input information, such as the file type, the date of the file creation or modification, and a description of data fields;</text></clause><clause id="H978522D711A743E19284D615DBC7FF27"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an explanation of the methodology by which the covered entity collected, inferred, or obtained the data or other input information and, if applicable, labeled, categorized, sorted, or clustered such data or other input information, including whether such data or other input information was labeled, categorized, sorted, or clustered prior to being collected, inferred, or obtained by the covered entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H5576E94633514AF6A913B69C5FD8A145"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether and how consumers provided informed consent for the inclusion and further use of data or other input information about themselves and any limitations stipulated on such inclusion or further use;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71D7730673DE491CAAEAEA3B44C8C871"><enum>(B)</enum><text>why such data or other input information was used and what alternatives were explored; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BDE80C66D5A4312BA2E2D4AD30ADBBB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other information about the data or other input information, such as—</text><clause id="HD062B76104F14BAE9770717278790562"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the representativeness of the dataset and how this factor was measured, including any assumption about the distribution of the population on which the augmented critical decision process is deployed; and</text></clause><clause id="HB9102386192B40A8A388D00FE0B47579"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the quality of the data, how the quality was evaluated, and any measure taken to normalize, correct, or clean the data.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FFB358775FE4804AF5478D4651E9B6E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Evaluate the rights of consumers, such as—</text><subparagraph id="H8E72A4AAC3314BAF96CEC21C5F4F9587"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by assessing the extent to which the covered entity provides consumers with—</text><clause id="H22EF0515265C473AB3957B0CAD0B49A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clear notice that such system or process will be used; and</text></clause><clause id="H21D284B189CC472AA498E44E28FCDD17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a mechanism for opting out of such use;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90412EEC64E743EAA208609C358B186B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by assessing the transparency and explainability of such system or process and the degree to which a consumer may contest, correct, or appeal a decision or opt out of such system or process, including—</text><clause id="HD3B0CFF6191A4099B86704ED78D858F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the information available to consumers or representatives or agents of consumers about the system or process, such as any relevant factors that contribute to a particular decision, including an explanation of which contributing factors, if changed, would cause the system or process to reach a different decision, and how such consumer, representative, or agent can access such information;</text></clause><clause id="H90AB90561E2A4709B346BC9BE7BBCEF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>documentation of any complaint, dispute, correction, appeal, or opt-out request submitted to the covered entity by a consumer with respect to such system or process; and</text></clause><clause id="HA1C94BE3160842EB88EA2B52B4DFDED5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the process and outcome of any remediation measure taken by the covered entity to address the concerns of or harms to consumers; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34D9E5601C4F484F95B51ACAF799158E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by describing the extent to which any third-party decision recipient receives a copy of or has access to the results of such system or process and the category of such third-party decision recipient, as defined by the Commission in section 3(b)(1)(I)(iii).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H614F047CA6CF45CCB98FEDAE35DE5A8C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Identify any likely material negative impact of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process on consumers and assess any applicable mitigation strategy, such as by—</text><subparagraph id="H906EF7FA677C4156BE592A5B167BC12F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and measuring any likely material negative impact of the system or process on consumers, including documentation of the steps taken to identify and measure such impact;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA09B7CF1F3704615892F58E11F580D7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>documenting any steps taken to eliminate or reasonably mitigate any likely material negative impact identified, including steps such as removing the system or process from the market or terminating its development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50C52573C30D44C488930942B5B96FD5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to the likely material negative impacts identified, documenting which such impacts were left unmitigated and the rationale for the inaction, including details about the justifying non-discriminatory, compelling interest and why such interest cannot be satisfied by other means (such as where there is an equal, zero-sum trade-off between impacts on 2 or more consumers or where the required mitigating action would violate civil rights or other laws); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DEDB8FD93E04B79AB99A1A3C6599BB8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>documenting standard protocols or practices used to identify, measure, mitigate, or eliminate any likely material negative impact on consumers and how relevant teams or staff are informed of and trained about such protocols or practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB713B6DB70F4A0A827170054F7D695F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Describe any ongoing documentation of the development and deployment process with respect to the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, including information such as—</text><subparagraph id="H33642516A4CD4E0EA20EAC2CD6325596"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date of any testing, deployment, licensure, or other significant milestones; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F263DA2B66442ECADAE040F800495DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>points of contact for any team, business unit, or similar internal stakeholder that was involved.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A904335B8E34B4C832BFCA1E6F7713C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Identify any capabilities, tools, standards, datasets, security protocols, improvements to stakeholder engagement, or other resources that may be necessary or beneficial to improving the automated decision system, augmented critical decision process, or the impact assessment of such system or process, in areas such as—</text><subparagraph id="H86171FC41E0443FA8B5A0714096BDA06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performance, including accuracy, robustness, and reliability;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBBA23A58E624BFE8EDB73FE0D08E3A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fairness, including bias and nondiscrimination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBD1EE702A51430F887FB114EFAF4379"><enum>(C)</enum><text>transparency, explainability, contestability, and opportunity for recourse;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA31018D7CFA49A28A1E2D8DA1038270"><enum>(D)</enum><text>privacy and security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE53AF66299524AF6B2754492443B9E12"><enum>(E)</enum><text>personal and public safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5DBBB64DEF54BFC92956748C365E481"><enum>(F)</enum><text>efficiency and timeliness;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BDFD04736534D118C989E6B60A189D7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>cost; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AD3222430654D7EB9722148FA213480"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other area determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC8D0762EB2449C88ABDEB36094763E6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Document any of the impact assessment requirements described in paragraphs (1) through (11) that were attempted but were not possible to comply with because they were infeasible, as well as the corresponding rationale for not being able to comply with such requirements, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HAFE476FAB0504137AC2D723EEA1AD682"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the absence of certain information about an automated decision system developed by other persons, partnerships, and corporations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75379F748E8B4A2E84CE419EA1B79778"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the absence of certain information about how clients, customers, licensees, partners, and other persons, partnerships, or corporations are deploying an automated decision system in their augmented critical decision processes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AA943178F2E4B018BA5E1F8DDB5F7F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a lack of demographic or other data required to assess differential performance because such data is too sensitive to collect, infer, or store; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2CE63BDE4894AEE8A9DF88E33411FE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a lack of certain capabilities, including technological innovations, that would be necessary to conduct such requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H891B1E02047B482EA96DFE083E40A698" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Perform and document any other ongoing study or evaluation determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H319BCF434259465486FDB8EB6B598A37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act should be construed to limit any covered entity from adding other criteria, procedures, or technologies to improve the performance of an impact assessment of their automated decision system or augmented critical decision process.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5B3F11105B034F1CB978B5584E0EF168" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nondisclosure of impact assessment</header><text>Nothing in this Act should be construed to require a covered entity to share with or otherwise disclose to the Commission or the public any information contained in an impact assessment performed in accordance with this Act, except for any information contained in the summary report required under subparagraph (D) or (E) of section 3(b)(1).</text></subsection></section><section id="H24D004FAED484D3DB7C877856DC71649"><enum>5.</enum><header>Requirements for summary reports to the Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The summary report that a covered entity is required to submit under subparagraph (D) or (E) of section 3(b)(1) for any automated decision system or augmented critical decision process shall, to the extent possible—</text><paragraph id="HADB37B734F0C405DB32138E8E7A4B32D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contain information from the impact assessment of such system or process, as applicable, including—</text><subparagraph id="H53DD3C4A92384F22B9ED060E48E1F884"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, website, and point of contact for the covered entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1BE33707FD64EB1B8797880B90D9D88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a detailed description of the specific critical decision that the augmented critical decision process is intended to make, including the category of critical decision as described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) of section 2(8);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF13630C56B1E48EB8CE474DAF95D6BF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the covered entity's intended purpose for the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EF261B7C8354100A66298DACB1339D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an identification of any stakeholders consulted by the covered entity as required by section 3(b)(1)(G) and documentation of the existence and nature of any legal agreements between the stakeholders and the covered entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22F4E5F9E2044497BAD0B68296B605C3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>documentation of the testing and evaluation of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, including—</text><clause id="H2855771617C548F3B3EFC8A6E1E81F4F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the methods and technical and business metrics used to assess the performance of such system or process and a description of what metrics are deemed successful performance;</text></clause><clause id="HDEE98D0D29824D44B6BCDBC89299B716"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the results of any assessment of the performance of such system or process and a comparison of the results of any assessment under test and deployed conditions; and</text></clause><clause id="HC0F88239A70F40B0A2768AA7B637D875"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an evaluation of any differential performance of such system or process assessed during the impact assessment;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F111E98FD1849E0BB058E596D802C43"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any publicly stated guard rail for or limitation on certain uses or applications of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, including whether such uses or applications ought to be prohibited or otherwise limited through any terms of use, licensing agreement, or other legal agreement between entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3E3DDF562EF4C46AEA4D954E7700C27"><enum>(G)</enum><text>documentation about the data or other input information used to develop, test, maintain, or update the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process including—</text><clause id="H9949892572D545C7BAD259BBC979B2A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how and when the covered entity sourced such data or other input information; and</text></clause><clause id="H1C08C13639CB4680BC5DB134ABD68C0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>why such data or other input information was used and what alternatives were explored;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8D886B175404F08BF73E3ECA7B0235D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>documentation of whether and how the covered entity implements any transparency or explainability measures, including—</text><clause id="HE4DDB5713D5B43F2B95EA72C201438D0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which categories of third-party decision recipients receive a copy of or have access to the results of any decision or judgment that results from such system or process; and</text></clause><clause id="H8A1DDDAB5A1544C995D29CD746618802"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any mechanism by which a consumer may contest, correct, or appeal a decision or opt out of such system or process, including the corresponding website for such mechanism, where applicable;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D28C7F462EF4F489CB07CB50B703485"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any likely material negative impact on consumers identified by the covered entity and a description of the steps taken to remediate or mitigate such impact; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4D2A6B3C0324D15AA1FA7E526DE303B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a list of any impact assessment requirements that were attempted but were not possible to comply with because they were infeasible, as well as the corresponding rationale for not being able to comply with such requirements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C321BB900B24DC28DC4C9BDF936C298"><enum>(K)</enum><text>any additional capabilities, tools, standards, datasets, security protocols, improvements to stakeholder engagement, or other resources identified by an impact assessment as necessary or beneficial to improve the performance of impact assessment or the development and deployment of any automated decision system or augmented critical decision process that the covered entity determines appropriate to share with the Commission; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H493E6849688C476A9CCB09BA5317AB13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include, in addition to the information required under paragraph (1), any relevant additional information from section 4(a) the covered entity wishes to share with the Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57554A4750354293A8782BBE3CD52D4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>follow any format or structure requirements specified by the Commission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84976DDA23F14F169EFE1A3ABC7EED84"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include additional criteria that are essential for the purpose of consumer protection, as determined by the Commission.</text></paragraph></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HF7BA557B6CB84807B155675FFF3EC8D4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting; publicly accessible repository</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HB73CDA1F796A44BE8042EAC51E86F205"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the effective date described in section 3(b)(3), and annually thereafter, the Commission shall publish publicly on the website of the Commission a report describing and summarizing the information from the summary reports submitted under subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of section 3(b)(1) that—</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HF68CFC2EC102426F9C4869334B970EF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is accessible and machine readable in accordance with the 21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note); and</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HB3681BB0F09444988D83279586BE15AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes broad trends, aggregated statistics, and anonymized lessons learned about performing impact assessments of automated decision systems or augmented critical decision processes, for the purposes of updating guidance related to impact assessments and summary reporting, oversight, and making recommendations to other regulatory agencies. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H8C43908B91CA400897CB3F6F27E587DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publicly accessible repository</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H675AEAEAD3524126BEC50D938B3697C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HF77207789B6049B0AF3893C827BDC466"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HBADBA535D5BC4CA2887FE8590B90B1B5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Development</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Commission promulgates the regulations required under section 3(b)(1), the Commission shall develop a publicly accessible repository designed to publish a limited subset of the information about each automated decision system and augmented critical decision process for which the Commission received a summary report under subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of section 3(b)(1) in order to facilitate consumer protection.</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H4697DD329C4747DAA2811B74C8EAACE9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the effective date described in section 3(b)(3), the Commission shall make the repository publicly accessible.</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H14C5ED383FF142908E151C4F36490ED5"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Commission shall update the repository on a quarterly basis.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H6BD42475438D4DC3B8917D5206BBE3C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purposes of the repository established under subparagraph (A) are—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HF30009ADD902405CA303642CD297198B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to inform consumers about the use of automated decision systems and augmented critical decision processes;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H07B72345EDF74FA3860E994189A44A6E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to allow researchers and advocates to study the use of automated decision systems and augmented critical decision processes; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HFDDFD8F1EE4C40F38D4B554B0C52CDF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to ensure compliance with the requirements of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HD383D25E78FE4BEAB0886D2A90CB179D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In establishing the repository under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall consider—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H838E50D1F4BF428583B127180FCB9F0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how to provide consumers with pertinent information regarding augmented critical decision processes while minimizing any potential commercial risk to any covered entity of providing such information;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HE4D48E6A884943BF83F757E2412C30CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what information, if any, to include regarding the specific automated decision systems deployed in the augmented critical decision processes;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H1F81AC0458564E2EA2CA52A287350C3C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how to document information, when applicable, about how to contest or seek recourse for a critical decision in a manner that is readily accessible by the consumer; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H36978BF6B8CF4DB3814173BF3394C1C2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>how to streamline the submission of summary reports under subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of section 3(b)(1) to allow the Commission to efficiently populate information into the repository to minimize or eliminate any burden on the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H2C2099E7A44B46D5A2D299D154901D33"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Commission shall design the repository established under subparagraph (A) to—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H6DA488E76E0D4C27BF0839262B08E596"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be publicly available and easily discoverable on the website of the Commission;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3D0BDCE9E23741BD913524C81FD66520"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allow users to sort and search the repository by multiple characteristics (such as by covered entity, date reported, or category of critical decision) simultaneously;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HD5D914976B4A4683BD6CAE8A70341FA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allow users to make a copy of or download the information obtained from the repository, including any subsets of information obtained by sorting or searching as described in clause (ii), in accordance with current guidance from the Office of Management and Budget, such as the Open, Public, Electronic, and Necessary Government Data Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/101">44 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note); </text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H415C8626CA4643BE805B4BD2628E4763"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>be in accordance with user experience and accessibility best practices such as those described in the 21st Century Integrated Digital Experience Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note);</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H36254687487D4175921797DB6DDBE6C1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>include a limited subset of information from the summary reports, as applicable, under subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of section 3(b)(1) that includes—</text><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HA11B15CCC1B0403A94C70932888CD500"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the identity of the covered entity that submitted such summary report, including any link to the website of the covered entity;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H04EB970FF0D745A5952E7B9086281C7E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the specific critical decision that the augmented critical decision process makes, along with the category of the critical decision;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H12CAECCBD950425FB85714F02DD460D2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any publicly stated prohibited applications of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process, including whether such prohibition is enforced through any terms of use, licensing agreement, or other legal agreement between entities;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H0F47ECB4213240B4A2FF968B1CC482F3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>to the extent possible, the sources of any data used to develop, test, maintain, or update the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H5DDD256F5C6B453DB95D3726555BA1D3"><enum>(V)</enum><text>to the extent possible, the type of technical and business metrics used to assess the performance of the augmented critical decision process when deployed; and</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H4C79DFD2476E41D3A8A2BBEB6100D955"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the link to any web page with instructions or other information related to a mechanism by which a consumer may contest, correct, or appeal a decision or opt out of the automated decision system or augmented critical decision process; and</text></subclause></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HE418973C51DA4965882CF4507A36A521"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>include information about design, use, and maintenance of the repository, including—</text><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H9837D4294B0047228BE9611F9E9F1F84"><enum>(I)</enum><text>how frequently the repository is updated;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H520B71F916AE41E895970D1FED7FD390"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date of the most recent such update;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HE4BD601EF51C40E09B8AF8152955B8C5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the types of information from the summary reports submitted under subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of section 3(b)(1) that are and are not included in the repository; and</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H141C0839D31A4D999F72BC496937F1A2"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>any other information about the design, use, and maintenance the Commission determines is—</text><item display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H252C0A50D89E409AA601404FD77B8BD6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>relevant to consumers and researchers; or</text></item><item display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H62FA0580AD1C4044B3BD38C6B4DAB481"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>essential for consumer education and recourse.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B17D63139A545938E44B58136F3E5A2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H105CA883953E483F8911CB21E0405FC4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Guidance and technical assistance; other requirements</header><subsection id="H06A94657569241DEBB2C58216C821F6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Guidance and technical assistance from the Commission</header><paragraph id="H7551176EBA374C2FB361BB8E1A689149"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall publish guidance on how to meet the requirements of sections 4 and 5, including resources such as documentation templates and guides for meaningful consultation, that is developed by the Commission after consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the National Artificial Intelligence Initiative, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and other relevant stakeholders, including standards bodies, private industry, academia, technology experts, and advocates for civil rights, consumers, and impacted communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5F6582E5624B46BFB73788519D6005"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistance in determining covered entity status</header><text>In addition to the guidance required under paragraph (1), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB6C7ADEC266B4EDDBCC7A65FB106CA07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue guidance and training materials to assist persons, partnerships, and corporations in evaluating whether they are a covered entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36485A5C225D44E688E5F3158AC7ABD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regularly update such guidance and training materials in accordance with any feedback or questions from covered entities, experts, or other relevant stakeholders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE087B9D0CC8848E8B3AB641AD5CC8F32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other requirements</header><paragraph id="H62E12315104740EAA8A196475394EE34"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit a covered entity from publicizing any documentation of the impact assessment maintained under section 3(b)(1)(B), including information beyond what is required to be submitted in a summary report under subparagraph (D) or (E) of section 3(b)(1), unless such publication would violate the privacy of any consumer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE9415B712BC4F9E8608FE77238BA1AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic review of regulations</header><text>The Commission shall review the regulations promulgated under section 3(b) not less than once every 5 years and update such regulations as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H727F15F09E5A419E8C611E1BBC035C66" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review by NIST and OSTP</header><text>The Commission shall make available, in a private and secure manner, to the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the head of any Federal agency with relevant regulatory jurisdiction over an augmented critical decision process any summary report submitted under subparagraph (D), (E), or (F) of section 3(b)(1) for review in order to develop future standards or regulations. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H9A2979A434924DFABC00D79D9A526725"><enum>8.</enum><header>Resources and authorities</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H522804CBFE15410C8818DD7FEC4178E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bureau of Technology</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HA42BDDBE771045B293DC72F06A14C502"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HB9E74A4A6C194DEE8CBC5B9337F347A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established within the Commission the Bureau of Technology (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Bureau</quote>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HC77D53183325467A9E67AD8B7443E0FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Bureau shall engage in activities that include:</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H63D5E3DC8E8C41209ECF657BEE67AFB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Aiding or advising the Commission with respect to the technological aspects of the functions of the Commission, including—</text><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HC148D616BB5B4FE887ADC85C44EE5B4D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>preparing, conducting, facilitating, managing, or otherwise enabling studies, workshops, audits, community participation opportunities, or other similar activities; and</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H183D00AE52294350ACDA12F4FE111D82"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other assistance deemed appropriate by the Commission or Chair.</text></subclause></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3281FD79680A4B61970456C5A39618AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Aiding or advising the Commission with respect to the enforcement of this Act.</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H8F2717D06EC9468BB4A69353A4709B57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Providing technical assistance to any enforcement bureau within the Commission with respect to the investigation and trial of cases.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HB9AFE88AC9904EB284AEB5DA664A5470"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chief Technologist</header><text>The Bureau shall be headed by a Chief Technologist.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H8A472FFA7E7441FCBB48AA861FCC89ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Staff</header><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H8887339F866F48EABC650CB5B276E287"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appointments</header><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H20DE68036B084DD684BD789CFA2B567E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the Chair may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint personnel with experience in fields such as management, technology, digital and product design, user experience, information security, civil rights, technology policy, privacy policy, humanities and social sciences, product management, software engineering, machine learning, statistics, or other related fields to enable the Bureau to perform its duties.</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3BC7E865CDDA4DCCA2767C0663820B65"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Minimum appointments</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chair shall appoint not less than 50 personnel.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H10E3FD7779C14017AEDAC7DF2EA84AEC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excepted service</header><text>The personnel appointed in accordance with subparagraph (A) may be appointed to positions described in section 213.3102(r) of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EAB055C017F4FFE8ACA6D48B451FE33"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57F7B3FFFB7B414FBA68B19D5F814D21"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional personnel in the Bureau of Consumer Protection</header><paragraph id="H8C17361A5FB1489F8D4E84D837A19B96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional personnel</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Chair may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint 25 additional personnel to the Division of Enforcement of the Bureau of Consumer Protection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC23F3BF736E4552AC6BD2999A47EECB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as are necessary to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H369E5536655F48FDA1F7103D50B209A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Establishment of agreements of cooperation</header><text>The Commission shall negotiate agreements of cooperation, as needed, with any relevant Federal agency with respect to information sharing and enforcement actions taken regarding the development or deployment of an automated decision system to make a critical decision or of an augmented critical decision process. Such agreements shall include procedures for determining which agency shall file an action and providing notice to the non-filing agency, where feasible, prior to initiating a civil action to enforce any Federal law within such agencies' jurisdictions regarding the development or deployment of an automated decision system to make a critical decision or of an augmented critical decision process by a covered entity.</text></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H40B112491FC14826A59224B7E783960F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="H90EC1D7DADA144B58D63A812D2D557A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by the Commission</header><paragraph id="HEF492678644C4620972337E8F261024A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34AE85EFC8114D6EAA05AB8AF32E188F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph id="H33B89A8D7BC14CEB85B345C814739BEA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this Act and the regulations promulgated under this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC86CAF73F774C79AA4CC07307BFD09C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Privileges and immunities</header><text>Any person who violates this Act or a regulation promulgated thereunder shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1FD213875F5432DBB7249A43C97E21D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority preserved</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EE9A7E4CAC64DD387A5259814BB60FB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such additional rules as may be necessary to carry out this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89913AA3605E4907A3217111859F72D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header><paragraph id="HA12878086F7F4AC2BA8A65EBE34A60E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is being threatened or adversely affected by a practice that violates this Act or a regulation promulgated thereunder, the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA297108EE90B42F9B95221D5E22F3BFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of Commission</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3205444754984DE49B41C91C7C7F9290"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice to Commission</header><clause commented="no" id="HA2DB8F339969481C9D10D3E2017B5596"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the attorney general of a State, before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), shall provide written notification to the Commission that the attorney general intends to bring such civil action.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9BC1E1103F5D48E5B04EE4F874DEE4F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required under clause (i) shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H3937D83F110643788A9B8EEE2B5C4A29"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required under clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDD3CF59E629D4E0A8606D6C9DBEAA5F3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention by Commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text><clause commented="no" id="H537D4AEFA0554DD7834549F9D15BC63C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5250522B389A427D912723193CE03104"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HDCA17F0DBE834559AE861CCFB043B6D2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HDF33972D4834406CB1C79CE77AF49E42"><enum>(II)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in the civil action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H85072973F1884F519E7A3F95E02439A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7277A19FC2DA4D7E83E1A4945C0D669B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H03801A6DDE2B41A3934344E9A218900E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in—</text><clause commented="no" id="H653C2D08BD684CE5B61555D991BB8DB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9CD31067A5B94481ABEAC8E0FAFEF425"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1463E2A96E1B4E33B898D3C66BD685E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under paragraph (1), process may be served in any district in which—</text><clause commented="no" id="H4386CCE49EA04715BAC5FFA7F2797BB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the defendant is an inhabitant, may be found, or transacts business; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H34E788B76B3F4453B2C1FA53DD5CF005"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>venue is proper under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0674C4ED580D4D5EABE7555A1296A5BE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Actions by other State officials</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7C4172DA96D44F3F9386338E332A0CAF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to a civil action brought by an attorney general under paragraph (1), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under paragraph (1), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5C6433B65F14C1EA19A1DAF68AC3DEF" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H81A9C839CB26453283C04929D7497868"><enum>10.</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out this Act, the Commission shall coordinate with any appropriate Federal agency or State regulator to promote consistent regulatory treatment of automated decision systems and augmented critical decision processes.</text></section><section id="HF5471E3998644EEF92B8336904538CF0"><enum>11.</enum><header>No preemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to preempt any State, tribal, city, or local law, regulation, or ordinance.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

