<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2FB670B3E1A405E98C91AF36E99CEDE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7738 IH: Security Clearance Portability for Departing Servicemembers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7738</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220512">May 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to make certain improvements relating to security clearances for recently separated members of the Armed Forces and retired civilian employees of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFCB20F09C1A14596A31BE25824C150B5" style="OLC"><section id="HEA87C9C71937443EAC8433069B9B3FB5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Security Clearance Portability for Departing Servicemembers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7DCF85A18F0D48309D6E0B068B596709"><enum>2.</enum><header>Security clearances for recently separated members of the Armed Forces and retired civilian employees of the Department of Defense</header><subsection id="HB43B8691E5FD420BA0A049362129463F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), beginning on the date on which a covered individual separates from the Armed Forces or retires from the Department of Defense (as the case may be), if the Secretary of Defense determines that the covered individual held a security clearance immediately prior to such separation or retirement and requires a security clearance of an equal or lower level for employment as a covered contractor, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HD073E3B89C144683A515F50BC8F3277D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the one-year period following such date, treat the previously held security clearance as an active security clearance for purposes of such employment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5B3B8E6A36742B0856EF6D7DBE09896"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">during the two-year period following the conclusion of the period specified in paragraph (1), ensure that the adjudication of any request submitted by the covered employee for the reactivation of the previously held security clearance for purposes of such employment is completed by not later than 180 days after the date of such submission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FC8B100D7FB40E195D0AE4477A96C6B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H9C779A122B9242349C9DAE980163C325"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to a former member of the Armed Forces—</text><subparagraph id="H4BD94C10B4284FD4A637EF41CA2245C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who separated from the Armed Forces under other than honorable conditions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF786D365B11743BCADF3E5F35ADB4698"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose previously held security clearance is, or was as of the date of separation of the former member, under review as a result of one or more potentially disqualifying factors or conditions that have not been fully investigated or mitigated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0817E403F604FC8B3599EE49BD31E0D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification of review exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exception specified in paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply with respect to a routine periodic reinvestigation or a continuous vetting investigation in which no potentially disqualifying factors or conditions have been found.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D0961436D014B298F0D4385B317B993"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3BFDFE915E2B4243AA186360EF791194" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered contractor</quote> means a contractor personnel who carries out work under a contract with the Department of Defense or an element of the intelligence community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4EDB874DF0448E38370204CDCB6BC74"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered individual</quote> means a former member of the Armed Forces or a former civilian employee of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53B6FD4E539A4A01BD8F591CB326F5F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

