<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H62A1CAC176174C70B83FA26605282EC1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6608 IH: Scratch Cooked Meals for Students Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6608</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220204">February 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act to establish a pilot program promoting scratch cooking in school meal programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6E97D09C163491DB5BAD5BEA7133048" style="OLC"><section id="H7CA29F294EC44357BE462BE272604E13" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Scratch Cooked Meals for Students Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H01BC596326F04BD3801DFBCEEBEBAAC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for grants promoting scratch cooking in school meal programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 18 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1769">42 U.S.C. 1769</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before subsection (b) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HED3714DA8AF7400CA3AEED0DAF7AC65E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HBE63F2F69D2F4B2E99CC547364E9B990"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Scratch cooking pilot program</header><paragraph id="H3C069F7BCD284FFFBF86A5703C1CB215"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HDA174AB36CE244438A050C87354C40B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall establish a pilot program to award competitive grants to school food authorities and local educational agencies to promote scratch cooking.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E4293CF55264890BBBB8E8A10004753"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Scratch cooking defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>scratch cooking</term> means the preparation of food using ingredients that are unprocessed or minimally processed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF5DB96EEE04DF598EEE93AFE575BBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amounts and duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this subsection shall be made—</text><subparagraph id="HFC6CD9141A554299A1F6DC2E6442E5CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a period of 2 school years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2867055EE96D4308BA1B73ED72654899"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in 1 installment in the first school year and 1 installment in the second school year, with each such installment equal to or less than $100,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E6C8203B3D4A028191AF371D74FAF6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be used by a school food authority or local educational agency to promote scratch cooking, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H1AE16CED08D543AEA586E70CBF0B6D58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting professional development and training related to preparing, procuring, advertising, serving, and creating menus of meals made with scratch cooking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCCFD8B32A7147C293E388703B826729"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchasing cafeteria equipment or making infrastructure modifications necessary for scratch cooking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DA0866E2C934FB281105F11510D2227"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">employee compensation for additional food preparation necessary for scratch cooking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6DE84B7C8B1452FB6F260BE8987E63A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing technical assistance, pupil engagement, and education related to scratch cooking, such as taste tests, recipe development, and culinary education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE73BDE4EF10845DF8EE21AB7F8FE5EB7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In evaluating grant applications under this subsection, the Secretary shall give the highest priority to school food authorities and local educational agencies that—</text><subparagraph id="HA40209949DF643E093C08664A5396BE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve the greatest proportion of students eligible for free or reduced price lunch under this Act; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90C967557B8B409CB5EC9198D3DDAC69"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are—</text><clause id="HBB069428B8C94064BE0F50D83C312419"><enum>(i)</enum><text>self-operated; or</text></clause><clause id="H236B4ABB478E4FE08261F88E88D4D92A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide an assurance to the Secretary that the school food authority or local educational agency will be self-operated on or before the date that is 1 year before the last day of the grant period; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C6AA6A2E0E041D6AE4E967A66C18E45"><enum>(C)</enum><text>either—</text><clause id="H48FBC666CE02403BB063AD05C0A8896B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have employees who are represented by a collective bargaining agreement or memorandum of understanding; or</text></clause><clause id="H9526E52E920F40709EE910A07455B7A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide an assurance to the Secretary that the school food authority or local educational agency will, with respect to the employees of such school food authority or local educational agency, negotiate a collective bargaining agreement or memorandum of understanding on or before the date that is 1 year before the last day of the grant period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD831D4B2926743A6B35274FDEAAC708A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><subparagraph id="HA0DCDD448D1A49E1933D5C363A66E183"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with one or more nonprofit organizations to establish and carry out a technical assistance and resource center to provide technical assistance with respect to carrying out subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96BB3930BB634B4BA22C701F47BFD9D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Collaboration requirement</header><text>As soon as practicable after receiving a grant under this subsection, a school food authority or local educational agency shall collaborate with the technical assistance and resource center established under subparagraph (A) to—</text><clause id="H418B8DF5D4724CC4945A0B61194C296F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a needs assessment to evaluate equipment needs, equipment utilization, procurement processes, and workforce capabilities of the school food authority or local educational agency; and</text></clause><clause id="H34B6012F3895405A9BCF2679039F9284"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on such needs assessment, establish a strategic plan to carry out the grant under this subsection. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79E0FF04B3C5478180DD4DBAE6CDD72B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>Each school food authority and local educational agency that receives a grant under this subsection shall report to the Secretary at the end of the grant period—</text><subparagraph id="H9B243AAB5CDE4C769F5E1DE6B4A565F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the change, from the beginning of the grant period, in the overall percentage of the 20 most expensive procurement items with whole ingredients, raw ingredients, or both;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2600321325714D2DAF9CEAB2444AAEEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the change, from the beginning of the grant period, in the overall percentage of procured food items that are locally procured;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B077F75CA924D7CB45B0DC283902E60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the change, from the beginning of the grant period, in the overall percentage of menu items in a 4-week menu cycle prepared with scratch cooking;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56E0C855D5144093BA4576DC06924906"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the change, from the beginning of the grant period, in the overall percentage of packaging that is single-serve packaging; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9297D99646C64A959C6672D18801B976"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the change, from the beginning of the grant period, to overall culinary, fiscal, procurement, and management operations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FD42809AB81443FA71A7871856D9E13"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the change, from the beginning of the grant period, in the overall percentage of students who participate in the school lunch program under this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B421CF573B84E089AF145DCE1A253EB"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subparagraph id="HCDEC7CFB030447C2889A1BD805F45D64"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $20,000,000 for the first fiscal year beginning after the date of the enactment of this subsection and for each of the four subsequent fiscal years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H987D991BDDC146209923A84F31117880"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>Of the amounts made available under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall reserve—</text><clause id="HBE285EDA9FC14110BD6B11CEDAF4B124"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not more than 15 percent for purposes of carrying out paragraph (5), including administrative expenses; and</text></clause><clause id="HCB36D818313E4BB3A318640A75397CA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not more than 5 percent for other administrative expenses of the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

