<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>113 HR 2471 EAS: Haiti Development, Accountability, and Institutional Transparency Initiative Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 2471</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220113" legis-day="20220110">January 13 (legislative day, January 10), 2022.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="idb937812eead44d2685883360a95facc5" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 2471) entitled <quote>An Act to measure the progress of post-disaster recovery and efforts to address corruption, governance, rule of law, and media freedoms in Haiti.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following: </text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="id7556f471-cac7-471c-8ff4-6c0cd57c7953" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Haiti Development, Accountability, and Institutional Transparency Initiative Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idd0981f87-bbe6-4fa4-b25c-72e5d39252db"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to support the sustainable rebuilding and development of Haiti in a manner that—</text><paragraph id="idd97a22f3-40f3-4653-a761-91135c5f2e4f"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognizes Haitian independence, self-reliance, and sovereignty;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idb2e5f57f-417a-43b2-bbd9-108c10b0b591"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promotes efforts that are led by and support the people and Government of Haiti at all levels so that Haitians lead the course of reconstruction and development of Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8C5E000F32714CAD9CF38CC8CAFC81F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>contributes to international efforts to facilitate conditions for broad, inclusive, and sustained political dialogue among the different actors in Haiti to restore democratic legitimacy and institutions in Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id273b5d47-36e7-4545-8aef-e5a2e24cc098"><enum>(4)</enum><text>builds the long-term capacity of the Government of Haiti, civil society, and the private sector to foster economic opportunities in Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7e591bb3-2c8a-41f5-acb2-2000141837e4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>fosters collaboration between the Haitian diaspora in the United States, including dual citizens of Haiti and the United States, and the Government of Haiti and the business community in Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide64dfd55-0350-4795-be1d-cb70799ce67f"><enum>(6)</enum><text>supports anticorruption efforts, promotes press freedom, and addresses human rights concerns, including through the enforcement of sanctions imposed in accordance with the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) on individuals implicated in human rights violations and corruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9089805b-a538-48a9-8a55-90dfb97ea6e1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>respects and helps restore the natural resources of Haiti and strengthens community-level resilience to environmental and weather-related impacts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b2413f7-a9a6-41e3-bf9f-d0ea4538631e"><enum>(8)</enum><text>promotes political stability through the holding of free, fair, transparent, and timely elections in accordance with democratic principles and the Constitution of Haiti;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4c189903-0a86-45b3-984d-e2e673677c67"><enum>(9)</enum><text>provides timely and comprehensive reporting on the goals and progress of the Government of Haiti and the United States Government, and transparent post-program evaluations and contracting data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id25c73bd7-483b-4cf5-9b66-afb8904a7a8b"><enum>(10)</enum><text>promotes the participation of Haitian women and youth in governmental and nongovernmental institutions and in economic development and governance assistance programs funded by the United States. </text></paragraph></section><section id="id099198a3-5444-4bf3-b343-329a3b5c2779"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definition of appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="id6f0fec0b-d17d-450c-87c6-14865f21109a" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ide19655fa-9c1b-4dcc-be3e-ee09b00f6dba" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id23b7dd0a-8492-4aa0-8884-24effd691b0c"><enum>4.</enum><header>Strengthening human rights and anticorruption efforts in Haiti and holding perpetrators of the La Saline massacre accountable</header><subsection id="id0e211cfa-7541-4159-be25-16a20931b973"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prioritization by Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary of State shall prioritize the protection of human rights and anticorruption efforts in Haiti through the following methods:</text><paragraph id="idebf1ab5b-db30-46e3-8352-28bfab71250a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fostering strong relationships with independent civil society groups focused on monitoring corruption and human rights abuses and promoting democracy in Haiti.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id642acaf9-2648-4732-85f9-2107187a93b5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Supporting the efforts of the Government of Haiti to identify persons involved in human rights violations and significant acts of corruption in Haiti, including public and private sector actors, and hold them accountable for their actions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idaeebc70f-f56c-43db-8020-0f065a971fd4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Addressing concerns of impunity for the alleged perpetrators of and the individuals who organized and planned the massacre in La Saline that took place on November 13, 2018.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id472acfb6-c29c-4294-9102-45c1595ab544"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Urging authorities to continue to investigate attacks in the neighborhoods of La Saline and Bel Air in 2018 and 2019 that left dozens dead in order to bring the perpetrators to justice.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id059e56c6-6065-4f5a-abc4-0a93f6bff95e"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><paragraph id="ida3be781a-c517-4839-9610-15d5ef956385"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the events that took place on November 13, 2018, in the neighborhood of La Saline, in Port-au-Prince, Haiti, and the aftermath of those events.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id35fb74f1-80d4-4d3d-a6b3-623abfdfab8c"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The briefing required by paragraph (1) shall include the following: </text><subparagraph id="idf655a770-44cf-4c92-8f68-9ce729c44147"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An examination of any links between the massacre in La Saline and mass protests that occurred concurrently in Haiti. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idc750987d-a8fe-405a-b19f-0a894865ef85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An analysis of the reports on the massacre in La Saline authored by the United Nations, the European Union, and the Government of Haiti.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id393eecd7-52b2-4515-96ba-26b705aa66a7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A detailed description of all known perpetrators of and the individuals who organized and planned the massacre. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4fe24102-ed90-4832-bb40-4dd0946b59ab"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An overview of efforts of the Government of Haiti to bring the perpetrators of and the individuals who organized and planned the massacre in La Saline to justice and to prevent other similar attacks.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4b18b43e-0433-429a-be34-226777864b46"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of the ensuing treatment and displacement of the survivors of the massacre in La Saline.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id6296598b-c048-4eff-adcd-d84b8af41163"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall consult with nongovernmental organizations in Haiti and the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide15d33bc-d139-4258-be3d-a172d4557b99"><enum>5.</enum><header>Promoting freedom of the press and assembly in Haiti</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall prioritize the promotion of freedom of the press and freedom of assembly and the protection of journalists in Haiti through the following methods:</text><paragraph id="idc55a4861-5e63-4bc1-8db9-8b275a8d5994"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advocating to Haitian authorities for increased protection for journalists and the press and for the freedom to peacefully assemble or protest in Haiti.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbffa6d91-61f1-46c7-abdb-cb12b0de0603"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Collaborating with officials of the Government of Haiti and representatives of civil society to increase legal protections for journalists in Haiti.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id48076db6-0ce5-484b-bd44-8dec2dd5e8e6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Supporting efforts to strengthen transparency in the public and private sectors in Haiti and access to information in Haiti.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id44083d38-e768-446a-9bcd-0048798ff228"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Using United States foreign assistance for programs to strengthen capacity for independent journalists and increase support for investigative journalism in Haiti.</text></paragraph></section><section id="id75255502-b992-4486-9cde-726b3d144625"><enum>6.</enum><header>Supporting post-earthquake, post-hurricane, and post-COVID–19 recovery and development in Haiti</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, shall prioritize post-earthquake, post-hurricane, and post-COVID–19 recovery and development efforts in Haiti through the following methods:</text><paragraph id="id750f7f72-72d5-428f-a676-3804b4743a9a"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Collaborating with the Government of Haiti on a detailed and transparent development plan that includes clear objectives and benchmarks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idf49946c7-3b29-4746-9fbe-bcf0c0405059"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Building the capacity of Haitian-led public, private, and nongovernmental sector institutions in Haiti through post-earthquake and post-hurricane recovery and development planning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idbdab5f18-97bd-4163-884f-61b61c862097"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Assessing the impact of the recovery efforts of the United States and the international community in Haiti since January 2010. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idee26c73a-96b3-4898-8482-b767d7524b66"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Supporting disaster resilience and reconstruction efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2850a071-027e-4426-93af-88d5e9f26529"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Addressing the underlying causes of poverty and inequality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id8761dde2-95d4-4755-b7ac-6bae170d6009"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Improving access to—</text><subparagraph id="idbf32931b-cd53-4d21-abfb-3bfe950007c2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>health resources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6b8719dc-2d84-437b-96cb-b8418f425efb"><enum>(B)</enum><text>public health technical assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd6d33b20-1fc3-4c60-800f-018404a8576d"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clean water, food, and shelter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id9d90a371-24c5-4c64-a9ec-ef18f4b588ae"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Assessing the impact of the COVID–19 pandemic on post-disaster recovery efforts and evaluating United States support needed to help with the pandemic response in Haiti.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id721c87adb1c74c5f8939268ad34acd11"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Supporting—</text><subparagraph id="idE96F2BEBC2F64F3BA29885350E7D2800"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the export of additional United States-produced COVID–19 vaccine doses to Haiti; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC0BF9F06B5294C91B368B21D5EC6304E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the safe storage, transport, and end-to-end distribution of United States-produced COVID–19 vaccines throughout Haiti, in light of ongoing humanitarian access challenges presented by Haiti’s security environment. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="idee08eed4-3ee9-4261-905c-f6d3f781c22c"><enum>7.</enum><header>Report on developments in Haiti</header><subsection id="idb1349186-e8fa-474d-8069-d5dbbfdbae31"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) and other relevant agencies and departments, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on developments in Haiti.</text></subsection><subsection id="id151363d3-a5c6-422a-afdd-64bf8713d4f1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph id="id8f801f0e-9764-43ea-b0e0-fc30e59f68c3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A strategy for carrying out sections 4(a), 5, and 6, including established baselines, benchmarks, and indicators to measure outcomes and impact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4dd2466d-9bea-4e0f-926f-345277d8f304"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of major corruption committed among the public and private sectors in Haiti, including identification of any individual or entity that financed corruption activities, and all corruption prosecutions investigated by the judiciary of Haiti since January 2015.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1eac26bf-47ce-4582-af27-7e5e1b61e2db"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An overview of efforts of the Government of Haiti to address corruption, including the Petrocaribe scandal, and corrective measures to strengthen and restore trust in the public institutions of Haiti. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id14322ff9-022e-4f55-8fe5-4441b4479db4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of efforts of the United States Government to consult and engage with officials of the Government of Haiti and independent civil society groups focused on monitoring corruption and human rights abuses and promoting democracy and press freedom in Haiti since January 2015.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9e768a3c-8126-49ef-9b47-a92f244e935e"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the response by the Government of Haiti to civic protests that have taken place since July 2018 and any allegations of human rights abuses, including attacks on journalists. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1b914dfe-59f1-41e0-9485-2e85abcc2fac"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of United States security assistance to Haiti, including United States support to the Haitian National Police and an assessment of compliance with section 620M of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2378d">22 U.S.C. 2378d</external-xref>) and section 362 of title 10, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Leahy Laws</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6f974ad-7906-4bb7-83df-38037b435e49"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of the efforts of the Government of Haiti to support displaced survivors of urban and gang violence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idF93D4E97D8CA40C9BCD42E7A8D486FB9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An assessment of United States interagency efforts to counter kidnapping and armed violence in Haiti. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6b301df4-1653-49f8-9d2b-e16fd2be9a40"><enum>(9)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of presidential decrees on the health of Haiti's democratic institutions and the safeguarding of human rights, including decrees relating to— </text><subparagraph id="id1f7e3aa6-c64f-49ee-999e-d2c126bae20e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reducing the authority of the Superior Court of Accounts and Administrative Litigation; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idbe756e87-5e0a-4083-9552-3d3fced16c87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promulgating an antiterrorism law; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id6ef3808e-c5bf-43eb-93d2-a5b78db0115b"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing the National Intelligence Agency; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idee88f1e0-1825-4af5-93ea-d6f978b3d59a"><enum>(D)</enum><text>retiring and subsequently appointing judges to the Supreme Court of Haiti.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id337bc1ad-870a-46e6-92c3-961994084c81"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A review of the alleged coup against President Moïse on February 7, 2021, and subsequent arrest and jailings of alleged perpetrators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id20184720-de77-470c-b901-a14bdffeb144"><enum>(11)</enum><text>An analysis, conducted in collaboration with the Government of Haiti, of efforts to support development goals in Haiti since January 2015, including steps taken—</text><subparagraph id="idabc98947-221a-4da9-80fb-643ce275320a"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to strengthen institutions at the national and local levels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide3d8855e-6c9b-4d07-895b-9c7e869f33fd"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to strengthen democratic governance at the national and local levels.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida533da37-b458-481a-b2c2-f6f378f3dc88"><enum>(12)</enum><text>An analysis of the effectiveness and sustainability of development projects financed by the United States, including the Caracol Industrial Park and supporting infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="ida6a500c0-3980-4d7e-9b86-28b3e8dfda7b"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A description of procurement from Haitian small- and medium-sized businesses and nongovernmental organizations by the Government of the United States and the Government of Haiti for development and humanitarian activities, dis­ag­gre­gated by year since 2015, and a description of efforts to increase local procurement, including food aid. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7d399be0-83c2-4e9d-bbe5-020956ffcb7a"><enum>(14)</enum><text>A description of United States efforts since January 2015 to assist the Haitian people in their pursuits for free, fair, and timely democratic elections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id62BB6F6C3AA14E0BAD73383F16A38F42"><enum>(15)</enum><text>An overview of United States efforts to cooperate with diplomatic partners in Latin America, the Caribbean, Canada, and Europe to engage with political leaders, civil society, the private sector, and underrepresented populations in Haiti to support a stable environment conducive to holding free and fair elections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id450af4ef-ab02-4b21-92e7-b417d9119481"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Quantitative and qualitative indicators to assess progress and benchmarks for United States initiatives focused on sustainable development in Haiti, including democracy assistance, economic revitalization, natural disaster recovery, pandemic response, resilience, energy and infrastructure, health, and food security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4892c733-1527-41ac-9781-e71a664ffa2b"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In preparing the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary and the Administrator shall consult, as appropriate, with—</text><paragraph id="iddfe7f687-5e93-474f-ae29-c77a68f88ccb"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations and civil society groups in Haiti and the United States; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1a4d43bf-6d62-454d-bac1-a32d5d03a3d4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Government of Haiti.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id0df5696a-5fb3-4493-a461-f9763fd6d6fc"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report required by subsection (a) publicly available on the website of the Department of State.</text></subsection></section><section id="idA38FEDB406F94BAF9A0438D424272338"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report on the assassination of President Jovenel Moïse</header><subsection id="idA0466968E9CD415EA79B962EAD244621"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the July 7, 2021, assassination of former President of Haiti Jovenel Moïse. </text></subsection><subsection id="id8D37A834C97F44D798364FB2993D007D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updated report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the submission of the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives an updated version of the report that includes any significant developments related to the assassination of former President of Haiti Jovenel Moïse. </text></subsection><subsection id="idF1CFCEA5F99A40238435F711BC8DD02D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) and the report required by subsection (b) shall each include the following elements: </text><paragraph id="id961C2530A63B4BF8957075ECCF36F6FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the events leading up to the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse and the subsequent investigation of the assassination, including a description and identification of key dates and the names of foreign persons related to the assassination and the investigation of the assassination. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB773F88B2F474B2BA26CDB25FAA1C58A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of United States support for the efforts of Haitian authorities to investigate the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id6D41865EBA1540E3886D21ACB0FC9D2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the independence and capacity of Haitian authorities to investigate the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse, including analysis of significant advances and deficiencies of the investigation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id74D463FAB6F0427190BF373A28D35A53"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any threats and acts of intimidation against Haitian law enforcement and judicial authorities involved in the investigation of the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse, including the identification of foreign persons involved in such threats and acts of intimidation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2ED15F6FE0694BF693FA4745F29E373B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of any efforts to interfere in or undermine the independence and integrity of the investigation of the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id90031564C6FC402280A656BF6FA8CD4F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of whether any foreign persons previously employed by or who served as a contractor or informant for the United States Government were involved in the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id359293A368D041DEA4EB4A1ECF4CA4F9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description and the identification of foreign persons involved in the execution and planning of the assassination of former President Jovenel Moïse and an assessment of the intentions of such foreign persons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2C72ADD1336B473296061D288803C227"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) and the updated report required by subsection (b) shall each be submitted in an unclassified form, but each may include a classified annex. </text></subsection><subsection id="idCBAD586EC27D4748AD7D5D729312A4E2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary of State shall post on the public website of the Department of State—</text><paragraph id="idC503314120D044FC8D0D703C97F07E62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the unclassified version of the report required by subsection (a) not later than 15 days after the date on which the report is submitted under such subsection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id41A2C3DB72E04ABCB23EA10A9E18B85D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the unclassified version of the report required by subsection (b) not later than 15 days after the date on which the report is submitted under such subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id7A23966EB6C2484D81B84A6644266324"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Briefing requirement</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Director of the Central Intelligence Agency, shall brief the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives on—</text><paragraph id="idC2C1EBB62B8A481585B909B1A2F37192"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the contents of the report required by subsection (a) not later than 15 days after the date on which the report is submitted under such subsection; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="idFABE5A7D600A49D1AB8980FE27B13B52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the contents of the report required by subsection (b) not later than 15 days after the date on which the report is submitted under such subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="ide8d1ca28-d401-468d-940c-2afdae9a5ca6"><enum>9.</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assessing Progress in Haiti Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/113/162">Public Law 113–162</external-xref>) is repealed. </text></section><section id="ide4c91287-178b-4d52-9ba2-210258b43cf6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>10.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on December 31, 2025.</text></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 

