<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H82988BBA17884115B5C28BB7140544A2"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8379 IH: Flying Mission Oversight and Transparency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8379</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220714">July 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require justification for transfer or elimination of flying missions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF4200B5B7D5B4D79866E3D9C27FE3E8D"><section id="H2DB18A769E514107A0E0F581F38C4D5C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flying Mission Oversight and Transparency Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEFB59CA16BB34692A87FC8E582BB3BEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Justification for transfer or elimination of flying missions</header><subsection id="HD38A46A18EBE49D5A01C5398E4B335A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to the relocation or elimination of any flying mission, either with respect to an active or reserve component of a covered Armed Force, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report describing the justification of the Secretary for the decision to relocate or eliminate such mission. Such report shall include each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HBA146F965D9C4BEFB8503A10F7E8BDDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of how the decision supports the national defense strategy, the national military strategy, the North American Aerospace Defense Command strategy, and other relevant strategies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5779EC3A4A84DD4BC5FB33ACDA8B084"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A specific analysis and metrics supporting such decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28D540AAEC654074A8AFBCDC1FB63A0D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis and metrics to show that the elimination or relocation of the flying mission would not negatively affect the homeland defense mission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D12C57C2C1E42C2B57F10B48C01FFCC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan for how the Department of Defense intends to fulfill or continue the mission requirements of the eliminated or relocated flying mission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFABE165A77F481C8455FCBC89201C97"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of the effect of the elimination or relocation on the national defense strategy, the national military strategy, the North American Aerospace Defense Command strategy, and the homeland defense mission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D7F07F971AC43A4AEEC33F5172C1610"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An analysis and metrics to show that the elimination or relocation of the flying mission and its secondary and tertiary impacts would not degrade capabilities and readiness of the Joint Force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20FAAFEA86B64BB3B27C8441DE3034D9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>An analysis and metrics to show that the elimination or relocation of the flying mission would not negatively affect the national military airspace system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H70D4B05CACE840DF85C13383BF071F02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered armed force</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered Armed Force</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H7498C1DC7D7D4AAB87289418A3CACD55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Army.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29A4BB7C7E6D4BFDA1A00DC24CF25439"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Navy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC19DB0E910B43568A6E9DA53AC8DD50"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Air Force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

