<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB99B942D4834417494A25BF3A861F68C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 6586 IH: Guaranteeing Enemy Nations Omit from Criminalizing, Impeding, or Detaining Exceptional Global Athletes Magnifying Exploitation during Sporting events Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001165">Mr. McCarthy</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001109">Ms. Cheney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000266">Mr. LaTurner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001135">Mrs. Steel</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the imposition of sanctions pursuant to the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act to certain members of the International Olympic Committee who are complicit in the perpetuation of human rights abuses in the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D861CA1EA5143B386C554D9629A6A2B" style="OLC"><section id="H47B249AA12B14085A0F5E05E09A77957" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Guaranteeing Enemy Nations Omit from Criminalizing, Impeding, or Detaining Exceptional Global Athletes Magnifying Exploitation during Sporting events Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GENOCIDE GAMES Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HC2CE7EE091F1456FB2A24522FD28CB3E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Global Magnitsky sanctions with respect to certain International Olympic Committee (IOC) officials who are complicit in the perpetuation of human rights abuses in the People’s Republic of China</header><subsection id="HA316FEAFF8BE453DBEC5E6EFB4D02FB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Determination required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, each time the President receives credible evidence that a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights has occurred against a 2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games participant, the President shall determine by a preponderance of evidence whether a foreign person described in subsection (b) materially supported such gross violation of internationally recognized human rights.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDFBB9952A3F54BEA817FE4000014162C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign persons described</header><text>A foreign person described in this subsection is a foreign person who is—</text><paragraph id="H714C257ABA9D4C99BEE06F03327381E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>President of the International Olympic Committee; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0052A16BA93848299D011A227FECCFDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other individual associated with the International Olympic Committee who the President determines has materially assisted a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79937EAE0E8B4C3B88640F7D2315362D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mandatory sanctions</header><text>The President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (f) with respect to each foreign person described in subsection (b) that the President determines materially supported a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB04D9B997E01459F8FD2C5661411F76B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, material support of a gross violation of internationally recognized human rights shall be construed to include false, reckless, or negligent assurances to 2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games participants regarding human rights assurances provided to the International Olympic Committee by the government of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, or any agent acting on their behalf or under their control.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAAE45CAFF87C4BA3AA80FB10E21CF8EC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header><text>Each time the President makes a determination pursuant to subsection (a), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of the foreign person concerned, the President’s determination, and the basis for such determination.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDCAC5EE39C434BD9AA3C3750F7663808"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="H16E41645ADC24A73A5331EFEFDC93D4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the sanctions described in section 1263(b) of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB143FBD1544017938B4CAE9EB5CAFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>The requirement to impose sanctions under this section shall not apply with respect to activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>), or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD614B4939FA4CB79A4D1087B4D94650"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the imposition of the sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEBD243D2059A40448430F1A15A5A3FB4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="H9C6C7C9CD0434CEEA306A8C0F944BDB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69D715F984D748BE85F8D17DFA5952AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to the importation of goods</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this Act shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H418359E192C6440F9E581FB7FB6AEAAE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply, or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment and excluding technical data.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A6CA24EA276411890255A6A2E6C1D2C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this section or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this section shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H91940778E26F4902AD2F52CF51EEDD24"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report on implementation</header><text>Not later than 15 days after imposing sanctions under subsection (a), the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding measures taken to implement this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7E88D2F2928B431A8244F20CB3EC9A78"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF255B2164A1449808A388C57243CCFE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H7619A3D50F154929AA7A6774AF832A35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B59C8B858004825BAF146C4E201CBA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF30A8BF1432143E4A52CDE38D4C18408"><enum>(2)</enum><header>2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games participant defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, a <quote>2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games participant</quote> is any United States or foreign person involved in the 2022 Olympic and Paralympic Winter Games, including athletes, spectators, government and private officials, members of the press, and persons involved in economic activity related to the Games.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H087FFA4A283E4D8C950AF48CE88E89C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0296A76D8B18401485E7A902B75B85EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB7D7F092D194493A9EC5937918117E86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1607959B054C4B81A336A61679D87CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6226910B37AC4E1ABB178563708B8EB6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on March 13, 2023.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

