<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7A9C665D99E49649393D7BAAF91F7B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6757 IH: Insulin Savings for Patients Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6757</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish under the Medicare prescription drug program a minimum amount of price concessions for insulin to be passed through to beneficiaries at the point-of-sale, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDED492460CE041859302ED403226E509" style="OLC"><section id="H776069F7B6264F71BCD115F72B3DB332" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Insulin Savings for Patients Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="HF03D65C89284429D9F1240060079F8F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Negotiated price concessions for insulin at point-of-sale under part D of Medicare program</header><subsection id="HEDA114794A7B43DDBE23B19E55DBC5EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–2(d)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H64BEB314E8AC4E4891AF2D5721B05C28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Under</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subparagraph (D), under</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12095B92F9B5404AA558F956056D923C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC89763E0FEB041D89488A7990FEC92AB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H05BB05D2F68F4374BDA7495684F804C8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Negotiated price concessions for insulin at point-of-sale</header><clause id="H6C8D330D9F444DD8A31697D20E72B9A7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For drugs dispensed in plan year 2022 or a subsequent plan year, the minimum percentage described in clause (ii) for such plan year of price concessions negotiated between manufacturers and a prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan (or any entity that provides pharmacy benefits management services under a contract with any such prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan) and taken into account under subparagraph (B) in determining negotiated prices for the plan year for covered part D drugs that are insulin provided under such a plan shall be provided to enrollees of such a plan at pharmacies or by mail order service at the point-of-sale of such drugs.</text></clause><clause id="HBF84C71D83F343159A7B15C55B3678E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount of price concession</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), and subject to clause (iii), the minimum percentage described in this clause is—</text><subclause id="H2FC3E544CC614B93A2DD90AB260D413B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for drugs dispensed in plan year 2022, 50 percent;</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF3DC85CABC143CE9A0DFE164B5AE9AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for drugs dispensed in plan year 2023, 75 percent; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H22E3840FE473411197C89B13F2F37CED"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for drugs dispensed in plan year 2024 or a subsequent plan year, 100 percent.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H93530E7328A345CC866E0F5D69C9141C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Modification of minimum percentage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2024, the Secretary may, through notice and comment rulemaking, specify a percentage other than the percentage described in clause (ii) for a plan year, except that in specifying such percentage the Secretary shall not specify a percentage that is less than 50 percent of the negotiated price concession for such plan year. Any percentage specified pursuant to the authority of the previous sentence for a plan year that would be less than the percentage otherwise described in clause (ii) for the plan year may only be applied if such reduction in percentage is justified as a benefit to individuals enrolled under this title.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA47B29D2B1014382BC18504EC04B1B8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of information in bid submission</header><text>Section 1860D–11(b)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-11">42 U.S.C. 1395w–11(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H67425FB3DC484D1B884685E87844526A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H778515B2C73B4B9D954673361EB74157"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H6C31B79393FF4CEBAD183593B748FAD9" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H131D3E92C7F84F84B10321B339426859"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Point-of-sale price concessions for insulin</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2022, an estimate of the aggregate price concessions for all insulin negotiated by the plan for such plan year.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F8031C3B2A941EFA4E1F2CFB3D7B515"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO study and report on insulin pricing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="HBBF9F88EE15148D18978221AA4A86CE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study on the effects of the implementation of the requirement described in subparagraph (D) of section 1860D–2(d)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(d)(1)</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), including an analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="HF3EEA784C40143ED8F052A814373A82C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trends in the list and net prices of insulin for qualified prescription drug coverage offered by a prescription drug plan under part D of the Social Security Act or an MA–PD plan under part C of such title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5C1BB4E5D3D4CFFA162397FB7D6B45A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>savings on insulin for individuals enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D of the Social Security Act or an MA–PD plan under part C of such title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55496059C89F46B0892EDA73679B28EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trends in out-of-pocket costs for individuals enrolled in such plans, as compared to individuals enrolled in a group health plan (as defined in section 2791(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-91">42 U.S.C. 300gg–91(a)</external-xref>), a State plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act, or a qualified health plan offered through an Exchange established under title I of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18001">42 U.S.C. 18001 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CFEBE4D9ECE4300AD80227A0410CB8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>approval and market entry of biosimilar insulin under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72531B92140D485DA1BF19B8C29D577E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means in the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Finance in the Senate, a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1), with recommendations on how to enhance the access of individuals enrolled in a prescription drug plan under part D of the Social Security Act or an MA–PD plan under part C of such title to lower out-of-pocket costs for insulin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D3772A599A49E2B340B6DFDDB8A2C6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transparency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–1(c)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-101">42 U.S.C. 1395w–101(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4DA82C0A2D174AD9A916DF3C66F346D8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HCDA8AB21E7B345C2B2D556B230D7CEF1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan year 2022 and each subsequent plan year, such information referred to in paragraph (2)(A) shall also include, for a plan year, information regarding the requirement described in subparagraph (D) of section 1860D–2(d)(1) with respect to insulin negotiated by the plan for such plan year.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

