<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43D854536E8F4B72A59F025D277002AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8496 IH: Fairness for Responsible Borrowers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8496</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220726">July 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the Attorney General from cancelling student loans except as specifically authorized by law.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCEBE2AB61051423F8868DB7425C7D7BE" style="OLC"><section id="H8CDD0A255C454598BBDF0434C9C40E0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fairness for Responsible Borrowers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4F8222A0C2E04D3EB9832E1E77D5E675"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H431099954EBB48D3B6A82B39914E536C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The executive branch does not have the statutory authority to cancel student loans on a large scale.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEAA5A05816D4A1692E3ABB81A1848E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Student loan forgiveness is unfair to those who have already paid off their loans and to those who did not attend college.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34D04A8B356B47E0A28D906A827D8A55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Student loan forgiveness is inherently regressive and would disproportionately benefit upper-class Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04C1B0E1800E437DB6278B8DC04932DC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An undergraduate degree is by no means the only option for a successful career path.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H004C7EB5677148ADB016A8EFA35692BC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Community and technical colleges are a fantastic way for students to learn a valuable skill set without taking on a large debt burden.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H752DAD169B6D49EABCAE5FAB0E704179"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on mass cancellation of student loans</header><subsection id="HCC3BCC6A4EBF48EA9ABFC1258247D4FE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H1AF110211F0546CB8FF1585C98CCF7CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Attorney General shall not take any action to cancel or forgive the outstanding balances, or portion of balances, of covered loans, except as provided in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BB5A6D5C65849A6B0851ADDB98A62DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The prohibition described in paragraph (1) shall not apply to targeted Federal student loan forgiveness, cancellation, or repayment programs carried out under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AD0CFD8F51D4D33B731C2B4D27196DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered loan</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H9255C814505A434E96938794E911FD1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B, D, or E of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>; 1087a et seq.; 1087aa et seq.) before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21683CDD83C94377BAB588973471EB2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a loan under the Health Education Assistance Loan Program under title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/292">42 U.S.C. 292 et seq.</external-xref>) made before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D1FD5ACBF87470AB0D2796BAE69B1E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary of Education, the Secretary of the Treasury, or the Attorney General may not implement, or publish in any form, any regulation, or take any action, that modifies, alters, amends, cancels, discharges, forgives, or defers the repayment of any student debt not expressly permitted within statute or regulation, regarding covered loans, except to the extent that such regulation or action reflects the clear and unequivocal intent of Congress in legislation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

