<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA20209D3429843C0B2121AD6A9517BB3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8065 IH: To authorize the development of a national strategy for the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, to authorize awards to support research on distributed ledger technologies and their applications, and to authorize an applied research project on distributed ledger technologies in commerce.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8065</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To authorize the development of a national strategy for the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, to authorize awards to support research on distributed ledger technologies and their applications, and to authorize an applied research project on distributed ledger technologies in commerce.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H3FFFCA60F10F47AA837226871E6A2E7D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H64D6718DB1244374B7207180705BE8F4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National R &amp; D Strategy for Distributed Ledger Technology Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE49E6B65B2C2412C9F2EA53FB412D4A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H551A41B652074889B589231B3CC3E527"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>Except as otherwise expressly provided, the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89F646CE0E874CCF9CE27C0A10E6080E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distributed ledger</header><text>The term <term>distributed ledger</term> means a ledger that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCE511107854D407EACD8238C8344C536"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is shared across a set of distributed nodes, which are devices or processes, that participate in a network and store a complete or partial replica of the ledger;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF07B3B127E9F46C09505E9C22F6770FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is synchronized between the nodes;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1224D06DCE564C8DB37EAEE00E38F385"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has data appended to it by following the ledger’s specified consensus mechanism;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H575D341425EF4E56963B75BAE44DDB4A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may be accessible to anyone (public) or restricted to a subset of participants (private); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EE06960308F4A8082DD0EAE5C64D8D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may require participants to have authorization to perform certain actions (permissioned) or require no authorization (permissionless).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BB7B5C5EC1B4AFC90ED2A3A5763541B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Distributed ledger technology</header><text>The term <term>distributed ledger technology</term> means technology that enables the operation and use of distributed ledgers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF36A688F6D54D7895BC6C24C4ECBE4D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>). </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1EDF308043564665914FE2F43915880E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD901821D05374CAF9DCEFE3830002B44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AA53B3354F24332932546996078DE06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1AED0CEF17D404CB6A458B225EEC9C0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Smart contract</header><text>The term <term>smart contract</term> means a computer program stored in a distributed ledger system that is executed when certain predefined conditions are satisfied and wherein the outcome of any execution of the program may be recorded on the distributed ledger. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H9D80C707476E41568E96E91907DEAA8D"><enum>3.</enum><header>National distributed ledger technology R&amp;D strategy</header> <subsection id="HABFB60773D024C23B6850D9CA6562B5B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director, or a designee of the Director, shall, in coordination with the National Science and Technology Council, and the heads of such other relevant Federal agencies and entities as the Director considers appropriate, which may include the National Academies, and in consultation with such nongovernmental entities as the Director considers appropriate, develop a national strategy for the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, including applications of public and permissionless distributed ledgers. In developing the national strategy, the Director shall consider the following: </text> 
<paragraph id="HFCC34315510D42D486951757C3CDBB45"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Current efforts and coordination by Federal agencies to invest in the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, including through programs like the Small Business Innovation Research program, the Small Business Technology Transfer program, and the National Science Foundation's Innovation Corps programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFE271726C094BD5ABB6ADF100D39FA7"><enum>(2)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6CC691D6DCC7470E889EFDBFE0A5A5BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The potential benefits and risks of applications of distributed ledger technologies across different industry sectors, including their potential to—</text> 
<clause indent="up1" id="HAFA14C8F2D5D46D69C28673AF31F7206"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lower transactions costs and facilitate new types of commercial transactions;</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="H1523CE4381DB49108CF58F2EEFAEB570"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect privacy and increase individuals’ data sovereignty;</text></clause> 
<clause indent="up1" id="H42A67947B3524B618331538B5C08D4F1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>reduce friction to the interoperability of digital systems;</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="H9910A27A231545F49FDDF401C79A8F11"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>increase the accessibility, auditability, security, efficiency, and transparency of digital services; </text></clause> 
<clause indent="up1" id="H37528C70EC334E2287189169A30C4D32"><enum>(v)</enum><text>increase market competition in the provision of digital services;</text></clause> <clause id="HFEBC71A4112E4ACD90D12E9D7DF64B99" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>enable dynamic contracting and contract execution through smart contracts;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7B2D933DC7484725ABD96A6284F63885" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>enable participants to collaborate in trustless and disintermediated environments;</text></clause> <clause id="H3E822B3FD0104E7BA50223F5C0EFB54B" indent="up1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>enable the operations and governance of distributed organizations; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HD784E4E7D6924AABB02E3EE428B301AF" indent="up1"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>create new ownership models for digital items; and</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="HD8CDDB73128140B4995515387357F77E"><enum>(x)</enum><text>increase participation of populations historically underrepresented in the technology, business, and financial sectors.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph indent="up1" id="HAC8591FF3F2545E584DF0A0F7AC91DA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In consideration of the potential risks of applications of distributed ledger technologies under subparagraph (A), the Director shall take into account, where applicable—</text> <clause id="HF700FD948ACD43709ADFA71A49155882"><enum>(i)</enum><text>additional risks that may emerge from distributed ledger technologies, as identified in reports submitted to the President pursuant to Executive Order 14067, that may be addressed by research and development; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H49A5DADBB2454F90B425E63C88C84206"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>software vulnerabilities in distributed ledger technologies and smart contracts;</text></clause> <clause id="H79EEC2271F364E7394B7F3D631B3CC31"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>limited consumer literacy on engaging with applications of distributed ledger technologies in a secure way;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE5145E1DF81493595C77919725CBC19"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the use of distributed ledger technologies in illicit finance and their use in combating illicit finance;</text></clause> <clause id="HF9F763470AA4465686F361D8513DD9A2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>manipulative, deceptive, and fraudulent practices that harm consumers engaging with applications of distributed ledger technologies;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9A38FEE4DA164D08B1982B6248B9C61F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the implications of different consensus mechanisms for digital ledgers and governance and accountability mechanisms for applications of distributed ledger technologies, which may include decentralized networks;</text></clause> <clause id="H5A43C723D3104C58B2E9F54174BC7551"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>foreign activities in the development and deployment of distributed ledger technologies and their associated tools and infrastructure; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H340644A32849437D935609ADDF201431"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>environmental, sustainability, and economic impacts of the computational resources required for distributed ledger technologies. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2ABB0277C6EC42D7964D1CCDDB268D7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Potential uses for distributed ledger technologies that could improve the operations and delivery of services by Federal agencies, taking into account the potential of digital ledger technologies to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE2CF0EFB52C849D189E4BCBEEEC40D8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the efficiency and effectiveness of privacy-preserving data sharing among Federal agencies and with State, local, territorial, and Tribal governments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA811D467C9054680B1811D6E98AE638F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote government transparency by improving data sharing with the public;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC7CEC9743354AB29346BA7A72A3C4E7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>introduce or mitigate risks that may threaten individuals’ rights or broad access to Federal services; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB857386112FB4487A9B035035ECC393E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>automate and modernize processes for assessing and ensuring regulatory compliance; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H691E2555217C4F71ACFB34A47782CA74"><enum>(E)</enum><text>facilitate broad access to financial services for underserved and underbanked populations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA648527A99C64CB0AD253B2652709B38"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Ways to support public and private sector dialogue on areas of research that could enhance the efficiency, scalability, interoperability, security, and privacy of applications using distributed ledger technologies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1E0E9890F7B5419E9B83A2DE6217E82D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The need for increased coordination of the public and private sectors on the development of voluntary standards in order to promote research and development, including standards regarding security, smart contracts, cryptographic protocols, virtual routing and forwarding, interoperability, zero-knowledge proofs, and privacy, for distributed ledger technologies and their applications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H39E0ABEE76EF41B0BDADBE5F6ACE7076"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Applications of distributed ledger technologies that could positively benefit society but that receive relatively little private sector investment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H42550B41FA51409395F475966A67D7E2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The United States position in global leadership and competitiveness across research, development, and deployment of distributed ledger technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2191C431513C44B69862944662CEED7B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header> <paragraph id="HA801625B82E04E9391E7796288E32725"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the Director's duties under this section, the Director shall consult with the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3762C3B599AD4DCDBEBD2EE17A0C10F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Private industry.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A7A2877BFC44683AA46C259E3F4AED4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Institutions of higher education, including minority-serving institutions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H93B0E988B59F49A4BEDF316AD46B7B43"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nonprofit organizations, including foundations dedicated to supporting distributed ledger technologies and their applications.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1C40027107CC43C5B0DB9C0046FB624E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>State governments.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3BC4233C2DF64C8BAAE6102F83941C6C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other persons as the Director considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFF085EF9E63B4F909B11150FD0FC733D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Director shall ensure consultations with the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H434F21227432469884CB713FEDBDE2AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Rural and urban stakeholders from across the Nation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF84684252DBC49D39362924BF87586DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Small, medium, and large businesses.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0E921BA6A921490E8FB42FDB3B398C2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subject matter experts representing multiple industrial sectors.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H584A43DDC8A649B59A924C1F72CAB9D0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A demographically diverse set of stakeholders. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H484460CBB1E843059CE9A03F66311801"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Director shall, for purposes of avoiding duplication of activities, consult, cooperate, and coordinate with the programs and policies of other relevant Federal agencies, including the interagency process outlined in section 3 of Executive Order 14067 (87 Fed. Reg. 14143; relating ensuring responsible development of digital assets).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB6578F77A2114C7589E4EF249E79C7AB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National strategy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the relevant congressional committees and the President a national strategy that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HEB49C56FC8764BE3A1759A984DF21D8B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Priorities for the research and development of distributed ledger technologies and their applications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C42BC72B7024DC587AB1F0D877F0F3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Plans to support public and private sector investment and partnerships in research and technology development for societally beneficial applications of distributed ledger technologies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6771BD2C51344D89D5287815C8AB90E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Plans to mitigate the risks of distributed ledger technologies and their applications.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06216E76F08C44D185849358AFCED2AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of additional resources, administrative action, or legislative action recommended to assist with the implementation of such strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBCD05716F0F34296AFF646430DEBD200"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Research and development funding</header><text>The Director shall, as the Director considers necessary, consult with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and with the heads of such other elements of the Executive Office of the President as the Director considers appropriate, to ensure that the recommendations and priorities with respect to research and development funding, as expressed in the national strategy developed under this section, are incorporated in the development of annual budget requests for Federal research agencies.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H7820BCD8154B4A869F173F0750BBE99A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Distributed ledger technology research</header> <subsection id="H261FB25E58D04F2FB9D1BA6082B88457"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall make awards, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education, including minority-serving institutions, or nonprofit organizations (or consortia of such institutions or organizations) to support research, including interdisciplinary research, on distributed ledger technologies, their applications, and other issues that impact or are caused by distributed ledger technologies, which may include research on— </text> 
<paragraph id="H964C73DE86F94C2B9327A1BA617E7FDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implications on trust, transparency, privacy, accessibility, accountability, and energy consumption of different consensus mechanisms and hardware choices, and approaches for addressing these implications;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE9851DF001A40538822C83DB216CBE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>approaches for improving the security, privacy, resiliency, interoperability, performance, and scalability of distributed ledger technologies and their applications, which may include decentralized networks;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5F46A8C4856F42F585813B09281CADBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>approaches for identifying and addressing vulnerabilities and improving the performance and expressive power of smart contracts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C91A70DBA7B47B3AD9185F0714671AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the implications of quantum computing on applications of distributed ledger technologies, including long-term protection of sensitive information (such as medical or digital property), and techniques to address them;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDBC9B95F08DA4150838B9DCA0A628DA8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>game theory, mechanism design, and economics underpinning and facilitating the operations and governance of decentralized networks enabled by distributed ledger technologies; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93ADF31E0EA3484AB5388743FE89AFC8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the social behaviors of participants in decentralized networks enabled by distributed ledger technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A8E7F1C34344D779655653A82359CBC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>human-centric design approaches to make distributed ledger technologies and their applications more usable and accessible; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H059124EE9FED49FD91B5F5C64082A10C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>use cases for distributed ledger technologies across various industry sectors and government, including applications pertaining to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC63CA6F1F76044BFB80201A49088658D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>digital identity, including trusted identity and identity management;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1350A0A6E1F047D798AA724721DE4235"><enum>(B)</enum><text>digital property rights;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFB40A1555C7496587EE2171D2A63C52"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delivery of public services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF135E5AF73C4B1392FDE7869804EA1E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supply chain transparency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61571F85FCF9426E811AD07719742E2D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>medical information management;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H05D7A72F1B7746B78196099401CBC80F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>inclusive financial services;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6C472FCBED6D483FBA29F05C203BAECE"><enum>(G)</enum><text>community governance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7FFF51F60744640BC7B1CD6540D46F7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>charitable giving;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H446CFBDC4D3747069329C778968567F1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>public goods funding;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5498B519985C4B93BFA37BBB8D2981C4"><enum>(J)</enum><text>digital credentials;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9FC1514CC99945CD84783B9CEE41FCAA"><enum>(K)</enum><text>regulatory compliance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF240E57619146C5BD5972152F9D7F40"><enum>(L)</enum><text>infrastructure resilience, including against natural disasters; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H23E0C43AB93844D6A9A606F8046BFD40"><enum>(M)</enum><text>peer-to-peer transactions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C83CBCCB78C4E8DA6E7A3F0DCAAC3C1"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the social, behavioral, and economic implications associated with the growth of applications of distributed ledger technologies, including decentralization in business, financial, and economic systems. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H33C2E8D6E0BA4C5998C14F09C4C3ED30"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Accelerating innovation</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall consider continuing to support startups that are in need of funding, would develop in and contribute to the economy of the United States, leverage distributed ledger technologies, have the potential to positively benefit society, and have the potential for commercial viability, through programs like the Small Business Innovation Research program, the Small Business Technology Transfer program, and, as appropriate, other programs that promote broad and diverse participation. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H7E80035B52664DAAA141ADD02F4B8BB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of national distributed ledger technology research and development strategy</header><text>In making awards under subsection (a), the Director of the National Science Foundation shall take into account the national strategy, as described in section 3(d).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA2464DBAB4164A0B98F9B27C4E095AC3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fundamental research</header><text>The Director of the National Science Foundation shall consider continuing to make awards supporting fundamental research in areas related to distributed ledger technologies and their applications, such as applied cryptography and distributed systems.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFDA975E78AA84F18ABBC84FEAD385F05"><enum>5.</enum><header>Distributed ledger technology applied research project</header> <subsection id="HE7AF2C917A7246C192675CA441DAF2C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applied research project</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology may carry out an applied research project to study and demonstrate the potential benefits and unique capabilities of distributed ledger technologies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE80D1ED83ADC4051BD1F0384EBE2BEC1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out the applied research project, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB57406F06103490AA335CF0C73504C16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify potential applications of distributed ledger technologies, including those that could benefit activities at the Department of Commerce or at other Federal agencies, considering applications that could—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H110D39C0590D4E859010ED26F4720E74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the privacy and interoperability of digital identity and access management solutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA5111DCA10544DE5B188AC7D0E27A30E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase the integrity and transparency of supply chains through the secure and limited sharing of relevant supplier information; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7849D5AA28F8440C881D594D91CDD5C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>facilitate increased interoperability across healthcare information systems and consumer control over the movement of their medical data; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF211D8F76784CF7918B8E00AD2A56FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitate broader participation in distributed ledger technologies of populations historically underrepresented in technology, business, and financial sectors; or </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H432E476089754040B166CE3262F3754A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>be of benefit to the public or private sectors, as determined by the Director in consultation with relevant stakeholders; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD6B939108F8247D7B0D7FD4F0DF390FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit and provide the opportunity for public comment relevant to potential projects;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H50DFD26B995A42CDB87C5E7381ED3974"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider, in the selection of a project, whether the project addresses a pressing need not already addressed by another organization or Federal agency; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6499932AA50A4DA69ACAD3DF281BE18E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish plans to mitigate potential risks, including those outlined in section 3(a)(2)(B), if applicable, of potential projects;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BB62EBC76C24F5991CDA660985FF4DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>produce an example solution leveraging distributed ledger technologies for 1 of the applications identified in paragraph (1); </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3413E2C7F5534FE2B115F6C4E608E64F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>hold a competitive process to select private sector partners, if they are engaged, to support the implementation of the example solution;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B8501A7467B4F1E94D38B3589FBA338"><enum>(7)</enum><text>consider hosting the project at the National Cybersecurity Center of Excellence; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6BF86CAF07A4F5DBA92397FA9BCFA27"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ensure that cybersecurity best practices consistent with the Cybersecurity Framework of the National Institute of Standards and Technology are demonstrated in the project.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBD15081A4B244F7FA53A0DFD5582524F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefings to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall offer a briefing to the relevant congressional committees on the progress and current findings from the project under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H55B9DAD3E97143E9BD1EC215E8860B77" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public report</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the completion of the project under this section, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall make public a report on the results and findings from the project. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


