<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E5E10E544704031AB6065BE66FCBD27" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7131 IH: Great Lakes Authority Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7131</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote economic growth and recovery throughout the Great Lakes region, to restore and to protect America’s principal source of fresh water, which holds twenty percent of the world’s freshwater, making it the largest system in the world, to foster innovation and to advance world-class workforce, education, training, and adjustment institutions for better jobs in the Great Lakes region, to strengthen and to expand the core U.S. manufacturing and industrial base, and the required energy systems to sustain and to power production, and to work with the Federal Government and provinces of Canada on our mutual Great Lakes challenges including the Great Lakes-St. Lawrence Seaway, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7EBBD8615B7A495DA7822BA0BE41284B" style="OLC"><section id="H663BA10B3F84484BB6ADCFBCC5A82F82" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Great Lakes Authority Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE4890590DA2F48F1AB91B9B7061DB82F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD672894E56684DD287EFC36C937BBA5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The 8 States that comprise the United States portion of the Great Lakes watershed contain the core of America’s commercial and industrial base.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30164BBC1ECA443C8A574CC0118A591E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of Homeland Security defines these industries as <quote>America’s Critical Manufacturing Sector</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81956DAFAD62410D830EBB94AEAC3412"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The total economy for the United States Great Lakes region generated $3.1 trillion in gross domestic product while employing 25.8 million people and supporting $1.3 trillion in wages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA591205608E04FB8BDC50CD82ED4593D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Maritime commerce supports more than 147,500 jobs in the 8 Great Lakes States and generates annual binational economic benefits of $35 billion in economic activity ($26 billion in the United States), $10.5 billion in personal income and local consumption expenditures in the United States), and $4.6 billion in Federal, State, and local tax revenue in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AC9565138324F619D8D26EFC63B524C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Great Lakes region’s 5 Great Lakes—Erie, Huron, Michigan, Ontario, and Superior—are the source of 21 percent of the world’s surface fresh water and 84 percent of North America’s fresh water, making it the largest freshwater system in the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BF5FBE5618C4A2880E6BF6A9F7B72D1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Since the early 1980s, the inequalities between the few and the many, the coasts and the interior, and the developed and underdeveloped regions of the United States have widened.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70889DD2E1B64EC7951C9A7C6932D58E"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has closed 91,000 factories and lost 5 million manufacturing jobs since NAFTA was enacted in 1993 and since China joined the World Trade Organization in 2000. The 8-State Great Lakes region lost 1.5 million of those jobs—that is, 30 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11F61B7FA08149019EA8C434002D4678"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The losses of factories and jobs, in turn, have greatly weakened the fiscal capacity of the Great Lakes region’s State and local governments. A measure of this fiscal crisis is found in the high municipal indebtedness of the region’s cities, as well as debt burdens due to Federal Government mandates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H926B123E0E10483F92239547CA923208"><enum>(9)</enum><text>When workers’ jobs are outsourced or eliminated by increased foreign competition, entire communities feel the impact. Communities throughout the Great Lakes, including communities of color, have struggled to rebuild the economic conditions that once supported thriving working and middle class lives for their residents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A29E8FBF54E4B5CBFFAB0D41D7179DF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The loss of factories and jobs has hollowed out entire communities, leading to the spread of blight, pollution and vacant and abandoned properties that destabilize rural, suburban and urban communities across the Great Lakes region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H160E300A90104C159FE558DC87825819"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Great Lakes States have not kept pace with innovation. Specifically, in 1990, 51,000 United States patents were issued and in 2020 the United States Patent and Trademark Office granted 188,000—an increase of 265 percent, but not a single State in the Great Lakes region reached the national average by 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE898EAF406F845B598E8E3C02B91AD44"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Great Lakes region faces numerous ecological threats, including invasive species, toxic algae, erosion, development, waste plastics, and toxic pollutants, among other sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H751560C332774339AE6C1D5BD3351623"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Heavy power demands across the region require a dependable baseload energy supply with a highly skilled workforce. Today, the region has 17 nuclear reactors at 15 sites in operation. Nuclear power provides 15 percent of the electricity for Ohio and Wisconsin, 23 percent for Minnesota, 29 percent for Michigan, 33 percent for New York, 41 percent for Pennsylvania, and 53 percent for Illinois; however, competitive pressures from massive, new natural gas supplies have created financial pressures that can make nuclear power less competitive and more expensive.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6558302F787463CBB94B7C2A096A84C"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Building back better in the Great Lakes region is a challenge that requires an empowered and well-financed Great Lakes Authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40421D01DB7E46C19BF8E5FA9E0376B4"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Great Lakes Authority can support sustained growth and innovation through public and private sector initiatives and collaboration with regional stakeholders.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H66904DE548EC4736BA474FC35278868D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Great Lakes Authority</header><subsection id="H3DB283082A8947C98341262BBDFEED90"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subtitle VI of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H11ED332A65F645229AD2D6DC0299B2C8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><chapter id="H54AE5E98C9144BE09D20A008DC08BB33"><enum>185</enum><header>Great Lakes Authority</header><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter I—General Provisions </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18501. Purpose. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18502. Definitions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter II—Organization and Administration </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18510. Establishment; members. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18511. Meetings; decisions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18512. Functions. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18513. Administrative powers and expenses. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18514. Information. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18515. Regional development plan. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter III—Financial Assistance </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18520. Authority to provide financial assistance. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18521. Revolving loan fund. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter IV—National Energy Recycling and Conservation Laboratory </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18530. National Energy Recycling and Conservation Laboratory. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="subchapter">Subchapter V—Authorization of Appropriations </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">18540. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc><subchapter id="HB128B713EB884F71BFE866425F52C93C"><enum>I</enum><header>General Provisions</header><section id="HF7E6FEF65DC84656A7569FC15B5E1F20"><enum>18501.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this chapter shall be to establish the Great Lakes Authority to—</text><paragraph id="HA8C12B82E60E48CB85F472C80F4F8E4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote economic development and job creation and to create world-class workforce education, training, and adjustment institutions to spur economic growth, especially in communities that have been disproportionately affected by the outsourcing of jobs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H594F0914B99041B78700F3BCCA3CDCA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restore and to protect the principal source of surface fresh water in North America;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H560ADF495E9649E9BCB154312CE97C6E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>foster innovation to strengthen and expand the core United States manufacturing and industrial base and promote cleaner and more sustainable power production;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0119CC4104024EF79D712B76F7841A37"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish and administer funding mechanisms to finance clean energy, green infrastructure, water infrastructure, wastewater infrastructure, and broadband infrastructure projects in the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ADB308FAEB045EF84EB1DE1DE8045BA" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>create a regional development plan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48A10872FED149A286AE10E3D8B7A0A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>promote affordable access to energy and broadband services in the Great Lakes region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68F015B41F94BAE8ED0D98FEC675FDE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to entities receiving financial assistance from the Great Lakes Authority.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H20D5AD0823ED4FC3B54A1604B16E5900"><enum>18502.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this chapter:</text><paragraph id="H020CA9B1D3AA4F7BABB8BA48A6E17910"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apprenticeship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>apprenticeship program</quote> means an apprenticeship program registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35EA02D473F94774AE16CA1DFDA8F774"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bond</header><text>The term <quote>bond</quote> means any bond issued in accordance with this chapter if—</text><subparagraph id="H474279C3DADC47A0B7A24E720D8EF717"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proceeds from the sale of the bond are to be used for expenditures incurred after the date of issuance with respect to any eligible project, subject to such rules as the Great Lakes Authority may provide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6662720ECD546B580628B0809C1BFC7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the bond is issued in registered form;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BFDAE904B314B5DBB97F4DA9C722944"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the bond has such terms and carries interest in such an amount as determined by the Authority; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7285C25270CB491E858BAB2CB70B7F50"><enum>(D)</enum><text>payments of interest and principal with respect to the bond is the obligation of the Authority and is backed by the full faith and credit of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HECA9A6A0743C419B8541E46E23749C2D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Broadband infrastructure project</header><subparagraph id="H143767A5CDD54C2EB2B1A612C871D09F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>broadband infrastructure project</quote> means any project for the planning, design, construction, maintenance, or enhancement of any cables, fiber optics, wiring, wireless facility (including any pole, tower, base station, or other structure, whether or not such structure has an existing antenna facility, that is used or to be used for the provision of wireless service), or other permanent infrastructure integral to the provision of advanced telecommunications capability (as such term is defined in section 706(d) of the Telecommunications Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1302">47 U.S.C. 1302(d)</external-xref>) and as specified by the Federal Communications Commission as part of the annual inquiry conducted under section 706(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1302">47 U.S.C. 1302(b)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B93B9996C9F4800B41B45763EB24A01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual inquiry</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>annual inquiry</quote> means the most recent inquiry that concluded before the date on which an eligible entity submits an application for assistance under this chapter for a broadband infrastructure project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H432970AFF7D547148408D81013BF5165"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Clean energy infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>clean energy infrastructure project</quote> means a project that demonstrates 1 or more of the following technologies: </text><subparagraph id="HC37208C0D4E94470A50764A3D36778CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Solar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB7C27A72534064A6A46CB4E12D2352"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Wind.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC74065EE9FB44936B434BC018729F075"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Geothermal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H004B5127C17547A981D9F5A864E43562"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Direct air capture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3389E27E4EB64C1C9FEDC07793450461"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Diverse clean hydrogen sources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BA432DCC5D843298E2DF58BE4038BBB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Clean, low-carbon fuels.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC7ACB99D405460EB1B07BCCFC9CAF59"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Hydropower.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D8CC65667634C448714C86660EA007C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Wave energy technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD1FC0B24C504D809A47B4A34D6825ED"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Fossil-fueled electricity generation with carbon capture, utilization, and sequestration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFB15163CAF443F3976976D8F9DC3A5E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Thermal energy capture systems or other regional energy infrastructure systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H580451FA0CCA4FC799E93F5AE5E373D6"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Energy storage, including pumped storage hydropower and compressed air storage.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H987D0B06312D460DBA79897B218B018A"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Advanced nuclear technologies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H237D83EE8D7646EA97A81327F1821F9E"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Biomass.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AA259E7A8C84A20B91C9CA4C5CAE55E"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Any technology that supports a technology described in subparagraphs (A) through (M), including micro-grid, electric grid infrastructure, or other regional infrastructure systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67818A568E704584802E47D3C77F7C5B"><enum>(O)</enum><text>Any other technology that is similar to, or a successor to, the technologies described in subparagraphs (A) through (N), as determined by the Authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE6C55FC1FB04DD1A871DCD67431D3BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4B683AF654074BD39F4AA3268241E766"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State or a political subdivision thereof;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34951ADA0D90415884873D2D556EDAA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a public agency or publicly chartered authority established by 1 or more States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1BFDC54A06E46178F0BB035C44409CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a special purpose district with a transportation, energy, environmental, or economic development function;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C2E8D83854432E81891824D834AB04"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>), without regard to capitalization), or a consortium of Indian Tribes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0EC694F538A4F84A8BD90BCF45DEADA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a multistate or multijurisdictional group of entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H708BCD0B85734005BD963E6373DF0C1F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H997A32785D7C476B9FF56F2C7722D9C7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a nonprofit entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29E0AC8CE8534304ABE146F69891954F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an entity described in subparagraphs (A) through (G) jointly with a private entity or group of private entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FDDF41C7C8B46AA8ADBFD01D9DA08C5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text>The term <quote>eligible project</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9EE76050934B4E038DE3C543E6A2DDA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a project carried out in the Great Lakes region that is a—</text><clause id="H883516D6CC8B49849B864635FC4DC6B1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wastewater infrastructure project;</text></clause><clause id="HBDC6DB01E6474387885A726B5A99FABB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clean energy infrastructure project;</text></clause><clause id="HF0401D43DB4242D88FA68FED29CAC45C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>port infrastructure project;</text></clause><clause id="HD4E22CB4DB094B59B4015337AA2699F7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>broadband infrastructure project;</text></clause><clause id="H32398B749D3D49C7A5DB9197DE2827BC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>green infrastructure project;</text></clause><clause id="H9CDDBC79490B4DBC8178E037B29F8CA0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>lead abatement project;</text></clause><clause id="HA904BC1828BA49AEA48AA72D19313109"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>water infrastructure project; or</text></clause><clause id="H3ED386F66D7E400DB7D11367DD799B54"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>weatherization project; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF9210ECF081425F8134260CF84B6279"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any of the following activities carried out in the Great Lakes region:</text><clause id="H3CA1B747450747C69F74FE793E8699DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The acquisition or development of land and improvements of such land for use for public works, public service, or development facilities.</text></clause><clause id="H6CEE8FADC5004F8A92F5F4E3E21DFCEF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The acquisition, construction, rehabilitation, alteration, expansion, or improvement of development facilities, including related machinery and equipment.</text></clause><clause id="H0897F7D8F210484B8D4BCC713BB20ACC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Preparation for events that may cause economic, social, health, or infrastructure failures or contribute to inequities in the Great Lakes region, including development of mechanisms to respond to such events.</text></clause><clause id="HF78403717D404201BC3284CD5A5537A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The development of, and reinvestment in, land banks in the Great Lakes region.</text></clause><clause id="HFC60AE14813F42CDA907BD121FF49CEB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The protection and restoration of the environmental resources of the Great Lakes region, including increasing the resilience of facilities in the Great Lakes region to protect against threats to such facilities such as harmful algal blooms, invasive species, rising water levels, pollution, and coastal erosion.</text></clause><clause id="id05FE2B5D9E0845989A7EAD8683C9EB7A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The development of plans to increase the adoption of emerging technologies in rail, maritime, and surface transportation systems (including medium and heavy duty clean fueling corridors) of the Great Lakes region, including multi-modal transportation and technologies that significantly reduce greenhouse gas emissions.</text></clause><clause id="H8E078D97C76A48FDA5833D4A351D1A76" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promotion of workforce education and training programs in the Great Lakes region that can support a project described in subparagraph (A), including programs that—</text><subclause id="H1E13AB24572F450D8699E449BCB653A4" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>promote access to—</text><item id="HDEE083F39F9643839F4E0F79A4ECEA37" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>apprenticeship programs across skilled trades leading to publicly certified integrated certificates; and</text></item><item id="H9317394F2CF545A9892823DA9061817A" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>community college credit, associate, bachelor, and advanced degrees; </text></item></subclause><subclause id="H870719FDBA9A4A618856D72CF7558574" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support a major, seamless, nationally relevant workforce training program for vehicle conversion, repair, and innovation for mechanics and engineers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H715211E195BA4EC2BE57266EC95AC3FD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>are funded by State boards and local boards.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE006C0D17BD4C4EA3237E2EBF7E931F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Great Lakes Authority; Authority</header><text>The terms <quote>Great Lakes Authority</quote> and <quote>Authority</quote> mean the Great Lakes Authority established under this chapter. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H139F0606B67741D19E4BF80E62E6078C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Great lakes region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Great Lakes region</quote> means areas in the watershed of the Great Lakes and the Great Lakes System (as such terms are defined in section 118(a)(3) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1268">33 U.S.C. 1268(a)(3)</external-xref>)), in each of the following States:</text><subparagraph id="H6BED5437C6A14BB09156AE4019FB38E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Illinois.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C67B065610E46ECB2A97440D88CAB89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Indiana.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23D5457136AE49EEBC5DA1D52B213E94"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Michigan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC19D37A291E041EA912D85969CDBCF15"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Minnesota.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6E0239E63F94BF2BAC5A0318563D8B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>New York.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED5E8A9AC24941E48B4AA6D5F29246C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Ohio.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA974D1FF20AE4DED90FA376FDDFC1077"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Pennsylvania.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51652B23BD5F4372B9AA06B96EF715BC"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Wisconsin.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF96264AB3EC4099B66DEE1DF5E7110C"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Green infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>green infrastructure project</quote> means any project for the planning, design, construction, maintenance, or enhancement of green infrastructure (as such term is defined in section 502 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1362">33 U.S.C. 1362</external-xref>)), including through the use of any technology that the Authority determines to be consistent with the purposes of this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF11D0B8B354807861E4FE6FB8DB6AE"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Land bank</header><text>The term <quote>land bank</quote> means a government entity, agency, or program, or a special purpose nonprofit entity formed by 1 or more units of government in accordance with a State or local land bank enabling law, that has been designated by 1 or more State or local governments to acquire, steward, dispose of, or repurpose vacant, abandoned, or other problem properties in accordance with locally determined priorities and goals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CE85F79EBD49A8A3002E5374B6894B"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Loan guarantee</header><text>The term <quote>loan guarantee</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 502 of the Federal Credit Reform Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77C8C17949544075943000F765C309B1"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Local board; State board</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>local board</quote> and <quote>State board</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDADBC2DB84D472AB1A1314D99E58F9A"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Local development district</header><text>The term <quote>local development district</quote> means any of the following entities for which the Governor of the State in which the entity is located, or the appropriate State officer, certifies to the Authority that the entity has a charter or authority that includes the economic development of counties or parts of counties or other political subdivisions within the Great Lakes region:</text><subparagraph id="HD5290C42F0754E6E8A052B406F5B156C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A nonprofit incorporated body organized or chartered under the law of the State in which such nonprofit incorporated body is located.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C32C09FD7BB47FB968456F8070EB23F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A nonprofit agency or instrumentality of a State or local government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99CD632F6D2849299D6F478C54D7F37D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A nonprofit agency or instrumentality created through an interstate compact.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E75B626B3494E8CAD830C14A7715874"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A nonprofit association or combination of entities described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1409709DB774BCF88641BA62D7DE448" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Port infrastructure project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>port infrastructure project</quote> means construction, reconstruction, environmental rehabilitation of a port facility, or the acquisition of land, property, or equipment—</text><subparagraph id="H66BB85F15E474E5B96D67FD20DED9C9B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is—</text><clause id="H7F8471138BF24D29933AFC642B503076" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>within the boundary of a port;</text></clause><clause id="H4DBCAD2FB2C54C4C8B5F2A4351EE5995" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>outside the boundary of a port, but directly related to port operations; or</text></clause><clause id="H9EB350324FEF4B109085A469E690A952" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an intermodal connection to a port; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B240163DA2D45AABA17EA02D78C547F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will be used to improve the safety, efficiency or reliability of the loading or unloading of goods or passengers at a port.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1BAD27BAF2A44128B72F2B5EFAD7654"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Resilience</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>resilience</quote> means, with respect to a facility, the ability to—</text><subparagraph id="H3CA968B4A7C5413EA92F10C335C4AE44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>anticipate, prepare for, or adapt to conditions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC15B29005DE141B7A7B91643B74FA7BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>withstand, respond to, or recover rapidly from disruptions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66C81198A7F34E9DB3E34BACB7A1313D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>resist hazards or withstand impacts from disruptions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9505CF1688984C839F8736C48E4613D7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reduce the magnitude, duration, or impact of a disruption; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H894B18955CE345B6AA8026C64BDF606A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>have the absorptive capacity, adaptive capacity, and recoverability to decrease vulnerability to a disruption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD493A001830B4CD885C5F8A05D823C39"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Severely and persistently distressed area</header><text>The term <quote>severely and persistently distressed area</quote> means an area—</text><subparagraph id="HACC69C4CD8624C5D907195A4FBF89073"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with a high proportion of residential and commercial properties that are vacant due to foreclosure, eviction, abandonment, or other causes; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81AA8670D12C414CB6163240BF7CBAB6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with racial disparities in homeownership rates; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82C02E3627964005A06B079A64870073"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with population loss; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E355E1B4F5B47CCB22758D1F4470534"><enum>(D)</enum><text>where economic inequities have grown substantially due to job dislocation and outsourcing; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C96F6156C8A4F3FA6D9CF03638D1EA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in the case of a census tract located within a metropolitan area, where the median family income for such census tract does not exceed 80 percent of the greater of statewide median family income or the metropolitan area median family income.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H918AFAE950BB4D228E79C87C55DE180D"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Water infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>water infrastructure project</quote> means a project or activity described in section 603(c) of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1383">33 U.S.C. 1383(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93DAB9FCBF6543499AA669F89E5B9BA1"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Wastewater infrastructure project</header><text>The term <quote>wastewater infrastructure project</quote> means a project for the planning, design, construction, maintenance, or enhancement of a treatment works (as such term is defined in section 212 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1292">33 U.S.C. 1292</external-xref>) to intercept, transport, control, treat, or reuse municipal combined sewer overflows, sanitary sewer overflows, or stormwater.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H148F2256EAAA4229B3C1DC6E7C73C9B0" commented="no"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Weatherization project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>weatherization project</quote> means a project that, through the use of weatherization materials (as such term is defined in section 412 of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6862">42 U.S.C. 6862</external-xref>)), weatherizes dwelling units that are energy inefficient. </text></paragraph></section></subchapter><subchapter id="H56397E65405A41ABB23AF97FFD97EEFF"><enum>II</enum><header>Organization and Administration</header><section id="H1E7C75944F6C43D58BEE6817B43A5637"><enum>18510.</enum><header>Establishment; members</header><subsection id="H6622B43D3A224B27B31384D876871F3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established the Great Lakes Authority to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1A9D9A5E924442DBAC63FB7B81F92B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><paragraph id="HD3A394E28E5D4FD1B62A5A88A611986D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority shall be composed of 9 individuals as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HE5FAEC49836C4B659A16251C09B1031C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 Chairperson, to be appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39AC615D5A894EB9B68471ADECD32387"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member from each State in the Great Lakes region, to be appointed by the Governor of each such State. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30CE11A3B86E47F49FE7C616EA29C636"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>To be eligible to be appointed as the Chairperson or a member of the Great Lakes Authority, an individual shall meet the following qualifications:</text><subparagraph id="H549A6270408B49E2989F2E2E9769F16D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The individual shall be a citizen of the United States and, in the case of a member appointed under paragraph (1)(B), a legal resident of the State for which such member is appointed to represent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F46C5903E5043DC9D3C31567FC9F3A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual shall have management expertise relative to a large for profit or nonprofit corporate, government, or academic institution in the field of study or industries related to—</text><clause id="H0BCBF27B6F8D48BE8E076246E900D155"><enum>(i)</enum><text>clean energy;</text></clause><clause id="H93CA1AD1F96A41CEB0B09F64D85B116D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>green infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="HD7EDCCB0FC7F4B5E9A0338BAFB4482EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>water infrastructure;</text></clause><clause id="HFA77ED5CEBCA4A08A9134A42C090E528"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>wastewater infrastructure; or </text></clause><clause id="H93DB8B4069D44B00902992FC8AFEB595"><enum>(v)</enum><text>broadband infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7B9A031B9E345BDB7A27A11B1088C15"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The individual may not be an employee of the Great Lakes Authority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H851B1C7390F84513988231F56E7A3196"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The individual shall affirm that such individual does not have any financial interest in the industries described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0DE139631C4B04AA93ADE0AED6F666"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The individual may not be employed by, hold any official relation to, or be financially interested in any company or other entity engaged in the manufacture, business, control, or sale of technologies related to the industries described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D3C0BEABBF54295A69429B1D7FB2FA7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The individual shall affirm support for the purposes of the Great Lakes Authority, including being a national leader in the industries described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H607DF7B0494A47C1A94CD196D00C46C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Party affiliation</header><text>Including the Chairperson, there may not be more than 5 members from the same political party.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC59A30B478C543308442EBAD678D94D5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><paragraph id="H5FA429542D864E3DAE084BE081C579F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial appointment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this chapter, the President shall appoint the Chairperson.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62EF822C016B444A86981BE18E3252FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairperson shall be responsible for the executive and administrative operation of the Great Lakes Authority, including chairing meetings and functions of the Great Lakes Authority, with respect to the supervision of personnel employed by, or assigned to, the Authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EA035D9E8F64C56AA6E9F3B5F088F17"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Vice chairperson</header><paragraph id="H8B140FB4B98E4651B293EC728214E319" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The members of the Authority shall select a Vice Chairperson from the State members described in subsection (b)(1)(B) by a majority vote.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C6FF52B49964202BC8FC21982E1A2A4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chairperson vacancy</header><text>The Vice Chairperson shall serve as acting Chairperson when the position of the Chairperson is vacant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H025ED8092CF84A1780C8567E3C22C474"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The Vice Chairperson selected under paragraph (1) may not be a resident of the same State as the Chairperson.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8124E2604CDB47B58A56E1569D82810E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The Vice Chairperson selected under paragraph (1) shall serve a term of not more than 2 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CFA0EF1D9F04DC79AF1EA4380CAB999"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Term and vacancies</header><paragraph id="H725408431BF84FE09903A1EF7B42B29A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each member of the Great Lakes Authority shall be appointed for a term of 5 years, except as provided in paragraph (2), and such term shall begin upon appointment of such member.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8931B5600644475852C8F9177278980"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><subparagraph id="HBB67BC14A21D4FC9B4605E2B23EF98CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any member appointed to fill a vacancy occurring before the expiration of the term for which the member’s predecessor was appointed shall be appointed only for the remainder of such term. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A7DB8BB1354024A569A89946C70BF1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member may serve after the expiration of such member’s term until a successor has taken office, and if the Chairperson has taken the oath of office, may not continue to serve after the expiration of the session of Congress that begins after the expiration of the fixed term of office of the successor. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25B571AC75D24CAE907D4E4166FEC7F9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of vacancy</header><text>No vacancy shall impair the right of the remaining members to exercise all the powers of the Great Lakes Authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H898EE48BDE0940ADBC466AE3EAD5BEBA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Members of the Authority may be removed by the President only for inefficiency, neglect of duty, or malfeasance in office.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD14AFE6FB45A40988D0E16D124BDD4C3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Authority shall begin operations upon the appointment of the Chairperson and at least 2 State members described in subsection (b)(1)(B). </text></subsection><subsection id="HA7371BADAEC745238C62C71E11A3FEBF"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Executive director</header><paragraph id="H08AAF77F5FAE438A9FF62CA53901B92E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Chairperson shall appoint an Executive Director of the Great Lakes Authority, who shall meet the qualifications described in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7527830ECCEC49D69D6544CB93B643ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Executive Director shall be responsible for—</text><subparagraph id="H50ECA6220CE24B4BA17896206ECE6E9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out the administrative duties of the Great Lakes Authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC0C84E0BEB740FAA9D83F67DCB7959B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directing the staff of the Authority; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA72C05F122D49E3AE2662760E61C6B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other duties as the members of the Authority may assign.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6B76315229408E992F7C639A9A9794"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tenure</header><text>The Executive Director shall serve at the pleasure of the Chairperson. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7D61761F3E445A988992F51487ACC98"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Personnel; compensation</header><paragraph id="HE8D7E7A75ECD482ABE47E4DCB3BBFF5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>The Chairperson and each State member of the Great Lakes Authority may select and supervise personnel as personal staff for such Chairperson or member.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3DF25925A55418790594A0A00B6945D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Great Lakes Authority may appoint and fix the compensation of the Executive Director and other personnel as necessary to enable the Authority to carry out its functions, except that the compensation shall not exceed the maximum rate of basic pay for the Senior Executive Service under section 5382 of title 5, including any applicable locality-based comparability payment that may be authorized under section 5304(h)(2)(C) of title 5.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H22C4919B9CBB4F569F98FDBB278A2B47"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Offices</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority—</text><paragraph id="H306B7F7B64B8456F888852AFFB962406" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall establish a permanent office and headquarters located in close proximity to the center of the Great Lakes region, near the mouth of the largest watershed of any of the rivers feeding the Great Lakes System;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0573EB69A4574FFEBEDD7BD92FD5F91A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may maintain an office in the District of Columbia; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H559AAE080DB24F88B8BA07368577E062"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may establish field offices at other locations throughout the Great Lakes region, as the Authority determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA066EFE7BD0C4F24ADB34B37C122EE1D"><enum>18511.</enum><header>Meetings; decisions</header><subsection id="HB053A56E8B4441AAA35626A19A6CED42"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="HD3D50A9ED4E54E9297C902B8569BF45F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Authority shall conduct an initial meeting not later than 30 days after the Authority begins operations under section 18510(g).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AC3EEA73AA5409A885695F492158A4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent meetings</header><text>The Authority shall conduct at least 1 meeting every 6 months, and may conduct meetings by electronic means as the Authority considers advisable, including meetings to decide matters requiring an affirmative vote.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37F19E857B6045E2BE93A0658565904F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Decisions</header><paragraph id="H2992410149324BCEB5F10DF38D639644"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements for approval</header><text>Policy decisions by the Great Lakes Authority require the affirmative, majority vote of the members of the Authority.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H556F4D92F704415D98FD1BA44A6DAF83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority, to the extent practicable, may consult with the Federal and State agencies having an interest in a particular matter, including transportation planning entities in the Great Lakes region.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H690D85866320491D9E21BB548D2150CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quorum</header><paragraph id="H7BFAC78988D841598654135C3171CBAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a quorum of at least 5 members of the Authority shall be required to be present for the Authority to make, modify, or revise any policy decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C4C7D6A3BDA41148BCE2E5FA309621F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of quorum requirement</header><text>The quorum requirement under paragraph (1) shall not apply until at least 5 members of the Authority have been appointed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1F751709B3645F1ABE407588E00B1CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Policy decision defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>policy decision</quote> means a decision regarding—</text><paragraph id="H09B9B7285CE44D7BB285005677533B6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the approval of an annual budget for the Authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14FA8BAEB0FB4682A5C75598A8541786"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the approval of the regional development plan established under section 18515;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF6D4F91301948109978C1FF2B32982E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any conflict of interest policy that is applicable to members of the Board and employees of the Authority and is submitted to Congress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF5A90EF5CA34306B285EC08B9149BC3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the approval of compensation for personnel of the Authority; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59D4C461164747A083A62504FC9B5186"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the creation of committees of members of the Authority.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H86AD4033D82B413A888DF79635330ECF"><enum>18512.</enum><header>Functions</header><subsection id="H44D851D7764A4BD3BFACEFA01C65FEED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Great Lakes Authority shall—</text><paragraph id="HE17662124CAF4FDF810A50FEA15F5AC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop, on a continuing basis, comprehensive and coordinated economic and workforce development programs through State boards and local boards and establish priorities under such programs, giving consideration to other Federal, State, Tribal, and local planning in the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCB220942F164E8597A73D25BB583A5A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>review and study, in cooperation with the appropriate agencies and economic and workforce development programs, including State boards and local boards, in the Great Lakes region and, when appropriate, recommend modifications or additions to such programs to increase the effectiveness of such programs in the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE92F32AF3C54DC2BD529B52A3C36DC3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek to coordinate the economic development activities of, and the use of economic development resources by, Federal agencies in the Great Lakes region, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB468A671303349029FD55FA7C8B04857"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2554386E11C048C5884F21592EA95BD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99F06C07328241DFA03BA8D978FB3566"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Transportation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29322B6DC3C648379AFE0257BFCA74DF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B0AFA5CDD60494188E4D1EE4B4BBAC2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H806C0F8911DC47439D821658DBF8A029"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CC4FD9CB1A248A98EE5FC16B981AC95"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F0C45CCCC5645B0BCE64709EDD8676D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Corps of Engineers; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB3C843822764AABA87E3C3D8FCA367B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Coast Guard;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6395753A99B147E0BCDD28B3AD1D6FC5"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the Department of Health and Human Services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D826D4EF754D099E777C3C39860EAC"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Federal Communications Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48AD4389776F41169845BB987AF0DFC8"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D01B13E5B754B78ACB2C1E98722E00A"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Department of Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B4AC16C89104797B6DD3EE9F0C2958F"><enum>(N)</enum><text>the Department of Labor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9C52316F37A4821922F189EBF55ACA9"><enum>(O)</enum><text>any other Federal agency the Authority determines appropriate;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ED0E3632E4F405194D3DE40FD8EAE71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote coordination with the Government of Canada, including its provinces and local governmental entities located near the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H664B0C8CA2BB4F22AFC62B134AE444CB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>formulate and recommend, where appropriate, interstate compacts and other forms of interstate cooperation to work with State and local agencies in developing appropriate model legislation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6196A1A787CB42F2B199CBC8157A0DA2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support Tribal and local governments in the Great Lakes region that have incurred significant municipal debt;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4CAECA231F244749C475F39225475F5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>encourage the formation and support of local development districts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0479A6EA41CB4A88B708F02DF3E01AEF"><enum>(8)</enum><text>conduct and sponsor investigations, research, and studies, including an inventory and analysis of the economic resources of the Great Lakes region, and, in cooperation with Federal, State, Tribal, and local agencies, sponsor demonstration projects designed to foster regional productivity and growth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0288879AAB2C402F8ACE937F373F92EA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>encourage private investment in industrial, commercial, and recreational projects in the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9238BE3AB5084A428F74ED16D17EA6A4"><enum>(10)</enum><text>encourage the use of eco-industrial development technologies and approaches;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84F96A07F65E4F59B113B6A6122AECF4"><enum>(11)</enum><text>support broadband access and adoption in the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H137A98B0B14746E882D5C454E53F7E2F" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>serve as a focal point and coordinating unit for programs and regional planning organizations in the Great Lakes region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H416196E7DEB146A0994E1CF9550F586F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>provide a forum for consideration of economic and environmental problems of the Great Lakes region and proposed solutions to such problems, including promoting conservation and establishing and using, as appropriate, special advisory councils and public conferences.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H619BC7CA3FD24984978A35AD0A2350AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Needs and goals of subregional areas</header><text>In carrying out its functions under this section, the Great Lakes Authority shall identify the characteristics of, and may distinguish between the economic needs and goals of, appropriate subregional areas in the Great Lakes region, including the respective watersheds of each of the Great Lakes.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4A79DC2AA944577A12A7152085A0A18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority may make recommendations to the President, Governors, and appropriate Tribal and local officials of States in the Great Lakes region with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H2E4A3B8A754140238BBA588985B1981B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the expenditure of amounts by Federal, State, and local agencies in the Great Lakes region in the fields of natural resources, agriculture, education, technology, advanced manufacturing, training, health and welfare, and other fields related to the purposes of this chapter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EC913E43BF54E458186675A7A33B49E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>additional Federal, State, and local legislation or administrative actions as the Great Lakes Authority considers necessary to further the purposes of this chapter.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C53E9C31A964ED59E86C8A3250BDE85"><enum>18513.</enum><header>Administrative powers and expenses</header><subsection id="H4B114AB28DE242B4BC73715A43B5C9C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out its duties under this subtitle, the Authority may—</text><paragraph id="HE2315AD6A2164C3E8A2549050C531C77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>adopt, amend, and repeal bylaws and regulations governing the conduct of its business and the performance of its functions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8567E2C1A6AB4FF19AFE3D9282CDE0CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>request the head of any Federal agency to detail to temporary duty with the Great Lakes Authority personnel within the administrative jurisdiction of the head of the agency that the Authority may need for carrying out its functions, each detail to be without loss of seniority, pay, or other employee status; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A675FFA8AE6425CA4AA6230410F4DB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>arrange for the services of personnel from any State or local government, subdivision or agency of a State or local government, or intergovernmental agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38813A1097394492965ABA541326A2F2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>make arrangements, including contracts, with any participating State government for inclusion in a suitable retirement and employee benefit system of Great Lakes Authority personnel who may not be eligible for, or continue in, another governmental retirement or employee benefit system; or otherwise provide for coverage of such personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H758F2226820644E98BA20AD99211EC30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or any property; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H650F9C8F8F224396B91239966B60242C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>enter into and perform contracts, leases (including the lease of office space for any term), cooperative agreements, or other transactions, necessary in carrying out its functions, on terms as it may consider appropriate, with any person, department, agency, or instrumentality of the Federal Government, or State or political subdivision, agency, or instrumentality of such State; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB88B8F829CBA44948680C0F122254767" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to entities receiving financing from the Great Lakes Authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H090A2FBB35AF4D42A15724D64D89E580"><enum>(8)</enum><text>serve as a liaison between Congress, the executive branch, and State and local governments, and to represent the interests of the Great Lakes Authority; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5972A1A3746A4A97B7A245ECBB190E0D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>take other actions and incur other expenses as may be necessary or appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8B870676BAD476D9446D01D19787830"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expenses</header><paragraph id="HF5A5310982CB47A9B7C75AB8B0C1A09B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chairperson staff expenses</header><text>The expenses of the Chairperson and the staff of the Chairperson of the Authority shall be paid solely by the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB9272E7BF8F42EFA5FE985BCAA99B0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><subparagraph id="H539D0AE5249B491895B6554ADE0E0465"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under paragraph (1), 50 percent of the administrative expenses of the Great Lakes Authority shall be paid by the States participating in the Great Lakes Authority.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1190AB37E4A4C91A1217A9B0A92EA08"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State shares</header><clause id="H48D47C61F78747F58C68AEC3280E83C3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The share of administrative expenses of the Great Lakes Authority to be paid by the States shall be divided equally among the States participating in the Great Lakes Authority.</text></clause><clause id="H5449061C69D742A4BBA8BF99074F6164"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Delinquent States</header><text>In the case of a State that is delinquent in paying the share of administrative expenses for such State under this paragraph—</text><subclause id="HBDE7ACFC3D974E20B97AF579AA865133"><enum>(I)</enum><text>no assistance under this chapter may be provided to the government of such State; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4084D616F0D34FCA91EF38B8D83CA1E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the member representing such State may not participate in the Great Lakes Authority or vote in any proposed action to be taken by the Authority.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF7EE2541B1BB4290A18804D1E55DDAE0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Assistance to eligible recipients located in delinquent State</header><text>An eligible entity located in, or carrying out an eligible project in, a State described in clause (ii), that is not the government of such State, or a political subdivision thereof, may receive financial assistance from the Great Lakes Authority.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA8FF9C55BA1648769C47DF81ABD0E99A"><enum>18514.</enum><header>Information</header><subsection id="H40CB7A7949FC4DFE9F246BFA9A3E2AB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To obtain information needed to carry out its duties, the Great Lakes Authority shall—</text><paragraph id="H89282B70508D41CE8ED046D076D0CCB9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hold hearings, sit and act at times and places, take testimony, receive evidence, and print or otherwise reproduce and distribute so much of its proceedings and reports on the proceedings as the Authority may deem advisable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA56D775E4E81449CBC47B7C7A2222814"><enum>(2)</enum><text>arrange for the head of any Federal, State, or local agency to furnish to the Great Lakes Authority information as may be available to, or procurable by, such agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E147C36D774DDDBC332FA73F06D9A0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>keep accurate and complete records of its doings and transactions which shall be made available for public inspection and audit and examination by the Comptroller General of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20B214C3292F4C429EC5DE9887D5B1A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorizations</header><paragraph id="H71BD82F5E1974A3EB7DDF6584CB7520E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administer oaths</header><text>The Chairperson of the Authority may administer oaths when the Authority decides that testimony shall be taken or evidence received under oath.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H563EEB75BE324B2987422FAF4FF460E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Furnish information</header><text>The head of any Federal, State, or local agency, to the extent not otherwise prohibited by law, may carry out subsection (a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE44F0D13647B4ECEBF16FC86467DD203"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public participation</header><paragraph id="H68CE35A17FF24CF6B2F7FDEAAE2530F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority shall provide for public participation in the development, revision, and implementation of all plans and programs under this chapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F7F6C57951C4F95A967D97EB64DC0AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority shall develop and publish regulations specifying minimum guidelines for public participation, including regular public hearings held throughout the Great Lakes region, which shall include Tribal communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0C16F2B5C84AB4BC7C68DFA499D109"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration of public participation</header><text>In establishing any plans or programs under this chapter, the Great Lakes Authority shall identify how public comments were considered in the development and implementation of such plans or programs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2A888EB079E44F00BBABB28326E27C6B"><enum>18515.</enum><header>Regional development plan</header><subsection id="HE9316AD490EF4ACDA1E5D1C0AA98DF30"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which the Great Lakes Authority begins operations under section 18510(g), the Authority shall develop a regional development plan (in this section referred to as the <quote>plan</quote>) that—</text><paragraph id="H6AFACD6D266C4702BA04C259D9314EB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies priorities, major development objectives, and strategic guidelines for eligible projects in the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3C07E3B53854A3C9ACF4E362DDDED33" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishes budgetary guidelines for the full life funding of such projects, including the planning, construction, repair, rehabilitation, and replacement of such projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80010563E322416AA2C3ADC02187BF46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies responsibilities between the Great Lakes Authority, the Federal Government, and State and local governments for the development of infrastructure in the Great Lakes region.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44498C56BC9643058DC38E928F89221E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission</header><paragraph id="HCAD50F0865904CE293BE9C58F5A2A81D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon developing the plan under subsection (a), the Authority shall submit the plan to the Committees on Appropriations and Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Appropriations and Environment and Public Works of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H149DE30F98E34C1AB0C572D287B6BE53"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biennial updates</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date on which the plan is submitted under paragraph (1), and every 2 years thereafter, the Authority shall review, update, and submit such plan to the committees described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFA5957522D114AB18E5FF3872D6061A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>In developing and updating the plan under this section, the Authority shall—</text><paragraph id="HF5F7A82D6C264AEE924FF62288645A5B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with—</text><subparagraph id="HB38F0EDBB80746FC91A919E53077D39F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8370858E05F045C78ACF5AD422B1C57C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chief of Engineers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F0EDED8590E45AA91F08BFD7D3621F2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretaries of Transportation and the Interior; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF3789A2C4C343F9B24CF33A639CC3DA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Governors of each of the States in the Great Lakes region; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B87F85152C541DF9DA41D7541B2FB81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>regional planning organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF163C35DA7234135A8B1B55404E87082"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other stakeholders that the Authority considers appropriate, including Tribes; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEB0D4A09E394CCA942305EE19159F97"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the Great Lakes coastal resiliency study carried out by the Secretary of the Army under section 729 of the Water Resources Development Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2267a">33 U.S.C. 2267a</external-xref>), as required by section 1219 of the America’s Water Infrastructure Act of 2018 (132 Stat. 3811).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><subchapter id="H66B0ABE2FB074930867CB5A559E4E2FB"><enum>III</enum><header>Financial Assistance</header><section id="HC84AE4FFACF34378B77F668B43855970"><enum>18520.</enum><header>Authority to provide financial assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out the purposes of this chapter, the Great Lakes Authority may—</text><paragraph id="H5D9AF52A45864EBAAD0EBFC1F936CEAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make loans on such terms as the Authority may determine to be appropriate to assist eligible entities in the financing, development, or operation of an eligible project; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EFA5CC60E7549949661C44AAD7754DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make loan guarantees on such terms as the Authority may determine to be appropriate to assist eligible entities in the financing or refinancing of an eligible project; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BEB1A38B7BB4212B76A50FF0745D4F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>issue bonds and provide financing to eligible entities to carry out eligible projects from amounts made available from the issuance of such bonds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4354293BD9F0403CAE2BD1BDAF28DE2F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>make grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts with eligible entities to carry out eligible projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3444786A94F446469CF00C0CFB1CB3AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to entities receiving financing from the Great Lakes Authority.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF6BAEBA7E6A14082BC090EFAC8C2DEE6"><enum>18521.</enum><header>Revolving loan fund</header><subsection id="H0707EA56A10144E58671F1B2EC493EEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a Great Lakes Fund (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fund</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H445044B2BA4042B7AD73BBE0641E72C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Source of amounts in fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available to the Great Lakes Authority to carry out this section shall be deposited in the Fund.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA319ABEB5C18456FACECAC4DEA67AB12"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of amounts in fund</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority shall use the Fund as a revolving fund to make grants and loans from the Fund, under terms and conditions the Great Lakes Authority may prescribe, to eligible entities to carry out eligible projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="H19B85574DD424D17B0A29E6D09FE68A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Unused amounts</header><paragraph id="H8D26E4ADEA534DB6BA49F5B7123F9A06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts in the Fund not needed for operation of the revolving fund established under this section may be invested in bonds or other obligations the Federal Government guarantees as to principal and interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFFBA415C49B4DFA83B39AAF0EF8F3AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>General expenses of administration of this section may be charged to the Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A6B88AC4A84437A8E370E530A6E2AF4" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In awarding funds under this section, the Great Lakes Authority shall consider the following with respect to a project proposed to be carried out with such funds:</text><paragraph id="HBCB1050F6C9E44FFA1289CFD93AEDC39" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The relationship of the project to overall regional development and poverty alleviation, including consideration of whether a project will be carried out in a severely and persistently distressed area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79A3EAC03DB43278499C317BA7101BC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The population and area to be served by the project, including the per capita market income and the unemployment rates in such area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DD40C249B1F450DBFCAD6D3E8C83ACB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The relative financial resources available to an eligible entity that seeks to undertake the project.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31CD58A9F19A4ADCA0647EE739D2D4E0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The relevance of the project in relation to other projects proposed to be carried out with a grant under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D0EEEFAF8CA4CCE83036B0637E08AB5" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of potential revenue the project may generate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B082A4E39D6478891F2B1E418E7260E" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The potential for the project to improve, on a continuing basis, opportunities for employment, including opportunities for individuals in populations with the highest unemployment rates, the average level of income, or the economic and social development of the area served by the project, including areas where the median income has decreased due to significant job losses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H201834C858ED46C98D2DFCD6102E17AA" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The extent to which the project design provides for detailed outcome measurements by which the project may be evaluated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24181319463543D0B819F9A6C7E0233D" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the project is identified as a priority in the regional development plan under section 18515.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCECE874C4058454BB633A875FD42549E"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the project is also funded by a regional commission established under this title or a Federal agency and the possibility of partnering and sharing costs with such commission or agency to carry out the project.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><subchapter id="H6B6F11927B8244EEB34CEC20B02415BC"><enum>IV</enum><header>National Energy Recycling and Conservation Laboratory</header><section id="H759E65E2DB8D426B8DAF1BF66C30853E"><enum>18530.</enum><header>National Energy Recycling and Conservation Laboratory</header><subsection id="HA39C7055E9A245C0B3D36BCE0459E8F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a National Energy Recycling and Conservation Laboratory (in this section referred to as the <quote>Laboratory</quote>) to perform—</text><paragraph id="H39BBD87F130F4B639AF448D11A7C6037"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advanced research projects related to energy recycling technologies, including hydrogen, thermal heat extraction, biomass and waste conversion, geothermal, water recycling, and methane capture; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F9AC752AE9147AD8939F3DC5869CB99"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any research, development, and related functions as the Great Lakes Authority may determine to be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of the Great Lakes Authority.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7DAA35C7EEB419E8C034E6DBD84C4F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partnerships; coordination</header><text>In carrying out the research, development, or other related functions under this section, the Laboratory may coordinate with the Department of Energy or enter into partnerships with any nuclear power plant in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDED55FF4682E4342AC8B9C2E3723F937"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The Great Lakes Authority shall select a location for the Laboratory that is—</text><paragraph id="H93C414BB2D7E4EE79B075838FE817596"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in close proximity to the center of the Great Lakes region, near the mouth of the largest watershed of any of the rivers feeding the Great Lakes region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD01B4B37733F452B92F40745F846D6B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in close proximity to a nuclear power plant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD93F408D1514A318464DC77BC37B078"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in an area with heavy industry and manufacturing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40C1464B85A24E769DC56305FCF5038C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in an area with a high proportion of residential and commercial properties that are vacant due to foreclosure, eviction, abandonment, or other causes; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H554F2A1C51534599AF31A680D8C62054"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in an area with racial disparities in homeownership rates;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8FD1B9A00284E39BE3954F798AC6F50"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in an area with population loss; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC28991BA48FA46999B00EAD30409654F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in an area where economic inequities have grown substantially due to job dislocation and outsourcing; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32B81C5B6D2C4C6CA4A64F6753B21B64" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in the case of a census tract located within a metropolitan area, where the median family income for such census tract does not exceed 80 percent of the greater of statewide median family income or the metropolitan area median family income. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></subchapter><subchapter id="H073E7FD3BC124FEE9A202E6B14360AA8"><enum>V</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><section id="H8C3C2210207B404EA4388D7FDB64B6D8"><enum>18540.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this chapter—</text><subsection id="H73462B6C3BE64C7F9BB1B6A396D07621"><enum>(a)</enum><text>$30,000,000 for fiscal year 2023; and</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BF9CF73F99D4CAD810C78054DE42D34"><enum>(b)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subsection></section></subchapter></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA10383CEFCC64E1CB24FF56824D28727"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for subtitle VI of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H095BA6A01CC64ACC8D0C43FF2BB27E0B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><multi-column-toc-entry level="section" bold="on"><toc-enum>185.</toc-enum><level-header level="section" bold="on">Great Lakes Authority</level-header><target>18501</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

