<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC31CB996DB254C24B5116175963A0A78" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9107 IH: States Helping Apprehend Rogue Exports Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9107</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 46, United States Code, to require a State to enter into a data sharing agreement with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Transportation in order to be eligible for the port security grant program and the port infrastructure development program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H904EDF075ABC4E7FAD2BD1DB0ECCE082" style="OLC"><section id="H8CE92BE4A37F40BE8D38C46990776224" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>States Helping Apprehend Rogue Exports Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H00487223357C4A8FBC813B45D96332F2"><enum>2.</enum><header>State department of motor vehicle data sharing agreements</header><subsection id="H8FD0E4C6ED1940BD90F169C62E987629"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Port infrastructure development program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 54301(a)(5) of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H4E0B823C06CF468A843695ECD495B102" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H4BB2DEF2C4C34EFAB48628917526383A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>State department of motor vehicle data sharing agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this subsection or subsection (b), the State or States with respect to which a grant is being provided shall have in effect a data sharing agreement that requires the State or States to provide, upon request of the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Transportation, identifying information regarding any motor vehicle registered in the State, including registration, title, and vehicle identification number. </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H83BDFC6DE1A64FDB9E7026D9943805BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Port security grant program</header><text>Section 70107(i) of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H882F90635A0F4896AFDE285A6861E933" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HBC67522697AD4E9BB3F7F49C8249949C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State department of motor vehicle data sharing agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section, the State in which the entity subject to an Area Maritime Transportation Security Plan is located shall have in effect a data sharing agreement that requires the State to provide, upon request of the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Transportation, identifying information regarding any motor vehicle registered in the State, including registration, title, and vehicle identification number. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6AF87570C7E749429BF8A9E43AF27929"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Airport improvement program</header><text>Section 47106(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1AC576885A6B46B5A64A4C4177B15AF3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)(E) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1CB84952FF64951A448E7ACB00A034F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(D) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17C07B9B212049F5BB4A66403C768D2B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H0E5D52DAF93E42BBB0A75F2407C9A183" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H9CCBD3DA7AE84D1E8B834AA3779DD073"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State in which the project is located has in effect a data sharing agreement with the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Transportation that requires the State to provide, upon request of either such Secretary, identifying information regarding any motor vehicle registered in the State, including registration, title, and vehicle identification number.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

