<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6E2F7009285E4430870A279383B08AF5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6397 IH: Medical Student Education Authorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6397</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220113">January 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a grant program to award grants to public institutions of higher education located in a covered State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF0BEF70033704104A3C80B81826423A2" style="OLC"><section id="H26CDADE002BD46A3B0C7C0B7D3E325F3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Student Education Authorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H12F5ECD995E545A2BA9E11C5C7910F39"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD04A4FC3203740B38E290DAD75B024F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Access to high quality primary care is associated with improved health outcomes and lower health care costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D988B942224DCEBE42C5C75872512A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Substantial disparities exist in the distribution of primary care providers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H184BE7E5C2FF437AA8238350229DAACC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Shortages of health care providers affect Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities more than the populations of more densely populated areas, resulting in such communities experiencing significant health challenges and disparities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF587349B72DF40DEAF015619CC52322B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>American Indian, Alaskan Natives, and Native Hawaiians tend to have lower health status, lower life expectancy, and disproportionate disease burden when compared to other Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H642949F65180437697D60DE6ED78E2FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Having training experiences in, living among, and being a member of Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities increases cultural awareness and can influence career choice for physicians to better serve such populations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BB2E1CE16154742AA2CA4CFC7AED535"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Research shows there is a relationship between the characteristics of a physician and the eventual practice location, including being part of an underrepresented minority or growing up in a rural area.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5F100F1D31CD4932AC927BFC36662852"><enum>3.</enum><header>Education program to support primary health service for underserved populations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293">42 U.S.C. 293 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA06B9E10560C456C9F02F66BD2C53788" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H7535486A35864115AD3C0F861D0025A6"><enum>742.</enum><header>Education program to support primary health service for underserved populations</header><subsection id="HD15FD731DD8E459392580B9DC719E568"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall establish a grant program to award grants to public institutions of higher education located in a covered State to carry out the activities described in subsection (d) for the purposes of—</text><paragraph id="HF92A8600BFB5492EA21ED27302916609"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expanding and supporting education for medical students who are preparing to become physicians in a covered State; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E85103D493427982EE72C352C28CFC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preparing and encouraging each such student training in a covered State to serve Tribal, rural, or medically underserved communities as a primary care physician after completing such training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B90F7D52C864F78BF1C148400721FBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to be eligible to receive a grant under this section, a public institution of higher education shall submit an application to the Secretary that includes—</text><paragraph id="H0E649E27F2F0467E835C9F228D46BE91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a certification that such institution will use amounts provided to the institution to carry out the activities described in subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2901E66E6CC44468F7819A0D4FF8031"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how such institution will carry out such activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CF827BFF9A64DF3BF4A274A5C506FB5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to public institutions of higher education that—</text><paragraph id="H826C5C4121AB4378B7CD5A74791128E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are located in a State with not fewer than 2 federally recognized Tribes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C215750A9E436F9FF016F146831A1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrate a public-private partnership.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F0FB344F67B490EA8F82CDF563CCD72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the funds made available under such grant to carry out the following activities:</text><paragraph id="H5A82F25888FC4AECAC03A62D190D1040"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support or expand community-based experiential training for medical students who will practice in or serve Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H863E538948534814B8314E69AC19575A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop and operate programs to train medical students in primary care services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC39FBBA486B44FA090C719EBF857CBA7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Develop and implement curricula that—</text><subparagraph id="HD9E02327A85A4C3A94572E0B62655B5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes a defined set of clinical and community-based training activities that emphasize care for Tribal, rural, or medically underserved communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AB808B0782A45B4B3287833F287E1DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is applicable to primary care practice with respect to individuals from Tribal, rural, or medically underserved communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FCA022273534FA4BEF6828EA5BAE6D5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies and addresses challenges to health equity, including the needs of Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20E9A449F1AA44FBA772524EEA269C1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>supports the use of telehealth technologies and practices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C2039727F66469DBBF3164523190E61"><enum>(E)</enum><text>considers social determinants of health in care plan development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6F99F0795F74F6BA65597F3A73987B6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(F)</enum><text>integrates behavioral health care into primary care practice, including prevention and treatment of opioid disorders and other substance use disorders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H588EA2F9EEDE4B37AE65672868AA7175" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(G)</enum><text>promotes interprofessional training that supports a patient-centered model of care; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H173D060B16A6484A81B0AC5BA8962CC3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(H)</enum><text>builds cultural and linguistic competency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6606D373DE124E2282D75B6CF8BD822C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Increase the capacity of faculty to implement the curricula described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE045F02EE777419FB572D96A5A54734F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Develop or expand strategic partnerships to improve health outcomes for individuals from Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities, including with—</text><subparagraph id="H3B12673FB47745338CC5BFF3887B59ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>federally recognized Tribes, Tribal colleges, and Tribal organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H900BA2D2FBCC44578B58EEE36EA853C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federally-qualified health centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4D24ED2E2E448F4A032C3FF2E63AE4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>rural health clinics;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82DDCC2733BD40B3B03920F795C0E0A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Indian health programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B5BABF5A7A5438CBB57A31CEDC325F4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>primary care delivery sites and systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8C42558508D4293A04F00C4891CC13B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other community-based organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DCAE8BB5A684582BFDD99E16F727E27"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop a plan to track graduates’ chosen specialties for residency and the States in which such residency programs are located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F701C410CB44578503A45B771D1715"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Develop, implement, and evaluate methods to improve recruitment and retention of medical students from Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D5CFAD5DB904D399FAED6316B97EC6C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Train and support instructors to serve Tribal, rural, and medically underserved communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B6973D63AC44DF9AD62B6A43A10766"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prepare medical students for transition into primary care residency training and future practice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H741EE0DE88B24D84B5D22A2E17698781"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide scholarships to medical students.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AA8D34FB2614E2E92D00EB1893B2707"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6DEF4E5C0454685A4DE0518B552E406"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each fiscal year, the amount of a grant made to a public institution of higher education under this section shall be not less than $1,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F80CB872C1C424A85205445B31D314C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public institution of higher education that receives a grant under this section shall provide, from non-Federal sources, an amount equal to or greater than 10 percent of the total amount of Federal funds provided to the institution each fiscal year during the period of the grant (which may be provided in cash or in kind).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7604B45BC1EB42B1B979C2FE776C5338"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H109D8B52B7D14F5BA826785D1C2288ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered State</term> means a State that is in the top quartile of States by projected unmet demand for primary care providers, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H518C122B46EE4AE0A25352AB0D4EB3F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federally-qualified health center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federally-qualified health center</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1905(l)(2)(B) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H762C936CBD9A42F9ABB33622FEC01504"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Indian health program</header><text>The term <term>Indian health program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7CABA0A7D4D4C34867C8F7FBD305C68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965, provided that such institution is public in nature.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C99F510C5E34C90BE70E5B995860949"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Medically underserved community</header><text>The term <term>medically underserved community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 799B.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98B1AF20620547EE8522CD9FA575DF55"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rural health clinic</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rural health clinic</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D338BB1D2FF45B28037B2A1EB6BA2F8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rural population</header><text>The term <term>rural population</term> means the population of a geographical area located—</text><subparagraph id="H194A80C32F134DF2AB08213A0041A43C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a non-metropolitan county; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F0C12C2C45B4AB499804B661A49AB0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a metropolitan county designated as rural by the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBFEF1089E8B47DE8D9311714DE2CD29"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal population</header><text>The term <term>Tribal population</term> means the population of any Indian Tribe recognized by the Secretary of the Interior pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA829F83283F94F999C15D457FD61227D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $150,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

