<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA36498112F0A45E0AE7CE32247C4F920" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 7472 IH: Discounted Drugs for Clinical Trials Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7472</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to grant eligible researchers access to eligible products at a discounted price for qualified research, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4C2BF07EE0D74E1D9149F6E92A271BD6" style="OLC"><section id="H40F2706E59804FB1955E2467F200BFCB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Discounted Drugs for Clinical Trials Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H66E13914CEDE43818EAAF9E28E1E2AD7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Discounted sales of eligible products for qualified research purposes</header><subsection id="H5E3BFAE5A1234C9A8F484AEE86814923"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/351">21 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 505–2 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-1">21 U.S.C. 355–1</external-xref>) the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H069F137709FB432895468B894D183E20"><section id="HCB7DE22C8E3E4B6FA1FBDD67A0845142"><enum>505–3.</enum><header>Discounted sales of eligible products for qualified research purposes</header><subsection id="HDAF6443B029B4B569322951AC7154B17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application by researcher</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To obtain an eligible product for qualified research at the discounted price, an individual or entity shall submit to the Secretary an application certifying and demonstrating that—</text><paragraph id="HB3A8D7AB491748319AD5A2840DFEB341"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the individual or entity is an eligible researcher;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB8ECF3F0494043AAAD898C584B3F4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the product being sought is an eligible product;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38ECEE34D090426D9341AB3D849BA241"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the researcher seeks to use the eligible product for qualified research; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72E3EA8AEF7C4DD39E3062263B97FFDA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the amount of the eligible product sought is reasonable for completing the qualified research.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4A7CB5D8E344A4C8CD478BE59B85FAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H098C0FFEDFAD460DB038FF4A49717638"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review each application submitted under paragraph (1) in a timely manner;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BE8C867F9BE4B17A688F82312F524D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide to the applicant, within a reasonable time of such submission—</text><subparagraph id="H31B9D22C7FD349F0BB364EA88F3C254B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a written order specifying the sufficient quantity of the eligible product approved to be purchased by the eligible researcher at the discounted price; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5DC6E0C5CE6476DA8333E4AE41549D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a written denial of the application;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B3CB36783854AC9A526AD3C73F05C60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require manufacturers and license holders to report to the Secretary any additional information determined by the Secretary to be necessary to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84EF1DCFC3C8424DA8F94D5A0ED368CA"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">annually publish information on the number and types of applications granted and denied under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB03491CC800046DB88A348085E8D4510"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Acquisition of discounted drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt from an eligible researcher of an order obtained under subsection (b)(2)(A) for the acquisition of an eligible product for qualified research, the manufacturer or license holder of the eligible product shall sell to the eligible researcher the quantity specified in the order at the discounted price.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF44A53B53179402F8DF2F1512BB8F937"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Civil action for failure To provide sufficient quantity of an eligible product</header><paragraph id="HB2944298BC9141ACA2DAFA11EF73A9F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible researcher may bring a civil action against the manufacturer or license holder of an eligible product seeking relief under this subsection in an appropriate district court of the United States alleging that the manufacturer or license holder has declined to provide the quantity of the eligible product specified in a written order from the Secretary to the eligible researcher for the discounted price.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BC3FFB428DE4D82A3B7F0C986D41FE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>To prevail in a civil action brought under paragraph (1), an eligible researcher shall prove, by a preponderance of the evidence, that—</text><subparagraph id="HD82C83FBE4364E44B6C0FF84DFA6EFC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the eligible researcher has—</text><clause id="H032464C2D47E435A8D39B39B7C1389D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text> obtained a written order for the specified quantity of the eligible product from the Secretary in accordance with subsection (b)(2)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="H556FBCD3A1CD446490E740EF29E47F7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provided a copy of the order to the manufacturer or license holder; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC84FEE34EE9E4F88B0BD34FFB089165C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the date on which the civil action is filed, the eligible researcher has not obtained the specified quantity of the eligible product at the discounted price by 31 days after the date on which the manufacturer or license holder received the eligible researcher’s request for the eligible product, including a copy of the written order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D2F291757C3487BAA530A6A8C5A4863"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text>In a civil action brought under paragraph (1), it shall be an affirmative defense, on which the defendant has the burden of persuasion by a preponderance of the evidence—</text><subparagraph id="H172CC81121A34C1680F8F09EFB00BE18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that, on the date on which the eligible researcher requested to purchase the specified quantity of the eligible product from the manufacturer or license holder—</text><clause id="H5678687F2CFE48D6B3054A2956225F41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>neither the manufacturer, license holder, nor any of their agents, wholesalers, or distributors, was engaged in the manufacturing or commercial marketing of the eligible product; and</text></clause><clause id="H17940748C69148A8809A69120A117B73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>neither the manufacturer, license holder, nor any of their agents, wholesalers, or distributors, otherwise had access to inventory of the eligible product to supply the specified quantity to the eligible researcher at the discounted price;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11587228E33A4FEBA89E7EF5EBCF6EBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="H1E68626846264338B6EE35FA123F3D87"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the manufacturer or license holder sells the eligible product through agents, distributors, or wholesalers;</text></clause><clause id="H1CBE5C0D6D8442A19DD524A2650DA87B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the manufacturer has placed no restrictions, explicit or implicit, on its agents, distributors, or wholesalers on selling the eligible product to eligible researchers; and</text></clause><clause id="HE7D7A4FB5D404E5FB1C2BE33B855A57D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the eligible product can be purchased by the eligible researcher in the specified quantity at the discounted price or a lower price from the agents, distributors, or wholesalers of the manufacturer or license holder; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H894D5B84316B4E579E50708D396B298E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that the manufacturer or license holder made an offer to sell the specified quantity of the eligible product to the eligible researcher for the discounted price and the eligible researcher did not accept such offer by the date that is 14 days after the date on which the eligible product researcher received such offer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCA8D38074284CB0A47DADA2A0680AB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Methods for transmission of requests for eligible products</header><text>A written request for an eligible product, offer to sell an eligible product, or acceptance of such an offer between the eligible researcher and the manufacturer or license holder of the eligible product shall be made by—</text><subparagraph id="H6E6BAE9A208E4AB88028FA5280F88D7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>certified or registered mail with return receipt requested;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD00F4061F6043F88A5C13605687FB5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>personal delivery; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12CBD028CCCA42689DE7D8C9AA249FEB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>electronic means.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66109276F90348EFACE349E0C8A82D52"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Remedies</header><text>If an eligible researcher prevails in a civil action brought under paragraph (1), the court shall—</text><subparagraph id="HCF78DBBD2F5B4BBDB9C7A66F4EC17254"><enum>(A)</enum><text>order the manufacturer or license holder to provide to the eligible researcher without delay the specified quantity of the eligible product at the discounted price;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9D4BA7D71424B1D8512AA62115B65D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>award to the eligible researcher reasonable attorney’s fees and costs of the civil action; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5EB1790E2EC485DA0EAFEF947CCF9C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>award to the eligible researcher a monetary amount sufficient to deter the manufacturer or license holder from failing to provide eligible researchers with a sufficient quantity of an eligible product at the discounted price, if the court finds, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the manufacturer or license holder, without a legitimate business justification—</text><clause id="H55C21082926E4F909BD827E710CF3548"><enum>(i)</enum><text>delayed providing the specified quantity to the eligible researcher; or</text></clause><clause id="H9CA3C58764284B76B488DF6F9127FCC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>failed to comply with a written order under subsection (b)(2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC43892CD85BA4695A0B9B09C3238422E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Maximum monetary amount</header><text>A monetary amount awarded under paragraph (5) shall not be greater than the revenue that the manufacturer or license holder earned on the eligible product beginning on the date that is 31 days after the date on which the manufacturer or license holder received the request and ending on the date on which the eligible researcher received the specified quantity of the eligible product.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H634FBA73A4BC467AA5C797C402AA707C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Avoidance of delay</header><text>The court may issue an order under paragraph (5)(A) before conducting further proceedings that may be necessary to determine—</text><subparagraph id="H0E2758EF388E49018E336CED7697D5AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the eligible researcher is entitled to an award under subparagraph (B) or (C) of paragraph (5); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71CF6BCE6553400BA9253C348EA32FEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of any such award.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28FAD8F9A8544795922CC2AE9184776B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer or license holder of an eligible product obtained by an eligible researcher pursuant to this section shall not be liable for any claim under Federal, State, or local law arising out of the failure of the eligible researcher to follow adequate safeguards to assure safe use of the eligible product, including with respect to transportation, handling, use, or disposal.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0FD09656BA4F49819DB997ACD2CC0354"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section shall not be construed to—</text><paragraph id="HDF103A71955B48B59A24D5CC0E4DE3B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>undermine or abrogate any requirement imposed pursuant to a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy under section 505–1; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB8C7D2248124E118E1EFB795E62A36A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>interfere with the private right of action afforded under section 610 of division N of the Further Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355-2">21 U.S.C. 355–2</external-xref> note; commonly referred to as the <quote>CREATES Act</quote>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FD42CAB4E4B41B3B71A83AA64914364"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD1E6470B9E76493A97294F44CFC56066"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text>The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Commissioner of Food and Drugs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BBD95C0CDF64A209D7596EE3FA0DED0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Combination product</header><text>The term <term>combination product</term> means a combination product described in section 503(g).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD26DB1E3778543E0978FBADBFCF32759"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Discounted price</header><text>The term <term>discounted price</term> means the direct costs to the manufacturer or license holder of producing the eligible product.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0223B3C646A74DD3966BDA1733C53EF1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible product</header><text>The term <term>eligible product</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA0FE13689CFC4979A88FCB153E30FDAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any—</text><clause id="H2944C9FF25FD42F1947BC029251F25C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>drug approved under section 505(c) of this Act or biological product licensed under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act;</text></clause><clause id="H78732BD900C843C4896CB11A327CEDAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>combination product including such a drug or biological product; or</text></clause><clause id="H2987C76F7AB84FCC95306D3E976D5C37"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>product, including any device, that is marketed or intended for use with such a drug or biological product; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3940ABA616CB48A187D934C51AEE399B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any product that is—</text><clause id="HEA04E11F8E7247B49F9F6A2A209A3562"><enum>(i)</enum><text> a covered part D drug (as defined in section 1860D–2(e) of the Social Security Act) eligible for placement on, with respect to a plan year, a specialty tier (as defined in section 423.560 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations) of a formulary for such plan year of a prescription drug plan under part D of title XVIII of such Act or an MA–PD plan under part C of such title; or</text></clause><clause id="H69ED872215764B748A62793E22CA9D6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a drug (including any biological product), or combination product, whose cost is determined by the Commissioner to be prohibitive to the advancement of qualified research.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44AAAF8224484AF8911AFB1E3F8DA67A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible researcher</header><text>The term <term>eligible researcher</term> means any individual or entity seeking to obtain an eligible product for qualified research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF354AFE73E645E2B97A9498ED6D1FAE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>License holder</header><text>The term <term>license holder</term> means the holder of an application approved under section subsection (c) or (j) of section 505 of this Act, or a license under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act, for an eligible product.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A1C7552617D4E939D8A54BA51F6026F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified research</header><text>The term <term>qualified research</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H16E56F3E6E9D45B6BAB76282C16E9825"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research in furtherance of an application under section 505(b) or (j) of this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B6829A08A5148809C891A91C5850AC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>research in furtherance of an application for a license under section 351(a) or (k) of the Public Health Service Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD35CCF4EE1944D4B8FF472B5EA7AB7C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>research for which an exemption for investigational use is granted pursuant to section 505(i) of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27133DF446254B41B87F63F9B85CC8E8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research using an approved drug for an approved indication with the purpose of evaluating and comparing the clinical effectiveness, risks, or benefits of 2 or more of any of the following:</text><clause id="H135E96575FBF4E49AA544A8D30F628F6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Health care interventions, protocols for treatment, care management, delivery procedures, diagnostic tools, or integrative practices.</text></clause><clause id="HE40269D1FC464087B5F8900A25A9814B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Drugs (including biological products), devices, or combination products.</text></clause><clause id="H2D0AFA5C17244EB696161297E92D8D27"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Any other treatments, services, practices, or items being used in the treatment, management, or diagnosis of, or prevention of, illness or injury in individuals.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC817B9C44E744BF287F414B1863C3DB4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Sufficient quantity</header><text>The term <term>sufficient quantity</term> means an amount of an eligible product no greater than the eligible researcher determines to be necessary to accomplish the qualified research and fulfill any related regulatory requirements.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H36FFA4485FD0468D9943A9DDBE8C624A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days of the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate final regulations to carry out section 505–3 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as added by subsection (a), including regulations to appropriately calculate the discounted price applicable with respect to an eligible product (as such terms are defined in such section 505–3).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

