<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4903E1E595D84D70B44F8753C54850E6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6558 IH: Securing Enfranchisement and the Rights of Voters regardless of Inoculation Status Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6558</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220202">February 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001311">Mr. Bishop of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that the right to vote shall not be impaired due to vaccination status.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H284DA4AD6E0643AD983B2D92AFA477A9" style="OLC"><section id="HA059FE9AAB4542989D9F11CCC2DFF1B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Enfranchisement and the Rights of Voters regardless of Inoculation Status Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SERVIS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9F02E8AE748B45D0B08DF2AEC8B7C6C2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Right to vote shall not be impaired</header><subsection id="H8E7447DD61BF429FA35F11C9C66C95F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any State or political subdivision, as such term is used in the Voting Rights Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/10301">52 U.S.C. 10301 et seq.</external-xref>), to require or impose a requirement that a voter or voters must present a vaccine passport or otherwise present information regarding their vaccination status in order to exercise the right to vote, including to vote in person, in any election involving any candidate for Federal office.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1C90AFE37CF7406CB9C54570479CF553"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Masking requirement</header><text>A State or political subdivision may require that a voter wear a mask in order to enter a polling location only if—</text><paragraph id="H9C589A5D764C47E9A1F27563C0569D33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State or political subdivision makes readily available and at no cost to the voter or any individual who accompanies the voter a mask sufficient to comply with any applicable masking requirement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BAA26D5B8B94F6FA988CAB071326C09"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State or political subdivision provides reasonable accommodation from such requirement for individuals with a disability as recognized under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC63AE1D13DE742E98EC47F8D38460555"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>vaccination status</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H17A0EF0D51B9477BBCBD0521A8606F75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an individual’s status based on the voluntary election to receive or not to receive a COVID–19 vaccine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D24F4E5C73B4C21A31E929F05CA28FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>regardless of whether someone has or has not been vaccinated against COVID–19, an individual's status with respect to having or producing proof of such vaccination in the form of a vaccine passport or other medical records that would demonstrate whether an individual has been vaccinated against COVID–19. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

