<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD29ACA39420D41DDA7843001B4B74DBF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6536 IH: Stopping Traffickers and Their Accomplices Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Justice for Victims of Trafficking Act of 2015 to require abortion providers to notify the national human trafficking hotline of victims of trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC33440383F9C4C65949EDA94070F1D1E" style="OLC"><section id="H0FE93CC028674FD58296159DC46FD2C1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Traffickers and Their Accomplices Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4FDFF35452D04A92ABD0E18082186ABD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H97CD632044484D718319F0EBEF657F88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Slavery and involuntary servitude are incompatible with American society and law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C0ABF85DA874A6F9FC79CEB08B6D3DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The 13th Amendment to the United States Constitution abolished legal slavery and involuntary servitude in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4A78B1386B048BFAD305002DAB6BDC5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Despite slavery being abolished in 1865, modern forms of slavery still exist throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1FEBA1A2C47447B97F86AD8FA48C27F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Every year, hundreds of thousands of Americans and immigrants are coerced into commercial sex acts against their will.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6C3B4894E04E4194724B56E7D0A7EE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In addition to sexual exploitation, victims of trafficking suffer repeated physical, mental, and emotional abuse at the hands of their traffickers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78DCC7D803B849D5920946A353F23876"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Abortion providers and facilities aid sex traffickers by turning a blind eye to the plight of abused women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H246CCA1D49FB45B3A1A68CAB70F11CA1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Department of State’s 2017 Trafficking in Persons Report indicated that sex traffickers coerce women into receiving abortions against their will.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84A1F571561C439BAD3FFDC74EAD357C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Research conducted by Laura J. Lederer and Christopher A. Wetzel, entitled <quote>The Health Consequences of Sex Trafficking and Their Implications for Identifying Victims in Healthcare Facilities</quote> published in the Annals of Health Law Journal, indicated that 71 percent of women coerced into commercial sex acts reported at least one pregnancy and 21 percent reported five or more pregnancies while trafficked (23 Annals Health L. 61 (2014)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC3620FDCF9400BB9B37A4FA7379EEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Lederer and Wetzel’s research found that almost a third of women trafficked reported underwent numerous abortions as victims of trafficking. More than half of respondents answered that their abortion while a victim of sex trafficking was a result of coercion. One victim of sex trafficking recounted, <quote>[in most of my six abortions,] I was under serious pressure from my pimps to abort the babies</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H355631ACB8C344569645968F093A9FEE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>A moral obligation exists to report suspected instances of sex trafficking to authorities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H144C4FC044EF4C92AFA41F262C73BDFE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Section 2 of the 13th Amendment empowers Congress to enact appropriate legislation to combat all forms of slavery and involuntary servitude, including forced sex trafficking.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2A0D792F40254637ADE6027E59C0D94F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Combat human trafficking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 114 of the Justice for Victims of Trafficking Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20709">34 U.S.C. 20709</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H05DDF403C591423B989B1BF713D727B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H50F92C8A971B4AAB906B28B8F40B60B7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>National human trafficking hotline notification by abortion providers</header><paragraph id="H6844F8DFE3614971A8A6083ACBCE428F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><subparagraph id="HC53C16C2E7684A4BBDEF4423B508A452"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification to national human trafficking hotline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 hours after consulting with a patient, an abortion provider shall notify the national human trafficking hotline if the provider has a reasonable suspicion that the patient is a victim of trafficking. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB41A32F18A54C8B9B0973BFD396C409"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report to Attorney General and local law enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 hours after an abortion provider notifies the national human trafficking hotline under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall notify the Attorney General of such notification by the abortion provider. Not later than 24 hours after receipt of a notification from the Secretary of Health and Human Services under this subparagraph, the Attorney General shall notify the appropriate State and local law enforcement agencies. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45BB5E0D581445FFB85550780DBB642B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An abortion provider who violates subparagraph (A) shall be fined $10,000, imprisoned not more than 6 months, or both.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D02BC01B58F417CAD48AF914057D30F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training</header><subparagraph id="HD0165D1C7B59481890A551A519568300"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall make available to abortion providers the training entitled <quote>Foundational (101) Human Trafficking Trainings—SOAR For Health Care</quote> (or any substantially similar successor training). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5EE3DD9541A4E10BB90C1CED31E6BB6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each abortion provider shall complete the training provided under subparagraph (A) on an annual basis and prior to January 30 of each calendar year, and certify such completion to the Director of the Office on Trafficking in Persons of the Department of Health and Human Services. The certification under this subparagraph shall include the protocols that the abortion provider has in place to identify and assist victims of trafficking. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28D7D325BFD34D8AB27BE7073F998E22"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>An abortion provider who fails to comply with subparagraph (B) shall be subject to a fine in an amount of $1,000 per day of noncompliance. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4C461EFC86D4900B94CA4453CA244CC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subparagraph id="H503403C55CE64B6C8196ED72CBF34548"><enum>(A)</enum><header>No requirement for victims of trafficking to self-report</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to require a victim of trafficking to self-report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21BB215E6F83449788B85F198D6ED963"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No right to abortion</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to provide a right to an abortion. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5024C1C0B6EF463C9EA3BF51EC6D66C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H48439BD05CF14A1DB0CE6867812FD2CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>abortion provider</term> means a person who—</text><clause id="HE8353D2A2E92455094683757E411ED62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>performs an abortion and is licensed to practice medicine and surgery or osteopathic medicine and surgery; or</text></clause><clause id="H6446BF8DF3174CED9E3C2E6AFEBCD8DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is otherwise legally authorized to perform an abortion.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BEE6EF39C694B039B64A73C1B13E6A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>victim of trafficking</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

