<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H813A07D9B0AA4DA09C2DFFC3E13D1857" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7672 IH: Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7672</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220506">May 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to schools and school-based health centers to increase the number of mental health and substance use disorder care providers in such schools and health centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD36A1C3412024BE6BCA5440B8784C0B5" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEE82A8529D9145C8AD4336DC4E6A9918"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Student Services In Schools Today Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ASSIST Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7BB841007072412B845B8C5F28C9F19C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program to increase mental health and substance use disorder care providers in schools and school-based health centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart I of part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2140155BC76244CFA7BDAAEBB42D20DF"><section id="H7E860F7A56284383BA6F7C3DB40711F3"><enum>330O.</enum><header>Program to increase mental health and substance use disorder care providers in schools and school-based health centers</header><subsection id="H68B8F1626F1F4132938CA4C8E403B161"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities to increase the number of mental health and substance use disorder care providers in schools and health centers served by such entities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H25733F031E3E4BFB8FEECBCAE0C62126"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity seeking an award under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a description of—</text><paragraph id="H2336774886EE431D938634CA0115CAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the mental health and substance use disorder needs of the student population served by the eligible entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B456C7AF2843FBBF2E66705CD48855"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the student population served by the eligible entity, how the eligible entity will ensure that the mental health and substance use disorder care providers supported by the eligible entity, and the services administered by such providers, are culturally competent and linguistically appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H93843D892977413BB0F2A4813D529FFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds made available through an award under this section may be used for a threat assessment team. </text></subsection><subsection id="H0856BEA17F5845489EDC026DF35C3222"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H014582C82A1946F99E5DB5E89407D820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entities receiving an award under this section shall submit an annual report to the Secretary accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA0BBF12325F74CB49658C77043C99378"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of mental health and substance use disorder care providers working at the schools or health centers served by the eligible entity, and the number of such providers supported through the award;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA107F9D549264ECEB16C509A968CB9C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the types of services provided by the mental health and substance use disorder care providers and the efficacy of such services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4088421EFE24892AECC0C1F5ACB1615"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the practices used by the schools or health centers served by the eligible entity to recruit and retain mental health and substance use disorder care providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45E063BA66B44E6591470E7A4C105C48"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rates of retention of mental health and substance use disorder care providers at the school or health center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96884A4B80B8419994986F7DC4BCF969"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the effectiveness of the awards under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6B4FC2D5699474EB9A9170DE934D548"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0CF337616E154AD7BE91BDEC2634BB5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8226A5E8CDE54A7897E892405BDA2C17"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a local educational agency, as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE65E273846A04A50B7FDA5FD8F444DF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education, as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2111A751C6624091B8F585E71CE3FDC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a school operated by the Bureau of Indian Affairs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HBB3F22900B6E43338DAB58905B0A8068"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school-based health center, as defined in section 399Z–1(a)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD9A1105E6D46406F8A6EEEC65BF93F8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mental health and substance use disorder care provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>mental health and substance use disorder care provider</term> means an individual who is licensed or credentialed to provide mental health and substance use disorder services, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H735431BC85AC4439B61246BCEF6C67AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school counselor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA1F870444C0A4BFD978BBBE0E24216A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school psychologist or any other psychologist;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B9AC70CFB954997BC024C96AFF385C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a psychiatrist who specializes in child or adolescent psychiatry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8542A93A9D8405CA029E5028245FAF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a school social worker;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3461D73B5A9436D8BB3C9EC0ECDFCF4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a peer support specialist or peer recovery coach; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1142EE59ED649DC87840F73257E5E48"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other providers, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H211ACA289BCF4463B4F215C1B927A732"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increasing the applicable FMAP for State expenditures attributable to certain behavioral health services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD62BA33D1E014471A9B12000DBC9B78D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>and (ii)</quote> and inserting <quote>(ii), and (jj)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0854AB9E4228428E8FB6A7DE3AA24FAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H607A892A3FA141E3822955293B25A524"><subsection id="H12278DCC84BC4CD3B0B69A3F64E10CF7"><enum>(jj)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H19334B378F2D413398620BB3FDEA612A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any preceding provision of this section, with respect to State expenditures for medical assistance consisting of services provided by a mental health and substance use disorder care provider (as defined in section 330O(e) of the Public Health Service Act) and furnished at a school or at a school-based health center (as defined in section 399Z–1(a)(3) of such Act) on or after the first day of the first calendar quarter beginning on or after the date that is 3 months after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Federal medical assistance percentage otherwise determined under subsection (b) shall, subject to paragraph (2), be equal to 90 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92A8D361B754B2DB1416E88C5479811" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of State expenditures described in such paragraph if application of such paragraph would result in a lower Federal medical assistance percentage for such expenditures than would otherwise apply without application of such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

