<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC837824288714D33B350C5F839484D7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6878 IH: Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6878</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220301">March 1, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000589">Mrs. Lesko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To address the health needs of incarcerated women related to pregnancy and childbirth, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H239B927B5BC945DD8D7E5398D0A16530" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HACD0DB5EF8524E0A8D861B261673AECA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H56AEFB98EB6642078A18BECC5AFD666A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data collection</header> <subsection id="H22221D163D30498D8FF4FF4B3106BDF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, pursuant to the authority under section 302 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10132">34 U.S.C. 10132</external-xref>), the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics shall include in the National Prisoner Statistics Program and Annual Survey of Jails statistics relating to the health needs of incarcerated pregnant women in the criminal justice system at the Federal, State, tribal, and local levels, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H03AF652BF57F4744ADEB551E96C8E26D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demographic and other information about incarcerated women who are pregnant, in labor, or in postpartum recovery, including the race, ethnicity, and age of the pregnant woman;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4EBDB62C57545418ACD01703064C33A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the provision of pregnancy care and services provided for such women, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF4E379BE91434D10A3F2EC507C245C8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether prenatal, delivery, and post-delivery check-up visits were scheduled and provided;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6DB235176564154B4B000A870C3C214"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether a social worker, psychologist, doula or other support person, or pregnancy or parenting program was offered and provided during pregnancy and delivery;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H769CF953B2DF407E9E6ED92676B7C4A6" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether a nursery or residential program to keep mothers and infants together post-delivery was offered and whether such a nursery or residential program was provided;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17DBA27CD6D546D2AACCDADD398AD196" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of days the mother stayed in the hospital post-delivery;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2CA11DACD5B439E9471B0EB81514370" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of days the infant remained with the mother post-delivery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0383A72440DF45E2B9D771D4DC7A48C8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the number of days the infant remained in the hospital after the mother was discharged;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H003235C15F3742AD895933A0956017A2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the location of the nearest hospital with a licensed obstetrician-gynecologist in proximity to where the inmate is housed and the length of travel required to transport the inmate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73E50808FD6C4E07BB617A3E083F0FA3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>whether a written policy or protocol is in place to respond to unexpected childbirth, labor, deliveries, and medical complications related to the pregnancies of incarcerated pregnant women and for incarcerated pregnant women experiencing labor or medical complications related to pregnancy outside of a hospital;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H94A01390E99141F7B6EBCAF1099730C6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of incarcerated women who are determined by a health care professional to have a high-risk pregnancy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F8C2D373E5F4FC6B82CC09532B6B95C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of incarcerated pregnant women and the number of incarcerated women who became pregnant while incarcerated; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2AE990E0B6E4B3A8B649B617C9D0D7A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the number of incidents in which an incarcerated woman who is pregnant, in labor, or in postpartum recovery is placed in restrictive housing, the reason for such restriction or placement, and the circumstances under which each incident occurred, including the duration of time in restrictive housing, during—</text> <subparagraph id="HF599EA7CFC8E4042B80F66EA0F118BFD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>pregnancy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H848B0405AD124D65A4CAB6DAA72D7B88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>labor;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1629BBB60E2047868B6447DE249C0107"><enum>(C)</enum><text>delivery;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFFC727CECA0A4C0CBFE6287A80ED860D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>postpartum recovery; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB37E5C7527B44A338AC5571B3E971BCD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the 6-month period after delivery; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE51FBB42AA0B4FADAC9D48316C7B0E0C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the disposition of the custody of the infant post-delivery.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7DA898534E2245B582FB5D8F1087C626"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personally identifiable information</header><text>Data collected under this paragraph may not contain any personally identifiable information of any incarcerated pregnant woman.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE33E27CDE8BA4668BA0ACC90F52954EE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Care for federally incarcerated women related to pregnancy and childbirth</header> 
<subsection id="H5C6FBD2105684615BFF93FE568EA19CA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that appropriate services and programs are provided to women in custody, to address the health and safety needs of such women related to pregnancy and childbirth. The warden of each Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women shall ensure that these services and programs are implemented for women in custody at that facility.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H70CCD6DE3160405B914A9513D3A9D085"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Services and programs provided</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that the following services and programs are available to women in custody: </text> 
<paragraph id="H97CAAE5424F44006920A2BDDC729F398"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access to complete appropriate health services for the life cycle of women</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide to each woman in custody who is of reproductive age pregnancy testing, contraception, and testing for sexually transmitted diseases and provide each woman with the option to decline such services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H903B935CC1EC466CB530E8B0D6B975B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with protocols relating to health of a pregnant woman</header><text>On confirmation of the pregnancy of a woman in custody by clinical diagnostics and assessment, the chief health care professional of a Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women shall ensure that a summary of all appropriate protocols directly pertaining to the safety and well-being of the woman are provided to the woman and that such protocols are complied with, including an assessment of undue safety risks and necessary changes to accommodate the woman where and when appropriate, as it relates to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE04E6ADD92B6447FA038540063B806B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>housing or transfer to a lower bunk for safety reasons;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD5E865BFCD843F684D66BB1166358A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriate bedding or clothing to respond to a woman’s changing physical requirements and the temperature in housing units;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8EC59EF56F6F4CD19BC86F40E8F214A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>regular access to water and bathrooms;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F24D3A8CDA3417AB2B4131E2F807FF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a diet that complies with the nutritional standards established by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services in the Dietary Guidelines for Americans report published pursuant to section 301 of the National Nutrition Monitoring and Related Research Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/5341">7 U.S.C. 5341(a)(3)</external-xref>), and that includes—</text> 
<clause id="HB89CF2ECEECA4F99A65E916552D85EC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any appropriate dietary supplement, including prenatal vitamins;</text></clause> <clause id="HD98BFDB031BF4D3BAC95BC55559C3660"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>timely and regular nutritious meals; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HBB023DD66A454A5896F795DE3FD0ECAE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>additional caloric content in meals provided;</text></clause> <clause id="H214FEDD324DA48B8A91E5572628C5C1E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a prohibition on withholding food from an incarcerated pregnant woman or serving any food that is used as a punishment, including nutraloaf or any food similar to nutraloaf that is not considered a nutritious meal; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE609CDE699B4461BB1053FE3A785B5F8"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other modifications to the diet of the woman as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons determines to be necessary after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and consideration of such recommendations as the Secretary may provide;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48E1B3D9C0244B33988918A52510D05B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modified recreation and transportation, in accordance with standards within the obstetrical and gynecological care community, to prevent overexertion or prolonged periods of inactivity; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H854FA93EE65248D2A0497AAEEC65A891" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other changes to living conditions as the Director of the Bureau of Prisons may require after consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and consideration of such recommendations as the Secretary may provide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5B4EFD973C84E139FDE393DEA243A5F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Education and support services</header> <subparagraph id="H8C2B506F4BA0432C93191204E2C4879B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Pregnancy in custody</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a woman who is pregnant at intake or who becomes pregnant while in custody, that woman shall, at intake or not later than 48 hours after pregnancy is confirmed, as appropriate, receive prenatal education, counseling, and birth support services provided by a provider trained to provide such services, including—</text> 
<clause id="H2C517F3C472D452B9EDAE4671528E7E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the parental rights of the woman, including the right to place the child in kinship care, and notice of the rights of the child;</text></clause> <clause id="HBB55E89AAF6A46A8BC1F614CA00DDCB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about family preservation support services that are available to the woman;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDFDC181578254E64BF0091595DD65C2D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>information about the nutritional standards referred to in paragraph (2)(D);</text></clause> <clause id="H6A5A5CF13DEB45C881205A11221EBB55"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information pertaining to the health and safety risks of pregnancy, childbirth, and parenting, including postpartum depression;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF4CDF18541DF40E1AB71C23EB7A435CA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>information on breastfeeding, lactation, and breast health;</text></clause> <clause id="H5C7A03A3A7F04310907DBDBFD2212F00"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>appropriate educational materials, resources, and services related to pregnancy, childbirth, and parenting;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H15DABA5EBF8849AB9335A528B661F4FA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information and notification services for incarcerated parents regarding the risk of debt repayment obligations associated with their child’s participation in social welfare programs, including assistance under any State program funded under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/601">42 U.S.C. 601 et seq.</external-xref>) or benefits under the supplemental nutrition assistance program, as defined in section 3 of the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2012">7 U.S.C. 2012</external-xref>), or any State program carried out under that Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="H86A98AC3D54C4720AAA0E6897992E359"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>information from the Office of Child Support Enforcement of the Department of Health and Human Services regarding seeking or modifying child support while incarcerated, including how to participate in the Bureau of Prison’s Inmate Financial Responsibility Program under subpart B of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor program). </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H04DAEA073C714FBBB266F5E345453814"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Birth while in custody or prior to custody</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a woman who gave birth in custody or who experienced any other pregnancy outcome during the 6-month period immediately preceding intake, that woman shall receive counseling provided by a licensed or certified provider trained to provide such services, including—</text> <clause id="H25F2C77C16994EF4B8BD7243F2C331E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the parental rights of the woman, including the right to place the child in kinship care, and notice of the rights of the child; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H045A99FF92554C279A0670A2CF862AFC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about family preservation support services that are available to the woman.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0289A7F8E4E84377A267FA49DC8ED0DB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Testing</header><text>Not later than 1 day after an incarcerated woman notifies an employee of the Bureau of Prisons that the woman may be pregnant, a Bureau of Prisons healthcare care professional shall administer a pregnancy test to determine whether the woman is pregnant.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98C9476209C74E1DA6D708EDA1137C7F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each woman in custody who is pregnant or whose pregnancy results in a birth or any other pregnancy outcome during the 6-month period immediately preceding intake or any time in custody thereafter shall be evaluated not later than 4 days after intake or confirmation of pregnancy through evidence-based screening and assessment for substance use disorders or mental health conditions, including postpartum depression or depression related to a pregnancy outcome or early child care. Screening shall include identification of any of the following risk factors:</text> <subparagraph id="H8F7BEE731F9C49F1A728D9A3BCC349B5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An existing mental or physical health condition or substance use disorder.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2028CCE0E789491AAC03AA843BD1E218"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Being underweight or overweight.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5200276A49D46DCA30FF72194226BFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Multiple births or a previous still birth.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H744B22A5D6AB42DDA9C8670A34EA0689"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A history of preeclampsia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DF9AD93DB5C4E4CB79AEE05026E9C65"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A previous Caesarean section.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C3BC6C8720F4B00B1240D3E9A271B9F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A previous miscarriage.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FB0228E669D452EAA98CFD7C2C28A7C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Being older than 35 or younger than 15.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB196FD10F3CD4499960AAD79D8AED505"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Being diagnosed with the human immunodeficiency virus, hepatitis, diabetes, or hypertension.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H522789E1DA914A0D8BF6664A40CC81AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Such other risk factors as the chief health care professional of a Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women may determine to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H578548B496AC48459F37F060BF92AA80"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Unexpected births rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall make rules establishing procedures for responding to unexpected childbirth deliveries, labor complications, and medical complications related to pregnancy if a woman in custody is unable to access a hospital in a timely manner.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE918DBFCFF024A958079C010F13089AC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any woman in custody who, after an evaluation under paragraph (4), is diagnosed as having a substance use disorder or a mental health disorder, that woman shall be entitled to treatment in accordance with the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7DD5C8BD5C45402786D590ED99E6B7AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Treatment shall include participation in a support group, including a 12-step program, such as Alcoholics Anonymous, Narcotics Anonymous, and Cocaine Anonymous or a comparable nonreligious program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1574E8A29E074015873539EFD0C26DBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Treatment may include psychosocial interventions and medication.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H26009E7E9E224395A748DD5E0CDD654F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that adequate treatment cannot be provided to a woman in custody in a Bureau of Prisons facility, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall transfer the woman to a residential reentry program that offers such treatment pursuant to section 508 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-1">42 U.S.C. 290bb–1</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD3A050B92FE409BB35BF3EB3B125880"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To the extent practicable, treatment for substance use disorders provided pursuant to this section shall be conducted in a licensed hospital.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H68E2E2FDC9024551B99AEAEF8B9415A5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Use of restrictive housing and restraints on incarcerated pregnant women during pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery prohibited</header> 
<subsection id="H68EB651B199A461A8F394CF8C8DD5490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4322 of title 18, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H72C11B62B9B94A0ABD6BCEF313777CF7" style="USC"> <section id="H6F98918EA38E486FAA9A6F8D4FA91E76"><enum>4322.</enum><header>Use of restraints and restrictive housing on incarcerated women during the period of pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery prohibited and to improve pregnancy care for women in Federal prisons</header> <subsection id="HBCA7023D566549F5A4009E3A38A825EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), beginning on the date on which pregnancy is confirmed by a health care professional and ending not earlier than 12 weeks after delivery, an incarcerated woman in the custody of the Bureau of Prisons, or in the custody of the United States Marshals Service pursuant to section 4086, shall not be placed in restraints or held in restrictive housing.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H36FD9A60C5C3488B940A0589E201E5A1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<paragraph id="H37993DFB577D4655BC22370BD6E8A6E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of restraints</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply if the senior Bureau of Prisons official or United States Marshals Service official overseeing women’s health and services and a health care professional responsible for the health and safety of the incarcerated woman determines that the use of restraints is appropriate for the medical safety of the woman, and the health care professional reviews such determination not later than every 6 hours after such use is initially approved until such use is terminated.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC36A4F025235414EAF77D34F810EDCA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Situational use</header><text>The individualized determination described under paragraph (1) shall only apply to a specific situation and must be reaffirmed through the same process to use restraints again in any future situation involving the same woman.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1E1352865514697B083664D7284ACE5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Access to care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Immediately upon the cessation of the use of restraints or restrictive housing as outlined in this subsection, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or the United States Marshal Service shall provide the incarcerated woman with immediate access to physical and mental health assessments and all recommended treatment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D995891A166477CBBD12E56EEA2C10B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Response to behavioral risks in the Bureau of Prisons</header> <subparagraph id="H7F9FFD3C578F4BA6BAC95CAB37FE50C3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Restrictive housing</header><text>The prohibition under subsection (a) relating to restrictive housing shall not apply if the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or a senior Bureau of Prisons official overseeing women’s health and services, in consultation with senior officials in health services, makes an individualized determination that restrictive housing is required as a temporary response to behavior that poses a serious and immediate risk of physical harm.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F6C63D7BE1D4912A74C4D6B37BFA6D2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The official who makes a determination under subparagraph (A) shall review such determination every 4 hours for the purpose of removing an incarcerated woman as quickly as feasible from restrictive housing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H061D28E89AC94BD4BD93623ABBADDBF4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Restrictive housing plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The official who makes a determination under subparagraph (A) shall develop an individualized plan to move an incarcerated woman to less restrictive housing within a reasonable amount of time, not to exceed 2 days.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H78A7BC05000744A4AB9BA44AC93AF348" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>An incarcerated woman who is placed in restrictive housing pursuant to this paragraph shall be—</text> <clause id="H053C746BFB97466CA1E8B688CADD3CE9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>monitored every hour;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE6EF74E3A6F14BAA8C3FD4AA897AD67B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>placed in a location visible to correctional officers; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD5E31E913B3C4C3F8DE5D226E88B6253"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prohibited from being placed in solitary confinement if the incarcerated woman is in her third trimester.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H494A869E9B24417D8D2218D7FDFC5D59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H275189B134714224A7F356F901C59D9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to the director and health care professional after the use of restraints</header><text>If an official identified in subsection (b)(1) or a correctional officer uses restraints on an incarcerated woman under subsection (b), that official (or an officer or marshal designated by that official) or correctional officer shall submit, not later than 30 days after placing the woman in restraints, to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or the Director of the U.S. Marshal Service, as applicable, a written report which describes the facts and circumstances surrounding the use of restraints, and includes each of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H8B18E3AC650046CB8F7787B302A917B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of all attempts to use alternative interventions and sanctions before the restraints were used.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BB207BE31C64666962410D7DD0C230B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the circumstances that led to the use of restraints.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE3A004BE24EF4EAC9C4E8250053E60E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strategies the facility is putting in place to identify more appropriate alternative interventions should a similar situation arise again.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE6C7BC098AF4E9E806AF296739CAD69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women Act of 2022</short-title>, and every 6 months thereafter for a period of 10 years, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="H81AB3FBD0C9D4E6F90C0E641E32B3755"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the reasoning upon which the determination to use restraints was made; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H587425D2BD48494E9A7A5C0AD65ADA20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the details of the use of restraints, including the type of restraints used and length of time during which restraints were used; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H597E89AB97F34604945D4DD1235A601A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any resulting physical effects on the prisoner observed by or known to the corrections official or United States Marshal, as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H845575141F5A4E06A6738536285CF597"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to the director and health care professional after placement in restrictive housing</header><text>If an official identified in subsection (b)(3), correctional officer, or United States Marshal places or causes an incarcerated woman to be placed in restrictive housing under such subsection, that official, correctional officer, or United States Marshal shall submit, not later than 30 days after placing or causing the placement of the incarcerated woman in restrictive housing, to the Director of the Bureau of Prisons or the Director of the United States Marshals Service, as applicable, and to the health care professional responsible for the health and safety of the woman, a written report which describes the facts and circumstances surrounding the restrictive housing placement, and includes the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H7F3029919319497B96F679342187F36D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The reasoning upon which the determination for the placement was made.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H35F8553C566D420EA15081B0BC6A3683"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The details of the placement, including length of time of placement and how frequently and how many times the determination was made subsequent to the initial determination to continue the restrictive housing placement.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67DBB83C9A8E48BE9C4BC5FC0FED7304"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of all attempts to use alternative interventions and sanctions before the restrictive housing was used.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H56B8BC4B10D641509F43D9DE8AFD55FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any resulting physical effects on the woman observed by or reported by the health care professional responsible for the health and safety of the woman.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H982F9663A02C4304A4F4D8466DF26B8E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strategies the facility is putting in place to identify more appropriate alternative interventions should a similar situation arise again.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F1CB83978E24E2397D96E8E95E1904D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women Act of 2022</short-title>, and every 6 months thereafter for a period of 10 years, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the information described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H87E6BAFF6C934FE6BC1725DF0A02EEAD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 24 hours after the confirmation of an incarcerated woman’s pregnancy by a health care professional, that woman shall be notified, orally and in writing, by an appropriate health care professional, correctional officer, or United States Marshal, as applicable—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFDDCD714C5394EC797666365CC2FD95B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>of the restrictions on the use of restraints and restrictive housing placements under this section;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2DDA6E04C1844D48F60F0799D100353"><enum>(2)</enum><text>of the incarcerated woman’s right to make a confidential report of a violation of restrictions on the use of restraints or restrictive housing placement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F505F2DA2954CD9952974B59412F379"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the facility staff have been advised of all rights of the incarcerated woman under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1BC1B51166F0438BB0185336AEA2B4E7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Violation reporting process</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the Director of the United States Marshals Service shall establish processes through which an incarcerated person may report a violation of this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00DAB6A6E1D94C9BA8ABD43D42FDEBE2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Notification of rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The warden of the Bureau of Prisons facility where a pregnant woman is in custody shall notify necessary facility staff of the pregnancy and of the incarcerated pregnant woman's rights under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H65FF1769FF2440D58A777AC157FE3707"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Retaliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any Bureau of Prisons or United States Marshal Service employee to retaliate against an incarcerated person for reporting under the provisions of subsection (e) a violation of subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H31355221200C48CAB174296B2771C022"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women Act of 2022</short-title>, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the Director of the United States Marshals Service shall each develop education guidelines regarding the physical and mental health needs of incarcerated pregnant women, and the use of restraints and restrictive housing placements on incarcerated women during the period of pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery, and shall incorporate such guidelines into appropriate education programs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA27EDBA8E6D3442CAB0AE7F840B392E8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA47C5C416E8B4379B77205A3F1494B4C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Restraints</header><text>The term <term>restraints</term> means any physical or mechanical device used to control the movement of an incarcerated pregnant woman’s body, limbs, or both.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3185F599D5F64637970679B1B99F453A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restrictive housing</header><text>The term <term>restrictive housing</term> means any type of detention that involves—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HECA8A4100C3E4982AE93D79ECBD5B537" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>removal from the general inmate population, whether voluntary or involuntary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4A83A606F75D44B19FACCF5348A9734A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>placement in a locked room or cell, whether alone or with another inmate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H386204DF360843DF9AEAC0973B24956D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inability to leave the room or cell for the vast majority of the day.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H99CA492CB9694FAC8F7E767BD2745E83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/317">chapter 317</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by amending the item relating to section 4322 to read as follows: </text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H375265FEC8EC4D4E8D2A45BAC55B53FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">4322. Use of restraints and restrictive housing on incarcerated women during the period of pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery prohibited and to improve pregnancy care for women in Federal prisons.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2F6362C2259849C98FE16378FE9A6156" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Treatment of women with high-risk pregnancies</header> 
<subsection id="HE91054F01C884765B5181D6E41C26606"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/303">Chapter 303</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H93DC78F819844B648CF972F09D26707E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HBEFF88AB963C4A03BAAB0D3438D07B20"><enum>4051.</enum><header>Treatment of incarcerated pregnant women </header> <subsection id="H0CF19CBD69E646908C3C5EE3B2D1323C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>High-Risk pregnancy health care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall ensure that each incarcerated pregnant woman receives health care appropriate for a high-risk pregnancy, including obstetrical and gynecological care, during pregnancy and post-partum recovery. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H14995FD1CE5D4DE2BC11DDD03639A6E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>High-Risk pregnancies</header> 
<paragraph id="H49AB51270F01437E9142216EED0EC871"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall transfer any incarcerated woman, who is determined by a health care professional to have a high-risk pregnancy and who agrees to be transferred, to a Residential Reentry Center with adequate health care during her pregnancy and post-partum recovery.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B36A67C28EA4CE6B351A52CC1C06355"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Residential Reentry Center to which an incarcerated pregnant woman is transferred pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be in a geographical location that is close to the family members of the incarcerated pregnant woman. In the case that a Residential Reentry Center is unavailable, the incarcerated pregnant woman shall be transferred to alternative housing, including housing with a family member.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A2C38AB5C90410F87E19B5791B888AA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transportation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To transport an incarcerated pregnant woman to a Residential Reentry Center, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall provide to the woman a mode of transportation that has been approved by the woman’s health care professional, at no expense to the woman.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD41C88B72EAC403580EFC13A2D6222E2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case that an incarcerated pregnant woman transferred to alternative housing pursuant to this section is monitored electronically, an ankle monitor may not be used on the woman, unless there is no feasible alternative for monitoring the woman.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8F6B85F30144011B9CA7CE5F0A508CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Service of sentence</header><text>Any time accrued at a Residential Reentry Center or alternative housing as a result of a transfer made pursuant to this section shall be credited toward service of the incarcerated pregnant woman’s sentence.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FF31D7160634D6595540364AB6F4180"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Credit for pretrial custody</header><text>In the case of an incarcerated pregnant woman, any time accrued in pretrial custody shall be credited toward service of the woman’s sentence.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H71BA1C037F714DDFBCBD80F24D1C2A8F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H8FB23AF5D22C431FA0B730AB9F75F73C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Family member</header><text>The term <term>family member</term> means any individual related by blood or affinity whose close association with the incarcerated pregnant woman is the equivalent of a family relationship, including a parent, sibling, child, or individual standing in loco parentis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE8875ACB5B244C5A83C876752EF13A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Residential Reentry Center</header><text>The term <term>Residential Reentry Center</term> means a Bureau of Prisons contracted residential reentry center. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6D41435049940BA858B1915B69AD7BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health care professional</header> <subparagraph id="H8DE0F13E30DA4E808D7783C5E0544BB3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>health care professional</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H2C52C9A2BC17458FBE1581E5F5AD77C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a doctor of medicine or osteopathy who is authorized to practice medicine or surgery by the State in which the doctor practices;</text></clause> <clause id="H595FEE11D40C4F67A2D8FD010FCCE790"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any physician’s assistant or nurse practitioner who is supervised by a doctor of medicine or osteopathy described in clause (i); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H554533F5E078477191239D5EFE54A2AF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other person determined by the Secretary to be capable of providing health care services.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9E66A8A5EB74DE4A5F2C70E9CEF9DF7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other health care services</header><text>A person is capable of providing health care services if the person is—</text> 
<clause id="H30611E193ED04DA29E9C5491300A6D7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a podiatrist, dentist, clinical psychologist, optometrist, or chiropractor (limited to treatment consisting of manual manipulation of the spine to correct a subluxation as demonstrated by X-ray to exist) authorized to practice in the State and performing within the scope of their practice as defined under State law;</text></clause> <clause id="HB94B5AE34357411E8A13F7B52BECA446"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nurse practitioner, nurse-midwife, clinical social worker, or physician’s assistant who is authorized to practice under State law and who is performing within the scope of their practice as defined under State law; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3D3F2CDB8A7F44B7BC57E907BDDE8CF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any health care professional from whom an employer or the employer's group health plan's benefits manager will accept certification of the existence of a serious health condition to substantiate a claim for benefits.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A7593452E7C44499E81AF61FA74D40E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authorized to practice in the State</header><text>The term <term>authorized to practice in the State</term> means that a professional must be authorized to diagnose and treat physical or mental health conditions under the laws of the State in which the professional practices and where the facility is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA4CC4B198C054FD4A0BCE3204602D50A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-risk pregnancy</header><text>The term <term>high-risk pregnancy</term> means, with respect to an incarcerated woman, that the pregnancy threatens the health or life of the woman or pregnancy, as determined by a health care professional.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H770FEA226B1A47BF888367B6DF79F73F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Post-partum recovery</header><text>The term <term>post-partum recovery</term> means the 3-month period beginning on the date on which an incarcerated pregnant woman gives birth.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3FCF984B45441B98D8AD90861AD56FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/303">chapter 303</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7E75F89A110749A9B5B4BB0D583562B7" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">4051. Treatment of incarcerated pregnant women.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H6C86A83CAC39468AABAE90544C78A5CF" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6.</enum><header>Exemption of incarcerated pregnant women from the requirements for suits by prisoners</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Civil Rights of Institutionalized Persons Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1997e">42 U.S.C. 1997e</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5A17DE8BAA2F4DCAA96F109FA2466F7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting after the period at the end the following: <quote>This subsection shall not apply with respect to an incarcerated pregnant woman who brings an action relating to or affecting the woman’s pregnancy.</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCCF62E4F73549498D5262E750BB3EBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), insert <quote>, except an incarcerated pregnant woman,</quote> before <quote>who is confined</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H7F1FBE256EFD4012BA2101CBAB0344BC"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HB08EDFD8C4D6433EA9B08D67024C5816"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In custody</header><text>The term <term>in custody</term> means, with respect to an individual, that the individual is under the supervision of a Federal, State, tribal or local correctional facility, including pretrial and contract facilities, and juvenile or medical or mental health facilities. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H21119EE4D7D54B7CAD4BB15BFB7FD3C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other pregnancy outcome</header><text>The term <term>other pregnancy outcome</term> means a pregnancy that ends in stillbirth, miscarriage, or ectopic pregnancy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC5F0E2E9F6154CF487F358DE2D015AA2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Postpartum recovery</header><text>The term <term>postpartum recovery</term> means the 12-week period, or longer as determined by the health care professional responsible for the health and safety of the incarcerated pregnant woman, following delivery, and shall include the entire period that the incarcerated pregnant woman is in the hospital or infirmary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H115FC6B39ADA4531ADDD5D0885F6B798"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restraints</header><text>The term <term>restraints</term> means any physical or mechanical device used to control the movement of an incarcerated pregnant woman’s body, limbs, or both.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32AAC396620A49F7A7085B08B512A6FF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Restrictive housing</header><text>The term <term>restrictive housing</term> means any type of detention that involves—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA240ED50F1384F3FBC53FF7DD36C97DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>removal from the general inmate population, whether voluntary or involuntary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B8BC973EA26474996C6E5DB03EA0FC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>placement in a locked room or cell, whether alone or with another inmate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H912570087DE04E36966684DACAC8D91D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>inability to leave the room or cell for the vast majority of the day.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HCA88502804834D3A87D5A9175F3C49B3" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Education and technical assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute of Corrections shall provide education and technical assistance, in conjunction with the appropriate public agencies, at State and local correctional facilities that house women and facilities in which incarcerated women go into labor and give birth, in order to educate the employees of such facilities, including health personnel, on the dangers and potential mental health consequences associated with the use of restrictive housing and restraints on incarcerated women during pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery, and on alternatives to the use of restraints and restrictive housing placement.</text></section> 
<section id="H91917CF4FA8048CEB28BAF76E1B012E5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Bureau of Prisons staff and U.S. Marshals training</header> 
<subsection id="HE7C20C9790944B2FB795830E402C6247"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Bureau of prisons training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall train each correctional officer at any Bureau of Prisons women’s facility to carry out the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11A33921FB074E3DA0AA9C938C999628"><enum>(b)</enum><header>New hires</header><text>Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Bureau of Prisons shall train any newly hired correctional officer at a Bureau of Prisons facility that houses women to carry out the requirements of this Act not later than 30 days after the date on which the officer is hired.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A1E82FBF3B84A6F8F51566E9C84DDFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>U.S. Marshal training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, the Director of the U.S. Marshals Service shall ensure that each Deputy U.S. Marshal is trained pursuant to the guidelines described in subsection (d). Newly hired deputies shall receive such training not later than 30 days after the date on which such deputy starts employment.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H43C4B8BFBD854EFA9F9B173BE205431C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Prisons and the United States Marshals Service shall each develop guidelines on the treatment of incarcerated women during pregnancy, labor, and postpartum recovery and incorporate such guidelines in the training required under this section. Such guidelines shall include guidance on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF3209FF80A494220A7536972174A14F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the transportation of incarcerated pregnant women;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30C3A71A58034009A343CD5EA4065EEB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>housing of incarcerated pregnant women;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC3981AF4328487BA5C9B8BAA4D96302"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nutritional requirements for incarcerated pregnant women; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71E0715CCF3C4986A37283E571A8B15E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the right of a health care professional to request that restraints not be used.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA6C309E032154981B67255E84E0557CB"><enum>10.</enum><header>GAO study on State and local correctional facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study of services and protections provided for pregnant incarcerated women in local and State correctional settings, including policies on obstetrical and gynecological care, education on nutrition, health and safety risks associated with pregnancy, mental health and substance use treatment, access to prenatal and post-delivery support services and programs, the use of restraints and restrictive housing placement, and the extent to which the intent of such policies are fulfilled.</text></section> <section id="H2A796B426CBB4106A8494BBD09263B72"><enum>11.</enum><header>PWIC grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part E of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA003D3D5FDC14FA9A03273C4297960FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subpart id="H56F0F44BDEF44C7192E9F8B74090171A"><enum>4</enum><header>Women in custody</header> 
<section id="HB02D399D296B46E0A420774C4C85A8AA"><enum>531.</enum><header>Pregnant women in custody grant program</header> 
<subsection id="H567D30B5B55740009B678B18757D7FE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may make grants to eligible entities that have established a program to promote the health needs of incarcerated pregnant women in the criminal justice system at the State, tribal, and local levels or have declared their intent to establish such a program. Eligible entities shall—</text> <paragraph id="H264642327A60491BAB1F5F824C54BA74"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote the safety and wellness of pregnant women in custody;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H119D6B2F555E4930BC9D6EA758BA4246"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide services for obstetrical and gynecological care, for women in custody;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2FCDA5068FC479583782C69498212FF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilitate resources and support services for nutrition and physical and mental health, for women in custody;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF08BB4BEDC742BDA91A4C1E89FD574A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish and maintain policies that are substantially similar to the limitations imposed under section 4322 of title 18, United States Code, limiting the use of restraints on pregnant women in custody; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAE62E2B8AC344E8C8284CD0333B0814D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>maintain, establish, or build post-delivery lactation and nursery care or residential programs to keep the infant with the mother and to promote and facilitate bonding skills for incarcerated pregnant women and women with dependent children.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H727AC7195A0F41AAABE43D1555FC3152"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE803C6801C05421BB8414918A77FBE19"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>An entity is eligible for a grant under this section if the entity is—</text> 
<paragraph id="H9DAC5AB757EF4B9AB00A75DBEDC23E94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State or territory department of corrections;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB6BDD69A09D4CB68F10C385CDD4F761"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a tribal entity that operates a correctional facility; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65F6A9F2892E408AA2B442E083EE465A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a unit of local government that operates a prison or jail that houses women; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA4129D544494101AD0345E13676E955"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a locally-based nonprofit organization, that has partnered with a State or unit of local government that operates a correctional facility, with expertise in providing health services to incarcerated pregnant women.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H18AEF51DB1AB4DC7AE560577A0789AB7" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Attorney General may require, including a detailed description of the need for the grant and an account of the number of individuals the grantee expects to benefit from the grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H97F3CC5089DB447899CFE05B85FEC73A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Not more than 5 percent of a grant awarded under this section may be used for costs incurred to administer such grant.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB9E4C2835451422EBB435B912781B749"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Construction costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, no funds provided under this section may be used, directly or indirectly, for construction projects, other than new construction or upgrade to a facility used to provide lactation, nursery, obstetrical, or gynecological services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H82A641D416ED4930870CC230C800042F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Priority funding for States that provide programs and services for incarcerated women related to pregnancy and childbirth</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining the amount provided to a State or unit of local government under this section, the Attorney General shall give priority to States or units of local government that have enacted laws or policies and implemented services or pilot programs for incarcerated pregnant women aimed at enhancing the safety and wellness of pregnant women in custody, including providing services for obstetrical and gynecological care, resources and support services for nutrition and physical and mental health, and post-delivery lactation and nursery care or residential programs to keep the infant with the mother and to promote and facilitate bonding skills for incarcerated pregnant women and women with dependent children. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEF8ACAF2EA0A42AA96BB71F2958BDD36" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Subgrant priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives a grant under this section shall prioritize subgrants to a unit of local government within the State that has established a pilot program that enhances safety and wellness of pregnant women in custody.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD812F092C1094F8C9CCEA7C2C7F95DB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Federal share</header> <paragraph id="HD4A8E3EDEE6C40D289AB99F962413BA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of a grant under this section may not exceed 75 percent of the total costs of the projects described in the grant application.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60122DD686DB4091BAB4BB3D16A829C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement of paragraph (1) may be waived by the Assistant Attorney General upon a determination that the financial circumstances affecting the applicant warrant a finding that such a waiver is equitable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA88C2839A8D847D99DF32852350CC324"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Compliance and redirection of funds</header> <paragraph id="H140FCE5303DC43F98C6F867FDFF84D6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after an eligible entity receives a grant under this section, such entity shall implement a policy that is substantially similar to the policy under section 3 of <short-title>Protecting the Health and Wellness of Babies and Pregnant Women Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8E386A8300440D4AB719CFBF9F45B4C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Attorney General may provide a 120-day extension to an eligible entity that is making good faith efforts to collect the information required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8BC588AF1F6141C69C84467A7246B71C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, to remain available until expended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBA2B2664F53C48D4ACCCC789D9285EEC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for fiscal year 2023, $5,000,000;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31ACD045817F4DE89082866C842D05A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2024, $5,000,000;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H696616E189794F7FB23BF518A3061D20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2025, $5,000,000; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H974ED0B9C300486884BCB751124393D3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2026, $6,000,000; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3773A366ECC45B982B47858E24F067C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2027, $6,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF9081D6FE8444D14B26A316082056CDA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Funds To be supplemental</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To receive a grant under this section, the eligible entity shall certify to the Attorney General that the amounts received under the grant shall be used to supplement, not supplant, non-Federal funds that would otherwise be available for programs or services in the prison where funds will be used.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8729634126CF49E19D16B0FB0B4422B3"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Unobligated and unspent funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available pursuant to this section that remain unobligated for a period of 6 months after the end of the fiscal year for which the funds have been appropriated shall be awarded to other recipients of this grant.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA4469AD833B240DB98D175E0F51E4981"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Civil rights obligation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of a grant under this section shall be subject to the nondiscrimination requirement under section 40002(b)(13) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(b)(13)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEB6C6410032C476BA462C75F3FE4F77B"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>in custody</term> means, with respect to an individual, that the individual is under the supervision of a Federal, State, tribal, or local correctional facility, including pretrial and contract facilities, and juvenile or medical or mental health facilities. </text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="H932ED877452D4C2B9017944D462D6453"><enum>12.</enum><header>Placement in prerelease custody</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3624(c)(1) of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Notwithstanding any other provision of this paragraph, in the case of a pregnant woman in custody, if that woman’s due date is within the final year of her term of imprisonment, that woman may be placed into prerelease custody beginning not earlier than the date that is 2 months prior to that woman’s due date.</quote>.</text></section> 
<section id="H8E4BD9B2D485476BBCA258C564291E4F"><enum>13.</enum><header>Determination of Budgetary Effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

