<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE3D4C782418342DEBA018C9185312E32" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 6605 IH: Climate Security Intelligence Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6605</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220204">February 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Security Act of 1947 to make permanent the Climate Security Advisory Council of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8ACEA5B982254762ACC7A6D807616303" style="OLC"><section id="H795A5D5AD1C040E980989923EF2AEF7F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Security Intelligence Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H8CAF69D8329147B69DDAE24989BBDB4D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Climate Security Advisory Council and Climate Security Intelligence Center</header><subsection id="H8C57CBA91D4A48F88C32A1AB898E5169"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Repeal of sunset of Climate Security Advisory Council</header><text>Section 120 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3060">50 U.S.C. 3060</external-xref>) is amended by striking the first subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A96D83A780247A4A834927C4E39BC5A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan for Climate Security Intelligence Center</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the chair of the Climate Security Advisory Council established under section 120 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3060">50 U.S.C. 3060</external-xref>) shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a written plan to permanently establish within the Office of the Director of National Intelligence a Climate Security Intelligence Center (to be headed by a Director appointed by the Director of National Intelligence) to fulfill each of the duties described in subsection (c). Such plan shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H016A4ED917B94B4CBCFDA54E2356E2D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for the Center, developed based on findings by the Climate Security Advisory Council, as supported by the National Academies Climate Security Roundtable established pursuant to section 1622 of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 4054), in carrying out its duties and responsibilities that relate to—</text><subparagraph id="H83BF5F4620DB4213BEFD08CC85682FAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the scope of the mission, responsibilities, and functions of the Center, and its relationship with the elements of the intelligence community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE35E9E94DFC443D7B1A1EEEE86920D53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the composition and staffing of the Center with personnel from elements of the intelligence community and from departments and agencies of the United States Government that are not elements of the intelligence community, including through the detail to the Center of personnel who have the appropriate security clearances from such departments and agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF11BBF21E89D4E51B621C3EDAC336071"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the types of data, information, computer modeling, scientific and technical resources, and any other resources necessary for the Center to fulfill its duties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0141A4460E134F2E909F3DFFF0DD68AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the requisite scientific and technical education, training, skills, and expertise necessary for personnel of the Center to conduct their work; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE74D97215F24EB3AA5DD2E3D7ED95B5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>approaches and best practices with respect to data-sharing, information exchanges, and other types of collaboration, at the appropriate level of classification, on matters relating to climate security and environmental science between the Center and—</text><clause id="H8E6FEF1D58F6493F9193A8616BDFF7B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>elements of the intelligence community;</text></clause><clause id="H6D7C86E9CEA245DA9158ACF3E517676E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">departments and agencies of the United States Government that are not elements of the intelligence community; and</text></clause><clause id="H6649C1B0D4CB4ABDAB8AB8A29CEB4AF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other key stakeholders in the scientific enterprise of the United States, including institutions of higher education, Federal research laboratories (including the national security laboratories), private industry, and nonprofit research organizations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BCB02A84DEF4663A195A5EE2ADDAAE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A proposed process for transferring from the Climate Security Advisory Council to the Center recommended functions and duties currently carried out by the Council, including a timeline for the transfer and a statement on the feasibility of establishing the Center and completing the transfer not more than 1 year after the submission of the plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89B19BAAA98041EBA7320569BA3EA04C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A request for any additional resources, facilities, personnel, or authorities that the Climate Security Advisory Council determines necessary to ensure that, upon establishment, the Center and its Director may fulfil the duties described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H144BC8A73395481A9B50BA2693C10373"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties described in this subsection are the following: </text><paragraph id="H087465029A464CBCBE69D1D6F6CA6A3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To serve as the primary organization within the intelligence community for—</text><subparagraph id="HC4E06BA438D14C379708F04DE6B83191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addressing the climate security intelligence needs and priorities of policymakers, including information and intelligence sharing at the appropriate level of classification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CDC4DCF97BB4C8EB3F844247EB51D14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>analyzing climate security risks and the climate influence of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF65CF14DAD57420EB8B6848830570D14"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identifying and disseminating climate intelligence indications and warnings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B35035386964CE4A82530B6D0F05B80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conducting strategic forecasting for climate security opportunities and risks in future;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9122C35058B04DF7A1B54AB6296500C4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>identifying relevant climate security collection gaps, and driving collection to fill such gaps; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD16794232C914E8EA3A3EC99D0BD2B7D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>collaborating with appropriate counterparts throughout the intelligence community to ensure appropriate integration of climate security analysis into existing lines of analysis undertaken by the intelligence community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC91E7027CE704950903150972CCE6AB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To identify, disseminate, and maintain best practices in the analysis of climate security, and the provision of climate intelligence indications and warnings, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1C8A4278D95349C59AE1281FD6E29CEA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying publicly available information and clandestinely collected intelligence that enables such analysis and indications and warnings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14DCC4EA8FA94FD384E5D0BB1750DA12"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the use of advanced computer modeling, artificial intelligence, machine learning, and similar techniques that enables such analysis and indications and warnings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H84DD7C3EDFE243E98F52E50A7D42E716"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To assess and identify best practices with respect to prior efforts of the intelligence community to analyze climate security, specifically with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HFE0A4D0162DC4C4DA2F67378D6C6811E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Measurements of Earth Data for Environmental Analysis program of the Central Intelligence Agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8C8DD27950344A8A36C8EE348CADE28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Center on Climate Change and National Security of the Central Intelligence Agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B778160ABEF4180BC4AF7EC10DCBF40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any climate security-related activities of the Director of National Intelligence or the intelligence community that predate the establishment of the Climate Security Advisory Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94B422976F944B6AA53F8D9FE418DD24"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To use the best practices identified under paragraphs (2) and (3) to inform the work of the Climate Security Intelligence Center and the intelligence community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85CD87CCCBA445D6A9317C7BE69800E2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To consult, as appropriate, with other elements of the intelligence community and departments and agencies of the United States Government that are not elements of the intelligence community to avoid duplication of existing efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27DC84D6EC1340EF8A287D730D95C819"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To carry out any functions transferred pursuant to the process proposed in subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66E6A0F4E9CE4305B69652BE26FA2C32"><enum>(7)</enum><text>To perform such other duties as the Director of National Intelligence shall specify.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DF6BDDC37BF4C54931DE40DDF246BC4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE4DE71CF3D6145FFA94A584847C96181"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Climate security</header><text>The term <term>climate security</term> means the effects of climate change on the following:</text><subparagraph id="H11316ED16F7541F28B3BB87A480284A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The national security of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBD8C3FD766E400482D048F359CAF022"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Infrastructure that enhances the national security of the United States, including—</text><clause id="H7EFF325D97C24932AC9500BFD471C619"><enum>(i)</enum><text>military installations, Department of Defense facilities, intelligence community facilities, and other physical facilities that contribute to or otherwise support operations of the intelligence community or the Department of Defense; and</text></clause><clause id="HC48E98EE08EB46D9AAE2C2A7CB71DA0B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>critical infrastructure of the United States (as defined in subsection (e) of the Critical Infrastructures Protection Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EC1D4FB4E8C408091A60C4D8D8986FD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Subnational, national, regional, and global politics, governance, and political stability.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27F0494A3CC9429493F999D66617DADA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The security of allies and partners of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE44DB5CBCE4ED7BEA2CA16342FCDE4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Ongoing or potential political violence, including unrest, rioting, guerrilla warfare, insurgency, terrorism, rebellion, revolution, civil war, and interstate war.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CC6D6DA952A4F05BE094DB4AE2D5ABE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Climate influence of the United States</header><text>The term <term>climate influence of the United States</term> means the global influence and leadership of the United States with respect to the climate policies of other countries, international organizations, and transnational groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF25D213835E44EB680EE8435BDB8A567"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Climate intelligence indications and warnings</header><text>The term <term>climate intelligence indications and warnings</term> means climate security developments with the potential to—</text><subparagraph id="H68F888AE2836469C8961C539033A4DDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imminently and substantially alter the political stability or degree of human security in a state or region; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0A2B767B884604AC9655E3937B59DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>threaten the United States, the military, political, or economic interests of allies or coalition partners of the United States, or citizens of the United States abroad.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA57297A122714844BA846864AF8CC879"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Congressional intelligence committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>congressional intelligence committees</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9B04E150BCA419DAD39D2B61BBAD731"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <term>intelligence community</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

