<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA65856BBD7CC4E68A9B438759CCAB192" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6787 IH: Gas Prices Relief Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a gasoline tax holiday.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B1294F3935144A9A17FF0752E15D0E9" style="OLC"><section id="H8A90292E0249447FB7BCCF38AA3BFA99" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gas Prices Relief Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4988FEE01A6B4C7A8634F072BBB00E8D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD942E3AE08C74A85908322BB67941E5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As of February 2022, the Consumer Price Index rose 7.5 percent from one year ago, the largest increase in 40 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B28A05AC0F54DD2BDEFBAEC193369C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compared with 2021, the energy index rose 27 percent and food costs rose 7 percent, placing an unprecedented burden on American families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CF621A912FB4A1EB1F3FBB0C11A8F3A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Shipping costs have increased year-over-year, raising the price of important groceries like milk, eggs, bread, meat, and other goods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H500079D5E42346DEBD9ED6579E99822A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to data from the Federal Highway Administration, the average American driver drives 14,263 miles per year. A suspension of the Federal gas tax would save the average American more than $100 per year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF91EFEA7B2941A7B150789F1CFAA98A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act provided $118 billion in funding from the general fund to supplement the Highway Trust Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC53429D384EA4BE480A54C6DC98770E5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The 18.4 cent Federal gas tax disproportionately impacts rural Americans, who must travel longer distances to go to the grocery store, see their doctors, go to the pharmacy to pick up their prescriptions, or travel to their jobs or school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C06B8DC27E141B0A98EBDBD302B8F3F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On August 30, 2021, the Federal Trade Commission announced enhanced efforts to step up enforcement on oil and gas companies for alleged collusion that led to increased gas prices for American consumers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FAB074176174A4FA643C1A78B5BF123"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Since 2008, Congress has transferred funds from the general fund to the Highway Trust Fund three times to ensure the fund remained solvent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D3C3CDA76740FCA3CDDBB75B5EF7FE"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Oil companies reported record profits in 2021 while Americans continue to struggle under high gas prices, inflation, and ongoing impacts of a pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DFEC757466649C2968EBAB8247AF513"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) takes actions to control oil production by considerably influencing international oil prices at the expense of American consumers. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA108A10405854780B7E856BB8DDD91B6"><enum>(11)</enum><text>A temporary gas tax holiday is one way to lower prices for American consumers as we continue to work towards long-term energy independence.</text></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA3F44A8260E946E6917C539BFC74178F"><enum>3.</enum><header>2022 gasoline tax holiday</header><subsection id="H0873F8E5DA3543F5BA46BA2FEA090F96"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of gasoline removed, entered, or sold on or after the date of the enactment of this Act and before January 1, 2023—</text><paragraph id="HCBCECF32BCEA4C968DDD97C6E38B1DC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rate of tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4081">section 4081(a)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be zero; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA95F60B7FFBE42CC9AB2B0F420E8ACA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate under section 4081(a)(2) of such Code shall not apply to gasoline to which the rate under paragraph (1) applies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77D7FB6D9C5C48858B91588BB44A7D51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfers to Trust Fund</header><paragraph id="H90EB1E7894E1478A98E694329346A02F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the general fund to the Highway Trust Fund established under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9503">section 9503(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund established under section 9508(a) of such Code amounts equal to the reduction in amounts credited (but for this subsection) to each such Trust Fund by reason of subsection (a). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBD737F6AD6C4E90830B0459E46BBDDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination rules</header><subparagraph id="H11985979BBA24D6FA08FD954A85873DE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be treated for purposes of sections 9503(b)(1) and 9508(b)(2) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DBE1CAA291545D0B43A163D05BD6C6B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Highway Trust Fund</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Highway Trust Fund under paragraph (1) shall be treated for purposes of section 9503(b)(1) of such Code as taxes received in the Treasury under section 4081 of such Code which are not attributable to the Leaking Underground Storage Tank Trust Fund financing rate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0DC80B45553400888F21BF89B058707"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Benefits of tax reduction should be passed on to consumers</header><paragraph id="H61FD4F5285324B6ABF0DFBC4704988E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It is the policy of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="HF1DD7C09EF664AFF98E273217616FE97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consumers immediately receive the benefit of the reduction in taxes resulting from the application of subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C3976CDDC904DEFB5881D5E8D612608"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transportation motor fuels producers and other dealers take such actions as necessary to reduce transportation motor fuels prices to reflect such reduction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62EA8981278944D18D4ED0054153121A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>The Secretary may use all applicable authorities to ensure that the benefit of the reduction in taxes resulting from the application of subsection (a) is received by consumers. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

