<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H87D9D23906644ABABDA823D838755F5D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7578 IH: CLOUD Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7578</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Commerce to submit a report to Congress on data servicing operations owned by Chinese entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBA54DC8CC6804A619034A826A4D13F5E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H533CBF9786244659A823BDE3315A1CEB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Limitless Overtaking of User Data Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>CLOUD Act</quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAC5C5C01E7804CD382F3BAB57E454BB0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Data servicing operations owned by Chinese entities report</header> <subsection id="HE0DFB6F92E324DD1801AD13B2E806041"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Federal Communications Commission, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H57B84E8AC3F642909877CF159EAC6C35"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any data servicing operation or service owned by a Chinese entity is operating in the United States, the laws and regulations that might apply to such operation or service, and any data servicing operation that are offered or provided to United States persons by the entity.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE63F8524C904324BA4E03FDB5B732E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any Chinese entity that provides products or services for a data servicing operation is engaged in a joint venture or servicing arrangement with a United States entity and the nature of such operations.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H592BB2B6F9964AD1A971C08C7D737D8C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether consumers of data servicing operations have access to prominently identified information regarding the ownership of such operations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90C70A44370045BAAB3C27879B92AEA3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Whether United States entities can operate freely in the People’s Republic of China and what, if any, restrictions apply to the services and operations of such entities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB1FDCBE4C0C54A3C8D28C922774C2720"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each country in which a Chinese entity provides equipment or services for the provision of data servicing operations in a third-country market and whether the market share of Chinese entities in those markets may limit, in any way, the ability of United States entities to operate independently of such operations or without the use of such services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8ABC9595139443A7A556719520E9408A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any support the Government of the People’s Republic of China provides to Chinese entities that provide equipment or services for the provision of data servicing operations that may act as a subsidy for such operations or services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF1FCA9730EED4BD8BD918A9F43A17311"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H137705FB8B584EE1B2040D00B74B1380"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate Committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2340DB39C7174042ADE0AB2ADC69FED8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Financial Services Committee, the Foreign Affairs Committee, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Energy and Commerce Committee of the House of Representatives; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0D251B54E71467F8AB53664FD938A28"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Finance Committee, Foreign Relations Committee, the Select Committee on Intelligence, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2965F1FE18994F529034447DC8E60C35" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chinese entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Chinese entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of China or any jurisdiction within China, including a foreign branch of such entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H446B72696A3F49DE886A87207F73374A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data servicing operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>data servicing operation</term> means the management, storage, processing, and aggregation of data.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC17EE390773C4CB7AC6C00DDB5C76F8A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United States entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States entity</term> means an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0CF4ECCE5234C4398ADDA053FBE1433" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>United States person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBE43847AEC544DD787B05C8951B4A2E2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a citizen of the United States or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3BF899A52E034C8BAFD150C148640435" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

