<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HB8D6AD80109A4285A95D7F19E175C10B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 442 RH: Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium Land Transfer Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 489</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 442</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–670, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210121">January 21, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium located in Sitka, Alaska, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H8A4F57C6F7DF4B2B9FF71A7CD5413411" style="OLC"><section id="H5C6406BEF5A2463AA5F197624988B0CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium Land Transfer Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H248F746ACA7F4C8D8DF1CE50676FDB03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Conveyance of property</header><subsection id="H5BC3F87996B54802A7668DA6430CBE0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 2 years, after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall convey to the Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium located in Sitka, Alaska (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Consortium</quote>), all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in section 3 for use in connection with health and social services programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H628388F3EB7D44B6A7FEE07D66D4ABCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The conveyance of the property under subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H128403544F8E4A93B6B98CECE053CE02"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be made by warranty deed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B4A440C4758434CA08375105379206B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not—</text><subparagraph id="HC29DD79CB13E4CE7B28C0AE082CA2BD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require any consideration from the Consortium for the property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5E6437929D9426BB073C946A4304B22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impose any obligation, term, or condition on the Consortium; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7A05BBDC0F44AB4AE3D93CC17307785"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for any reversionary interest of the United States in the property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD0A67172A614825A01F9CA43CB1AA7B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on any quitclaim deed</header><text>The conveyance by the Secretary of title by warranty deed under subsection (a) shall, on the effective date of the conveyance, supersede and render of no future effect any quitclaim deed to the property described in section 3 executed by the Secretary and the Consortium.</text></subsection></section><section id="H861F31CB21644F9396B393291A760306"><enum>3.</enum><header>Property described</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The property, including all land and appurtenances, described in this section is the property included in U.S. Survey 1496, lots 4 and 7, partially surveyed T. 55 S., R. 63 E., Copper River Meridian, containing approximately 10.87 acres in Sitka, Alaska.</text></section><section id="HE0800DFF439C4260ACCF3FB2E574D430"><enum>4.</enum><header>Environmental liability</header><subsection id="HAE9DCE77C02A4398B51F41A1DCF9D3CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Liability</header><paragraph id="HAFF8BD07CC644F4698CE0B4422D35C5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Consortium shall not be liable for any soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination resulting from the disposal, release, or presence of any environmental contamination on any portion of the property described in section 3 on or before the date on which the property is conveyed to the Consortium, except that the Secretary shall not be liable for any contamination that occurred after the date that the Consortium controlled, occupied, and used the property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H650742E3F07B4DBBB0B8E3596DBC3E7F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental contamination</header><text>An environmental contamination described in paragraph (1) includes any oil or petroleum products, hazardous substances, hazardous materials, hazardous waste, pollutants, toxic substances, solid waste, or any other environmental contamination or hazard as defined in any Federal or State of Alaska law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF30B67E34E04D40BF1281D02D281D0F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Easement</header><text>The Secretary shall be accorded any easement or access to the property conveyed under this Act as may be reasonably necessary to satisfy any retained obligation or liability of the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C4C5C7DE982453A996A4F95D37B0E6E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of hazardous substance activity and warranty</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary shall comply with subparagraphs (A) and (B) of section 120(h)(3) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)(3)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

