<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H65899165D7E749FC9A4D8522FE3D2AFE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 7625 IH: Protection of Civilians in Military Operations Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7625</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enhance protections of civilians during United States military operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H21EB120D93B442A6B43FF9D4A95E175F" style="OLC"><section id="H292295CBC3504257865DCDA7EA50C4BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protection of Civilians in Military Operations Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H915EF8106AB341198787C9C0C4DE0679"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress—</text><paragraph id="H706F75F7CB944B0D8F4F842C13EFE274"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to commend the Department of Defense for its renewed commitment to preventing and addressing harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations and work to develop an action plan to implement meaningful changes to further prevent and address such harm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H113B9897ED594848A8D5E16176FFA1C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to agree with the Department that harms to civilians is a tragic and unavoidable part of war, and to recognize that—</text><subparagraph id="H7AA259E9DCF84922AC7421FF46A44DF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department endeavors to conduct all military operations in compliance with the international law of armed conflict and the laws of the United States, including distinction, proportionality, and the requirement to take feasible precautions in planning and conducting operations to reduce the risk of harm to civilians and other protected persons and objects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE3A3B8AC4564CA5BBC7288D8D8C2368"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the protection of civilians and other protected persons and objects, in addition to a legal obligation and a strategic interest, is a moral and ethical imperative; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49CB283BA3CB4A4EAA116E08A9BEDB9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>despite those commitments, military operations of the United States and partner countries during the two decades before the date of the enactment of this Act have resulted in civilian deaths and injuries, and damage to or destruction of civilian objects including critical infrastructure, in at least Afghanistan, Iraq, Pakistan, Somalia, Syria, and Yemen; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC60AA24E8088447591CBDE683503BF1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>more must be done to improve the protection of civilians;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB4B3566B53842D0ACFF09990A2AB9E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that the Department has submitted to Congress four successive annual reports on civilian casualties resulting from United States military operations for calendar years 2017, 2018, 2019, and 2020, and has updated reports as appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC44881E7BE649C0A243C19BD52CFAC0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to recognize the efforts of the Department, both in policy and in practice, to reduce the harm to civilians and other protected persons and objects resulting from United States military operations, and to encourage the Department to make additional progress in—</text><subparagraph id="H997CB648B48B4B529CEFB365AD9C32DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing at all combatant commands personnel and offices responsible for advising the commanders of such commands, and integrating into command strategy, the promotion of observance of human rights and the protection of civilians and other protected persons and objects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD03680924B3F48C29761B43BC712EF14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>finalizing and implementing the policy of the Department relating to civilian casualties resulting from United States military operations, as required by section 936 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/134">10 U.S.C. 134</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAE067D921574AAA96346DA38398642E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>finalizing and implementing Department-wide regulations to implement section 1213 of the National Defense Authorization for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2731">10 U.S.C. 2731</external-xref> note), for ex gratia payments for damage, personal injury, or death that is incident to the use of force by the United States Armed Forces, a coalition that includes the United States, a military organization supporting the United States, or a military organization supporting the United States or such coalition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99E2217C159848D3A173CD0590A5766F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>professionalizing foreign partner forces to minimize, mitigate, and respond to harm to civilians, including in connection with arms transfers, train and equip programs, advise, assist, accompany, and enable missions, and fully combined and coalition operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H3500261E66CD406EBE849031D73F219E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Integrity of civilian harm investigations</header><subsection id="H6EBDC2D6B19546ABB8BAF0947C2AED94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Investigations by officers outside unit or chain of command</header><text>A commander in the Armed Forces conducting an administrative investigation, commander directed inquiry, or equivalent investigation of harms to civilians resulting from a United States military operation that was undertaken by one or more units under the command of the commander shall—</text><paragraph id="H5FC942A8BF904D8F93496A19B338F722"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, select as an officer to conduct such investigation an officer in the Armed Forces outside of such units or chain of command; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA545BEA974644A5A221A2A1BBC1E740"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if selecting an officer outside of such units or chain of command is not practicable, include an explanation in the investigative report and submit to the Center of Excellence described in section 7 a report describing the reasons such a selection was not practicable. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80F5CAE721EE495494CE84D1197BAA37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Separation of investigative personnel from personnel involved in operations</header><text>The military or civilian personnel of the Armed Forces who conduct an investigation on civilian casualties resulting from a United States military operation shall, to the extent practicable, be operationally separate from members of the Armed Forces who were directly involved in such operation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H66264327BC7741E7B8F9256F7A51BB7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Witness interviews and site visitations in investigations</header><paragraph id="H527DF6E365384BE69B4702E03B2A4689"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each investigation of harm to civilians resulting from a United States military operation shall, to the extent practicable, include—</text><subparagraph id="HCB40DE02A274422F8AC0AC19BEEAB3D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interviews, remotely if necessary, of civilian survivors and witnesses (after obtaining their informed consent), including first responders and local medical authorities, and witnesses that may have moved to other locations; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA87943750705407CB1F8F67A3DD28EFB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a visit by appropriate members of the United States Armed Forces to each site at which civilian casualties were confirmed or reasonably suspected in connection with such operation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CCB20F446214830BC64B59BEA6274B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interviews or visits by alternative personnel</header><text>If the Secretary of Defense determines that an interview described in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1) or a visit described in subparagraph (B) of that paragraph is not practicable, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HA4E72B739D7347A0AF6095C0FFE25B7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>memorialize, in writing, the justification for such determination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBDEAF43B6FD483193973C15509EF90A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make every reasonable effort to obtain, as the case may be—</text><clause id="HC5F82274953B43D6A1F7B7F87AF7488B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such an interview, remotely if necessary; or </text></clause><clause id="H46E30489A8394CFBA83F80AB38A46C8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a visit by appropriate military or civilian personnel of a partner or coalition military force, or by personnel of the national government concerned, or a local government capable of making such a visit in connection with the investigation concerned; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50E5911050D44EDFB4CD36613B036EFF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>memorialize, in writing—</text><clause id="H0FCA88C59A8D4919B638AAE54A4498FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the results of any interview or visit under subparagraph (B); or</text></clause><clause id="HB3C3F5392FDB497194C1A2FF907039F9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if no interview or visit could be obtained under that subparagraph, the gaps in evidence in the investigation concerned as a result of the lack of such an interview or visit, as the case may be.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H074A92F557224263B0328A8560CC3AA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration of civil society information</header><text>Each investigation of harm to civilians resulting from a United States military operation shall—</text><paragraph id="HF8D3272EFAB24C2EB5745D6ABE9C0693"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, obtain and incorporate open-source information and civil society documentation regarding the possible incident of harm to civilians; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D6A0A754A444B4BB4CD3FA89A1A839F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider all sources of relevant and credible reporting, including information from public reports and nongovernmental sources; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F3D4118146545399FFB44B7E11420C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include a reporting mechanism for the receipt and processing of information received under paragraphs (1) and (2) that is relevant to the investigation, including online portals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD97F9BEC6EA94F078CEB674A04C10AD5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coordination between geographic combatant commands and Special Operations Command and the Department Of State</header><subsection id="HA5A405CBED2C424CAB393DEA29A4E877"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall direct each commander of a geographic combatant command and the Commander of the United States Special Operations Command to coordinate with the Department of State to establish and maintain an uninterrupted line of communication between such commands and the Chief of Mission (or the Chief's designee) in any country in which any such command is conducting military operations in order to assist in the response to reports of harm to civilians resulting from such military operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCEB1CE6920884E40AF1978705538ABAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Primary objective</header><text>The primary objective of the line of communication under this section shall be to serve as a channel for fielding and coordinating reports of harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations undertaken by the command concerned in the country or operation concerned.</text></subsection></section><section id="H57B3661A88E64842A454353B9D19D945"><enum>5.</enum><header>Database on reports on assessments and investigations</header><subsection id="HFCFE6992973844729736E8945F56C976"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Database required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish and maintain within the Department of Defense a database that preserves and organizes reports of the Department on assessments and investigations of harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations (including reports under section 1057 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018), and the status and results of such assessments and investigations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0170BAC123344BEBB22C7C884F6C3159"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Searchability</header><text>The database required by subsection (a) shall be searchable by personnel across the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF3A5A139CE2D478CB410BC87BC450F45"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability to public</header><text>The public shall have access to, and be able to search, the database required by subsection (a) through an internet website of the Department that is available to the public. For purposes of such access, appropriate information in the database may be maintained in a classified annex in the interests of the national security of the United States, and access to such annex appropriately limited.</text></subsection><subsection id="H89349DAB16FE4DCDABFBE92E24C108CE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Update</header><text>The database required by subsection (a) shall be updated not less frequently than once every 30 days.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0BB779D4E20F44F6935BB0A168BEFDAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Past reports on civilian harm</header><text>The database required by subsection (a) shall include, to the extent practicable, any Department of Defense reports already conducted on assessments and investigations of harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations between January 1, 2001, and the date of the enactment of this Act, as well as any reports conducted retroactively.</text></subsection></section><section id="HAE864A35778140C3B3CBE6478BDD9C98"><enum>6.</enum><header>Resources to implement Department of Defense policy on civilian harm in connection with United States military operations</header><subsection id="HC559847069DE4716B1FD8C110BA0FEA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to facilitate fulfillment of the requirements in section 936 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/134">10 U.S.C. 134</external-xref> note).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6F21A9EE439D4936A14A6AA16B968570"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall do the following:</text><paragraph id="HFE56660DDA734AD7B686F50FE3A9FB3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Add to, and assign within, each of the United States Central Command, the United States Africa Command, the United States Special Operations Command, the United States European Command, the United States Southern Command, the United States Indo-Pacific Command, and the United States Northern Command not fewer than two personnel who shall have primary responsibility for the following in connection with military operations undertaken by such command:</text><subparagraph id="H9FB02EAB081A4012A97FAA37C7C2CB83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Providing guidance and oversight relating to prevention of and response to harm to civilians, promotion of observance of human rights, and the protection of civilians and civilian infrastructure, including ensuring implementation of the policy of the Department of Defense on harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A6A8C5FF9224A6D8672E3B04331A060"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Overseeing civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response functions on behalf of the commander of such command.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88D7E2D3C9014720B5F4231801B7EA1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Receiving reports of harm to civilians and conducting assessments and investigations relating to such harm.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85EFEF532C694683BDE727C87E1D0AF7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Analyzing incidents and trends with respect to harm to civilians, identifying lessons learned, and ensuring that lessons learned are incorporated into updated command guidance and practices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DF2A1D9C60A40BFB0AAD6E7BD783102"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Offering condolences and amends for harm to civilians, including ex gratia payments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D686E08BEA145C2B62555FA4CDA98C7"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Ensuring the integration of activities relating to civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response, the protection of civilians, and promotion of observance of human rights in security cooperation activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF617987DAF7422F9166978DC1EDB4A1" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Working with the Center of Excellence established under section 7.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB26258B1CA694F60B5F9BCF47B5BD5EB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Consulting with non-governmental organizations on civilian harm and human rights matters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H733D89FE008140E1BC0D65FB117A983E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Add to, and assign within, the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy not fewer than two personnel who shall have primary responsibility for implementing and overseeing implementation by the components of the Department of Defense of Department policy on harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F8D4E633DC447D896173751A9FF5D5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Add to, and assign within, the Joint Staff not fewer than two personnel who shall have primary responsibility for the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2F0D828F573A4248993458C4BD7795D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Overseeing implementation by the components of the Department of Defense of Department policy on harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9BF07160AC14E5187795C17A6E8F1FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing and sharing in the implementation of such policy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAD6D7FCD4684DA9B6D85DE2F55AF58C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Communicating operational guidance on such policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6389696EC4D648CFBEA2290F4E52BBE8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training, software, and other requirements</header><paragraph id="H0C5A41E5608C48C3B57B6F6A32DE3CA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025, the Secretary of Defense and each Secretary of a military department may obligate and expend, from amounts specified in paragraph (2), not more than $5,000,000 for the following:</text><subparagraph id="H5AFDD28123BC4ADA9E7A20DA31996D92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training related to civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC938045D79640FB85F44F8F51699521"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information technology equipment, support and maintenance, and data storage, in order to implement—</text><clause id="HD4EBAEA1344449D6B0CB80ABC3034226"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the policy of the Department relating to harms to civilians resulting from United States military operations as required by section 936 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019; and</text></clause><clause id="HC2B59C08C8244149A1B7FAE96DE68EBD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the database required by section 5.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50F12F8B61834E5485CE3ABDBEAF81C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>The funds for a fiscal year specified in this subparagraph are funds as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H3D157D4CD4A549859B4FFB9ED4F3FDFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of the Secretary of Defense, amounts authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EA80FCEE1BF4A79AC505CC4D3731790"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a Secretary of a military department, amounts authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for operation and maintenance for the components of the Armed Forces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB39B2058B18549FA86C03EAFB75B736A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Department of Defense Center of Excellence for the Protection of Civilians</header><subsection id="H608D9C1032F04A2C9E6AA7C964ED7F72"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/4">Chapter 4</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H9D66C83DED5C4989A32CF744B706644C" style="USC" act-name=""><section id="H05C9782DAE474CF199ECD5EB19C2DCAB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>148</enum><header>Center of Excellence for the Protection of Civilians</header><subsection id="H380ADEAAB7974AD796E18557F5125184"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Center of Excellence for the Protection of Civilians</header><text>There is within the Office of the Secretary of Defense a Center of Excellence for the Protection of Civilians (in this section referred to as the <quote>Center</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HAEB24AD6648B4748A9D13A364288CACA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Functions and composition</header><text>The Center shall serve as the primary organization in the Department of Defense responsible for—</text><paragraph id="HAD605A3A7A444299BE83C2D88FD2C9F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advising the Secretary of Defense and senior United States Government officials on efforts to prevent, mitigate, and respond to harm to civilians during United States military operations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACB34D5E42844A6EAEBCF324CA12EDAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring the full implementation of the Department of Defense Instruction on Responding to Civilian Harm in Military Operations and subsequent guidance pertaining to civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2906176B9E14C8DBF5D4A8EBB2F57DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conducting regular audits of civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response policies and practices across the Department of Defense, including at the combatant commands, including alignment of Department policies, practices, and other guidance with the law of armed conflict and other applicable international law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14355461D4454C438E60EA123972D0EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>convening on a quarterly basis an interagency task force to assess progress on civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response, which shall include the Department of Defense, the Department of State, the Central Intelligence Agency, the United States Agency for International Development, and such other agencies as the President considers appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB4914E7F01A45BA8A924F2E48366A2C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>tracking data relating to harm to civilians, analyzing such data over time for trends, and ensuring the public release of such data on a regular basis;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46CB53B4DCB94C1CAD66770FB89E4B07"><enum>(6)</enum><text>conducting post-strike assessments and investigations of suspected harm to civilians, including wherever possible interviews with victims and survivors, and in consultation with civil society organizations and relevant United States Government agencies, and publicly releasing all such assessments and investigations with minimal redactions only for legitimately classified information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E87E717A8604155A6FA9FE03A926782"><enum>(7)</enum><text>based on post-strike assessments, investigations, and trend analysis, recommending individual amends and remedies for harm to civilians, recommending accountability measures in cases of wrongdoing, and suggesting changes to policy and practice based on findings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE045FD0FC2694B9A89B5A25F405674E9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>issuing amends for harm to civilians caused by the use of force by the United States Armed Forces, a coalition that includes the United States, a military organization supporting the United States, or a military organization supporting the United States or such coalition, including formal apologies, ex gratia payments, and other assistance, in consultation with civilian victims, survivors, and their representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA56AB1E8208F4949BB9132BCA586839D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>engaging with civil society no less than biannually to ensure the most accurate and comprehensive information about harm to civilians is known to the United States Government and that United States Government efforts to improve civilian harm policies and practice are informed by the experiences and needs of civilians affected by military operations of the United States and partner countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79528F45C336400FBE00562987A4D35B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>conducting assessments and investigations and reporting on instances of civilian harm that have occurred in the past; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9211B38DAEAD41F9B4F66278780D1756"><enum>(11)</enum><text>ensuring that lessons learned from civilian harm assessments, investigations, and other sources are reflected in updated doctrine, policies, procedures, and practices, and monitoring and assessing implementation of lessons learned.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED31C6E1DE9149FCA6DFEF7AB0FDA5AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H41DCD88E36B24E49B42B87BC9F8F0252"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is a Director of the Center, who shall be the head of the Center, and who shall be appointed by the Secretary of Defense. The Director of the Center shall be a civilian with significant experience and expertise relating to the protection of civilians.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="H595EE951B2A44AE78002BF5867AC9D2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the Center shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6C066728F21D4C14939B6053C55E84DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report directly to the Secretary of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F6E1BD42036425A848004271296AFC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out the functions of the Center under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5135AB0F72C04D61A66B5846DE48355E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Staff</header><text>The Center shall have sufficient staff to carry out the functions of the Center under subsection (b), including—</text><paragraph id="H7B210069909646A08112BA7F8F90A17A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a general officer (as defined in section 101(b) of this title) with significant experience and expertise on the protection of civilians; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF9CC998311B41FBA39F1FC1C4131A57"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analysts and investigators detailed from the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Central Intelligence Agency, and civil society organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H854307CB611248A0A1885EED331B374F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Access to intelligence</header><text>The Center shall be provided with access, in accordance with applicable provisions of law, to all intelligence and other reporting possessed or acquired by the United States Government pertaining to harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations. </text></subsection><subsection id="HDB11B534B3FF40A1BF9E581A1F2C4614"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9A691C382314457C9B2F94D5CE2980E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>At the direction of the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Center shall submit to the congressional defense committees, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives an annual report on the activities of the Center. The Director shall also publish an unclassified form of the report on an internet website of the Department available to the public concurrently with its submission to Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph indent="up1" id="H63CEE5DAECA94948B12595AE0A994E47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) shall include a discussion of—</text><subparagraph id="H2BFF267D681D42DBA253E0A2C18D2E04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities of the Center and its progress toward implementing the functions of the Center under subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BB10ADC583E423DB720B44CDC12DCBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the assessment of the Director of United States Government policies and practices for civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F5444BD53FA4D79B8C3B3B5A10C6F96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Director for improved civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response policies and practices; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9248019DF50499EA01201667C603E4D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Director for any legislative or other actions necessary to improve the ability of the Center to carry out its functions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC81AAC75F20C49018AF65180A8ED81E2"><subsection id="H85AD7352DEDD4BB89DB8640C4BAE2919" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the Center shall, at the direction of the Secretary of Defense and in consultation with civilian victims and survivors, develop further guidance on the provision of amends or condolences for harm to civilians, including monetary and non-monetary mechanisms.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1A572F36D544943BD9F23D5EA100A24"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025, there is authorized to be appropriated for the Department of Defense $25,000,000 for the Director to carry out the functions specified in subsections (a) through (g).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD22CB890C7134089AE2847FC48C71BCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 147 the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55CB02FF001D487DB9E03FB3021226A7"><toc><toc-entry level="section">148. Center of Excellence for the Protection of Civilians.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H58359C1F6C0D4559A8C3F25A43F3051E"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report on Department of Defense practices regarding distinction between combatants and civilians in United States military operations</header><subsection id="H3EFA43B407514833986F7C42FC236D1D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into an agreement with a federally funded research and development center to conduct an independent report on Department of Defense practices regarding distinguishing between combatants and civilians in United States military operations. </text></subsection><subsection id="HB85186FB0D134C96B6057AE6B122A0C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following matters:</text><paragraph id="H3E954E3FE1224201AC915376E6BFE1FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of how the Department of Defense and individual members of the Armed Forces have differentiated between combatants and civilians in both ground and air operations since 2001, including in Afghanistan, Iraq, Syria, Somalia, Libya, and Yemen, including—</text><subparagraph id="H57D9C6FE9F5D47DCA54F32A51308F2A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant policy and legal standards and how these standards were implemented in practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F8B3CD7693B4354B5ACAD21512FC4E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>target engagement criteria; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C59F16221D74742B14D418012231C96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether military-aged males were presumptively targetable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4327C4906D14C22A19DF89215B67176"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the Department of Defense has differentiated between combatants and civilians when assessing allegations of civilian casualties since 2001, including in Afghanistan, Iraq, Syria, Somalia, Libya, and Yemen, including—</text><subparagraph id="H607E609A31E5446AA62FD9FA788F252C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant policy and legal standards and the factual indicators these standards were applied to in assessing claims of civilian casualties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB339F919CCD4254AB2BD9FB30A9D5C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other matters the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC25EE1C3676B4406BF1FCE2CEC659079"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><paragraph id="HDE609C529EFE4D1E857CF07A2E884209"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than July 1, 2023, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth an unaltered copy of the assessment under this section, together with the views of the Secretary on the assessment. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4DC7C8F01784DDDB21007D68797AB76"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H22D2A85FB3FC4EE395F3688ABF482979"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD5B015931E994D64A8C48F447BEBE6D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civilian harm</header><text>The term <term>harm</term>, with respect to civilians, means—</text><subparagraph id="H24A5D67F71734D26B3365D7649F8F929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>injury to, death of, or destruction of property of civilians; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6105A5B3A075498D9A9B71657B743660"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other harm to civilians caused as a result of the use of force. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52B7FC8A9E674CDAA2D8A147E9303507"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional defense committees</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a)(16) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H147D254D17774E5292F57B564A05BB10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>United states military operations</header><text>The term <term>United States military operations</term> includes any mission, strike, engagement, raid, or incident involving United States Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

