<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4185027EE38746AB93454BFF54B96599" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7321 IH: Safe Aircraft Maintenance Standards Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7321</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. Garc&#237;a of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require certain air carriers to provide reports with respect to maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4BD2232D9E6343B5A052BEA61E942E67" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2A9DF39D4FBA4383A216C553127D134B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Aircraft Maintenance Standards Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H241946350EE445A2B553DAEB679A6EEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F1B3B5D05174F72841299B4B14930C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the safety of the United States aviation system requires the highest standards for aircraft maintenance, repair, and overhaul work;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC227852D52BA414B94752B0FFC799408"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the safety of aircraft operated by United States air carriers should not be dependent on the location where maintenance, repair, and overhaul work is performed; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7D82A5403F04B06AB3E0F0574A862DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Aviation Administration must fully enforce its standards for maintenance, repair, and overhaul work at every facility, whether in the United States or abroad, where such work is performed on aircraft operated by United States air carriers.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0D70063A1AB7455791F3E2A468D60252"><enum>3.</enum><header>Oversight of repair stations located outside the United States</header> <subsection id="H31F0340883394C65B4734FA4BD0867F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44733 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD70111F06F294343B23C41E76D250C81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Inspection</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Oversight</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H211ECAC60BC54208ABA857D1C9D3BDB1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9DF62515A4554DEC95658DE58A68E61C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, without prior notice,</quote> after <quote>annually</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA07489719675476FA66A7030EA2E88DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence and inserting <quote>The Administrator may carry out announced or unannounced inspections in addition to the annual unannounced inspection required under this subsection based on identified risks.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D2FA1C5DEF64E3B90A6331425ACADC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (k); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5FFBE5D0D56474F94F45E87F3F82FAB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H87E4F405A86E442184915D4CCD5752E5" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H581FC1E871E5401A9AF112A554B47A8A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Data analysis</header> 
<paragraph id="H0E03D2F368C643DF901B86B56966AC1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An air carrier conducting operations under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, shall provide to the responsible Flight Standards office of the Administration, not later than the last day of each calendar month, a report containing the information described in paragraph (2) with respect to maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alteration of an aircraft that is performed during the preceding calendar month.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB91877D71B5747FD9043BAFCB62A8DBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>A report under paragraph (1) shall contain the following information:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA1AC6906737048BBBDADCE1247334287"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The location where any maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alteration was performed outside the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF89EE6AAA33A442EA4CD285F2823D9B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB8A8269252F54828BB3FE0C497A65190"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date of completion of the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04FD63BD2AB14C2F9AB52842D092919A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The total man-hours associated with completing the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3506131A68AD4D1A902CD7EBB5F919F6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A list of all failures, malfunctions, or defects affecting the safe operation of an aircraft identified by the air carrier as requiring corrective action after return to service, organized by reference to aircraft registration number.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF1966E316B8646A6ADAF673516079629"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The certificate number of the person approving an aircraft, or a powerplant or part, for return to service following completion of the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H933505A38B7844F8A6576471AF88F138"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which an aircraft returns to service, an air carrier shall update the information described in paragraph (2)(E) with respect to any failure, malfunction, or defect discovered by the air carrier following return to service during such period.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA46E953B1B24C61A4B7D74AF179481D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4B8B3948911041F38B773EFE0978F878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>analyze reports submitted under paragraph (1) of this subsection and sections 121.703, 121.705, 121.707, and 145.221 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor provisions, to detect safety issues associated with maintenance, preventive maintenance, and alterations performed outside the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61CDD00BF5AE472DA54CE3D9624C0CDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require appropriate actions in response to such reports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H00E7972945B4430A8258EF9F8646B553"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual reporting requirement</header> 
<paragraph id="HDF6DBC7764E343348539F2AC1DEC2EA2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, and annually thereafter, each air carrier conducting operations under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, shall upload to the online repository described in paragraph (2) a report containing—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D6ED5FDE70A42F682B84D4B1521C54A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a minimum of 1 year of heavy maintenance work history for each aircraft (organized by reference to aircraft registration number) that conducted operations under such part 121 during the previous calendar year;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H072BDD6A40854029AA3F3E9E34F77402"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage and total number of mechanics carrying out maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations on aircraft for the air carrier during the previous year who are employees and who are not employees of the air carrier;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HADA4CBC6BF0B45D8B42FD3EEC03F110F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the percentage and total number of mechanics certified under part 65 of such title carrying out maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations on aircraft for the air carrier during the previous year who are based and who are not based in the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48C59ED6DC7B4E1E9CA8D5FD9A769133"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the percentage and total number of mechanics, regardless of certification, carrying out maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations on aircraft for the air carrier during the previous year who are based and who are not based in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H565CF9207C3F4772A822A8B24B275F29"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the percentage and total number of mechanics carrying out maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations on aircraft for the air carrier during the previous year who are certified under part 65 of such title and who are not certified under part 65 of such title;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF279480C88A54A1D978D771A6CAFB70D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other information to be provided by the air carrier regarding maintenance, safety, and the aircraft fleet of the carrier that is of interest to the traveling public, as determined appropriate by the Administrator;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40463BEA1ADB4AE8B051AB0A1E5031D6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>all locations where aircraft in the fleet of such air carrier have undergone heavy maintenance work in the past 3 years, listed by total man-hours; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC9EB51AC9C1C4B9CBD5216FA2DA0D811"><enum>(H)</enum><text>all locations where heavy maintenance work on an aircraft may be carried out for the air carrier under an existing contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF24557452ECE44329ABD1A00FD89FFA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Online repository</header><text>The Administrator shall establish an online repository for information submitted under paragraph (1) that allows an air carrier to electronically upload the data required to be submitted under such paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5530F044AC6C403F8DCC0737446110C9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>International standards for safety oversight of civil aviation</header> 
<paragraph id="H4F20C54BAD4142DFA4BFBFE552EB2723"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications and requests for renewal</header> 
<subparagraph id="H41AD1B1AA2A84FF49B5EF4A388F700E9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may not approve any application or request for renewal under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, from a person located or headquartered in a country that the Administration, through the International Aviation Safety Assessment program, has classified as Category 2.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33DBBD88A96E410F9D2AB6D510E32AFF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maintenance implementation procedures agreement</header><text>The Administrator may elect not to enter into a maintenance implementation procedures agreement with a country that the Administrator has classified as Category 2 to the extent the Administrator determines is necessary to comply with the requirements of this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9834272B0E244CB48814A551F7199C54"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued heavy maintenance work</header><text>No air carrier conducting operations under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, may contract for heavy maintenance work with a person located or headquartered in a country that the Administration, through the International Aviation Safety Assessment program, has classified as Category 2.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAA7F7EAB10C94F07AA7F613951B028B3"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Minimum qualifications for mechanics and others working on U.S.-Registered aircraft</header> <paragraph id="H74D710FAE4B8490F84947B7B9B47511F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall require that, at each covered repair station—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H520AB09E0AFF49DB8DCD902E58EDB374"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all supervisory personnel are appropriately certificated as a mechanic or repairman under part 65 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54CA4E0E840A449784204C020842F5AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all personnel authorized to approve an article for return to service are appropriately certificated as a mechanic or repairman under part 65 of such title; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB1A55A5C3E043F9B38227C423C867F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>all personnel performing required inspections under part 145 of such title are appropriately certificated as a mechanic or repairman under part 65 of such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA89920CD1E204499B861565009CA8222"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Physical presence</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall require that any individual who is responsible for authorization of return of an article to service or who is directly in charge of maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations performed on aircraft operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBE5C25E7DA9E434FB5CE7539AC16C1A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be physically present near the aircraft and available for consultation while work is being performed; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13DC3B6F80374121BAF967A59A1800D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>personally perform the work.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A2322232A9F4561855BC4692E8D817F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of covered repair station</header> 
<paragraph id="HE54E07CCAA584E339AF224414B760A0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 44733(k) of title 49, United States Code (as redesignated by this section), is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HF0A4F589A5E84280B4D38839EDA28AC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as paragraphs (2) through (4); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1025637EC65D44B2A82CEDED47BC8333"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2), as so redesignated, the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE01CA5330724C3AB57A0C72AEE56F22" style="USC"> <paragraph id="H688143DE713349E887889823B93E8709"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered repair station</header><text>The term <quote>covered repair station</quote> means a facility that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H26A077F3C7684A8FB3B8EECF419E7185"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located outside the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H840C747E259E424ABCEE34AE9692A9FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is certificated under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB237C1D8A5664B3C85996FDA7BB778AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performs maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations of aircraft, including powerplants and parts of such aircraft, operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F1CF39D6F1E4C0C980C32F03588C9EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44733(a)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>covered part 145 repair stations</quote> and inserting <quote>part 145 repair stations</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1F91E9765E604EB699152FED8293C190"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/447">chapter 447</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 44733 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E89A50D1B0D45CF84A15847EC68FCE4" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">44733. Oversight of repair stations located outside the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H17CF85B582C84E70B08917AFEF0638B2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Moratorium</header> <subsection id="H9C0CCF1D732F49FD904C5A51707D4C55"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Moratorium on issuance of part 145 certificate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator may not issue any new certificate under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, with respect to a facility located outside the United States until—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF663E722E5F341D7B27C63278B4ACB35"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the final rule required under section 2112(b) of the FAA Extension, Safety, and Security Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/190">Public Law 114–190</external-xref>) has been issued;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38A140FE80BC4D749A0591848C01D95C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Administrator has issued the final rule required under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33EC28425B704CD78E7A30E6E616AF8E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any regulatory changes required by this Act or the amendments made by this Act have been implemented.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H14C7F33400B54D6BB361AC4F9316A44D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final rule on assessment requirement</header><text>With respect to any employee not covered under the requirements of section 1554.101 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, the Administrator shall issue a final rule that requires a covered repair station to confirm that any such employee has successfully completed an assessment commensurate with a security threat assessment described in subpart C of part 1540 of such title.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3E64DC45CCEB4DFE9527CB2F2F07D47A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H9DF32103C92448979CAA281101A295F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62D72E41C8BE45538C18D2A956DCC98B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered repair station</header><text>The term <quote>covered repair station</quote> means a facility that—</text> <subparagraph id="H2C9C00E1AD2A4AB6AC71C13463697D93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located outside the United States;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FCC5A33084C4F858FBFC6EB2E15C7C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is certificated under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A0FB989A4E8497DA36416CD2E30D86D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performs maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations of aircraft, including powerplants and parts of such aircraft, operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

