<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HB6FFEBB2940E4808B511872184F8E95F" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7314 : Assessing Xi’s Interference and Subversion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7314</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to submit to Congress a report on the People’s Republic of China’s support to the Russian Federation with respect to its unprovoked invasion of and full-scale war against Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1382699E57244E4C970DA36E7BD9B91F" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H4E1553D28062494AA1530B1157783B0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assessing Xi’s Interference and Subversion Act</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>AXIS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2C9371B964EC4A5DB8DC6D8C68274CCB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H149726AE075D4E94A02DECA9FD44CB0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HFE461437BB4C49D99B44B3F2418B2944"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On February 4, 2022, weeks ahead of the Russian Federation’s invasion of Ukraine, Russia and the People’s Republic of China released a joint statement following a meeting between Vladimir Putin and Xi Jinping, which outlined a strategic partnership with “no limits” and no “forbidden” areas for cooperation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H663E4A2BEA1B430D8655531F59A32389"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On February 24, 2022, Russia invaded Ukraine in an unprovoked and unjustified act of war.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69D1F8B3D4A34BBEA96D72528B9A3DDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>China abstained from voting on the February 25, 2022, United Nations Security Council resolution and the March 2, 2022, United Nations General Assembly resolution condemning Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3944E7560FF141DA8940E30C93296F1D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As of April 1, 2022, China has not publicly condemned Russia’s unprovoked and illegal invasion of Ukraine. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C7A6D547D34E309208EAB6272CD3A8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In his call with Xi Jinping on March 18, 2022, President Joe Biden communicated that there would be <quote>implications and consequences if China provides material support to Russia as it conducts brutal attacks against Ukrainian cities and civilians</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50F8300459E8467190BA2CCA6F561EAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H60FFA3F560144CCDA8A0AA2E20F5BFF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China’s disinformation efforts relating to the Russian Federation’s war against Ukraine make it culpable in whitewashing Russia’s war crimes, which include the indiscriminate killing of countless Ukrainian men, women, and children; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26F6C22728A648D2A36E040CC8A15559"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if China is found to be materially supporting Russia in its war against Ukraine, there should be swift and stringent consequences for China.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H95F342D4B0104D26A85F90B78F330D1F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H3C71E7ABB1D04E27AA14C76BB6DC2378"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce and the Director of National Intelligence as appropriate, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on whether and how the People’s Republic of China, including the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, any Chinese state-owned enterprise, and any other Chinese entity, has provided support to the Russian Federation with respect to its unprovoked invasion of and full-scale war against Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8FDBEF7088DF46FCB1609746010B2A1E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include a discussion of the People’s Republic of China support to the Russian Federation with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HB04CFFFA872C450FB795341749BDFC63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>helping the Government of Russia or Russian entities evade or circumvent United States sanctions or multilateral sanctions and export controls;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94392EDC7D9B4722876C950511DB50E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deliberately inhibiting onsite United States Government export control end-use checks, including interviews and investigations, in China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60CC55602CEA42FB89FEE6647AFC2793"><enum>(3)</enum><text>providing Russia with any technology, including semiconductors classified as EAR99, that supports Russian intelligence or military capabilities; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A8283D0D3F143FFA7505A81FFFEFC41"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing economic or financial arrangements that will have the effect of alleviating the impact of United States sanctions or multilateral sanctions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H101345066BAA4B0BB9CDF539CFA77645"><enum>(5)</enum><text>furthering Russia’s disinformation and propaganda efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11CB5E35519E4490B42D6A4F6B504A65"><enum>(6)</enum><text>coordinating to hinder the response of multilateral organizations, including the United Nations, to provide assistance to the people or Government of Ukraine, to condemn Russia’s war, to hold Russia accountable for the invasion and its prosecution of the war, or to hold those complicit accountable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4697ABCF77E44EBB8117262D2F5F9070"><enum>(7)</enum><text>providing any material, technical, or logistical support, including to Russian military or intelligence agencies and state-owned or state-linked enterprises.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD88E056F9EF54C93B9BF527A99135241"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form and published on the Department of State’s publicly available website.</text></subsection><subsection id="H60D0D05D0F794A1CB3E1CB06D369259D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to submit the report required by subsection (a) shall terminate on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HA4A2130FAFF14FFC992932FDC660A062"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary of State determines the conflict in Ukraine has ended; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFAA6E7D043643CDAC0C780075A2E3C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H983DF37412154F08B98CA7D2A14E7FE4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H3CBD473252364EFE98A4740B25C7E345"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9345E36605FB4E46AB74104CF263B6C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220427" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 27, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

