<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F34F9E4373E4AB1B2CD84B2BB22341B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 HR 8731 IH: Protect Children’s Innocence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8731</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220819">August 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000596">Mrs. Greene of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit gender affirming care on minors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB319488CF8654A15810E564E29A7AF11" style="OLC"><section id="HE5AA72D3467E484F8E3A43FBB1B72572" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Children’s Innocence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><title id="H2E4B447231E24DB88FEA2F263D764A6E"><enum>I</enum><header>Gender affirming care for minors prohibited</header><section id="H8AEBC6E68F494AF69031DDE887B59F2E"><enum>101.</enum><header>Gender affirming care on minors prohibited</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/110">Chapter 110</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF023F3EA47944D9C85E81F74E302A467"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HD0E0BBF6E6844A768675E01042AB9074" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H6DB1DE01EEAB4FD8BF552797E01BCA99"><enum>2260B.</enum><header>Gender affirming care for minors</header><subsection id="H6FF0249C166C43C4BF96C11BF7FBD568"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, in any circumstance described in subsection (e), knowingly performs any gender affirming care on a minor is guilty of a class C felony.</text></subsection><subsection id="H07695212315B404F8A5277A01E625DC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on prosecution of person on whom intervention is performed</header><text>No person on whom the gender affirming care under subsection (a) is performed may be arrested or prosecuted for an offense under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H70F89AE265C14293B9BBDAB5FB7C5F8D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person on whom gender affirming care is performed under this section may bring a civil action for appropriate relief, including compensatory and punitive damages, against each person who performed the gender affirming care.</text></subsection><subsection id="H84DFE2A6F9A146829D2160D4F101937E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H12D1C32B716343FEB29997E8E7CC4401"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Gender affirming care</header><subparagraph id="HD2E963A5CDFA4D7BAE4057995F22117D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this chapter, except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>gender affirming care</term> means, with respect to an individual, any of the following:</text><clause id="HACAE877023AC446892F6A32DAD84093E"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performing any surgery for the purpose of changing the body of such individual to correspond to a sex that differs from their biological sex, including—</text><subclause id="H4B01F80C54EE42A39EE646A348EE6BE3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>castration;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDFD8071A6EFA44ECAD88CCB745BEDDFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>orchiectomy;</text></subclause><subclause id="H76B356D0A54A42E48D7FB6515EBD68B6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>scrotoplasty;</text></subclause><subclause id="H39A2B6071BF84613BF65529AB2AEAF1A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>vasectomy;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBD09D801572B479AA28108D4F8040905"><enum>(V)</enum><text>hysterectomy;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCA6766E87DCB431198DE878220E62EF4"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>oophorectomy;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9BC1E0344637419096FB1336D24C6AAC"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>ovariectomy;</text></subclause><subclause id="H41F5ADDC2B90449088FEA37023DFE87E"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>metoidioplasty; </text></subclause><subclause id="H57DBCDE6E19E49658BA30DFE42EBD02C"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>penectomy; </text></subclause><subclause id="HB99CC86D00C640E08EF7052389AEEFC2"><enum>(X)</enum><text>phalloplasty; </text></subclause><subclause id="HA42B958A145F4053BD323083D8F0E4A2"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>vaginoplasty; </text></subclause><subclause id="H22EE499BDE02416EBCBB7D6412C9ACA5"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>vaginectomy; </text></subclause><subclause id="H51FE2BBA98EC4D3F90C29A7BEAF3D527"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>vulvoplasty; </text></subclause><subclause id="H0F0813BAA3D44B06A2067C53781DE19B"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>reduction thyrochondroplasty;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6E7DC23B876D4D7F90CC30D168BD7A98"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>chondrolaryngoplasty; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF34EB7DC3D5046C392449CBC2CF3FB1A"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text>mastectomy.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFE3AA7DAB2B54F2FB295B15B56E44C9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Any plastic surgery that feminizes or masculinizes the facial features for the purposes described in clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="H3ED28272C27A4BDB8CA965B340E82ED1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any placement of chest implants to create feminine breasts for the purposes described in clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="HE579A0014F65486190B71FAACB87FA72"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any placement of fat or artificial implants in the gluteal region for the purposes described in clause (i).</text></clause><clause id="HCDB9AF59858A4BB5A6E863D637DA6EBA"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administering, supplying, prescribing, dispensing, distributing, or otherwise conveying to an individual medications for the purposes described in clause (i), including—</text><subclause id="H9E7028DAA5A943F291A911C14C5DFB5F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) analogues or other puberty-blocking drugs to stop or delay normal puberty;</text></subclause><subclause id="HAA3AACE7C0124E798F27F407897525E1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>testosterone or other androgens to biological females at doses that are supraphysiologic to the female sex; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H45C32671D48D45FFB5F987F67285C999"><enum>(III)</enum><text>estrogen to biological males at doses that are supraphysiologic to the male sex.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4672E1BB18D644A4B155B8261D92B6D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to the following individuals:</text><clause id="HA1BE07A44CAB40C88BCDEFB5A8C0CD32"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual with both ovarian and testicular tissue.</text></clause><clause id="HCA40D8E5FECC4101A6FE1482C675F9F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An individual with respect to whom a physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action.</text></clause><clause id="HD5BBA028B5C64411951687D355ACFF71"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An individual experiencing infection, disease, injury, or disorder caused or exacerbated by previous gender transition procedures.</text></clause><clause id="H78F665E0AC364B9289B766C7F35E206B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An individual suffering from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness that would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of a major bodily function unless the procedure is performed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4401730FAFA476088E7FA08B4DFF054"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biological sex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biological sex</term> means the indication of male or female sex by reproductive potential or capacity, sex chromosomes, naturally occurring sex hormones, gonads, or internal or external genitalia present at birth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FAB31CA5D904C5BBB53EDCDC3139DC1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minor</term> means any person under the age of eighteen years. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5DC02ED3561943629310F1832C759CA8" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text>For purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text><paragraph id="H2D0D3C8B48EE4693BC64859684DA0614" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant or victim traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D474242038C4680970761C2C51F00A2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45893EC5E42D4C73A72271DAF91FF452" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC746BB59054F4810B6D095E123E186F7" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08F258EB186149329F09AC8388FCFD28" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB218FC62CC4711AF5C8C98F3DB7610" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0E2EA8828554D1DA0820249BA4E76A4" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F72C793BD754402821591918A65C706"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed as prohibiting provision of the medical services described in subsection (d)(1)(A) to address legitimate health issues, such as any male or female reproductive cancers, apart from changing the body to correspond to a sex that differs from one’s biological sex.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H75698402E8BF4FB6BFB13E8A48C910D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending the table of sections for such chapter by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCA8024B02D1E47EB895574E2566ED8E2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">2260B. Gender affirming care on minors.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="HDF0E22E63FD94930BD2C12C85775503C"><enum>II</enum><header>Prohibiting Federally Funded Gender Affirming Care</header><section id="HB4E70321DBCA4137BC7F521A7D9D8B52"><enum>201.</enum><header>Prohibiting taxpayer-funded gender affirming care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title 1, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new chapter: </text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EDEC56B0D46425EA955E08719934273" style="USC"><chapter id="H18F247937DE845B8BB02948AA3A4F6A7"><enum>4</enum><header>Prohibiting taxpayer-funded gender affirming care</header><toc container-level="chapter-container" idref="H18F247937DE845B8BB02948AA3A4F6A7" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="H430EC2696C044AC0830EED6D41C82F82" level="section">301. Prohibition on funding for gender affirming care.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDF92573383B24A27900152D4B2D208BB" level="section">302. Prohibition on funding for health benefits plans that cover gender affirming care.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H67A781966B37489DAD503D8022C2CF64" level="section">303. Limitation on Federal facilities and employees, Federal lands and territories, and Tribal territories.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H91917B848D9940B9BF758C525C17BD25" level="section">304. Construction relating to separate coverage.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H03A8A34E61AF4EB586B1386F33F39641" level="section">305. Construction relating to the use of non-Federal funds for health coverage.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9C087A15B9144FABABD6CFF495016FEC" level="section">306. Construction relating to complications arising from gender affirming care.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H55F2628FCD3F4AF5A60CC483C9F2BDAD" level="section">307. Treatment of individuals born with medically verifiable disorder of sex development.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBF5D4EB9BE6B47A993E31414CB774186" level="section">308. Gender affirming care defined.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD8497D41C1CD497F82586AE2B2F61258" level="section">309. Rule of construction.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H430EC2696C044AC0830EED6D41C82F82"><enum>301.</enum><header>Prohibition on funding for gender affirming care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds authorized or appropriated by Federal law, and none of the funds in any trust fund to which funds are authorized or appropriated by Federal law, including funds provided under titles XVIII, XIX, and XXI of the Social Security Act, shall be expended for any gender affirming care.</text></section><section id="HDF92573383B24A27900152D4B2D208BB"><enum>302.</enum><header>Prohibition on funding for health benefits plans that cover gender affirming care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds authorized or appropriated by Federal law, and none of the funds in any trust fund to which funds are authorized or appropriated by Federal law, shall be expended for health benefits coverage that includes coverage of gender affirming care.</text></section><section id="H67A781966B37489DAD503D8022C2CF64"><enum>303.</enum><header>Limitation on Federal facilities and employees, Federal lands and territories, and Tribal territories</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No health care service furnished—</text><paragraph id="H56331B178E944091B630A06DCF05A599"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by or in a health care facility owned or operated by the Federal Government, Federal land or territory, or a Tribal territory; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05A461B0E00B4977854609FAC9242A25"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by any physician or other individual employed by the Federal Government, Federal land or territory, or a Tribal territory to provide health care services within the scope of the physician’s or individual’s employment,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="section">may include gender affirming care. </continuation-text></section><section id="H91917B848D9940B9BF758C525C17BD25"><enum>304.</enum><header>Construction relating to separate coverage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as prohibiting any individual, entity, or State or locality from purchasing separate coverage for gender affirming care or health benefits coverage that includes gender affirming care so long as such coverage is paid for entirely using only funds not authorized or appropriated by Federal law, federal programs, platforms, or infrastructure, such coverage does not cover any practice that would be subject to penalty under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code, and such coverage shall not be purchased using matching funds required for a federally subsidized program, including a State’s or locality’s contribution of Medicaid matching funds.</text></section><section id="H03A8A34E61AF4EB586B1386F33F39641"><enum>305.</enum><header>Construction relating to the use of non-Federal funds for health coverage</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as restricting the ability of any non-Federal health benefits coverage provider from offering coverage for gender affirming care, or the ability of a State or locality to contract separately with such a provider for such coverage, so long as only funds not authorized or appropriated by Federal law are used, such coverage does not cover any practice that would be subject to penalty under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code, and such coverage shall not be purchased using matching funds required for a federally subsidized program, including a State’s or locality’s contribution of Medicaid matching funds.</text></section><section id="H9C087A15B9144FABABD6CFF495016FEC"><enum>306.</enum><header>Construction relating to complications arising from gender affirming care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed to apply to the treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that has been caused by or exacerbated by the performance of a gender affirming care. This rule of construction shall be applicable without regard to whether the gender affirming care was performed in accord with Federal or State law, and without regard to whether funding for the gender affirming care is permissible under section 307.</text></section><section id="H55F2628FCD3F4AF5A60CC483C9F2BDAD"><enum>307.</enum><header>Treatment of individuals born with medically verifiable disorder of sex development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The limitations established in sections 301, 302, and 303 shall not apply with respect to an individual described in section 2260B(d)(1)(B) of title 18, United States Code.</text></section><section id="HBF5D4EB9BE6B47A993E31414CB774186"><enum>308.</enum><header>Gender affirming care defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this chapter, the term <term>gender affirming care</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2260B(d)(1) of title 18, United States Code.</text></section><section id="HD8497D41C1CD497F82586AE2B2F61258"><enum>309.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this chapter shall be construed as prohibiting provision of the medical services described in section 2260B(d)(1)(A) of title 18, United States Code, to address any male or female reproductive cancers, apart from changing the body to correspond to a sex that differs from one’s biological sex.</text></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H59668286328F401AA1AD738E36CDA363"><enum>202.</enum><header>Amendment to table of chapters</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of chapters for title 1, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2221097894F149F9B9D1B5FE4178E270" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><multi-column-toc-entry bold="on" level="section"><toc-enum>4.</toc-enum><level-header bold="on" level="section">Prohibiting taxpayer-funded gender affirming care</level-header><target>301</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="H2E2F3A1A3E044972BD6EFCB3012A89F4"><enum>III</enum><header>Application under the Affordable Care Act</header><section id="H060DA4667D9546E8B9359386DE84E27A"><enum>301.</enum><header>Clarifying application of prohibition to premium credits and cost-sharing reductions under ACA</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1EE2356CFE164EAD9A34FC8EE2757B6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HC709E736179F4D26AB918891B44D179E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disallowance of refundable credit and cost-sharing reductions for coverage under qualified health plan which provides coverage for gender affirming care</header><subparagraph id="H5DC4825F46DF4789B6D5807848F03A43"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36B">section 36B(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>or any health plan that includes coverage for gender affirming care (other than any gender affirming care or treatment described in section 306 or 307 of title 1, United States Code)</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28C5DED56FA841B58F5744FF2831FBE5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Option to purchase or offer separate coverage or plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (3) of section 36B(c) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA4B2A266A714900BE4FCD6EFF5FF4F0" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HE04C3E36B58843B8BB2BF2157308424B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Separate coverage or plan for gender affirming care allowed</header><clause id="H7BCE1E6FCF7148D29197E703E615BAD2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Option to purchase separate coverage or plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed as prohibiting any individual from purchasing separate coverage for gender affirming care described in such subparagraph, or a health plan that includes such gender affirming care, so long as no credit is allowed under this section with respect to the premiums for such coverage or plan and such coverage or plan does not cover any practice that would be subject to penalty under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="H92E50EBB17084F9785DDEA9728B0FBF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Option to offer coverage or plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall restrict any non-Federal health insurance issuer offering a health plan from offering separate coverage for gender affirming care described in such subparagraph, or a plan that includes such gender affirming care, so long as premiums for such separate coverage or plan are not paid for with any amount attributable to the credit allowed under this section (or the amount of any advance payment of the credit under section 1412 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act) and such coverage or plan does not cover any practice that would be subject to penalty under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1990D5B3AB674258ADF690683741BC1A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disallowance of small employer health insurance expense credit for plan which includes coverage for gender affirming care</header><text>Subsection (h) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45R">section 45R</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H110D0243EF214F77899386DEC9134C66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Any term</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H53EE96CBF6784D6C9222F58EFED3E7AC" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE5D0B7779FD84A4CA160CB28EBABEC97"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any term</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC269D800C7048A395E311731B871D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62956170AAB64429B1955BE215CBE29F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HAA59DB62D2C940A89E093166E8A59DBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion of health plans including coverage for gender affirming care</header><subparagraph id="H5384CA1057A94F4ABD3F69418F2339B8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified health plan</term> does not include any health plan that includes coverage for gender affirming care (other than any gender affirming care or treatment described in section 306 or 307 of title 1, United States Code).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2B7AFC0AEFD46CCA18DABDF5A55AF25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Separate coverage or plan for gender affirming care allowed</header><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF71DDA30A4D44978B34F93D9FD90EB6B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Option to purchase separate coverage or plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed as prohibiting any employer from purchasing for its employees separate coverage for gender affirming care described in such subparagraph, or a health plan that includes such gender affirming care, so long as no credit is allowed under this section with respect to the employer contributions for such coverage or plan and such coverage does not cover any practice that would be subject to penalty under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="H23670E4E96CF42A392881235AAA0F355"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Option to offer coverage or plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall restrict any non-Federal health insurance issuer offering a health plan from offering separate coverage for gender affirming care described in such subparagraph, or a plan that includes such gender affirming care, so long as such separate coverage or plan is not paid for with any employer contribution eligible for the credit allowed under this section and such coverage or plan does not cover any practice that would be subject to penalty under section 2260B of title 18, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42426E730B804D2F970AD6472754F192"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to multi-State plans</header><text>Section 1334(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18054">42 U.S.C. 18054(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA07EE41F0794569AA7CBF8474A5C4F2" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HB0BE05F0E98C4324B2F9D1972790381E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Coverage consistent with Federal policy regarding gender affirming care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In entering into contracts under this subsection, the Director shall ensure that no multi-State qualified health plan offered in an Exchange provides health benefits coverage for which the expenditure of Federal funds is prohibited under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/1/4">chapter 4</external-xref> of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5DDBAE6FBB3F42268436542A63E118CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall apply to taxable years ending after the date that is one year after the date of enactment of this Act, but only with respect to plan years beginning after such date, and the amendment made by subsection (b) shall apply to plan years beginning after such date.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HA9643FFE7CB64AB5BA07AEE488F816AB"><enum>IV</enum><header>Additional Provisions</header><section id="H9FC93ED1062744F7AD9A16874C6FC2FC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><header>Prohibition on institutions of higher education and accrediting agencies or associations</header><subsection id="H8C8289C762A741E1A5A6A3EC8B8815E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on institutions of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3E8BC5BCF96D4F3295FC350CF251E028" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HDB63798A6EEF4A6EB439F4747132286D"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will not offer instruction in gender-affirming care (as defined in section 2260B(d) of title 18, United States Code).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC901C85C6CD34BF7897D73B4423BFD5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on accrediting agencies or associations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 496(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFAFAAC1B00BA4006AA0ECE4DB329492F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (7); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF9C591FF0341649AA028060681AB19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (8) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11FCF55C830C41ABABDFDE8FA460B240"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF505D6AE69BC4CCD910CBE9BBC4725CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3552005B1CBF4E7BAE00C118C8A7C3AD"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such agency or association does not accredit any institution that offers instruction in gender-affirming care (as defined in section 2260B(d) of title 18, United States Code).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H42E1BE346CAA40E7B4D9AA078A988DD1"><enum>402.</enum><header>Immigration consequences with respect to providing gender affirming care</header><subsection id="H6A6BBEE1DB1047F7979E0A550CE31D59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3DCF5BDFB7C1493CAE77BAFBB7F9644F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB1D62C8020A449EE8D3A930E0A81ED12"><enum>(53)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gender affirming care</term> shall have the meaning given such term in section 2260B(d) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDB84D2E54DCC48FC8D03A7DCA26A893B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Classes of Aliens Ineligible for Visas or Admission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(a)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6A66E769D6E44AE1A83C94D0E33E50CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (iii)(II), strike <quote>or</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF42A6CCF30430AA79F8510ABA1A216"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iv), strike the comma at the end and insert <quote>, or</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99B2F2B2C34A4FE39B1BEF5FE41A951D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCB0AB3293CB44A638E651AC2276850DA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H850E18D82FAE4F648E0EF5958B8A3F66"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who is determined to have performed gender affirming care on a child that has not attained the age of 18 years old, </text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EAAE4D8924540AF978875EC84A85603"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Classes of Deportable Aliens</header><text>Section 237(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFDBD393D8D31452E89F69982671BFD1A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H608B8EE74B0B48E8B866B26AE29EDFCA"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Gender affirming care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien who has performed gender affirming care on a child that has not attained the age of 18 years old is deportable.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

