<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEA55349F968D4FB2B5A34DC4CD40DE1B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6930 IH: Asset Seizure for Ukraine Reconstruction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6930</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220303">March 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the confiscation of assets subject to United States jurisdiction of certain foreign persons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H35D96DA0C1EF4218B1BFA7D93EAC3636" style="OLC"><section id="H38EBCBD9C08B454F929CAB1D5A541A55" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Asset Seizure for Ukraine Reconstruction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H70511B964CC847C3A73D3D01A58E5A8D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Presidential authorities with respect to the conflict in Ukraine</header><subsection id="H7FC2765DCFB7425189F5A51881A3E2DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President upon determination that Russia remains engaged in a conflict of territorial conquest in Ukraine, may, by means of instructions, licenses, or other regulations as may be promulgated, confiscate any property or accounts subject to the jurisdiction of the United States and valued over $5,000,000 of any foreign person described in subsection (b). All rights, title, and interest in any property so confiscated shall vest, upon the terms directed by the President, in such agency or person as the President may designate from time to time, and upon such terms and conditions as the President may prescribe. Such interest or property may be held, used, administered, liquidated, or sold, by such agency or person and such designated agency or person may perform any and all acts incident to the accomplishment or furtherance of these purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H83C3E38EBDE44687BAC3158E1E3D52E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign person described</header><text>A foreign person described in this subsection is a foreign person—</text><paragraph id="H528CEB01A62D41CD9B5FC1FAAD548D65"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whose wealth, according to credible information, is derived in part through corruption linked to or political support for the regime of Russian President Vladimir Putin; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48E6A69184B349129E5284BC6D3BE35C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to which the President has imposed sanctions relating to corruption, human rights violations, Russian malign influence, or conflicts in Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H932405A301B04CDEB2B98FF92561E873"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Liquidated Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any funds derived from liquidation or sales pursuant to subsection (a) shall be used solely for the benefit of the people of Ukraine, for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="HADAF2F8A84D64C77A9D258A9886D04F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Post-conflict reconstruction in Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A1E3138CA4F40628ECFAFDD30C4EEFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Humanitarian assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDEC61330DDB4EEBBE223FA975EC0076"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Weapons for the uniformed military forces of the elected Government of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C821A066E3E4E9B93971A4E62B1EA52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provisions to support refugees and refugee resettlement in neighboring countries and in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FC1C2B15EC94500B51019DDFB614BB9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Technology items and services to ensure the free flow of information to the Ukrainian people in Ukraine, including items to counter internet censorship by Russian authorities, to circumvent efforts to shut down internet or communication services by Russian authorities, to bolster cybersecurity capabilities of Ukrainian Government or non-governmental organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE583D0B2D7D54510AF5E3772F97F12AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Humanitarian and development assistance for the Russian people, including democracy and human rights programming and monitoring.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H591E76528A714248BF070355AE3F63EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority provided by subsection (a) shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

