<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0772B88A2F3343F1833A0925668C26D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6996 IH: Accelerating Access for Patients Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6996</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. Rodgers of Washington</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act with respect to the accelerated approval of a product for a serious or life-threatening disease or condition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC95E02C7E78243FCB2C2BAB8992CE587" style="OLC"><section id="HDFE8535DA52C48C08CAA8DAF51820946" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accelerating Access for Patients Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7009CF9633764B9AB1522F3C38A22DF6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Accelerated approval</header><subsection id="HD250CEDFC872435C830F6B2F42398784"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 506 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356">21 U.S.C. 356</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9CAD58A680594449A585B35272D3D438" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H1EE750E3EFAC49FCA3CA2E2EDB9DEB0E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Accelerated approval of a drug for a serious or life-Threatening disease or condition, including a fast track product</header><paragraph id="H6DE5BEB14E6248E1A5D6271B7764902D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H2E4ECD8DB4A44FB7833405E5DDEA0D5B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Accelerated approval</header><text>The Secretary may approve an application for approval of a product for a serious or life-threatening disease or condition, including a fast track product, under section 505(c) of this Act or section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act upon a determination—</text><clause id="HA69DE665BFAA4C95B41BAF3CA9318166"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the product has an effect on a surrogate endpoint that is reasonably likely to predict clinical benefit, or on a clinical endpoint that can be measured earlier than irreversible morbidity or mortality, that is reasonably likely to predict an effect on irreversible morbidity or mortality or other clinical benefit, taking into account the severity, rarity, or prevalence of the disease or condition and the availability or lack of alternative treatments; or</text></clause><clause id="HB0C7D1859F0A4545823545FED89EEA4D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of the safety and effectiveness of the product based on the known benefit-risk profile of such product in the intended population, taking into account the severity, rarity, or prevalence of the disease or condition and the availability or lack of alternative treatments.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A5873B1C5044B49B8B83E4EA634D5B3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Comprehensive clinical development plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish procedures by which a sponsor of a product seeking approval described in subparagraph (A) may meet with appropriate officials of the Food and Drug Administration to develop a plan to provide clarity and certainty for the sponsor regarding the applicability of the requirements of this subsection. Such a plan shall include—</text><clause id="H4F3457AA96E346278826F834A7BE1797"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a determination as to whether the product subject to such approval is intended to treat an unmet medical need;</text></clause><clause id="H4AD4E48DBDC64CFDA0FCA4D49531651C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an agreement on the surrogate or intermediate clinical endpoint to be assessed, if applicable;</text></clause><clause id="H841493D471B3409792523C179AA7A449"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an agreement on the design of the studies to be conducted to support the approval;</text></clause><clause id="H517AACA890AF46C482A7C57B04906670"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for a postapproval study to satisfy paragraph (2)(A), if required, including a plan for reaching agreement on the design of any such study;</text></clause><clause id="HEAB72CDFE80A49FD9CD24D34D13F1AC1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a plan for reaching agreement on the types of developmental milestones to be met; and</text></clause><clause id="HA0E5C56F7E484922A2D1EDB5FA249467"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a strategy for the inclusion of diverse populations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1370CC9570854FC58084896FFFC99973"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evidence</header><text>The evidence to support that an endpoint is reasonably likely to predict clinical benefit under subparagraph (A)(i) may include epidemiological, pathophysiological, therapeutic, pharmacologic, or other evidence developed using biomarkers, for example, or other scientific methods or tools.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0099CF0647494A3B9761B05B1D901169"><enum>(D)</enum><header>References</header><text>In this section, approval described in subparagraph (A) is referred to as <quote>accelerated approval</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4B3A99A3C634EDCB6273F9F5022F10F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Approval of a product under this subsection may be subject to 1 or both of the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="HA50257C9B9904FD289A064E60BDB6F66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">That the sponsor conduct appropriate postapproval studies (which may include clinical evidence, patient registries, or other sources of real world evidence) to verify and describe the predicted effect on irreversible morbidity or mortality or other clinical benefit.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59180972A3F04BD08F54A3B2323CC275"><enum>(B)</enum><text>That the sponsor submit copies of all promotional materials related to the product during the preapproval review period and, following approval and for such period thereafter as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, at least 30 days prior to dissemination of the materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFDD8DB741854B719FD3BEBAA7DCE5DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue—</text><subparagraph id="H5FA3FABD0A3F4036A3868810432A9277"><enum>(A)</enum><text>guidance describing criteria, processes, and other general considerations for demonstrating the safety and effectiveness of drugs submitted for approval described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A9CB505E8044BA6A81B3C774D8CE6B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">guidance on the use of novel clinical trial designs that may be used to conduct appropriate postapproval studies as may be required under paragraph (2)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE759A77BDB4944038F5C79713C5F79E1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Approval of study protocol</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 calendar days after the submission by the sponsor of a product of a proposed protocol for a postapproval study required under paragraph (2)(A), the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4E4D688CC59D43059B13D3DEDBFCDFC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approve the protocol; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB62F00F2DC5348E88C288F98EBF745D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify changes to the protocol that would enable such approval. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB4432AB883D49ADB82DFEE1BCFF5BC4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expedited withdrawal of approval</header><text>The Secretary may withdraw approval of a product approved under accelerated approval using expedited procedures (as prescribed by the Secretary in regulations which shall include an opportunity for an informal hearing) if—</text><subparagraph id="H790B53F7A0B84716A6F76C0509DE5D72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sponsor fails to conduct any required postapproval study of the product with due diligence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45862D6E350641BBA90A047C083BC89E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a study required to verify and describe the predicted effect on irreversible morbidity or mortality or other clinical benefit of the product fails to verify and describe such effect or benefit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0861F66E23E84D8EBD0C917D50735D07"><enum>(C)</enum><text>other evidence demonstrates that the product is not safe or effective under the conditions of use; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DFB299B7B2A4CEABE321B005A1511ED"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the sponsor disseminates false or misleading promotional materials with respect to the product.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD2E2A0A79124A46A7A4AF32505E6FBF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Accelerating Access for Patients Act of 2022</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report describing—</text><subparagraph id="H26613F5D2F364A3284BBED4259A72AD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the circumstances and number of applications submitted for approval described in paragraph (1)(A) for which real world evidence was deemed appropriate to support or fulfill postapproval studies required under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8DECBE810E84862979CB1863A5DDDB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the circumstances and number of applications submitted for approval described in paragraph (1)(A) for which real world evidence was submitted for such postapproval studies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H019882915E8E4AA492E8C35E1C606739"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial guidance</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs—</text><paragraph id="HDBD482964A844C9B8986EBAA521D706D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall issue draft guidance pursuant to section 506(c)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as amended by subsection (a), not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89CFD982000440CE98093C28FDCF1996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall promulgate final guidance pursuant to such section 506(c)(3) not later than 18 months after the close of the public comment period on such draft guidance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB77F092F3584791A111CA64BC014CD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may approve products as described in section 506(c)(1)(A) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act, as amended by subsection (a), prior to issuing initial draft or final guidance under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

