<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0BE18697D8934A688C5A1B6A2CDAC721" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9002 IH: Veterans’ Cancer Care Coordinator Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9002</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a pilot program for gynecologic cancer care coordination at the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H478370B356294A159D0BE121E3B16DE1" style="OLC"><section id="H6113494982A8412192375CBCF44973C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans’ Cancer Care Coordinator Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBE372FAB133542409CDFF8699C58AFB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on gynecologic cancer care coordination</header><subsection id="H146C0B2B79324397B97E1B4AE7D2732F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall establish a pilot program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) for gynecologic cancer care coordination at the Department of Veterans Affairs, including through the designation of a gynecologic cancer care coordinator of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA7EF84BCC0954C08A20FBDB3DF8D0CE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible participants</header><text>A veteran is eligible to participate in the program if the veteran—</text><paragraph id="H55A52215AE2F437AAC2EB35B155638F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has been diagnosed with a gynecologic cancer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CB07DB137BE46B7843C7BA7BC5C743E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is eligible for health care furnished through the Veterans Community Care Program under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, at a non-Department facility.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H573CD59E2ADB4BC2B631FB9A29857E78"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall select not fewer than five medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs at which to carry out the Program, including one medical center that primarily serves rural veterans, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0531DE2F1A8C4F26B1BFB075A1F6C03D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties of gynecologic cancer care coordinator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the Program, the designated gynecologic cancer care coordinator shall be responsible for carrying out the following duties:</text><paragraph id="HE907BD468B714012BE1DFF3146317707"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring the coordination of care between—</text><subparagraph id="HC6E92D1C8E24420389FAEDB804A83D76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>clinicians of the Department and community gynecologic cancer care providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0387054461F4B3CBC12AE63546959BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clinicians of the Department, Women’s Veteran Program Managers, and Women’s Health Medical Directors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H382CF63DAF724D7B9984E40D344B4B7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other relevant clinicians of the Department and community care providers who provide care to participating veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F6A5F94324F41BE8CA55552D187EA1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Working with the Office of Community Care of the relevant medical facility of the Department regarding authorizations of care in the community, including for participating veterans whose mental health screening results indicate the presence of military sexual trauma, depression, domestic or intimate partner violence, or post-traumatic stress disorder.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H545FA3D146114B1BA10FD88A006FF836"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Making regular contact with each participating veteran when the veteran receives care from a community care provider to evaluate the needs of the veteran, including through an assessment of the mental health of the veteran (including as such mental health and trauma history related to the cancer diagnosis of the veteran).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H903B8FA3360C45E0A36481304833395C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Monitoring—</text><subparagraph id="H9734ADCD55E54184831480EFE1945B91"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the services furnished under the Program to participating veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5402EFFF5C4441BBCFD140D9A996271"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the outcomes relating to the health of such participating veterans, including remission, metastasis, and death; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC41CD336F7543A884E8375EC6EE9602"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the data relating to gynecologic cancer care collected at a medical facility of the Department (using relevant databases of the Veterans Health Administration or other Department databases), including—</text><clause id="H6ADF998FA84F471C8C626C17832BEEAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demographics of participating veterans who have gynecologic cancer; and</text></clause><clause id="H73C4B1D52D3340719D8ECCE85951C052"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of participating veterans being treated for gynecologic cancer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEE67D7A64CF4D53839BE0351377E68C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Providing particular information to participating veterans, including—</text><subparagraph id="H4ABA62EECBC84BF3AEB10B2D445E1237"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to seek emergency care at the emergency department closest to the veteran, including the requirement for the veteran or the community care provider to notify the Department when the veteran receives emergency treatment relating to the cancer of the veteran for the Department to authorize payment for such emergency treatment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB99D18A752CE4458A62EF43A09C1BC2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about mental health resources, including with respect to information encouraging follow-up care for depression.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9351E7D135E497FAF4B40AC67E802FE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Documenting certain information in the electronic health records of participating veterans, including—</text><subparagraph id="HAFBBD923B8C0483CAEA43FC313B81B9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the documentation of the contact described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F0ECC03406542898DC920FDC51FD76E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the contact information of the community gynecologic cancer care providers of such participating veterans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFBDBB89B42D4510A10BFC6D7CF8D6CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the cancer diagnosis of such participating veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0D7B03A17C4422A027B12B93EB4945"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Carrying out such other duties as may be determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE0DF24B417F48ECBD8C259C132E2A9D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HD190477DF70F4BD7A05E3A2D69861202"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than two years after the date on which the Secretary commences the Program, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report containing the following:</text><subparagraph id="H9DA0470B45314F238295A7A7A70FA213"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A comparison of the outcomes of veterans who have participated in the Program to the outcomes of non-participating veterans described in paragraph (2), including with respect to the following:</text><clause id="HC1F1F601DED3401CAB81C11C1600CDA0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health outcomes, including (for the most recent two years of available data)—</text><subclause id="H55337B9CCB2C4451AADF5CBF7539993F" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of such veterans who have experienced a cancer-related death;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2359E5DD53BB4D05A1B257865DADBBE2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of such veterans who have entered remission for gynecologic cancer; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H38A7F57C254C41FBA65D78EB946EE85A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of such veterans who have been diagnosed with mental health disorders determined relevant by the Secretary for purposes of the comparison (including anxiety, depression, and post-traumatic stress disorder).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H69C60EA3ADCD4CF18B263CC9D7A9592A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timeliness of care furnished under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/17">chapter 17</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, including the average time that elapses between the initial diagnosis and each successive stage of treatment for gynecologic cancer.</text></clause><clause id="HB958E160850C45168EE23E851D1D52C8" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Patient safety associated with such care, including the number of errors in medical care that rise to the level of <quote>never events</quote> (such as a foreign body left in a veteran during surgery).</text></clause><clause id="HA5AEA667F9434950BD1416F6AF404510" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Patient satisfaction associated with such care, including the results of a patient satisfaction survey administered to such veterans on the receipt of adequate pain management from health care providers of the Department, mental health resources from such providers, and overall quality of such care.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01E2F7E107FC4539905501034CB3AD2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An evaluation of whether to expand the Program or make such Program permanent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39B8E3266E8B433EBCA51C597F66124D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other matter the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8601429C2D1B4FE58F5336F7EC92C534"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Non-participating veterans described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A non-participating veteran described in this paragraph is a female veteran who—</text><subparagraph id="HE34ECCC6495D4CEB8F899973578CB4F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has not participated in the Program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7427544A621485691888D7680C28BF1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department of Veterans Affairs established and operated under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31853FF872D84DA48C6509814FD4B162"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been diagnosed with gynecologic cancer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5C5AC5A6959411995F0B9E92EF20746"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="H0CDAE1B438F04043AFA1D6B19C2A35A4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>community care provider</term> means a health care provider located at a non-Department facility who provides care (other than care related to gynecologic cancer) to veterans under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, or any other law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF62768238B45E2BEF8DBFCEF15CF90"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community gynecologic cancer care provider</term> means a gynecologic cancer care provider located at a non-Department facility who provides care related to gynecologic cancer to veterans under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code, or any other law administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H589F950596334C9E91C3BF01ED037927"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gynecologic cancer</term> means cervical cancer, ovarian cancer, uterine cancer, vaginal cancer, and vulvar cancer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D21A3917A994AAA81BB4A4196726957"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>non-Department facilities</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1701 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEE606B747374C1D870AE61B68D8DFDE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>participating veteran</term> means a veteran who is participating in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5ECF0EA706844EB3B0BB85A46D801A20"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>Women’s Health Medical Director</term> means a Women’s Health Medical Director described in the directive of the Veterans Health Administration titled <quote>Health Care Services for Women Veterans</quote> (directive 1330.01), or any successor directive.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EA06F875A10486E8EC1E596BE93F321"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Women’s Veteran Program Manager</term> means a Women’s Veterans Program Manager described in the directive of the Veterans Health Administration titled <quote>Women Veterans Program Manager</quote> (directive 1330.02), or any successor directive. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

