<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFD360B40D1A94E4FAEC5164C1D5F2AF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8532 IH: Atrocity Crimes, Relief and Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8532</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220727">July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide assistance for suspected victims and witnesses of war crimes in Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H853A93F3FB9E4E70A0D3F8E79E468D6B" style="OLC"><section id="H23F3384A58254570B6731D22BF59C83D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Atrocity Crimes, Relief and Accountability Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ACRA Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H83E9738301424840A26A90A37669698D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HEEB6AD857C7C468085286D0D18C53169"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Russian Government’s war on Ukraine has exposed the systemic lack of compliance with international humanitarian law, jus in bello, on the part of the Russian military.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80EE6BFBBE3F4E24883EA0F6C918E625"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ukrainian civilians have been actively targeted by Russian troops, compounding their needless suffering and forcing non-combatants into a state of terror.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBFD6A104CC240298ACA73C31DDAC57A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>These barbaric ways of war are inconsistent with five key principles of the law of armed conflict: distinction, proportionality, military necessity, hors de combat and unnecessary suffering.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCBD90216A60488CA14154921F8E045A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It is vital that Russian war criminals are brought to justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EBA38470C344786A158AB2A8C31CE1E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A key component of any atrocity crimes investigation includes the accurate and reliable testimony of witnesses. As war crimes judicial proceedings could take years, and cross many national jurisdictions, investigators must protect and have ready access to potential witnesses for a long period of time. Within the first 100 days of the war, over 11 million people – one quarter of Ukraine’s 44 million population – had been displaced from their homes, including five million people who fled the country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H702BA998490E49229ACFF0DB49A089F0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>There is reasonable concern that suspected atrocity crimes victims and survivors are less likely to testify as witnesses in potential legal proceedings, as they may be in danger of intimidation or not stay actively engaged due to lack of a support structure to sustain a lengthy investigation and trial, or as a result of having fled the country in which the atrocities were committed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBE1EB9DB90C4445B94D2DC894ED407A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Legal experts and civil society groups have identified an immediate need for supporting and protecting victims, survivors and witnesses of atrocity crimes, no matter where they are located, including ensuring such efforts are coordinated to minimize the risk of retraumatizing survivors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF37597356D4549C8B63A241A667F540D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Without requisite support, victims and survivors are less likely to accept the onerous burden of testifying against criminals, undermining their ability to attain some justice for their suffering, and reducing the ability to hold war criminals accountable for their actions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC0100AA5A845D4B15E60E9C9AA080D"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Therefore, it is necessary that the United States assist relevant authorities and civil society groups in protecting and supporting this vulnerable population within Ukraine and across borders.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H41279A56E71C4FEE8720D043FE83B6CC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of assistance for suspected victims and witnesses of war crimes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(d)(1) of the Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8926">22 U.S.C. 8926(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1FCC22E23A0B4EEBA3A17D1D442F9E2F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EAF6054AAC84CA3AE74176B443902DB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F948FFD445D4068B77DDC55056004E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6FE248D63D8643879B1243CF6CE9F876" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H1499FAA512CE4834977CCADA390683CA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide support for suspected victims, survivors, and witnesses of atrocity crimes, wherever located, through direct or in-kind assistance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H631A8EF688CF4053A0A68566D2883898"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide assistance to the Ukrainian Prosecutor General, the war crimes units of the Office of the Prosecutor General and other appropriate Ukrainian judicial and law enforcement authorities to support accountability through the documentation, investigation, and prosecution of atrocity crimes.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H26ED5DB47D6A43EE9E4A09F6133D1E6F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of assistance with respect to the prosecution of war crimes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of the Ukraine Freedom Support Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/8926">22 U.S.C. 8926</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEAC1DBE4C3534E3F972A4C01D342BA73" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7101DCA75F6148B59FF2162C77960F5D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assistance for prosecution of war crimes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, or the head of any other appropriate Federal department or agency, may assign or detail, on a rotational basis, employees of such departments or agencies to advise, assist, and provide training to build the capacity of Ukrainian prosecutorial, law enforcement, forensic and judicial authorities, with respect to the prosecution of atrocity crimes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H557D08E4B6874E78A92F5CB5718B2C34"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Victims Trust Fund</header><paragraph id="HC2220CD5EEE44A1D876DFBB9C058848E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall establish a Ukraine Victims Trust Fund, to assist victims, survivors and witnesses during investigations and while awaiting judicial proceedings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H966EA53358994658A0ED146029E6AAE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rewards authorized</header><subparagraph id="HAE77E0A4033F467585110FE311CF9F50"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the sole discretion of the Secretary, the Secretary may pay assistance to any individual who—</text><clause id="HD152FCE8B92D447BAC5E91D3DFFD6961"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides credible information that they were a victim or witness of an atrocity crime;</text></clause><clause id="H454C5D7113B9422080A7669ACEDA74B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates the need for compensation while furnishing information on suspected criminals; and</text></clause><clause id="H2364AD90FB764B908FE3FF1D4555B59F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is awaiting trial in order to testify against their attacker.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92EAA5310921421DA8895032935B0C5D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible proceedings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of the authority provided by this subsection, the term <term>judicial proceedings</term> includes cases brought forth by the Ukrainian Prosecutor General, the International Criminal Court, or any United Nations-sanctioned tribunal with jurisdiction over the prosecution of atrocity crimes committed in Ukraine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70196CFAFBFF4148B5BFFEBB63F71168"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for the Ukraine Victims Trust Fund established under paragraph (1), which shall be authorized to remain available for 10 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20AB740FA3904FADBFE7C341D13899A7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Atrocity crimes rewards program</header><paragraph id="HF56BAEDA4C354CDA8F66AC8F38E08349"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall establish a Ukraine Atrocity Crimes Rewards Fund, under the War Crimes Rewards Program to assist in the prosecution of atrocity crimes committed in Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70626624FC484A4D8A61900CB4AB12ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rewards authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the sole discretion of the Secretary, the Secretary may pay a reward to any individual who furnishes information leading to the arrest or conviction in any country of any foreign person indicted with respect to the commission of atrocity crimes by the Ukrainian Prosecutor General, the International Criminal Court, or any United Nations-sanctioned tribunal with jurisdiction over the prosecution of atrocity crimes committed in Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H621592BFCEC248FB8032B5836647EA8A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for the Ukraine Victims Trust Fund established under paragraph (1), which shall be authorized to remain available for 10 years after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6A7ACB41A9F44481B4A12B0CE2A8A076"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of international criminal court and investigations with respect to the prosecution of atrocity crimes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2004(h) of the American Servicemembers Protection Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7423">22 U.S.C. 7423</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD21BAC2221714175B556892C39DDE614"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Agents</header-in-text>.—No agent</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H48F72FA360F34AF298F04B9CC61B63A2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Agents</header-in-text>.—</text><paragraph id="HDEF6104FBF2048EEA8D5D26FB6FF1E52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No agent</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H02C779030633426DA1BAC5BAB988DC2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>The prohibition in the preceding sentence shall not apply in the case of investigative activities that</quote></text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B6EE8AEFCF64A9E94947BB64E5AE55F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H127391BAB20E4D26839510F69F3A764E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to investigative activities that—</text><subparagraph id="H35751AE6721A47D1BB1C11E2C93E54E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifically target foreign nationals suspected of atrocity crimes on foreign soil;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86A98B6F7E204B1D80409F5B32438FE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are undertaken in coordination with the Attorney General; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87AA3132A76243E8B0CC1EF479964A7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relate solely to investigations of crimes occurring in Ukraine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4154571D8B48BB949982C4F90830BA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days before initiating investigative activities pursuant to the exception authorized by paragraph (2), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees written and electronic notice of—</text><subparagraph id="H278DECD2C4194E60B2C676A5CAB8E717"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the names of the investigators on behalf of the International Criminal Court who are entering the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E98F1C9177E4465BE9F8D938D31235F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the witnesses those investigators will meet; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E6B7CCF67054082A9C99AC81A5CBF3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the year in which the suspected crimes occurred.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

