<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H90300F31A150499FB607E950486B1C25" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7308 IH: Justice for Vaccine Victims Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7308</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000596">Mrs. Greene of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to investigate and report on the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H468F8D10AB054DB6AF6BE63605C69E84" style="OLC"><section id="H7E1F4965C60E4BB6973202FE9AFFBA53" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for Vaccine Victims Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1CC7E447F38046478F417447F317BB41"><enum>2.</enum><header>Investigation on Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System</header><subsection id="H2D4C85F6738445F9A338C96301865C0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall investigate the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and Food and Drug Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF698C40BADC4FCEAC5561B0314252FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required questions</header><paragraph id="H40CA6BE16095450AA6512016564A86BC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Individuals</header><subparagraph id="H4A2E46232C6045A3AA72671829372A7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In conducting the investigation under subsection (a), the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall ask every individual who reported an adverse event to a COVID–19 vaccine at a minimum the following questions:</text><clause id="H0A5C1CE4B75E47C2AE16ACE959A0CC61"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Which COVID–19 vaccine did you receive?</text></clause><clause id="HBFBAA6B42076436382A9FC0A561DAD37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Which vaccine did you receive as a booster shot?</text></clause><clause id="HFAD1474D1FDC4063830EF153DA666C3D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Do you have any allergies or preexisting conditions?</text></clause><clause id="H6F8EC482B13F48069EFF229B4D6BCEF4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Was the adverse event mild, such as minor pain or swelling, or severe, such as leading to hospitalization, disability, or death?</text></clause><clause id="H86B1F8580D504C949713F00D5A619804"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Can you describe in detail the symptoms of the adverse event?</text></clause><clause id="H91D0F06195F74BB78E5778EFF5B3094D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>In detail, can you describe any health problems you believe were caused by the adverse event?</text></clause><clause id="HC9B77B61FFB4461C84618362D9ABEC94"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Are you aware of any other individuals within your community who had a similar adverse event?</text></clause><clause id="H670862FC792A418BA57CB5C74C1FC40D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>When receiving a vaccination did you notice anything suspicious regarding how the vaccination was administered?</text></clause><clause id="H3E227E78DDD64DBC934292D758726864"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>How soon after the adverse event did you report it to the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System?</text></clause><clause id="H5B4F7C73DC8847E1AB2F20F468B099FE"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Did you seek compensation for the adverse event through the Countermeasures Injury Compensation Program?</text></clause><clause id="H62445BEEDD2C49B3948A6BBF1A143D1B"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Would you be willing to testify under oath to a congressional committee?</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7183521CFE546FF9DD0C38919E02994"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an individual described in subparagraph (A) is deceased, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall ask one or more of the individual’s immediate family members to answer (on the individual’s behalf) the questions listed in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EDB18D38BE04944B98B154F01E3AF5C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manufacturers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the investigation under subsection (a), the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall ask each manufacturer of a COVID–19 vaccine that is distributed in the United States, at a minimum, the following questions and requests:</text><subparagraph id="H7DAC3DE099544D66BEC9D84D81CDA833"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">What are the ingredients in your COVID–19 vaccine or vaccines distributed in the United States?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3C8E5E3F43F47D88010F560889346F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Can you provide all information relating to your manufacturing methods and your data on the stability and safety of the product?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18C04F897606465493504AF1F6186508"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">What is the address of each of your locations involved in the manufacture of the vaccines? </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H171D43CE0557429883D1BB4D780CAA79"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Did you include labeling of the vaccine or vaccines containing a specific statement describing how suspected adverse events can be reported?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE8057DF22694320A1BFFCB215B7AA35"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Can you provide substantive evidence you have followed all Food and Drug Administration guidance regarding product safety?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCA7DEB7C90940A4A82C65A25DD269CD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How many adverse events did you report to the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System pursuant to section 2125 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300aa-25">42 U.S.C. 300aa–25</external-xref>) or other applicable law?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA77BBAD815F545408B0AE50E4022FDCC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Are you conducting your own internal review of any adverse events caused by the vaccine or vaccines? </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FAFD7BC898E4BC79A6590A1EE284288"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Are you ensuring that all public statements regarding vaccine safety are accurate?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A33F894AE8A47DAA76CF8D6076FB359"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Are you limiting reporting data regarding adverse events?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8CC63793E6B41FF91D8F38247CE4D98"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Would you be willing to direct representatives to testify under oath to a congressional committee?</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07ACBB81CD3343DC9DCEB9C7C204AD26"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health care providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the investigation under subsection (a), the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall ask a representative sample of health care providers, at a minimum, the following questions:</text><subparagraph id="HDE4926535A09439E8F152FFB42F2552E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> How many adverse events did you report to the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System pursuant to section 2125 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300aa-25">42 U.S.C. 300aa–25</external-xref>) or other applicable law?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7517070888EC447886DB5D64F74F7B21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>What kind of compensation does your facility receive for vaccine administration and from which source or sources?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C1800DA3E7640BCA709C5DB63C59DF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Is your facility keeping a record of any increase in hospitalization rates for individuals with adverse events following vaccination? </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A19C049C47B4040920C5277AD209AE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>How many severe adverse events has your facility encountered?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6FC894B66C64FA3BCEE6202FF56FB1B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>How many mild adverse events has your facility encountered?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H401E89D5430D44F894E5F35C6301764A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Has your facility determined if adverse events are caused by an immune response to the vaccine?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17BF3607CDF843E3A63929AB091EB18B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Is your facility keeping a record of any problems with vaccine administration?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B60008C3B094215BEC1DFB208C573F3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Is your facility keeping a record of all breakthrough cases of COVID–19 in fully vaccinated patients?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6179EDAFF0A54A1C976C70357AF500E4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Has your facility terminated any health care professionals who are opposed to vaccine mandates or who have raised questions regarding adverse events?</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8A62FA5352D4AD3950A8C56DD69D2B3"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Would you be willing to direct representatives of your facility to testify under oath to a congressional committee?</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8945C50CBEE4C95B29F5222E9B9A7BC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HDE8E272C6BA141888CB0FE5AFB3BDE45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report on VAERS</header><subparagraph id="H86C9601F2C8A4CD29F20CEE18FBCF1DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall—</text><clause id="H2699D2E223DA44C89A273BCE1913288B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>complete the investigation under subsection (a); and</text></clause><clause id="HA97AE2B90B9C44E59657EF4DF6C39A9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>publish a report on the results of such investigation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D21126261243D7A5A1FEB341D9B4B4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall include the following:</text><clause id="H4DD4059C14A84C83BB450F8BE1B6AC37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A list of all reported COVID–19 vaccine related deaths and injuries in chronological order.</text></clause><clause id="H8AFCB2859D7B43838255108A94B6348D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Transcripts of all interviews conducted by the Inspector General pursuant to this section with an individual described in subsection (b)(1), a manufacturer described in subsection (b)(2), or a health care provider described in subsection (b)(3).</text></clause><clause id="HEBCD0534BC0C4D53BA6C90BC08858937"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of recommendations on how the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Food and Drug Administration can strengthen the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System to be a more reliable method of obtaining information about adverse events. </text></clause><clause id="HCE376A7CA4834487BFF03A0867A41A65"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A determination on whether the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention or the Food and Drug Administration is hiding data regarding adverse events.</text></clause><clause id="HA53332CA37EA4407886B0CF74006F7BD"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination on whether the Food and Drug Administration is suppressing data on the effectiveness of monoclonal antibodies that are used to treat COVID–19. </text></clause><clause id="H980809B6E433451481189EF20C971546"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Recommendations on further actions the Congress can take when conducting oversight regarding data collection by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Food and Drug Administration.</text></clause><clause id="HF34369E25CDE461C9B66B403887DA040"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination on whether adverse events are common or rare following administration of a COVID–19 vaccine.</text></clause><clause id="H8F262809D1C44442A6A6CB1B0D9F73E9"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>A determination of any causal relationship between any COVID–19 vaccine and specific adverse events using clinical, laboratory, or epidemiologic evidence.</text></clause><clause id="H8B8141D57AFA4D0DBA6196E6BD132EB3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A determination on whether adverse events are intrinsic to the COVID–19 vaccine (meaning provoked by the immune response caused by the vaccine) or related to faulty production or administration of the COVID–19 vaccine.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63217220987F43E0B79BBD12AA26BF5B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on investigation</header><subparagraph id="H96A8FEBA8C20456594574D7EDB7C7C30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after publishing the report required by paragraph (1)(A)(ii), the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the implementation of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFF72748983645B59DE3F3BB8B006FD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subparagraph (A) shall—</text><clause id="HF7FCD9A5E289453D9AF8F2F40AC2B237"><enum>(i)</enum><text>specify, of the amount authorized by subsection (c)(1) to be appropriated to carry out this section, the total amount obligated and expended; and</text></clause><clause id="H30B9AAD88BE4470982054ABAA70EC41B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>describe how such amount was used.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B819F2F66E8447C840BA0B5B681D8CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subpoena power</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services may, pursuant to authorities vested in the Inspector General by other applicable law, issue subpoenas requiring the attendance and testimony of witnesses and the production of any evidence relating to any matter under investigation pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H03FD6B66B7B4451AA5A727D4A335081B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H30B792635B8B490EA387D55ECF967270"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date of submission of the report required by subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49D6A1D9DD2B4FC9AA9513B64EF82B89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offset</header><subparagraph id="H16C985142A794630A9FCEEED7BE5435D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Repeal of deduction for certain State and local, etc., taxes of individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/164">Section 164(b)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by—</text><clause id="H4D487A9763FE486A8C449C8AD2A3E63E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>striking <quote>and before January 1, 2026—</quote> and all that follows through <quote>a separate return).</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of subsection (a) and paragraph (5) of this subsection shall not apply.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H22A89BD6921C45C496DAC7CC5D180C1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">for taxable years 2018 through 2025</header-in-text></quote> in the heading thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3248C6382E3B4F15AD8145E742F71DF6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this paragraph shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF5AB5B1A6B8F468F9441320FA9D0EEC9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Termination of COVID–19 public health emergency declaration under Public Readiness and Emergency Preparedness (PREP) Act</header><subsection id="H05B04DBE31C642F2AED8482DC172A095"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text><paragraph id="H38E3A79FBB4B4044BAED8EACF351B403"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 3 months after the date of enactment of this Act, terminate the public health emergency declaration issued in connection with COVID–19 pursuant to section 319F–3 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d-6d">42 U.S.C. 247d–6d</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H834E5A705F1B424DB7BFBB878A51591E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not reissue any such declaration or any substantially similar declaration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABF89542C32747C78C1B779CB4805DCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Corresponding termination of liability protection</header><text>No immunity from suit and liability under section 319F–3 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d-6d">42 U.S.C. 247d–6d</external-xref>) shall apply with respect to the administration to or the use by an individual of a covered countermeasure if—</text><paragraph id="H158CF5A6B8954C138ED92D32E1CD141C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the immunity relies on a declaration described in subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFC2B54E17394317B8DAD6114E986C9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the administration or use occurs after such declaration is terminated,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">except that the Secretary of Health and Human Services, pursuant to section 319F–3(b)(3)(B) of such Act (42 U.S.C. 247d–6d(b)(3)(B)), shall specify an additional immunity period of 3 months for the manufacturer to arrange for disposition of the covered countermeasure and for covered persons to take such other actions as may be appropriate to limit administration or use of the covered countermeasure, as described in clauses (i) and (ii) of such section 319F–3(b)(3)(B). </continuation-text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

