<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H85FB73A25F4046A092EDB0EF81B039D9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1934 EH: Promoting United States International Leadership in 5G Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1934</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Federal Government to provide assistance and technical expertise to enhance the representation and leadership of the United States at international standards-setting bodies that set standards for equipment, systems, software, and virtually defined networks that support 5th and future generations mobile telecommunications systems and infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HABD48F25E1504887840C513BE0521544" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3BE424381B74477BB4BF58388DC69832" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting United States International Leadership in 5G Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H84B791E3A7994A5FB85D9613A2F4EF61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB09A12D3EE204728BDF90A716FAE66BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and its allies and partners should maintain participation and leadership at international standards-setting bodies for 5th and future generations mobile telecommunications systems and infrastructure;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2BFF79C356D41BFACD294BDD27C36A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should work with its allies and partners to encourage and facilitate the development of secure supply chains and networks for 5th and future generations mobile telecommunications systems and infrastructure; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H648B402BF0704F9DB99574961244DC3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the maintenance of a high standard of security in telecommunications and cyberspace between the United States and its allies and partners is a national security interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H2FB0207839BA4FEAA0184C6E5F9BD14F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enhancing representation and leadership of the United States at international standards-setting bodies</header> <subsection id="H5DBB7D1701DA4985B8B256C270BA3EB8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall establish an interagency working group to work with allies and international partners to increase and align their engagement at multilateral international organizations, such as the International Telecommunications Union (ITU), that address communications networks, standards, and security, including 5th and future generations mobile telecommunications and infrastructure.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H23935E9BDFDE4DF5A4B2D560D5B6E151"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interagency working group</header><text>The interagency working group described in subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD7C669FFD52648FBAEF92715F6D4C78B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be chaired by the Secretary of State or a designee of the Secretary of State; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA96204C01A4E42C9B0F0551C8250A707"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consist of the head (or designee) of the Department of Commerce and each Federal department or agency the President determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7B592F18B2D843409B2ED0AC97D55CFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Function</header><text>The Secretary of State shall coordinate with the members of the interagency working group to develop and implement a strategy for diplomatic engagement with allies and partners and monitor engagement by the Government of the People’s Republic of China and entities under its ownership, control, or influence at multilateral international organizations described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE03CB9752A134BC8A809D1CE0A3BD66A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the interagency working group shall provide to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a briefing that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H741C508105524C378674850758469CC4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a strategy for diplomatic engagement with allies and partners to share security risk information and findings pertaining to equipment that supports or is used in 5th and future generations mobile telecommunications systems and infrastructure and cooperation on mitigating such risks; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H761B5EDC3D144BDE9FCE43D43F796D50"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a discussion of China’s presence and activities at multilateral international organizations described in subsection (a) relevant to 5th and future generation mobile telecommunications systems and infrastructure, including information on the differences in the scope and scale of China’s engagement, as well as the success rate of proposals by Chinese entities adopted into standards at such organizations compared to the engagement and success rate of proposals adopted by the United States or its allies and partners, and noting any mandatory domestic Chinese standards that are adopted at such organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220714" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 14, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

