<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1AB2177FAF3B4F889E0A7B23D0C8D758" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7554 IH: Offshore Wind for Northeastern Energy Revenue Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220421">April 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To distribute revenue from offshore wind projects in the New York Bight Area to certain coastal States, and promote conservation and workforce development.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE39E10FF11904A9DA8081A1ECE236A7A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2EC232C852944F63AD23B15823801AAA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Wind for Northeastern Energy Revenue Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>OWNER Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HE5345F820A11425AA2B8486288F66F55"><enum>2.</enum><header>Parity in offshore wind revenue sharing within the New York Bight Area</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8(p)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(p)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2D7D19AEF6964D3090A3D16BAEC4F268"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(A)</enum-in-header></header-in-text> The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE8708418F82A4CCBA5822B5D57931273" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H8EA6A25C5FD9408A8B155D570B521755"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), the Secretary</text> </subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F18202BEFE94E9A88773AD8042EBE2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(B)</enum-in-header></header-in-text> The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H34F70BDECCFC46DC9216807E1474E518" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H1F1B6A5533504F6486EC02210578BA72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Disposition of revenues from projects located within 3 nautical miles seaward of State submerged land</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06C718FFC6C646FD8E795AFB83F8A979"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFD0313A7DC0D4522A7EDCA7C8E8A7898" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HDEC0ECD6655343B095F9D40DCA7A13C2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disposition of revenues from offshore wind projects in certain areas</header> <clause id="H7C3593BD1F164F39A821FC1BE502B3F4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit—</text> 
<subclause id="H3A74F462D48F4CD0A605C9DD9196740E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">50 percent of qualified revenue in the general fund of the Treasury and credited to miscellaneous receipts; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA191FB656AD64B5BA60E513A7A43AE45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>50 percent of qualified revenue in a special account in the Treasury to be allocated to eligible States and coastal political subdivisions in accordance with clause (ii).</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H8A2C7B4CDC1642B8A4D504B237A42325"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Allocations</header> 
<subclause id="H2EDD19ED09284A7DB002F3B5EDFBF243"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Eligible States</header> 
<item id="HD2760C0B95A34EDA87295C988B6613BD"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to item (bb), for each fiscal year the amount made available under clause (i)(II) shall be allocated to each eligible State in amounts (based on a formula established by the Secretary by a regulation issued not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph) that are inversely proportional to the respective distances between the point on the coastline of each eligible State that is closest to the geographic center of the applicable leased tract and the geographic center of the leased tract.</text></item> <item id="H2B2185360A0D4695B22FF687521E75EA"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Minimum allocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount allocated to an eligible State each fiscal year under item (aa) shall be at least 10 percent of the amounts made available under clause (i)(II).</text></item> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H26CD1778481642A78985E09FED5F8F87"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Coastal political subdivisions</header> 
<item id="HE230732A3B6B4C1B9AD53F9BC08CD329"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For each fiscal year, the Secretary shall pay 25 percent of the allocable share of each eligible State, as determined under subclause (I), to any coastal political subdivisions of the eligible State.</text></item> <item id="H1FE7E9F452EE46F0B7B93BF9EBACDB24" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount paid by the Secretary to a coastal political subdivision under item (aa) shall be determined in accordance with section 31(b)(4)(B).</text> </item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H2D866E128BD44E4AA5732B7825BD38EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts required to be deposited under clause (i)(II) for the applicable fiscal year shall be made available in accordance with clause (i)(II) during the fiscal year immediately following the applicable fiscal year.</text></clause> <clause id="H8962F6FEACAC45379D6E0A0BBB1B4C5C"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header> <subclause id="HDD0326F6428A4B7FA09A24DCA14F605F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subclause (II), each eligible State and coastal political subdivision shall, in accordance with all applicable Federal and State laws, use all amounts received under clause (ii) for one or more of the following purposes:</text> 
<item id="H0293E3F9D27543C791F8143250BF0E63" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>Coastal protection, including conservation, coastal restoration, hurricane protection, and infrastructure directly affected by coastal wetland losses.</text> </item> <item id="H27B55F833CCB4D798A877B7C15F02A53" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Workforce training, including for employment in the renewable energy sector and related sectors.</text></item> 
<item id="H6A6FB0026D6B46CC9D9BFF8B87A5F3C8" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Infrastructure development to support renewable energy projects, including the transmission of renewable energy.</text></item> <item id="H87E27F6869174C8894DDCF9DD331FAF3" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>Supporting science, technology, engineering, and mathematics education.</text></item> 
<item id="HA25CE042874343E39CCF0DD6E6751BAA" commented="no"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>Reducing carbon dioxide emissions and improving air quality.</text></item> <item id="H916CD5C90E9D481EBE04BFA7F3E91B2C" commented="no"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>Mitigation of damage to fish, wildlife, or natural resources.</text></item> 
<item id="H3B30AE5F42A146BCBCF81C4929E450F2"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>Mitigation of the impact of outer Continental Shelf activities through the funding of onshore infrastructure projects.</text></item> <item id="H8F5C316AC953464699149A31DB2FC58E" commented="no"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>Planning assistance and the administrative costs of complying with this subparagraph.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6995B024E2D54299A7B00D7F0B16A1DF"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An eligible State and coastal political subdivision may not use more than 3 percent of the amounts such eligible State or coastal political subdivision receives for a fiscal year under clause (ii) for the purposes described in subclause (I)(hh).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF152D0882B44440988087741B06A50CF"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Subject to clause (vi)(III), amounts made available under clause (i)(II) shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H074D9433F42040BF80DC4C89B21ACFC8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be made available, without further appropriation, in accordance with this subparagraph;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H42310B75C2444F1A9B38E17E1D21DB49"><enum>(II)</enum><text>remain available until expended; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0698E2014F6E4285B997F88832E88061"><enum>(III)</enum><text>be in addition to any amount appropriated under any other provision of law.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HC2CEECAA72B94633A46C9D689A78E25A"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Reporting</header> <subclause id="HB0871BDC83004FEA9503C9302F422C61"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the end of each applicable fiscal year, the Governor of each eligible State that receives an amount under clause (ii) for a fiscal year shall submit to the Secretary a report that describes the use of such amounts by the eligible State during the period covered by the report.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDCBF68908304479DB015953779536AAB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On receipt of a report under subclause (I), the Secretary shall make the report available to the public on the website of the Department of the Interior.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H419B09C86B87425587DB0783C6C0B6A9"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Governor of an eligible State that receives an amount under clause (ii) for a fiscal year fails to submit the report required under subclause (I) by the deadline specified in that subclause, any amount that would otherwise be provided to the eligible State under clause (ii) for the succeeding fiscal year shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury and credited to miscellaneous receipts.</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H83FDB8DF91F14507897527140B62CC3A"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph:</text> <subclause id="HD27DC87ADC034B3EAB018BD73E2875A9"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Coastal political subdivision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>coastal political subdivision</term> means a political subdivision of an eligible State any part of which political subdivision is—</text> 
<item id="H5CB36B6CC6AB4FEFBA7AE6A9A7648D5A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>within the coastal zone (as defined in section 304 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1453">16 U.S.C. 1453</external-xref>)) of the eligible State as of the date of enactment of this subparagraph; and</text></item> <item id="H33226F2C5F404A99AB580EB4675BF080"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not more than 100 nautical miles from the geographic center of any covered offshore wind project.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H35B84247B4CC4E4F83E93D7519AA5D08"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Covered offshore wind project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered offshore wind project</term> means a wind-powered electric generation project in a wind energy area on the outer Continental Shelf within the New York Bight Area that is not wholly or partially located within an area subject to subparagraph (B), including—</text> <item id="H13192FE7A6EE40E2BB063FDB473A50F2" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>Hudson North OCS–A 0544;</text></item> 
<item id="H16A24D4C31564AD3BC45FD79EC135753" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Central Bight OCS–A 0537; and</text></item> <item id="HEEA031B1017243C2B741A13A8FB9FE08" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>Hudson South OCS–A 0538, OCS–A 0539, OCS–A 0541, and OCS–A 0542.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7EB9D6C0C76B493EB31AF725F9A07455"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Eligible State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible State</term> means a State a point on the coastline of which is located within 75 nautical miles of the geographic center of a covered offshore wind project.</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H0698296A31914207AAC4F7BE17D02826"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>New york bight area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>New York Bight Area</term> means the area extending generally northeast from Cape May in New Jersey to Montauk Point on the eastern tip of Long Island, as described by the Bureau of Ocean Energy Management in the final environmental assessment titled <quote>Commercial and Research Wind Lease and Grant Issuance and Site Assessment Activities on the Atlantic Outer Continental Shelf of the New York Bight</quote> (December 16, 2021; BOEM 2021–073).</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H6591E4818BEF49C5933B974D2E32F710"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Qualified revenue</header><text>The term <term>qualified revenue</term> means all rentals, royalties, bonus bids, and other sums due and payable to the United States from leases for covered offshore wind projects.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> </section> <section id="HFEF7E0654E0B4D0599BD1517314B6DE1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Revenue sharing for wind lease sales in the new york bight area in fiscal year 2022</header> <subsection id="H9A0DDE67BD304A6B939700BB0422392D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any lease sales held in the New York Bight Area before the date of enactment of this Act, including OCS–A 0544, OCS–A 0537, OCS–A 0538, OCS–A 0539, OCS–A 0541, and OCS–A 0542, the Secretary of the Interior shall disburse the revenue generated by the bonus bids from such lease sales to eligible States pursuant to subparagraph (C) of section 8(p)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, as added by this Act.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H963B7B682C8C4717AECD02ACEC91B89D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible State; New York Bight Area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>eligible State</term> and <term>New York Bight Area</term> have the meanings given such terms in subparagraph (C) of section 8(p)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, as added by this Act.</text> </subsection></section> <section id="H2AD75C00A73B4C6690B469D3C6D5474D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Exemption of certain payments from sequestration</header> <subsection id="H6D190A0E650D4F0FAE22FCB7A93A06DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 255(g)(1)(A) of the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/905">2 U.S.C. 905(g)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after <quote>Payments to Social Security Trust Funds (28–0404–0–1–651).</quote> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE974AB6ACD41436FB366D8C731CC758F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause indent="subparagraph" id="H8137FDB690AA4B55B8A77EA750F586B1"> <enum> </enum> <text>Payments to States pursuant to subparagraph (C) of section 8(p)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1337">43 U.S.C. 1337(p)(2)(C)</external-xref>).</text> </clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HFD148123402A4CD2856402BB0892261E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The amendment made by section shall apply to any sequestration order issued under the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/900">2 U.S.C. 900 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

