<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C64DCB7FE7948C8A9902BACD9520FD0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6383 IH: National Security Moratorium on Foreign Purchases of U.S. Land</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6383</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the purchase of public or private real estate located in the United States by foreign persons, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HA2CF01324C244F4CA1809460FE6AD925" style="OLC">
<section id="H2BDE741BF850411AA59DA0282ACE219B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Security Moratorium on Foreign Purchases of U.S. Land</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HAE173789D6FB45A294AED8162E9B4AF4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H9F8F72017FE844CEB47164B9BFFDC83C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Foreign investors now account for almost one-third of institutional investment in single-family rental homes in the United States. This increases the price and makes it more difficult for Americans to purchase a home.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15673F7CA3C34824B0F1A29383354AA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increased foreign investment in Washington, DC, and other urban areas has led to a rise in gentrification, pushing many long-time residents out of their homes, including some of our most vulnerable and poor communities. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H256347E60C3A4B60B159B3A532C49FE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Roughly 47 percent of rural renters pay a third or more of their income in rent each month. The Federal Government has done nothing to help rural Americans deal with the rising costs in housing. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF21C267C727F493BA526BE11A039140E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Chinese nationals have led foreign investments in homes in the United States for the past seven years. The Chinese Communist Party is attempting to buy land in the United States, with an emphasis on farmland to gain strategic leverage over the United States. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H622A16B541F14DE586989CC4B0AADE0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Foreign companies and individuals have purchased 1.7 million acres of agricultural land in Texas over the past decade, which is more than in any other State. The purchases are worth approximately $3.3 billion. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40391C30EF6F400B9723AAE66B510C9E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Foreigners have been abusing the EB–5 visa system, which allows foreign nationals to obtain green cards if they invest in specific business ventures. The rules to acquire an EB–5 visa should be made more stringent. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4BF7027E1DF1403587E2F6487FC9265C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Current United States laws are designed in a way that makes it more profitable for foreign investors to invest in property in the United States than their country of origin. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC41B819EA6D4B0996AC68E7A76BC701"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Foreign Investment Risk Act of 2018 strengthened the Committee on Foreign Investment in the United States (CFIUS) by among other measures giving it more jurisdiction over real estate transactions. Specifically, CFIUS now has jurisdiction to review purchases and leases of real estate by foreign nationals regardless of whether the transactions involve United States businesses. More action is still needed to make the rules of CFIUS more strict. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDE512A2CF7849809DC35BAC662659F3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>With each additional land purchase made by a foreign national or foreign entity, American sovereignty is further eroded.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H68B2165354CF44D0A260D461AAB7846F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on purchase of public or private real estate located in the United States by foreign persons</header> <subsection id="H24726EC05C1F42B499683AE5B7C5B900"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, for the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall take such actions as may be necessary to prohibit the purchase of public or private real estate located in the United States by any foreign person. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H40C2D7B5161F4F689B50F199F88DA14C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header>
<paragraph id="H7F9CED25BCD24728A7A4F04A3862CDD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H389B6A55FE6E455992DF9A23674ADB6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details the history of purchases of public and private real estate located in the United States by foreign persons;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H590B1012CAA841E19FEB53EB7A7C4090"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides more information on the percentage of real estate located in the United States that is owned by foreign persons; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H75FADA7D9F954D5CA266BCEAF6982997"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offers recommendations to make it easier for United States citizens and harder for foreign persons to purchase real estate located in the United States, including farmland.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA9E9447806C54709B09248AB80BCFFC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H52D23B7B807341A09DEB2E6405C9D218"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H3C283400E7A141A7A8385974064FD446"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>foreign person</quote>—</text> <subparagraph id="H2B0FAE0BC86044529F5227BD4C7E1929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text>
<clause id="HE8CDFE84B0FA49C9BD594FED23F0E757"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any foreign national, foreign government, or foreign entity; or </text></clause> <clause id="H9FFF9009D0A24CC5B2C0398649D3E0DC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any entity over which control is exercised or exercisable by a foreign national, foreign government, or foreign entity; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H39200A7AB9FC4B00811619E2787169BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a corporation, partnership, or other association—</text> <clause id="H6973F45AE34748029C1AAD7B479DA597"><enum>(i)</enum><text>created under the laws of a foreign country; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HECCC1CF09804489D877476FB96085BEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>substantially beneficially owned by nationals of that foreign country or any other foreign country.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6188FD8BCD3E4BF688BA2477106816D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>United States</quote> means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States. </text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


