<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5813D898C3E4481CBDBA171912242B78" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7398 IH: Prohibit Wildlife Killing Contests Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7398</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220405">April 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit wildlife killing contests on public lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF3D8F04FA6CF43C893CF393A3E61BFFD" style="OLC"><section id="H6395F1B3E5084EBCBCADEE31C1217A87" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prohibit Wildlife Killing Contests Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H002F9787C2F4438CA37F18E574288E3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H47FAB0972F534DDB88E0E864E071637D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Wildlife killing contests are organized events in which participants kill animals for cash, prizes, entertainment, or other inducements. Judging categories for wildlife killing contests include, but are not limited to, the number of animals killed, the weight or the sex of animals killed, a tiered point system by species killed, or the smallest or largest body or body part size of animals killed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC349974DE4144E73A6DB22FC2C9BB647"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Wildlife killing contests often target ecologically important carnivores, including foxes, bobcats, and coyotes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2DB00788F4D488E9C40077D04FAD2F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Scientific evidence does not support claims that wildlife killing contests permanently reduce populations of targeted species, increase populations of deer or other game species, or prevent conflict between native carnivores, humans, pets, and livestock.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC17608B12026462680EF68117E898EE2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Because participants often wastefully discard targeted wildlife, wildlife killing contests do not embody the hunting principles set forth by the North America Wildlife Conservation Model, which includes a requirement that wildlife only be killed for a legitimate purpose. As a result, numerous State agencies and officials have recognized that these contests can undermine public support for hunting and damage the reputation of sportsmen and sportswomen who abide by traditional hunting ethics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FD4D6C31F774CEBB1790E8F2B390727"><enum>(5)</enum><text>As of March 1, 2022, Arizona, California, New Mexico, Vermont, Massachusetts, Colorado, Maryland, and Washington have banned wildlife killing contests that target certain species.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7ED54E19AED46DDA8B1A819D46BCC26"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Wildlife killing contests held on Federal lands undermine Federal wildlife management practices, public trust duties, and conservation ethics.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9E3343FEE9F3427A8C9B8AABCD8AA293"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on wildlife killing contests</header><subsection id="HE6294E6344314929883FFECE4B8B3856"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><paragraph id="H7C57E39884BF4B7DBBD367946CD44447"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), it is unlawful for any person to organize, sponsor, conduct, or participate in a wildlife killing contest on public land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58A6B27C80474A26A0396E5F06F39A06"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>This subsection shall not apply to—</text><subparagraph id="HF4C8C04802DE4F379ED7AEDD10DE48F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>field trials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF02FFD04F07F49E79D44D914BA59EAEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wildlife killing contests that exclusively target ungulates or birds of the orders Galliformes or Anatidae; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2A8AA89EB2E4AC19C1152BE411960B1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lethal control actions by State or Federal agencies that target wildlife classified as invasive by the National Invasive Species Information Center.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FB8FFAC420D487793A9B2407EB3450C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, each head of a public land management agency shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H46C6854B582C4FC7AAE79923CC1047D0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect on preemption</header><text>This section shall not be construed to preempt or limit any requirement of any law or regulation of a State or political subdivision of a State that is more restrictive than the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FC9D1A612A34082AEDA5337BC90CF3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H31F0C6B8A1A64F249CDA8048E8B967E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Wildlife killing contest</header><text>The term <quote>wildlife killing contest</quote> means an event in which participants kill wildlife for cash, prizes, or other inducements regardless of value.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC883C71AEDB4D8686E70F2000809548"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wildlife</header><text>The term <quote>wildlife</quote> means all animal life except for fish, shellfish, and crustaceans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75EA5AD500194D53B104F81ABD767F00"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public land</header><text>The term <quote>public land</quote> means any land—</text><subparagraph id="HD44150B694244B3B9DAB5A888127AF84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>owned by the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB4F4254A43043DB930A88F4F1FDD863"><enum>(B)</enum><text>managed by the head of a public land management agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8A600184E2249738D1BB9428FDDAB14"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public land management agency</header><text>The term <quote>public land management agency</quote> means the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, the Bureau of Reclamation, or the United States Forest Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H455D4730570846AA9DE5AB2633E58949"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Field trial</header><text>The term <quote>field trial</quote> means a trial of sporting dogs under field conditions where dogs chase or pursue wild animals under specific rules of nationally or regionally recognized hunting dog associations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

