<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB27D6E0B47242A78C5A217B491E1C8B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6832 IH: To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Defense Production Act of 1950 to prohibit the Federal Government from limiting State access to key therapies, such as monoclonal antibodies, and from prioritizing Federal contracts over State contracts relating to purchasing supplies to combat the COVID–19 pandemic.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6832</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and the Defense Production Act of 1950 to prohibit the Federal Government from limiting State access to key therapies, such as monoclonal antibodies, and from prioritizing Federal contracts over State contracts relating to purchasing supplies to combat the COVID–19 pandemic.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HFC443FD438FA4F2EB0FE3DFD92240178" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBC26D5DBEECA4FDF9BBA8445677EFC59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Ensuring fairness for State contracts relating to supplies to combat COVID–19 pandemic</header> 
<subsection id="H270D8C6E3CBE49AD85029EE0DDB62299"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment under Defense Production Act of 1950</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 101 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4511">50 U.S.C. 4511</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HF51B0B0CBC714DC287ECF85788CC2A29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as provided by subsection (e), the President</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9D22DAD4E024CEBBCB69BEFC6805F91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3932D948AF224E6793E51FEF8D44CD28"> <subsection id="HE14FB0482ECD4A959C12FAF39F74C6C6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exception for State contracts relating to COVID–19 pandemic</header><text>The President may not exercise the authority provided by subsection (a) on or after the date of the enactment of this subsection to prioritize the performance of contracts or orders of the Federal Government relating to the purchase of supplies to combat the COVID–19 pandemic over the performance of contracts or orders of the government of a State or territory or possession of the United States relating to the purchase of such supplies.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4FA7C4CEF01C4ACBA28052F71135A31C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment under Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act</header><text>Section 564(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360bbb-3">21 U.S.C. 360bbb–3(j)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H86AC1AFA91AE4AC8A981C8E3E84CC6CF"> <paragraph id="H9B2D199F11B247C3B84ADC62D5DBEB7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Nothing in this section or any other provision of law shall be construed to authorize the Secretary to ration a drug authorized for use under this section, limit or restrict access to such a drug, or otherwise control the quantity of such a drug made available for or distributed to any State or territory, including by imposing any limitation on distribution of such a drug to governmental entities, such as requiring a State- and territorial-coordinated distribution system or similar distribution system.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB0623AE47A6C488186199D577090BC01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of COVID–19 relief funds To purchase supplies for States</header> 
<paragraph id="HC6B49979FCDA4EF096907C13C628C7C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a State or territory or possession of the United States may use funds described in paragraph (2) to purchase supplies to combat the COVID–19 pandemic that the State, territory, or possession was unable to purchase before the date of the enactment of this Act because of the invocation by the President of the authority to prioritize contracts and orders under section 101 of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4511">50 U.S.C. 4511</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DA8D13E855E490AA7B6FB0FFBD4A3CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funds described</header><text>Funds described in this paragraph are funds made available to a State or territory or possession of the United States pursuant to any of the following Acts and available for obligation as of the date of the enactment of this Act:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA90BE3E8B5AA4D1FACE364277936ABA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Coronavirus Preparedness and Response Supplemental Appropriations Act, 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/123">Public Law 116–123</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 146).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H626F812A802C478887903A0885A405EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Families First Coronavirus Response Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/127">Public Law 116–127</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 178).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB2AE72D08E245CCB28C86BA4B4F6F27"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/136">Public Law 116–136</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 281).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59AD9FF0E08B4956A3CA10E03A25E92A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Paycheck Protection Program and Health Care Enhancement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/139">Public Law 116–139</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 620).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAF4FD23BBD9248CF87C8351BE9727476"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H71BA3176A6C14099B34D495AFBB831C5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB4662F2EF4344D62A770800611FF21A7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other Act providing funding relating to the COVID–19 pandemic. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

