<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0888631139E24851B788E5AB86DC3711" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6402 IH: To grant a Federal charter to the National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6402</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220113">January 13, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To grant a Federal charter to the National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HCC2B5F46DC8A4D0EACBC9D9F9394F18B" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H3F751BB741454DC881098275D74786A6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Recognition as corporation and grant of Federal charter for National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated</header> 
<subsection id="H6A27DEF3A2FA42A2AE188F2FB6A95B6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part B of subtitle II of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after chapter 1503 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H03EFF6CEF84E432AB205747EC5719E4A"> <chapter id="H8F2896E441F24275AD0FACB6E33F00CE"><enum>1504</enum><header>National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated</header> <toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150401. Organization.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150402. Purposes.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150403. Membership.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150404. Board of directors.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150405. Officers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150406. Nondiscrimination.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150407. Powers.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150408. Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150409. Restrictions.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150410. Duty to maintain tax-exempt status.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150411. Records and inspection.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150412. Service of process.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150413. Liability for acts of officers and agents.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150414. Failure to comply with requirements.</toc-entry> <toc-entry level="section">150415. Annual report.</toc-entry></toc> <section id="HA6A4E1824C7C4626B204AD44606392D1"><enum>150401</enum><header>Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated, a nonprofit corporation organized in the United States (referred to in this chapter as the <quote>corporation</quote>), is a federally chartered corporation.</text></section> 
<section id="H93B79E76FC4241E19C55A59FF01066AC"><enum>150402.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of the corporation are those stated in the articles of incorporation, constitution, and bylaws of the corporation, and include a commitment—</text> <paragraph id="H9B3D1FF0EDF34CAF9AD7D6464E8AC9DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to uphold and defend the Constitution of the United States while respecting the sovereignty of the American Indian Nations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2EB5F1F9AC1144A59E4BFA0D7BB48113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to unite under one body all American Indian veterans who served in the Armed Forces of United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H133EFDE13E1F488AB0ED8E496097A4E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to be an advocate on behalf of all American Indian veterans without regard to whether they served during times of peace, conflict, or war;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E0DF0798A7947BA91ED591B53B11BC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote social welfare (including educational, economic, social, physical, and cultural values and traditional healing) in the United States by encouraging the growth and development, readjustment, self-respect, self-confidence, contributions, and self-identity of American Indian veterans;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB020D1C9F1542849F3036334EB13212"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to serve as an advocate for the needs of American Indian veterans and their families and survivors in their dealings with all Federal and State government agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91AEDF5F61F04F5486A62172B1F61B9B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to promote, support, and utilize research, on a nonpartisan basis, pertaining to the relationship between American Indian veterans and American society; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2BE6359A7EB4F0B935A7806E8215D0F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to provide technical assistance to the Bureau of Indian Affairs regional areas that are not served by any veterans committee or organization or program by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3B366495EEC148BE84D276E891E4E5C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing outreach service to Indian Tribes in need; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H25136FC2427A49D685AEE232176D877F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training and educating Tribal Veterans Service Officers for Indian Tribes in need.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HC8CDF492C9D34C9182C95C0A4CE5D362"><enum>150403.</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to section 150406, eligibility for membership in the corporation, and the rights and privileges of members, shall be as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation.</text></section> <section id="HF65BC52A8FCE4C41ACED61A4DEF1258F"><enum>150404.</enum><header>Board of directors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to section 150406, the board of directors of the corporation, and the responsibilities of the board, shall be as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation and in conformity with the laws under which the corporation is incorporated.</text></section> 
<section id="H41449B1BB57441698617496F73F2C869"><enum>150405.</enum><header>Officers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to section 150406, the officers of the corporation, and the election of such officers, shall be as provided in the constitution and bylaws of the corporation and in conformity with the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated.</text></section> <section id="H4F675A2B83BA4EF693FB897C01F36F8A"><enum>150406.</enum><header>Nondiscrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In establishing the conditions of membership in the corporation, and in determining the requirements for serving on the board of directors or as an officer of the corporation, the corporation may not discriminate on the basis of race, color, religion, sex, national origin, handicap, or age.</text></section> 
<section id="HAF7D819773A148ECA2D255C9D2A75495"><enum>150407.</enum><header>Powers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall have only those powers granted the corporation through its articles of incorporation, constitution, and bylaws, which shall conform to the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated.</text></section> <section id="HA0DEC12F86094A7A9D2EAB85E2718C13"><enum>150408.</enum><header>Exclusive right to name, seals, emblems, and badges</header> <subsection id="HD358347B137B43C5B3103555B0755EE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The corporation shall have the sole and exclusive right to use the names <quote>National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated</quote> and <quote>National American Indian Veterans</quote>, and such seals, emblems, and badges as the corporation may lawfully adopt.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H06A663BAAF3042E8A02521071F8DFA82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section interferes or conflicts with any established or vested rights.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3A3515CF098B434692044FB4BF10B616"><enum>150409.</enum><header>Restrictions</header> <subsection id="HF0CC517B441445A2BDC76F5D943D16D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Stock and dividends</header><text>The corporation may not—</text> 
<paragraph id="H96DF97A555F64ED5B74A55C716C03417"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue any shares of stock; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECB613C775D142279176C0FAF8246AEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>declare or pay any dividends.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H621C195C7F774742A94DC8F345E7AE47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of income or assets</header> 
<paragraph id="HBF3CFDF19431452DB9EF1ED354880025"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The income or assets of the corporation may not—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D12B77368BB4CD8950BEE055BED0903"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inure to any person who is a member, officer, or director of the corporation; or </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6F7C73CB72CD4B4FA083B284E88D3DBF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be distributed to any such person during the life of the charter granted by this chapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H882D317210AC48DCB27300A05112CCFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this subsection prevents the payment of reasonable compensation to the officers of the corporation, or reimbursement for actual and necessary expenses, in amounts approved by the board of directors.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8E7C0C545A3946D79443421FC0CAAC22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Loans</header><text>The corporation may not make any loan to any officer, director, member, or employee of the corporation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H25D2D892D6D34E73802070D546009A50"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No federal endorsement</header><text>The corporation may not claim congressional approval or Federal Government authority by virtue of the charter granted by this chapter for any of the activities of the corporation.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H5E804F405B794D6C8DBD25EDC1C0F0E5"><enum>150410.</enum><header>Duty to maintain tax-exempt status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall maintain its status as an organization exempt from taxation under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></section> <section id="H8A5ACE597AC94551B67C769DC3B64460"><enum>150411.</enum><header>Records and inspection</header> <subsection id="HA441648775FC47E8A41788F49C45B5AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Records</header><text>The corporation shall keep—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2921CB7708AD45DC8687530F90F49DE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>correct and complete books and records of accounts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2B490241B2EA462EA020D971D9C2F57A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>minutes of any proceeding of the corporation involving any of member of the corporation, the board of directors, or any committee having authority under the board of directors; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE35E2244BD38451D954D71C7E7BA6786"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at the principal office of the corporation, a record of the names and addresses of all members of the corporation having the right to vote.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H08A487B0C52B4DD69E020753E4E65F2D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspection</header> <paragraph id="H29D9D79552714247A46FAE280A42168B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All books and records of the corporation may be inspected by any member having the right to vote, or by any agent or attorney of such a member, for any proper purpose, at any reasonable time.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD086EBC9F99420DA8A14A6D22DEEDAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section contravenes—</text> <subparagraph id="HAF591DFFF5014AA68FCEC9BF6E63356F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the laws of the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated; or </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC8E261A583494CB3995C80A23A2C1729"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws of those jurisdictions within the United States and its territories within which the corporation carries out activities in furtherance of the purposes of the corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H41A18B8DF7804152B3640D71F61F7511"><enum>150412.</enum><header>Service of process</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to service of process, the corporation shall comply with the laws of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA8ADDFECF42E4F7A82FE989082939E97"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the jurisdiction under which the corporation is incorporated; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD851CC7AF788414E9F32C26DD5639AF0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">those jurisdictions within the United States and its territories within which the corporation carries out activities in furtherance of the purposes of the corporation.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD595975096834D218FED0647497F57AC"><enum>150413.</enum><header>Liability for acts of officers and agents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The corporation shall be liable for the acts of the officers and agents of the corporation acting within the scope of their authority.</text></section> <section id="HB3BDCB575DEF4D17803DC2D0BDA447A2"><enum>150414.</enum><header>Failure to comply with requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If the corporation fails to comply with any of the requirements of this chapter, including the requirement under section 150410 to maintain its status as an organization exempt from taxation, the charter granted by this chapter shall expire.</text></section> 
<section id="H071DA5F64BDF40C198F2E75569258E32"><enum>150415.</enum><header>Annual report</header> 
<subsection id="HC33E2CCF98364738A59204D082B69CEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The corporation shall submit to Congress an annual report describing the activities of the corporation during the preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6200BB79F0BE4FD58BC01CF3FA23EA16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submittal date</header><text>Each annual report under this section shall be submitted at the same time as the report of the audit of the corporation required by section 10101(b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H26F944FF93834A41922FF41487A4E9E2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report not public document</header><text>No annual report under this section shall be printed as a public document.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H8DB31257AE4046ECB383547FE51A3649"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for subtitle II of title 36, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to chapter 1503 the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB90654647503441AB78BEC13C58FEDDF"> 
<toc> 
<multi-column-toc-entry bold="off" level="section"><toc-enum>1504.</toc-enum><level-header level="section">National American Indian Veterans, Incorporated</level-header><target>150401</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


