<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A4D49E03FCB47FAAC66410145DA2120" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8602 IH: Foreign Medical School Accountability Fairness Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8602</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish fair and consistent eligibility requirements for graduate medical schools operating outside the United States and Canada.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H521C82591BAF4ED5B7B531073AFCDD76" style="OLC"><section id="H3988990F675F4880B49B5A31EAD56BF6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Foreign Medical School Accountability Fairness Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H07A2BBC007454E9784DB40289EFC4B48"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to establish consistent eligibility requirements for graduate medical schools operating outside of the United States and Canada in order to increase accountability and protect American students and taxpayer dollars.</text></section><section id="H8440294E22EC42CF9FE0D3121AE6477A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of grandfather provisions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(a)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBAA089024FE74E9B9A517C3F0C9523BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking clause (i) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93047D65B8FE469E8822B9467DC04D0D" style="OLC"><clause id="HB9777725C5AB409ABE8A9D0103A78E08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a graduate medical school located outside the United States—</text><subclause id="HA37E6C3D93F74AD69EE4D50B2C5AEB8C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>at least 60 percent of those enrolled in, and at least 60 percent of the graduates of, the graduate medical school outside the United States were not persons described in section 484(a)(5) in the year preceding the year for which a student is seeking a loan under part D of title IV; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD08CBBB0EFF4C7895E9E8C84E421030"><enum>(II)</enum><text>at least 75 percent of the individuals who were students or graduates of the graduate medical school outside the United States or Canada (both nationals of the United States and others) taking the examinations administered by the Educational Commission for Foreign Medical Graduates received a passing score in the year preceding the year for which a student is seeking a loan under part D of title IV;</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H801324EE40A0485197630DA8F43F5F97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iii), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCE2FA405DD75402D8909E94FB3F65098" style="OLC"><subclause id="H4C943EEA338D41BEAABF9D81B36A6F81"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Expiration of authority</header><text>The authority of a graduate medical school described in subclause (I) to qualify for participation in the loan programs under part D of title IV pursuant to this clause shall expire beginning on the first July 1 following the date of enactment of the <short-title>Foreign Medical School Accountability Fairness Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H8AB8B7EEAD854003AA35BC25E30956CB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Loss of eligibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a graduate medical school loses eligibility to participate in the loan programs under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>) due to the enactment of the amendments made by section 3, then a student enrolled at such graduate medical school on or before the date of enactment of this Act may, notwithstanding such loss of eligibility, continue to be eligible to receive a loan under such part D while attending such graduate medical school in which the student was enrolled upon the date of enactment of this Act, subject to the student continuing to meet all applicable requirements for satisfactory academic progress, until the earliest of—</text><paragraph id="HA68B6FF72F4A4E72A35D814F1EB30236"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withdrawal by the student from the graduate medical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF09A17C17797400E8B6AB7BE37EDE58C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completion of the program of study by the student at the graduate medical school; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B353BCC6B0F455C831DE77EDB9CD022"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the fourth June 30 after such loss of eligibility.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

