<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H344998A491FE4051A01D66EE12369AA3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8687 IH: Wounded Warrior Workforce Enhancement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8687</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to award grants to establish, or expand upon, master’s degree programs in orthotics and prosthetics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA09F30673B9648AF821237D38BCD94CE" style="OLC"><section id="HF5D6FBBF1F4C41B5BC54EC5EC28DE12B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wounded Warrior Workforce Enhancement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8FEEEC943FF645DF97A07D654102AFAC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Orthotics and prosthetics education improvement</header><subsection id="H4CF5F96361174A0CAFFAFB493AF5CFB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants required</header><paragraph id="H07C1695981D9437D968C3C6B72265EB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall award grants to eligible institutions to enable the eligible institutions—</text><subparagraph id="H420FF602CE2E4A5FA64DBCAFC1925A67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish a master's degree program in orthotics and prosthetics; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CD545B9A6FD4E0FB1FC07526FEB41C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to expand upon an existing master's degree program in orthotics and prosthetics, including by admitting more students, further training faculty, expanding facilities, or increasing cooperation with the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE9286F294F43B18BAC7AA5EC2942A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority in the award of grants under this section to eligible institutions that have entered into a partnership with a medical center or clinic administered by the Department of Veterans Affairs or a facility administered by the Department of Defense, including by providing clinical rotations at such medical center, clinic, or facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC933B4E9C2634E0DA40C035D58713DC8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be in amounts of not less than $1,000,000 and not more than $1,500,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H587A23B7B1ED4165BD33770A9CB0ECC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requests for proposals</header><paragraph id="HBFA30916785541679DFFB646DA151ECD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less frequently than annually thereafter for two years, the Secretary shall issue a request for proposals from eligible institutions for grants under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B2B89A991484305819BD884749D7DD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text>An eligible institution that seeks the award of a grant under this section shall submit an application therefor to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3BDA7DD066224098AA4BC95DF685FB18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstration of a willingness and ability to participate in a partnership described in subsection (a)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0743B863E7F243AE8C210097C77CA205"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a commitment, and demonstration of an ability, to maintain an accredited orthotics and prosthetics education program after the end of the grant period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42002E503BE648F69B392BE56B7FD5A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant uses</header><paragraph id="H8F47A92C566443E9836F0A6D34EACF95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall use grant amounts to carry out any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H93A89C6A5C5A40898570DAFABB53B0A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Building new or expanding existing orthotics and prosthetics master’s degree programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF43517DDE49842A58FD690CFF8172599"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Training doctoral candidates in fields related to orthotics and prosthetics to prepare them to instruct in orthotics and prosthetics programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADEA40BC1A9D414B8B290DC98353DD74"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Training faculty in orthotics and prosthetics education or related fields for the purpose of instruction in orthotics and prosthetics programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H611C48875F78467C8F878EE956CCD110"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Salary supplementation for faculty in orthotics and prosthetics education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1B8010D23BA45CEB921BE03B7E30F3C" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Financial aid that allows eligible institutions to admit additional students to study orthotics and prosthetics, with a priority given to covered veterans.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE9317BA3FD439793DD3DCFD69695D8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Funding faculty research projects or faculty time to undertake research in the areas of orthotics and prosthetics for the purpose of furthering their teaching abilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBB30899D6F948CCBF11FED836509CF4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Renovation of buildings or minor construction to house orthotics and prosthetics education programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF41FEB204EE4332B61FF3962393BEA8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Purchasing equipment for orthotics and prosthetics education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06734895DDB24C359A471CE8E7DD50EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on construction</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section may use not more than 50 percent of the grant amount to carry out paragraph (1)(G).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD5D12F0ADBA44C4904E685FE25F90BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Admissions preference</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall give preference in admission to the orthotics and prosthetics master’s degree programs to veterans, to the extent practicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B92A2EB5F2E441B83237441576D0184"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Financial aid preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section shall give preference in awarding financial awarded to students in the orthotics and prosthetics master’s degree programs to covered veterans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H684A1305868D4D7B91E797D5D853AE96"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Period of use of funds</header><text>An eligible institution awarded a grant under this section may use the grant amount for a period of three years after the award of the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C6C74EE467847F5AC9F9B7419AD9A96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H711D96781A3C4D138BE4E3D684F7DE86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an educational institution that offers an orthotics and prosthetics education program that—</text><subparagraph id="HBD3E053B4D6148299DC7D62A85447E30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is accredited by the National Commission on Orthotic and Prosthetic Education in cooperation with the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H93F1258A5CF446D4BE032EC97671D84A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates an ability to meet the accreditation requirements for orthotic and prosthetic education from the National Commission on Orthotic and Prosthetic Education in cooperation with the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs if the institution receives a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3B36815349284E17A5EE7E3EE8FC478D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BB46B4248834CBCBF974C74DF4A16C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered veteran</quote> means a veteran with lived experience with limb loss or mobility impairment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE389DD8A2D942FB97D3C7B6A8BBBB08"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HDF432AE7071F43ABB39C5655E2686B5D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023 for the Department of Veterans Affairs, $15,000,000 to carry out this section. The amount so authorized to be appropriated shall remain available for obligation until September 30, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58CB66A3DBE344C2BDEA487DA41CE4E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unobligated amounts to be returned to the treasury</header><text>Any amounts authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) that are not obligated by the Secretary as of September 30, 2025, shall be returned to the Treasury of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE07FBCA967ED4324A9824F9D5B67BC6F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Center of Excellence in Orthotic and Prosthetic Education</header><subsection id="H0B216B5BC2A841618433B79D88757BF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grant for establishment of center</header><paragraph id="H628FAC4A6E6443E58FE5AE6A7F60D6F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall award a grant to an eligible institution to enable the eligible institution—</text><subparagraph id="H3266C836290046E58A609669CC1019C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to establish the Center of Excellence in Orthotic and Prosthetic Education (in this section referred to as the <term>Center</term>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52B0F3C028A94F72A91421A6D48319F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to enable the eligible institution to improve orthotic and prosthetic outcomes for veterans, members of the Armed Forces, and civilians by conducting evidence-based research on—</text><clause id="H4915CB83DE324032A7B913C153F027BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the knowledge, skills, and training most needed by clinical professionals in the field of orthotics and prosthetics; and</text></clause><clause id="H879A910141834D39B2C7292C639641EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how to most effectively prepare clinical professionals to provide effective, high-quality orthotic and prosthetic care.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDCD4157256F44119E8B792CF52E2188"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall give priority in the award of a grant under this section to an eligible institution that has in force, or demonstrates the willingness and ability to enter into, a memoranda of understanding with the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, or other appropriate Federal agency, or a cooperative agreement with an appropriate private sector entity, which memorandum of understanding or cooperative agreement provides for either, or both, of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC343BDA05D244331B0AC3261FDB3C4AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The provision of resources, whether in cash or in-kind, to the Center.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65BC4028F8D3458085FF44B6A6AF6031"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Assistance to the Center in conducting research and disseminating the results of such research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H62CC4471085A4DE386D99C74975DA040"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>The grant awarded under this section shall be in the amount of $5,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4866D0939F5D46549B123FD653094533"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requests for proposals</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HA67008C2BDB14D7AA7EE0E3B35EC015C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue a request for proposals from eligible institutions for the grant under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H34507465F6E84D0194B85DCFFF0117C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Proposals</header><text>An eligible institution that seeks the award of the grant under this section shall submit an application therefor to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H6A323511F1BE41D1BF462CCDC75EAE8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant uses</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HF85BE8B735B54E72BDA5F253547BEF92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The eligible institution awarded the grant under this section shall use the grant amount as follows:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C9EF32579604B2E9B5D43E2E4990826"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To develop an agenda for orthotics and prosthetics education research.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H813A1ABDAA79474ABB4F88BB531A5F32"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To fund research in the area of orthotics and prosthetics education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H11C090E4E4AA46538F8EB4388A4B84A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To publish or otherwise disseminate research findings relating to orthotics and prosthetics education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB53BDF9DB4C44CC58BC5D1D63CA28DFD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period of use of funds</header><text>The eligible institution awarded the grant under this section may use the grant amount for a period of five years after the award of the grant.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A24B53A7CF74559BAE1D357BED0876D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H177D17EA0ADF428D8AE05C5BDDAA68CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an educational institution that—</text><subparagraph id="H0DBCF592B06D4A9FB9CA9F36A879C3B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a robust research program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D76568A25484387BEB5A574823F2EC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offers an orthotics and prosthetics education program that is accredited by the National Commission on Orthotic and Prosthetic Education in cooperation with the Commission on Accreditation of Allied Health Education Programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF12B8E6B360B452480906FB206056325"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is well recognized in the field of orthotics and prosthetics education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H380A715D93A24DB5A5BD4A1C5E120156"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has an established association with—</text><clause id="H31C2BDCDE79C414F9B428D94AA0F3908"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a medical center or clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></clause><clause id="H3A81B3EB4DCA4519B744AD002F136F3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a local rehabilitation hospital.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4ED00A7AAA6046338202CBDDE4E70509"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFAA1F92376984C9AB5919C4927976C89"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023 for the Department of Veterans Affairs, $5,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

