<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD12F8493CD0F41A2AFE619FDCE5B489D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7053 IH: Hospital Inpatient Services Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7053</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220309">March 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend acute hospital care at home waiver flexibilities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H57253AAE65A341FDBC689341EF36EA4D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H0ADB77BC0E9542B3AB52D665B01DCAC6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hospital Inpatient Services Modernization Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBFC48BB5CF3A4E50908AB909B43B883E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extending acute hospital care at home waiver flexibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1812 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395d">42 U.S.C. 1395d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H47DC0D503DE3417EB07C57A3EDBA4CA2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F25994495E642AE914ADA8B45315A7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H14E38E6F028544058B4BB1CC2B0FC5E6"><subsection commented="no" id="H58F2838F53D440F9BC7465EC8CF797B5"><enum>(g)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFEC91165EAA84C2CB7DAD7C8DF0FF257"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subsection and ending on the date that is 2 years after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), inpatient hospital services or inpatient critical access hospital services described in subsection (a)(1) shall include services (including telehealth services as defined in section 1834(m)) furnished to an individual by an Acute Hospital Care at Home Program (as defined by the Secretary).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4F57D5D474E4A1985A69D775C19BB7F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to telehealth services furnished by an Acute Hospital Care at Home Program during the period described in paragraph (1), the requirements described in section 1834(m)(4)(C)(i) shall not apply and the sites described in section 1834(m)(4)(C)(ii) shall include the home or temporary residence of the individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H398D7FCA5F8448C8A9A60B722F7A191F" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>With respect to services furnished in the home or temporary residence of the individual through an Acute Hospital Care at Home Program during such period, the requirement for providing 24-hour nursing services and immediate availability of nursing services as conditions of participation shall also be satisfied by providing virtual access to nurses, advanced practice providers, or physicians 24 hours per day.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25BEC63D1E9343BBAE592B5E527959F9" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With respect to services furnished in the home or temporary residence of the individual through an Acute Hospital Care at Home Program during such period, life safety code requirements shall be deemed satisfied for homes or temporary residences determined to be safe and appropriate for this care by the Acute Hospital Care at Home Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25DBFFC6676943D6852C58659299607A" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary shall issue regulations establishing health and safety requirements for Acute Hospital Care at Home Programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H9732FD84954B47498D5BFE40C22383B4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Evaluation and report on acute hospital care at home and hospital without walls waivers</header><subsection id="HB0C6C81922F946BBB0E4FAD5A293A5D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct an evaluation of the Acute Hospital Care at Home and Hospital Without Walls waivers issued pursuant to the authority under section 1135(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(b)</external-xref>). Such evaluation shall include an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H39B6B31B1DE34D63B61D7ACEB5A54441"><enum>(1)</enum><text>relevant data collected by the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services related to such waivers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4723D6626624FADB118CAC974E724D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the quality of care provided, patient outcomes, beneficiary access, health disparities, patient safety, cost, and utilization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H527A32184EC44022B234991873AD3AA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the evaluation conducted under subsection (a), together with recommendations for such legislation and administrative action as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

