<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8E61C88DE6B047EE80865F0EE3417F2F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6655 IH: Sarah Collins Rudolph Civil Rights Compensation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6655</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to provide compensation for direct victims of civil rights movement violence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B2BAEAA25D54424847D8A0105B0670E" style="OLC"><section id="HFFD3BB9E6AC34DA58AFC13417778ADD5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sarah Collins Rudolph Civil Rights Compensation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H53E72E2F947844A691AC6C392EEBCCCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Compensation for direct victims of civil rights movement violence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Chapter XIV of the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20101">34 U.S.C. 20101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCA6469DF0C50459EA7C5C728A79EE3CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 1402(d) by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBD1ED29F7AFA4019B7FDF3E7C914393F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3FFB2F80CBB34385B447D4F5268A2276"><enum>(7)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEB6456794DB64997ACD31A3D3A1E1BEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In addition to the amounts distributed under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6) the Director shall set aside up to $10,000,000 from the amounts transferred to the Fund to award grants to an individual who is a direct victim of civil rights movement violence in accordance with section 1404G. The Director may replenish any amounts obligated from such reserve in subsequent fiscal years by setting aside up to 25 percent of the amounts remaining in the Fund in any fiscal year after distributing amounts under paragraphs (2), (3), (4), (5), and (6). Such reserve shall not exceed 10 million dollars.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBC64580C786496B92F151C65B0FC975"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The grants to an individual who is a direct victim of civil rights movement violence referred to in subparagraph (A) may be used for grants under section 1404G of this title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAD12DC0BD4547C28CFB66639A5ECBCA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts for grants to an individual who is a direct victim of civil rights movement violence established pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be carried over from fiscal year to fiscal year. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D17B79BD6EE4D7BB8D1F21F1F642458"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 1404F the following new section: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H37CA3C921CA847E9863A7A09EF3B46FC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H09AC2ABEF1B2430AB518581EF189086A"><enum>1404G.</enum><header>Grants to direct victims of civil rights movement violence</header><subsection id="H9EA978382B2F465DBC3424E9000B86F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Department of Justice and Office for Victims of Crime shall make grants as provided in section 1404(d) to an individual who is a direct victim of civil rights movement violence. </text></subsection><subsection id="HE3C6D7096A49479FA135B3B30592A77B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><paragraph id="HBE4FF0B956AD471984A1FA21856F7B16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial grant amount</header><text>A direct victim of civil rights movement violence shall be eligible for a grant under this section in the amount that is equal to the cost of the individual’s medical care associated with an injury sustained during the civil rights movement, as demonstrated by the medical records of such direct victim.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AE853A53331445EA7813B5386FB6DB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional amounts</header><text>A direct victim of civil rights movement violence may apply for an additional grant amount if—</text><subparagraph id="HC82F66E5A4974D4BAFD18F30A7B22497"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost of the individual’s medical care associated with the injury sustained during the civil rights movement has resulted in additional expenses after a grant amount under this section was awarded; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B1DE3D9EC3A4424AE4CD932EA25D124"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the direct victim of civil rights movement violence submits medical records demonstrating costs greater than a grant amount awarded under this section. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA210548F998E4928B2DA16C759D49CC2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survivors of a direct victim</header><text>A family member of a direct victim of civil rights movement violence shall be eligible for a grant under this section if such family member is responsible for the costs related to the injury sustained during the civil rights movement and the direct victim is deceased.</text></subsection><subsection id="H330A5B05A2AF4E5ABFF322104C3A4859"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HD0789ECA32674428A21118836D4EBFFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil rights movement</header><text>The term <quote>civil rights movement</quote> means the time period of 1954 through 1965.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9477B0F64C1E4E1A9EE00B802843C14D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Direct victim of civil rights movement violence</header><text>The term <quote>direct victim of civil rights movement violence</quote> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H2DAFA2F6DB6C43E7BF7FBF2275594CB6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is an citizen of the United States; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF438A34CE76343D7AB8AC431A76B9319" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sustained an injury as a result of racial violence during the civil rights movement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03C58B27A0FF46A393FCA5A536C92CDD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">can provide evidence of the injury sustained through medical records; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41D2E2C6378646C5B1163CA0B6B090CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has or is incurring expenses related to the injury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC3B68DB1BB4B34929884E16089B790"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Family member</header><text>The term <quote>family member</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB4809A80E11F4A01B33210E4D5411EBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a person to whom the direct victim of civil rights movement violence is legally married, even if physically separated, under the laws of the jurisdiction where the marriage took place; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65D8ACD5298C40E386102683F1B8CE79"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a child that is natural, illegitimate, adopted, posthumous, or a stepchild of the direct victim of civil rights movement violence; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91DDAAE45ACE4DB0BBAA61BF98904F96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other family member that provided medical care or funding to medical expenses to a direct victim of civil rights movement violence. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9C16D0DCF1D47FF848010F1F7B3CBD0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Injury</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>injury</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4E0E178557B444818DC3C3A37C5EEBB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a traumatic physical wound (or a traumatized physical condition of the body) directly and proximately caused by external force (such as bullets, explosives, sharp instruments, blunt objects, or physical blows), chemicals, electricity, climatic conditions, infectious disease, radiation, virii, or bacteria; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6DB2BE307764A06B8F659F45A3F7CEA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any associated or resulting traumatic physical wound that occurred as a result of a traumatic physical wound described in subparagraph (A), even if such resulting traumatic physical wound did not occur during the civil rights movement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A41EF71A9AD449383F5AEF3F0CB657A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any associated or resulting psychological condition that occurred as a result of a traumatic physical wound described in subparagraph (A), even if such resulting psychological condition did not occur during the civil rights movement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C17F833CA6491B809A4C10B3D7807B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Medical records</header><text>The term <quote>medical records</quote> includes medical records and bills that document an injury during the civil rights movement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB66950F5C0034EBE891A8EBAD516C7DB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Racial violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>racial violence</quote> means violence in which the individual intentionally selects a victim, or in the case of a property crime, the property that is the object of the crime, because of the actual or perceived race, color, religion, national origin, ethnicity, gender, disability, or sexual orientation of any person. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

