<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H80FCF139F5A24F238E32399B05986757"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8153 IH: Indo-Pacific Engagement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8153</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220621">June 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support diplomatic and development resourcing to the Indo-Pacific, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCDAE282BB8C74C48B075CDA5E286B2DC"><section id="H9B9A9B2D058F42618AB0078CAF63CD26" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Indo-Pacific Engagement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H387031E46AB44AAE993145F378526FDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HC4694F6D2A0B41BF8DFBD137244C190B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Indo-Pacific region is home to some 60 percent of the world’s population.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC7B06298A894AA19EAA1C17D2491095"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Indo-Pacific region contains some of the most dynamic and rapidly growing economies in the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H700C1198FC0F47A39705B5F333865E61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A free and open Indo-Pacific is essential to American security and prosperity in the 21st century.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F55B5BC7D51461DAA1CCD7BCD128E09"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has made significant commitments of diplomatic and foreign assistance resources to the region over the past century, which have supported shared growth and prosperity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBCBBF92B9544B1EBA526869D206B15D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A sustained and enhanced commitment is required to advance American interests in the 21st century.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H920920A9AA704424BCC5EB238B356E4E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Historically, independent cost assessments have served as effective tools to enhance public debate over resource allocation and have helped Congress make more informed decisions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3B8F0D5041D4F3EA84BC6C73EDF9074"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The importance and urgency of enhancing U.S. engagement in the Indo-Pacific is such that similar tools are required to ensure a proper level of engagement with the region.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4EA55F4A2B8E46BE8A621A11A428054A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="HD8F9F58A8C55450D8015F4DD259F1440"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the same time as the submission of the budget of the President (submitted to Congress pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, United States Code) for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028, the Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs, and Assistant Administrator for the Bureau for Asia of the United States Agency for International Development (USAID), shall submit to the congressional foreign affairs committees a report assessing the resources and activities required to achieve the policy objectives described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFFEE252B0544F0581266EA65B1056B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The report required in subsection (a) shall be developed in accordance with the following criteria:</text><paragraph id="H9AEF55E9F3084468B1D41DCF8BB6BDDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>It shall reflect the objective, autonomous, and independent assessment of the activities, resources, and costs required to achieve objectives detailed in subsection (c) by the principals, the subordinate and parallel offices providing input into the assessment, and ultimately by the Assistant Secretary of State for East Asian and Pacific Affairs as the final decision-making authority on the contents of the final report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A2F0B40F7A04EC7B0B80A65EAF54E50"><enum>(2)</enum><text>It shall cover a period of five fiscal years, beginning with the fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the report is submitted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE67D3692D0AB4CF494EBC4A7695FD941"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It shall incorporate input from U.S. Ambassadors in the Indo-Pacific region provided explicitly for the required report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96EF003F7FDA459FA5D845486C9B8E05"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It may include information gathered through consultation with program offices and subject matter experts in relevant functional bureaus, as deemed necessary by the principals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49D2959DD275432C933960D38DB096FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>It shall not be subject to fiscal guidance or global strategic tradeoffs associated with the annual President’s budget request.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA916A3BFD0B64520A0E4C4745A1F2E8C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Policy objectives</header><text>The report required in subsection (a) shall assess the activities and resources required to achieve the following policy objectives:</text><paragraph id="H9750FC1C699B4C72A3C1091FC9B78A63"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Implement the Interim National Security Strategic Guidance, or the most recent National Security Strategy, with respect to the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48117B7A45E04DBEB3038E51A50A2E91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implement the 2022 Indo-Pacific Strategy, or successor documents, that set forth the U.S. Government strategy toward the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34804CF871C64F228B670B87BD07D49B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Implement the State-USAID Joint Strategic Plan with respect to the Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66A6BDF98E544AC3B19CB93F4F7E39EF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Enhance meaningful diplomatic and economic relations with allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific and demonstrate an enduring U.S. commitment to the region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DFF2774AAE3404885472B07F55B50D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Secure and advance U.S. national interests in the Indo-Pacific, including through countering the malign influence of the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACC5D0B9A7784DEE833D3CEB15150478"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H50B7F6CD5B684BB0AA9194529F85460B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the Bureaus’ bilateral and multilateral goals for the period covered in the report that the principals deem necessary to accomplish the objectives outlined in subsection (c), disaggregated by country and forum.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3ECC9FD25104CCDA80112C42AC9F7A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A timeline with annual benchmarks for achieving the objectives described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE751C83F5A83473C9F1DC85AAF77DD1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the sufficiency of U.S. diplomatic personnel and facilities currently available in the Indo-Pacific region to achieve the objectives outlined in subsection (c), through consultation with U.S. embassies in the region. The assessment shall include:</text><subparagraph id="HB57F2CA26A324E539FC6F00FB896478D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list, in priority order, of locations in the Indo-Pacific region that require additional diplomatic personnel or facilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE19F47ED9488410FADC5B2CDA999C95D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of locations where the United States may be able to collocate diplomatic personnel at allied or partner embassies and consulates.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B395340AF6431AB5FE3181C4003E5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A discussion of embassies or consulates where diplomatic staff could be reduced within the Indo-Pacific region, where appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2469AD109BF480FAB581CF1A9986FF6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A detailed description of the fiscal and personnel resources required to fill gaps identified.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1C3E6A6E0924835ACBF4555368F0F39"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A detailed plan to expand U.S. diplomatic engagement and foreign assistance presence in the Pacific Island nations within the next five years, including a description of <quote>quick impact</quote> programs that can be developed and implemented within the first fiscal year of the period covered in the report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H729768E5E5164BA09F626340323A946F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A discussion of the resources needed to enhance U.S. strategic messaging and spotlight coercive PRC behavior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF28D21FD30BE4D2DAF91E05914967013"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A detailed description of the resources and policy tools needed to expand the United States ability to offer high-quality infrastructure projects in strategically significant parts of the Indo-Pacific region, with a particular focus on expanding investments in Southeast Asia and the Pacific Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B6AA1EFB2A04AE3A2DA0EEABCF81CFA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A gap assessment of security assistance by country, and of the resources needed to fill those gaps.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1859BE717A8F4F01A36231384B1E3C7F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A description of the resources and policy tools needed to facilitate continued private sector investment in partner countries in the Indo-Pacific.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H167369EA1DF1425494E12A2405935B38"><enum>(9)</enum><text>A discussion of any additional bilateral or regional assistance resources needed to achieve the objectives outlined in subsection (c), as deemed necessary by the principals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FB97C7293DB4409B0FDB10E53EE42AC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in an unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD8311FC53B341009AE9A3C2FEFE2E88"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Not later than February 1 each year, the Assistant Secretary for East Asian and Pacific Affairs shall make the report available to the Secretary of State, the Administrator of the USAID, the Deputy Secretary of State, the Deputy Secretary of State for Management and Resources, the Deputy Administrator for Policy and Programming, the Deputy Administrator for Management and Resources, the Under Secretary of State for Political Affairs, the Director of the Office of Foreign Assistance at the Department of State, the Director of the Bureau of Foreign Assistance at the USAID, and the Director of Policy Planning.</text></subsection><subsection id="H587469CBAA6442AAB30964565137D150"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA2F1CFB1FBEC4F32AF50C0C73E2DC99D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indo-pacific region</header><text>The term <quote>Indo-Pacific region</quote> means the countries under the jurisdiction of the Bureau for East Asian and Pacific Affairs, as well as the countries of Bangladesh, Bhutan, India, Maldives, Nepal, and Sri Lanka.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H795E1A4C0FF841BF85D1808CDF1E5EF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foreign affairs committees</header><text>The term <quote>foreign affairs committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; the Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, Related Programs of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and the Subcommittee on State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF284287CD6422EBC3658D3B18596F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Principals</header><text>The term <quote>principals</quote> means the Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of East Asian and Pacific Affairs, the Assistant Secretary of State for the Bureau of South and Central Asian Affairs, and the Assistant Administrator for the Bureau for Asia of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

