<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAD41D60410A540A6A9237E4C4F074D5C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8175 IH: Stop Pills That Kill Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8175</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to prohibit certain acts related to fentanyl, analogues of fentanyl, and counterfeit substances, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17AF24AB341F4D059FB07D581DD785DC" style="OLC"><section id="HCD24CF5C2F204E16B199B84F8472E70E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Pills That Kill Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE9329FE5B0CC434ABEF2300A03CC4C06"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substance</term> means a substance that—</text><paragraph id="H56CCBC18B2CB4D7D967C69992D2CF2E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>contains fentanyl, any analogue of fentanyl, or methamphetamine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71FFB65228724F1D9DED5599A4C9D346" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is marketed, sold, or falsely bears the trademark, trade name, or other identifying mark, imprint, number, or any likeness thereof of another product. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HF2F4E7791383468BA96C7B2DCBC6614A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibited acts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403(d)(2) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/843">21 U.S.C. 843(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, fentanyl, an analogue of fentanyl, or a counterfeit substance</quote> after <quote>methamphetamine</quote>.</text></section><section id="H4450326AE36041CEAD7F8874F9F1A897"><enum>4.</enum><header>Directive to the United States Sentencing Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Sentencing Commission shall review and amend, if appropriate, the sentencing guidelines in accordance with section 994 of title 28, United States Code, to provide for a 4-level enhancement for a defendant who knowingly misrepresented as either a prescription or over-the-counter medication in pill or tablet form a counterfeit or otherwise adulterated pill or tablet that contained a detectable amount of fentanyl, or a fentanyl analogue, or methamphetamine. </text></section><section id="HB5405C0930FD47DFBF1EC2C50C94C857"><enum>5.</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration shall establish and implement an operation and response plan to address counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances that includes—</text><paragraph id="H3D555935DF4842D6A715276AB699659C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strategies to enable and empower Federal law enforcement efforts to investigate and seize counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D98C51E69C84E2D9FAC4FA509D4C358"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specific ways that education and prevention efforts to stop the use of counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances will be increased, including how—</text><subparagraph id="H576710C7EFA14C73873313C50A0DAACA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ongoing efforts, such as Operation Engage, are effective in increasing education and prevention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6341CECF26BD4977AE59E2F9D7055C47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the efforts described in subparagraph (A) are tailored to youth and teen access; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C479DB7A2A34C418FDA417CA462C4AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an audit of current campaigns, including the <quote>One Pill Can Kill</quote> campaign, on counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances, including a review of data and other available information on how such campaigns can be tailored, adjusted, or improved to better address the flow of counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HFA2281D73F9E4EBE873EFA2914D37FFC"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><subsection id="H5620933A44C44B3AB7CB98022CB9B99F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration and Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, shall submit to Congress a report on information regarding the collection and prosecutions of counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0A2D67BE55B4B4CB7B45501B4BCE32E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H486D06A75A5B4068929B638A97BE9EF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Data on the aggregate number of counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances seized and collected by Federal law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE3E91665D314DF693B1F5A895B37131"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A breakdown on how many counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances are in pill form.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F3C1F50B5814280AD429EF240CB883F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A breakdown on which illicit substances are present in the counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances that are in pill form.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F6729C952644E6AFE11DBD9BD3A406"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Data outlining where and when counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances were seized.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0AC735E6704660B67C3E097A7C64EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Data on the charges filed against those manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing, or possessing with the intent to distribute or dispense a counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substance, particularly in pill form, pursuant to paragraph (1) or (2) of section 401(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(a)</external-xref>), unless disclosure of such data would require unsealing an indictment or would undermine investigations and charges brought by the Department of Justice. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H053B425C9AFA4BB6871B79560AB74733"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Data on the convictions and sentences against those who are found guilty under paragraph (1) or (2) of section 401(a) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(a)</external-xref>) as it pertains to counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances, particularly those in pill form.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE112985D6A2745B59D65923662041ADA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any prevention measures that the Department of Justice, Drug Enforcement Administration, or Office of National Drug Control Policy are undertaking to limit and reduce the spread of counterfeit fentanyl or methamphetamine substances in pill form, including ongoing public awareness campaigns.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

