<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDAB16CEBE60240369FAB44D0DD2F9A03" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6445 RH: Small Business Development Centers Improvement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 190</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6445</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–260, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001088">Mr. Hagedorn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to require an annual report on entrepreneurial development programs, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HB3D3118B21D24A7299A3650CD2564646" style="OLC"><section id="HED44C57984BD4B6EA1B06767C23A4B25" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Development Centers Improvement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1C19770A9D91483A8B4936DAF63F00C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on entrepreneurial development programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/639">15 U.S.C. 639</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HD58742D7C70F4807A744F468C04D636E" style="OLC"><subsection id="H78591C59E186459D8A4E195DDDCE575D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Annual report on entrepreneurial development programs</header><paragraph id="H1BE9E85F12AD4D4FB96F99FE47A5129D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall include in the comprehensive annual report required under subsection (a) the following data:</text><subparagraph id="H86758F4040734B558A6BC19240E49EC8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of all entrepreneurial development activities undertaken during the fiscal year preceding the date of the report through a covered program, including—</text><clause id="HBB61084851D247F9AF5C29E99B983D27"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description and operating details for each such covered program and the activities performed under each such covered program;</text></clause><clause id="H0B278F5FFA014589AF27ABE516352CC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operating circulars, manuals, and standard operating procedures for each such covered program;</text></clause><clause id="H7238BF54AB20460BB102A4D8BD726756"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the process used to make awards relating to the provision of entrepreneurial development activities under each such covered program;</text></clause><clause id="H8EDEF5BF513747BDBC18321B26E282CC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a list of all recipients of awards under each such covered program and the amount of each such award; and</text></clause><clause id="H4C4919C379C24DE2829DC8D074721A92"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a list of contractors, including the name and location of such contractor, of an award recipient.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14E602F7EEA241C98A7C80E910F830A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total amount of funding obligated for a covered program and the entrepreneurial development activities conducted under each such covered program for the fiscal year preceding the date of the report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H992289B013C54CE6923742A4F2AEB840"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The names and titles of the individuals responsible for carrying out a covered program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED02B8A455824774B088EF1BCD62C945"><enum>(D)</enum><text>For entrepreneurial development activities undertaken during the fiscal year preceding the date of the report through the Small Business Development Center Program established under section 21 (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>)—</text><clause id="H6FA14C380AFE483EB8575AAD6957F863"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of individuals counseled or trained through the Program;</text></clause><clause id="H123EFD6B1114445D837F64C197A783EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total number of hours of counseling and training services provided through the Program;</text></clause><clause id="HAF9ABEF4A84D4A82B3A20F7020463EF1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the demographics of participants in the Program, which shall include the gender, race, and age of each such participant;</text></clause><clause id="HD5BED8F9A8B9425CB20387355AE7FC9A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of participants in the Program who are veterans;</text></clause><clause id="H0A522D38730F4509BD6DD904863FD9C9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of new businesses started by participants in the Program;</text></clause><clause id="H1382E1BF7B65466E8A61F25FF36F83E5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, the number of jobs supported, created, or retained with assistance from the Program;</text></clause><clause id="H7C846BEA9520405EBD6179FF84FB19AD"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the amount of capital secured by participants in the Program, including through loans and equity investment;</text></clause><clause id="H7EC90DBDFE254396BFF663B445D4411F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the number of participants in the Program receiving financial assistance, including the type and dollar amount, under a loan program of the Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H3675090D4D2F4ABF9AD65BFA7AFB389A"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>an estimate of gross receipts, including (to the extent practicable) a description of any change in revenue, of small business concerns assisted through the Program;</text></clause><clause id="H26FBB470280F48388A0B0BCE8C95E8B2"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the number of referrals of individuals to other resources and programs of the Administration;</text></clause><clause id="HAB6EA4DC973540DA86125ED481389437"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the results of satisfaction surveys of participants in the Program, including a summary of any comments received from such participants; and</text></clause><clause id="H5B40C03E4D5B4B1A9DA33AE05E7432BF"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>any recommendations by the Administrator to improve the delivery of services by the Program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H60243CA24AD346A8B311762569E2D95B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H2754870025EC4BE9905D07F59A5E4C3F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered program</term> means a program authorized under section 7(j), 7(m), 8(a), 8(b)(1), 21, 22, 29, 32, or 34 of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B731430B9AF4F63837EBEFFE8E746AF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Entrepreneurial development activity</header><text>The term <term>entrepreneurial development activity</term> means an activity related to the delivery of entrepreneurial development services, entrepreneurial education, or support for the development and maintenance of business training services carried out through a covered program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H504E29BBB1B24FA5AB62197C7050F9E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Marketing of services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H442A58BBD3854DDFBD9A62A7F09E2B2B" style="OLC"><subsection id="HCA2DE5E9F921414288B6B000A4475F98"><enum>(o)</enum><header>No prohibition of marketing of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An applicant receiving a grant under this section may use up to 10 percent of their budget to market and advertise the services of such applicant to individuals and small business concerns.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H0E580174ABD14FA4AE075256008D061E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Data collection by the small business development center association</header><subsection id="HAADA6092999747059AD29E5F816AFD09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 21(a)(3)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H7EFFC40440BE40CEA291D8730F38B6CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>as provided in this section and</quote> and inserting <quote>as provided in this section,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37F9D85106134F55B41200396D4DD2B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and (iv) governing data collection activities related to applicants receiving grants under this section</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96A56F84B07A44D0A94E50A000295E97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report on data collection</header><text>Section 21 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648</external-xref>), as amended by section 3 of this Act, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2D44A989C6B44F72894AB4D1219DCED4" style="OLC"><subsection id="H2CAB8EDB623A4C06865BE6D6A07F09DD"><enum>(p)</enum><header>Annual report on data collection</header><text>The Administrator shall annually submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report on any data collection activities related to the Small Business Development Center Program.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9E04B64E8AC74407AACEDD3CE46D2DD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Working group To improve data collection</header><paragraph id="H19F986EBA75E442981D8DDEA8E8D661E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment and study</header><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall establish a group to be known as the <quote>Data Collection Working Group</quote> consisting of entrepreneurial development grant recipients, the associations and organizations representing such recipients, and officials from the Small Business Administration, to carry out a study to determine the best methods for conducting data collection activities and create or revise existing systems dedicated to data collection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H545BA99A6963458A9264A11ABF913284"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Data Collection Working Group shall issue a report to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate containing the findings and determinations made in carrying out the study required under paragraph (1), including—</text><subparagraph id="H3AA709A60F4F4B408BEF3D8B57E49A6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommendations for revising existing data collection practices for the Small Business Development Center Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F8D92C60A6E42D9BA84D43235F5C027"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a proposed plan for the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to implement such recommendations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1C31CB1DECC9435F9724B77F2A33C033"><enum>5.</enum><header>Fees from private partnerships and cosponsorships</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(a)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEC7CADE9585848609050C3F1766FA5A0" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H56442EAC171F4D72A4B6F02DEA01F59D" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Fees from private partnerships and cosponsorships</header><text>A small business development center that participates in a private partnership or cosponsorship, in which the Administrator or designee of the Administrator also participates, may collect fees or other income related to the operation of such private partnership or cosponsorship.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H86C68DF6EC3247098948ECDC118E67D2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Equity for small business development centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subclause (I) of section 21(a)(4)(C)(v) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(4)(C)(v)(I)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H4A429972289E417AB22F4BA2718DD6CC" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H14305F7DAB0A4CFAAE98355A1A4DC518"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Of the amounts made available in any fiscal year to carry out this section, not more than $600,000 may be used by the Administration to pay expenses enumerated in subparagraphs (B) through (D) of section 20(a)(1).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HD437F1B5969149B4AA732E06CAA93B70"><enum>7.</enum><header>Confidentiality requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(a)(7)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(7)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H237DD02B95A445809DDCCAB73D7D2919"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or telephone number</quote> and inserting <quote>, telephone number, or email address</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECDB095C5CC34351B305769466831582"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, or the nature or content of such assistance, to any State, local, or Federal agency, or to any third party</quote> after <quote>receiving assistance under this section</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5CC892BF8BB64901BA8E861BF2275BA7"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitation on award of grants to small business development centers</header><subsection id="H92B42F400A144BF3B253DE12B607642C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 21 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648</external-xref>), as amended by section 4, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HCDC207CF8F244259B9BCCE64809A5414"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HAE40C4AF4A7940CF831DDCB4983E7ECD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>any women’s business center operating pursuant to section 29,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F57CEE1EB924CFB92804B7C9B98F495"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or a women’s business center operating pursuant to section 29</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE310D914100E423F91647E802F961BDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and women’s business centers operating pursuant to section 29</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2116CED88527488483FAF30726D0DB98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFA8C77E3A14A47ECB63801BE55BA2A2F" style="OLC"><subsection id="HB6214DBDF71341D29C544081CB3B99A3"><enum>(q)</enum><header>Limitation on award of grants</header><text>Except for not-for-profit institutions of higher education, and notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator may not award a grant or contract to, or enter into a cooperative agreement with, an entity under this section unless that entity—</text><paragraph id="HA8E6D6A3CB814745B8187930AD71F8E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>received a grant or contract from, or entered into a cooperative agreement with, the Administrator under this section before the date of the enactment of this subsection; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB84EE00D7041E0B8554EE75C3A38D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>seeks to renew such a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF592DE7D83944A79966325CE3660B84"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>The amendments made by this section may not be construed as prohibiting a women’s business center (as described under section 29 of the Small Business Act) from receiving a subgrant from an entity receiving a grant under section 21 of the Small Business Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9F3CE1BE11B44DF581219D5D5E89EDEF"><enum>9.</enum><header>Management of program activities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(a)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(3)</external-xref>), as amended by section 4, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H9DD5299C37F2413FAB6789C8B5C7780F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>upon, with full participation of both parties,</quote> and inserting <quote>upon with the full participation of all parties (including the association authorized in subparagraph (A)), and carried out</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BC329343BB048B7AE8668CA965013BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and develop</quote> and inserting <quote>and negotiate the development of</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BAD72F7485C410C9633F50F37E065B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subparagraph id="H40D3742487D7436685FB84D85E6AA0E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Whereas</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB227C3CD23254ABAB71103CD660DD50A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>Program</quote> after <quote>Center</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74E009F47A19473389EE306A7E988621"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>National</quote> and inserting <quote>national</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0337095C209041098D2BE89A7BD88CC1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by moving such subparagraph 2 ems to the left.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HAE6AFFD55AE8428CAA02ABC3F9BF99CA"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for formula grants received by States</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(a)(4)(C) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(4)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H21A81824961E40DCBBB651369A4D7A11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (vii), by striking <quote>subparagraph</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>subparagraph $175,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2025.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B1E56F9964547E896624002A5148A45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (viii), by striking <quote>shall reserve not less than $1,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>shall reserve not more than $2,000,000</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H44554D5419FE4A01801A7FCEFFA9367C" commented="no"><enum>11.</enum><header>Requirements relating to matching funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(a)(4)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>Such matching funds shall be evidenced by good faith assertions from the applicant, and the expenditure of matching funds shall not be made a prerequisite of the reimbursement of Federal funds, notwithstanding the final reconciliation payment for the close-out of each award.</quote>. </text></section><section id="H65A37C69CBF24477BDA3466793EB47C1"><enum>12.</enum><header>Contract prerequisites</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(a)(5)(B) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(a)(5)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the second sentence and inserting the following: <quote>Each contract shall be deemed approved under subparagraph (A) unless the Associate Administrator certifies in writing within 15 business days after award of the contract that the contract will not provide assistance to small business concerns and that performance of the contract will hinder the small business development center in carrying out the terms of the grant received by the small business development center under this section.</quote>.</text></section><section id="HB96AB9A91F2A4303827DDE613D70C3ED"><enum>13.</enum><header>Duties of the Associate Administrator for Small Business Development Centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21(h)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648(h)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC8E6B0840FF34F5BBDFBAC8295E19F55" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HE346077F7F58499990B0CFF6AB728B7E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Marketing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Associate Administrator for Small Business Development Centers shall market and advertise the Small Business Development Center Program and participants in such Program as a resource available to any Federal program providing assistance to small business concerns, including the FAST program established under section 34.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE59D3C41DF034130A3D2AFFDFA0AA5CC"><enum>14.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc><action-date>March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HBU00">Committee on the Budget</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

