<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1B577FFED3FB48DF84E968D0CD10E239" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9118 IH: Cruising for Alaska's Workforce Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9118</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000619">Mrs. Peltola</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To permit under certain conditions the transportation of passengers between the State of Alaska and other United States ports on vessels not qualified to engage in the coastwise trade that transport more than 1,000 passengers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H049F1A84BC1F46AE96A17364DD3FD5E8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H90D6E4437E4D43FEA7C1D8AEE4125167" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cruising for Alaska's Workforce Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC2205B69E58549EB9AE7356AFE5A29A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transportation of passengers between Alaska and other ports in the United States</header> <subsection id="H49314D11C1E2443BB32DDCDC10D11933"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/551">Chapter 551</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD4F5DE0206EB43A78D463317B4C85D27"> 
<section id="H7EEDEB817DF24D7ABDEFBB8DC43B229D"><enum>55124.</enum><header>Transportation of passengers between Alaska and other ports in the United States </header> 
<subsection id="HFDBAA982CD49442F9061653EF8A63927"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H77B745D66D114544965AF08DE29263B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certificate</header><text>The term <term>certificate</term> means a certificate of financial responsibility for indemnification of passengers for nonperformance of transportation issued by the Federal Maritime Commission under section 44102 of this title. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H654801A96307460FB4A3EDAA5C84B854"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Passenger vessel</header><text>The term <term>passenger vessel</term> means a vessel transporting more than 1,000 passengers that is of similar size, or offering similar service, as any other vessel transporting passengers under subsection (b). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2417F9048D53411C84346ED55BDE2AF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, a vessel transporting more than 1,000 passengers that is not qualified to engage in the coastwise trade may transport passengers between a port in the State of Alaska and another port in the United States, directly or by way of a foreign port.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H83B585035D5B458A9F5543F5363F3DD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expiration of exemption</header> 
<paragraph id="HF5411C54823E46E4926B4C870EFB8038"><enum>(1)</enum><header>When coastwise-qualified vessel offering service</header><text>On a showing to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, by the vessel owner or charterer, that a United States passenger vessel qualified to engage in the coastwise trade is offering or advertising passenger service between a port in the State of Alaska and another port in the United States, directly or by way of a foreign port, pursuant to a certificate, the Secretary shall notify the owner or operator of each vessel transporting passengers under subsection (b) to terminate that transportation within 270 days after the Secretary's notification. Except as provided in subsection (d), the authority to transport passengers under subsection (b) and the applicability of subsection (f) shall expire at the end of that 270-day period. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAF52D60C96740C49771E664E354186B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>When non-coastwise qualified vessel offering service</header><text>On a showing to the Secretary, by the vessel owner or charterer, that a United States passenger vessel not qualified to engage in the coastwise trade is offering or advertising passenger service between a port in the State of Alaska and another port in the United States, directly or by way of a foreign port, pursuant to a certificate, the Secretary shall notify the owner or operator of each foreign vessel transporting passengers under subsection (b) to terminate that transportation within 270 days after the Secretary's notification. Except as provided in subsection (d), the authority of a foreign vessel to transport passengers under subsection (b) and the applicability of subsection (f) shall expire at the end of that 270-day period.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8B58CBF49170471DB4A13F443ED40450"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Delaying expiration</header><text>If the vessel offering or advertising the service described in subsection (c) has not begun that service within 270 days after the Secretary's notification, the expiration provided by subsection (c) is delayed until 90 days after the vessel offering or advertising the service begins that service.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2DB18C8416324FD79A816713757208B4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reinstatement of exemption</header><text>If the Secretary finds that the service on which an expiration was based is no longer available, the expired authority to transport passengers and the applicability of subsection (f) shall be reinstated. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54124D8D7A754143B6A6C02D80139378"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Employment of alien crewmen</header><text>Alien crewmen on a vessel transporting more than 1,000 passengers under the authority of subsection (b) shall be deemed to have complied with, during the voyage of such vessel, the 29-day authorized stay pursuant to their nonimmigrant visas issued pursuant to subparagraph (C) or (D) of section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB8E2137E55624A9DB72EAA9C0B7C6869"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/551">chapter 551</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87B355412EAB4EA1A5E42482516C198A"> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" bold="off">55124. Transportation of passengers between Alaska and other ports in the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

