<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BCA2F779E9846A4B4F9A8EE4B07DB0E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7906 IH: To establish a civil action for disqualification under section 3 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7906</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a civil action for disqualification under section 3 of the 14th Amendment to the Constitution, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H62944D1A106A435CBE5C8D4AF33DF27B" style="OLC"><section id="HB46DCDA4AEE74624A4E6EF38EA331FBF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Civil actions for disqualification under section 3 of the 14th Amendment</header><subsection id="H6D212697C02246D6A93F463923DB8A79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General is authorized to—</text><paragraph id="H166CDA016C4E4900B824DF7A5FDA9676"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investigate conduct that would constitute cause for a disqualification pursuant to section 3 of the 14th Amendment; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD57B94A5D30546A287E8361D403DCE9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bring an action in the United States district court for the District of Columbia seeking declaratory and injunctive relief providing that a candidate seeking an office described in section 3 of the 14th Amendment is disqualified from holding office under section 3 of the 14th Amendment, and preventing that candidate’s name from appearing on a ballot in an election for Federal or State office. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB43F4B1E80234E2CA8E5235663B352EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Actions by private persons</header><paragraph id="H2E34180A42A64B2296A830A88C4806E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person may bring an action in the United States district court for the District of Columbia seeking the relief described in subsection (a)(2) against an individual described in paragraph (2) who is a candidate for public office if the person is eligible to vote in an election in which the candidate is seeking office and is harmed by the individual’s candidacy. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF00FF8A0D32C48A29515948C99CFA484"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individual described</header><text>An individual described in this subsection is an individual who has engaged in insurrection or rebellion against the United States, or has given aid or comfort to the enemies of the United States. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6ED89C91EE1445D8A3C9B69DDE3551C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice to Government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an action brought under subsection (b), a copy of the complaint and written disclosure of substantially all material evidence and information the person possesses shall be served on the Government pursuant to Rule 4(d)(4) of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. The Government may elect to intervene and proceed with the action within 60 days after it receives both the complaint and the material evidence and information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CDF243BAE6741EDADB7B7DDB46B6F71"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Government may, for good cause shown, move the court for extensions of the time to review the complaint, material evidence and information. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7114111ECF8B44D99FA7D94DD5A0B8DD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Determination of Government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before the expiration of the 60-day period or any extensions obtained under paragraph (4), the Government shall—</text><subparagraph id="H719D4F2D6FD842BE850EB159D1414EAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proceed with the action, in which case the action shall be conducted by the Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D67D18D994C4C699052654E8931EF63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify the court that it declines to take over the action, in which case the person bringing the action shall have the right to conduct the action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE52D47E479443CA84FFA9C0FE170989"><enum>(c)</enum><header>3-Judge panel; appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An action under this section shall be heard and determined by a court of three judges in accordance with the provisions of section 2284 of title 28, United States Code, and any appeal shall lie to the Supreme Court. It shall be the duty of the judges designated to hear the case to assign the case for hearing at the earliest practicable date, to participate in the hearing and determination thereof, and cause the case to be in every way expedited.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4499F9959CCC4E918AA180A1A56C26BF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Standard of proof</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court shall grant the relief described in subsection (a)(2) in an action under subsection (a) or (b) upon a showing, by a preponderance of the evidence, that the defendant should be disqualified from holding office pursuant to section 3 of the 14th Amendment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02B76A6484EE44D79743A14DC2D2D08D" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chief State election officials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The court may require the joinder, and shall permit the intervention, of a chief State election official (as such term is defined in section 2) having an interest in the action under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="HB68E6D30123E4A9D912BD971C102B2EB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rights of the Government</header><paragraph id="H6307B927B17C488FA4661F3542D05292"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>If the Government elects not to proceed with the action, the person who initiated the action shall have the right to conduct the action. If the Government so requests, it shall be served with copies of all pleadings filed in the action and shall be supplied with copies of all deposition transcripts (at the Government’s expense). When a person proceeds with the action, the court, without limiting the status and rights of the person initiating the action, may nevertheless permit the Government to intervene at a later date upon a showing of good cause.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CFEAEC73B2442A486FDE53A20B206BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stay of discovery</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether or not the Government proceeds with the action, upon a showing by the Government that certain actions of discovery by the person initiating the action would interfere with the Government’s investigation or prosecution of a criminal or civil matter arising out of the same facts, the court may stay such discovery for a period of not more than 60 days. Such a showing shall be conducted in camera. The court may extend the 60-day period upon a further showing in camera that the Government has pursued the criminal or civil investigation or proceedings with reasonable diligence and any proposed discovery in the civil action will interfere with the ongoing criminal or civil investigation or proceedings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FC3772B593D4E17A55F00132266B75C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Insurrection against the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H66E812D8FB574827901055E65B0F675E"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCE5F91DFCF7449419AC1E2CC3548B5D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the January 6, 2021, attack on the United States Capitol Buildings constitutes an insurrection against the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8600396B822249508CDA5A0E1D2A6182" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the attempt to bypass constitutional order and obstruct through corrupt means the counting of certified electoral votes of the several States under section 15 of title 3, United States Code, on January 6, 2021, with intent to displace the lawfully elected President of the United States or thwart the will of the majority of electors, constitutes an insurrection against the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5BF989F719C4598AABD13D97553B042" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person who was a participant in an activity described in paragraph (1) is deemed to have engaged in insurrection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDFF475E4A8C341098F3EC87E77DC6231"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFC7110E606B14C71B784609D6740B66D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>participant</term> means, with respect to the activity described in subsection (g)(1), any person who—</text><subparagraph id="H8EC20079B10F499A97C6074F85CFFFF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was physically present within the Capitol Buildings on January 6, 2021, without authorization, who knew or reasonably should have known that their actions would have the effect of disrupting Congressional proceedings or intimidating Members of Congress, the Vice President, or Congressional personnel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E2ED46F5E6F461DA36DCC0AB59DFE03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>gave direction, information, funding, or otherwise provided aid to facilitate access to the Capitol Buildings on January 6, 2021, and knew or should have known there was a reasonable likelihood that the person to whom such direction, information, funding, or other aid was provided, would enter the Capitol Buildings unlawfully for the purpose of disrupting Congressional proceedings or intimidating Members of Congress, the Vice President, or Congressional personnel, from executing of their duties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAA05AD8D5344A7FAB87B62F947EAB55"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incited, or attempted to persuade, another to gain unauthorized access to the Capitol Buildings on January 6, 2021, and knew or should have known that the individual incited or persuaded would likely attempt to disrupt Congressional proceedings or intimidate Members of Congress, the Vice President, or Congressional personnel from executing their duties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA89667568B9C4D7CA2F3CCCC41D01DE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>had the duty or authority to halt the attack on January 6, 2021, but knowingly failed, refused, delayed, or obstructed others in doing so; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF48401C07004C99A8928650A9334F4C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>conspired or attempted to bypass constitutional order and obstruct through corrupt means the counting of certified electoral votes of the several States under section 15 of title 3, United States Code, on January 6, 2021, with intent to displace the lawfully elected President of the United States or thwart the will of the majority of electors. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H378BA20BA40348CB8A72B4D010600376"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>candidate</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="HBC45DE24695941258CC4726F43A6F6BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses general public political advertising to publicize his or her intention to campaign for office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90860C9C70E945BCA5C5B1937AEC9D8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>raises funds in excess of what could reasonably be expected to be used for exploratory activities or undertakes activities designed to amass campaign funds that would be spent after he or she becomes a candidate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADA6230FD235471E8CBA35EFD1F244DA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>makes or authorizes written or oral statements that refer to him or her as a candidate for a particular office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42F13003CF4C46B5AA88967C6795B187"><enum>(D)</enum><text>conducts activities in close proximity to the election or over a protracted period of time; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCE87F0B982D4512B97F4B42E985764E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>has taken action to qualify for the ballot under State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H975001EA38B04BBB93BB52F2D07D76D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>office, civil or military, under the United States</term> includes the Office of the President and Vice President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EB3E5725720480EA54F42C082015BC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>officer of the United States</term> includes the President and Vice President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E81319767D543FEBD89AC78463C1FD3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Capitol Buildings</term> has the meaning given such term in section 5101 of title 40, United States Code. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1ACA07CD41754E5B858C968A90564851"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal offense</header><subsection id="H246DFFA03B834FEEB552630D795460AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whoever, being a chief State election official, places on a ballot in an election for Federal or State office the name of an individual who has been found, pursuant to this Act, to be disqualified from holding public office under section 3 of the 14th Amendment, shall be fined under title 18, United States Code, or imprisoned not more than one year, or both. </text></subsection><subsection id="HE20C6FC3D72242D9864EB93D99C33C18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>chief State election official</term> means the individual designated by the State under section 10 of the National Voter Registration Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20509">52 U.S.C. 20509</external-xref>) to be responsible for coordination of the State’s responsibilities under such Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="H70795C6D4AA34AB2A7205F70575B11E2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or any application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act and the application of this Act to any other person or circumstance shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

