<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF77BCF19036047AC9ABF2E694FE38BC4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8469 IH: Combating Harmful Actions with Transparency on Social Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8469</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to modify the uniform crime reporting program to include data on internet platforms used in connection with criminal offenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6AA26FD7CA6641E198A1D4BCA50A3EDF" style="OLC"><section id="HC2ABC0300B224CD1B764F425D0E1E2A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Combating Harmful Actions with Transparency on Social Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CHATS Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H7D437258FDEA4C71B65F99D35300C57A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collection of data on internet platforms used in connection with criminal offenses</header><subsection id="HC279C8844E864C5AA63AAB2F1CAB4BD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Under the authority of section 534 of title 28, United States Code, the Attorney General shall modify the uniform crime reporting program in the Federal Bureau of Investigation to include, for any offense for which data is collected under the program, data on any internet platform used in connection with such offense.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB6E33B1335824A44BEBE858329D82B92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish guidelines for the collection of the data described in subsection (a), including criteria for use by law enforcement agencies in determining whether an internet platform was used in connection with an offense. </text></subsection><subsection id="H616340434C7F4405904E65CF62677E20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No right of action</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to—</text><paragraph id="H8056D63F373246EDBCCED8D911322A2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>create a private right of action; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AB596151A504BB6BDF443BD994CC096"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limit any existing right of action, including any action under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FD27A156A1A4E109756C97FFE1D93D5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No personally identifiable information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data collected under this section may be used only for research or statistical purposes and may not contain any personally identifiable information.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFC50B4DB633143EEACA13666DE7B8FDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Attorney General shall publish an annual summary of the data collected under this section, including—</text><paragraph id="HD94EFF0D29334908A73B996C50910FFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the specific internet platforms used in connection with offenses for which data is collected under the uniform crime reporting program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6942A40E20ED4B4BA3B802E8CB3829BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>offenses committed by, and offenses committed against, juveniles, with respect to which an internet platform was used in connection with such offense. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC1E23D10874F451994904E8DEC336D11" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5EBA7FDC0F9443FA957B543299ABFC03"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>used in connection with</term> includes, with respect to an offense, planning, conspiring, facilitating, and perpetrating the offense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F84FFB2AF1E4A34ADAFC0A4E730ACC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>internet platform</term> means a commercial electronic service provided by means of the internet, including through a software application that connects to the internet.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H60791A17795E4B42ABFE6DE3FF6FB8A0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

