<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HA45F5D2E52A5438A8C9D0587E48A3ED3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7277 EH: Improving Oversight of Veterans Community Care Providers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7277</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To improve the methods by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs identifies health care providers that are not eligible to participate in the Veterans Community Care Program.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCE0E2F60F4994DE59ED78A87406BE7A3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD260DD3B81D6478382BB270BA74DE232" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Oversight of Veterans Community Care Providers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HFF85000F69594AF89DC925B3B211E71D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Identification of health care providers that are not eligible to participate in Veterans Community Care Program</header> <subsection id="H4A85D81CE3C3440F984E5981D567B53D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header> <paragraph id="HBB1CA953447F468EBCC2F196BD268E51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, acting through the Under Secretary for Health, shall carry out a plan to improve the methods by which the Secretary identifies health care providers that are not eligible to participate in the Veterans Community Care Program.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4AA4AE8A14F4FA7842025DEEB2CE40B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters included</header><text>The plan under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB2BE9F066A5F49EAB3B04AC4CE906CF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Modifying the standard operating procedures of the Office of Community Care of the Veterans Health Administration regarding the exclusion of health care providers from participating in the Veterans Community Care Program to require the automated continuous matching of health care providers in the Provider Profile Management System of the Veterans Health Administration, or such successor system, with covered data systems using multiple unique identifiers, including taxpayer identification number, national provider identifier, Social Security number, and date of birth.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72596AB4F3C94FD59AEA6BD1A7BD1487"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fraud risk analysis conducted by the Office of Community Care regarding the exclusion of health care providers from participating in the Veterans Community Care Program that includes—</text> <clause id="H51C597DC11E045A2AB9C136A03CF1DFA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the likelihood and impact of inherent fraud risks relating to the self-certification of State licenses and addresses provided by health care providers;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7BE7286F0AB04E849C3C3E1C95AA87F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a determination of the fraud risk tolerance; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBEDA69930C87466CA62FEC5D0E259C78"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an examination of the suitability of existing fraud controls.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03D85E5FBA754ECF80120C311E5F2054"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other matters the Under Secretary determines will improve the oversight of health care providers participating in the Veterans Community Care Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEED05F9E8E19406C9F8EBA6FDF335F41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall certify to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate that the Secretary has implemented the plan under subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H71EEA212DC2A479E881B83BC07A908F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header> 
<paragraph id="H30B3DE16E64342CC8650948551FF57FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H5BC906E512C54A18A1983ACFCB929715"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the progress the Under Secretary has made in carrying out the plan under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FB61F1CEB7C40488711F711512C290F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes recommendations for legislative action to further improve the methods by which the Secretary identifies health care providers that are not eligible to participate in the Veterans Community Care Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBF897017D8748F2B41CE47DF0890CEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date on which the Secretary submits the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate an update to the report.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1B124F9691BF49CA93AD4D6DEC5C82E4" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4043658D35C84CF7BA09581CB9B284AD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>covered data systems</term> means the following: </text> 
<subparagraph id="H111D7A6DCBC94A30B945DCCD0DB3F68F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The List of Excluded Individuals/Entities of the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC98265CCBC6B4FD8A8C5A935ACD39E85" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The System for Award Management Exclusions list described in part 9 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations, and part 180 of title 2 of such Code, or successor regulations.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB84CA3F668E24972AE8D64AD54350B6A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The monthly deactivation file of the National Plan and Provider Enumeration System of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85E0D7A33FCE4573BA20EF9A507B7143" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Practitioner Data Bank established pursuant to the Health Care Quality Improvement Act of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11101">42 U.S.C. 11101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD089A3D039184DFB9D02B85B1870C586" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Veterans Community Care Program</term> means the program established under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20221115" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 17, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

