<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H29D18F1698E440D4A352DA5626EE8EB5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7615 RH: Lodging Options Developed for Government Employees Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 499</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7615</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–682]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001213">Mr. Moore of Utah</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on April 28, 2022</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to enter into partnerships to develop housing, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HBA7879A950A44BD9BF9DFE396584E60A"><section id="H489CC7E33B38467CABB504ABDCA707BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lodging Options Developed for Government Employees Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LODGE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H293DBE1848904EF3A049037DAD85AAAB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Housing partnerships; occupancy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1013">chapter 1013</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE5E7C3CEED124777AAEEEDA23C94D057"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending section 101331 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H2815F9A60AD342ADBC8AA853CD08E34F" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><section id="H37A2784084E749BD9214C8411CF39863"><enum>101331.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this subchapter:</text><paragraph id="HDB314E824B84420BA6F145579DCF237F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Field employee</header><text>The term <term>field employee</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HCDC6BE2CC5194F1B80CF15552BDF5047"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an employee of the Service who is exclusively assigned by the Service to perform duties at a System unit, and the members of the employee’s family;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB44A3F3B3E54D33A72BE05C37C637D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual performing duties at the System unit who is employed by a Service concession, partnership, educational, or conservation organization, whose work supports the mission of the System unit, and the members of the individual’s family;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A094BAB1E304EC4B9ABEA9CD5B54801"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an individual who is authorized to occupy Federal Government quarters under section 5911 of title 5 in the vicinity of the System unit, including individuals who are employees of other Federal agencies, and the members of the individual’s family; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B6DFB4EBD334A2ABBAA3698455BBAE3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an employee of the Federal Government who is—</text><clause id="H983EAA8D022B4473835DE9916619D754"><enum>(i)</enum><text>eligible to live in government housing; and</text></clause><clause id="H3534A17D9DD84E66A7915256B3F31B95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not an employee of the Service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BAF2B8D29E140168B30C6F3392F9494"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fundamental resources</header><text>The term <term>fundamental resources</term> means resources essential to achieving the purposes of the System unit and maintaining its significance, as identified by the agency in planning documents, including Foundation Documents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36079277F204F939E3E7F4355191EFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Housing accommodation project</header><text>The term <term>housing accommodation project</term> means a project for the development, construction, rehabilitation, repair, maintenance, operation or management of housing accommodations, including related facilities and infrastructure, pursuant to an agreement entered into under section 101334.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A73753343149A6A87BA0F6B5A7C699"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Housing partnership agreement</header><text>The term <term>housing partnership agreement</term> means an agreement for a housing accommodation project entered into under section 101334.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89829D556D004D93B72AAF68A828D74B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Housing units</header><text>The term <term>housing units</term> means housing units occupied by members of the public in housing accommodations developed or leased on non-Federal lands under this subchapter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF1C340594B54BB3A7311C5A3100D245"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Member of the public</header><text>The term <term>member of the public</term> means an individual, and the members of the individual’s family, who is not a Federal Government employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB96EA9DE690049C6B26663BDA40AE7C6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Primary resource values</header><text>The term <term>primary resource values</term> means resources that are specifically mentioned in the enabling legislation for that field unit or other resource value recognized under Federal statute.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27E36F856E334EAC8FC6E27F79684931"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text>The term <term>public lands</term> means lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C864356369B4273B4663BEFB8EE3DCB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Quarters</header><text>The term <term>quarters</term> means quarters occupied by field employees and are, for such purpose,—</text><subparagraph id="H64482EC7DB794C3F8142ADC9371477D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provided by the Federal Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69D8A4337DF548809D6066630026F4CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developed or leased by the Federal Government in accordance with a housing partnership agreement, lease, or contract under this subchapter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H98E8EBD77A4448CC96D2B846C837EFD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 101332—</text><subparagraph id="H2E30901224AB4DCDBAF14CF4CBBDB6B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by—</text><clause id="H8AAC460FF6464E37ADD48F2639798541"><enum>(i)</enum><text>striking <quote>rates</quote> and inserting <quote>affordable rates</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HE46BEC5359D6470DBB6FEBF5FE33E63D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, unless otherwise authorized,</quote> after <quote>at rates based</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H235995222C284ADD80ED964B8443665D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause id="H0347CFE183A841C7A6CAC2954ED76760"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>under the administrative jurisdiction of the Service</quote> after <quote>any land</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HD9D36F6DAF044636B94D8A0EF3FA753D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or fundamental resources</quote> after <quote>primary resource value</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2987157133524978A121D2C43FF9086C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by inserting <quote>, unless otherwise authorized,</quote> after <quote>that are based</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54843F3F12D8471F8DF218BB8619BA13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 101333, by inserting <quote>or affordability</quote> after <quote>lack of availability</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD837C1267D614A859123FBC8016D631D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending section 101334 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H83A7CB5FEBFE46A2A5288D243C00A829" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><section id="HC39CEE1A2D84497BBB47E9EDF977360A"><enum>101334.</enum><header>Authorization for housing accommodation projects</header><subsection id="H50A8D6519C55439F8EB99E759148A5D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may, pursuant to the authorities contained in this subchapter and subject to the appropriation of necessary funds in advance, enter into housing partnership agreements with other Federal agencies, State or local governments, Tribal Governments, housing entities, or other public or private organizations, for the purposes of facilitating housing accommodation projects for rent to field employees and members of the public—</text><paragraph id="H48DA08F8F5034CC19C06CE024C5930D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on public lands, including System units;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2148567FD30D45969009B32FB38A5539"><enum>(2)</enum><text>off public lands in the vicinity of System units; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF6715B2E6CC4FD891727E8782B72156"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a combination of public lands described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5074A18DF034063BCF915A1CF5263E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><paragraph id="HBD12F101850B485A991EF8E2EF2AE6C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National park lands</header><text>For any housing partnership agreements for housing accommodation projects on lands under the administrative jurisdiction of the Service, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7C1D31067637497BAF9F11195C478F97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the housing accommodation project and the use thereof are in conformity with the approved plans, including housing management plans, for the System unit and Director’s Orders and reference manuals related to Service housing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BF2B47EE78C4A1090AE8470132278E0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the location of the housing accommodation project will avoid degradation to the primary resource values and fundamental resources within the System unit, and will not adversely affect the mission of the Service; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB895CD1CF555426EAC49FB46235559F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure the entities responsible for the housing accommodation project comply with applicable law and policies, including the provisions of this subchapter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FAA43551EF94AB287CB860343A7BA26"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify the funding to be used in performing the housing accommodation project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD643ED0E32684DC1BC698B035C48E513"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide standards that must be met, as applicable, to ensure that the housing accommodation project, including related facilities and infrastructure, are kept in good condition and repair; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCC18BAAE0F74217B565E41B3B3730E5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>that the agreements include any other terms and conditions the Secretary may consider advisable to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB7C70001D834CBC8333C654D24041C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other public or private lands</header><text>For any housing partnership agreements for housing accommodation projects on other public or private lands located in the vicinity of the relevant System unit and not under the administrative jurisdiction of the Service, the Secretary shall ensure the agreements—</text><subparagraph id="HB9EDA5DEA7D641E390910B8A0B41206D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have received the approval of each appropriate State or local government, Tribal Government, or other public or private entity involved;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48C76FFD953D4B2FB30917A5FD0F42F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify both the Federal and non-Federal funding to be used in completing the housing and related facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DCE632F8332491AA30906E041D4FCFC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other terms and conditions the Secretary may consider advisable to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27796A660AE74E66BAF98B1490CDAB52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Housing occupancy</header><paragraph id="HD09DC68DFBF44233904B9BB2CEBE3782"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may allow field employees and members of the public to occupy and lease housing accommodation project quarters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5376DFEB79FD46CBAE5EFAF2086C3E46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>Members of the public occupying quarters shall be subject to the same laws and policies with which field employees are required to comply, as applicable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70E6E13D59574DBEA4916175102CCB46"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Field employees and members of the public shall be prohibited from subleasing housing units or quarters developed or leased in accordance with a housing partnership agreement under this section, including all forms of short-term rentals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B17D0BB63644941878D7053D679E8C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preference</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, priority for occupancy in project quarters shall be given to field employees.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6847B0C230D4B6A97DE7277199B5C70"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contracting procedures</header><text>Each housing partnership agreement awarded pursuant to this section shall be awarded through the use of publicly advertised, competitively bid, or competitively negotiated procedures, unless the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H230B45C887054ED4985FE8E7606EB818"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that it is in the public interest to use procedures other than competitive procedures with respect to the particular housing partnership agreement concerned; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7654080AE4924480A95343AF33CA5904"><enum>(2)</enum><text>notifies, in writing, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives of such determinations and the rationale for such determination</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DBDA0BAA74846CDA0F14DC606FC9095"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rent</header><paragraph id="H43198BB5022D4B44B3F803E8C765C7E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collection</header><text>The Secretary may collect, or may authorize entities who have entered into partnership housing agreements under this section to collect, rents directly from field employees and members of the public occupying housing units or quarters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E1AF8896AE34E8484BDA68CEFD7CB0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rates</header><text>For field employees, rent collected under this subsection may not exceed the rates determined pursuant to guidance in the document entitled <quote>Circular No. A–45 Revised</quote> and dated November 25, 2019 (or subsequent guidance).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83130B9D2C4E4EF4B53D591262E1E0C8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expiration of agreements</header><paragraph id="H7EFA80A73BEA45DAB84F4C3385CEBC07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Within system units</header><text>The Secretary may allow long-term leases or term-limited ownership of housing units or quarters on public lands, as appropriate, to facilitate the ability of an entity with whom a housing partnership agreement has been entered into under subsection (b) to secure financing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60E8171373954DD5AEB27270DBF80188"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expiration of term on public lands</header><subparagraph id="H473E0D8C61D3404CA999C7B273BECB9D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon expiration of a term of ownership under paragraph (1), the Secretary may—</text><clause id="H5391895175844C0EB63029C65C81B60D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>renew the housing partnership agreement for terms not to exceed 10 years;</text></clause><clause id="H89069D0B7FD8422080FC4AEBA9B911A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require the entity with whom a housing partnership agreement has been entered into under subsection (a) to demolish the housing accommodations and related facilities and infrastructure, and restore the land to conditions generally existing before construction on the lands upon which the housing accommodation project is located without any cost to the Federal Government;</text></clause><clause id="H93288D15B14C438F89A213E42E9D6176"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>take ownership of the housing accommodations and related facilities and infrastructure, including fixtures and personal property necessary for the operation of the property; or</text></clause><clause id="HA1BF4ACE33AD46F1973E9A3CCEBEF1BD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enter into a new housing partnership agreement.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAADACDD61CD4988B625A0E78F0A1122"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covering costs</header><text>If taking ownership of buildings under subparagraph (A)(ii), the Secretary may require the owner whose term of ownership is expiring to cover costs associated with preparing the building site for new or continued use.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD85CD04E9A2545B9B408709701DE1CE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>On non-federal lands</header><text>Upon expiration of a housing partnership agreement for housing accommodations on non-Federal lands, the Secretary may extend the housing partnership agreement for terms not to exceed 10 years.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H96315766D90741698AB631341B01022A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 101335—</text><subparagraph id="HC482EFB7908D4B56A07A89612A4DAB51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="H86AD364D6F41449F976864E92D43CF1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>50</quote> and inserting <quote>60</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H8FD344474D4D4FA993F5E764540D4739"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subclause id="H33B5776B601D448EA89F75A5557D6A2A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>procedures.</quote> and inserting <quote>procedures, unless—</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9D80AA0892014EB48659C975E43BD932"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0B860DDD41D04C188AD4856FB3F77CF2" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subparagraph id="HCD7906426C604D35B44B82A1D56097A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the lease is awarded to a nonprofit or government entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06E31D82D3D4452FAC25080B28A0DC4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that it is in the public interest to use procedures other than competitive procedures in the particular lease concerned and notifies, in writing, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives of such determination and the rationale for such determination.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="HF4604FF134BB4B6FBD47D2044B1CEE5D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(D), by inserting <quote>, affordability,</quote> after <quote>improve the quality</quote>; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1C2D62F98DA4A9EB6662865BE330826"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="HFA0D3D896B094D6386811FE055CB9380"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (2) and (3); and</text></clause><clause id="H560B9338899D4AA8BBD4F4DC0C404D02"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H847AC822AD7D475AB774D95238934FC1" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><paragraph id="HA5EFC905FC95437EA1DAD091A81EA2B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text>Any arrangement made pursuant to this subsection shall contain such terms and conditions as the Secretary considers necessary or appropriate to protect the interests of the United States and ensure that necessary quarters are available to field employees.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A43121C27034278A97430A835574517"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (4) as paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EE58DD16F74AD296EDF3A9A23E2F6F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 101336, by inserting <quote>rehabilitation,</quote> after <quote>repair,</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AB65A4E0C4A4D968C926FE54073ACC3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by amending section 101338 to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H9A2A84672AEB4EAFA16A643068118CDD" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><section id="H7820FC7F1EAF42268901FC2024A1F2CD"><enum>101338.</enum><header>General provisions</header><subsection id="H6188D3A829D74E78B9C1A0E541E4C98C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The following provisions shall not apply to leases contracts, or housing partnership agreements awarded by the Secretary under this subchapter:</text><paragraph id="H3242DE6629A14BBDAC6BCB61825B3972"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sections 102102 and 102901 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13E1356E12F448D4857EE9001773684B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1302 of title 40.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A1F88B5F24F44399A79A48F7E1FB709"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds from leases</header><text>The proceeds from any lease or housing partnership agreement under this subchapter from which the Service directly collects the proceeds shall be retained by the Service and deposited in the special fund established for repair, maintenance, rehabilitation, and operations of housing units and quarters and associated facilities and infrastructure.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H00EA45FBAF5D4D57998652393A9C5644"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in section 101340—</text><subparagraph id="H049BA6FE59B64C3DB144D5A05EC482AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to strike <quote>, in sequential order,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF34F4B1F829C4291AB7A9C0F3542CA57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H6DCC58207A614F3DA65576DFA49466EF" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="HA093F7A56EB44889832601E6DCD7B249"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual budget submittal</header><text>Each fiscal year, the President’s proposed budget to Congress shall include—</text><paragraph id="HA99B36FA0EA0479AA4D606D9A77D9754"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of non-construction funds to be spent for Service housing maintenance and operations that are in addition to rental receipts collected;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E55C2C80EB84DD189C416C0502589BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the use of each of the authorities provided to the Service under this subchapter;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0289BC36D68C4C97805332FB04D12537"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of additional housing units needed within the National Park System;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF79B16B2420C4267987EDCC00693631A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any barriers that have been identified to providing the needed housing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H758002F094C344E39D8C574E65DC08B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any recommendations for changes to existing authorities that would help to remove those barriers.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

