<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC7EEF08D7E284877AE9A2E4C47538DEB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9364 IH: Strengthening the African Continental Free Trade Area Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9364</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221130">November 30, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To promote the African Continental Free Trade Area, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HF389CC404B1C4B84B3BC37553E2C2A19" style="OLC">
<section id="H4A88C9AB65A54FD7AA2782FAF6AE08B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening the African Continental Free Trade Area Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Strengthening the AfCFTA Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H99D291864205430799B5036E4BED5457"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H5A0DD5A1CF1F4965A890DCADD8CFCDB7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>By 2035, the gross domestic product of African countries is projected to increase by $450,000,000,000 with the implementation of the AfCFTA and lift 30,000,000 Africans out of extreme poverty while boosting the wages of African women and unskilled workers in particular, according to World Bank estimates.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H338A3FC914B742AF94F5D87011C97096"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the World Bank, the total intracontinental exports from African countries would increase by 81 percent under the AfCFTA. By economic sector, the AfCFTA is expected to be especially important for expanding manufacturing, by increasing intracontinental manufacturing exports by 110 percent, which will diversify African economies and decrease the reliance of such economies upon extracting natural resources.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6BB6E2CADCB04D22809F99EB66E24ABC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The AfCFTA will also increase African manufacturing exports to the rest of the world by 46 percent. As a result of the AfCFTA creating new commercial opportunities and diversifying global supply chains, the rest of the world’s gross domestic product is expected to increase by $76,000,000,000.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H73B6358707B342ECB7750A8D66417886"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text>
<paragraph id="H23990B48A0894184BC9E7FE8D24DB7B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the African Union’s Agenda 2063 efforts to promote regional economic development, diversification, and integration by stimulating greater trade and investment among African countries and between Africa and the global trade partners of Africa, notably including greater collaboration with the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A555CC2F517443ABE57904A795DFAEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>partner with the African Union Commission, African Union entities such as the African Continental Free Trade Area Secretariat, regional economic communities, and other intergovernmental African organizations to bolster trade and investment at the regional, intracontinental, and international levels;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAB8F6FD65E4049F1A7F8423A4D36FD96"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase opportunities for trade and investment between African countries and United States businesses, including those owned by members of the African diaspora, thereby contributing to potential United States economic growth; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B5563217D9E45C0BB0D9C8F887B8654"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote the goals of the African Continental Free Trade Area (AfCFTA), formed by the Agreement Establishing the African Continental Free Trade Area, done at Kigali, Rwanda on March 21, 2018, to simplify and expedite trade and investment among African countries and expand commercial opportunities for underserved groups, women, and youth entrepreneurs.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HB5FC22AADD6F44C8BE5E5F1947DFB38C"><enum>4.</enum><header>President’s strategy to promote the African Continental Free Trade Area</header>
<subsection id="H3F422381E4B6478E875FF2F6692F61B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Development of strategy</header>
<paragraph id="H5BD2BECAF288406B837DD5DF5995AF84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>United States Trade Representative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall, using existing interagency trade policy development and coordination authority and mechanisms, direct the United States Trade Representative to develop a 10-year Federal strategy to promote the AfCFTA to achieve the following goals:</text> <subparagraph id="HE450C33691CD48BCB4C8795B737CAD88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Improving the efficacy, efficiency, and coordination of United States development aid and technical assistance focusing on trade capacity building that is provided to African countries, regional communities, and intergovernmental or multinational entities, including to the AfCFTA Secretariat.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD4E4051E1654450A78F82C1B6D1B225"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Implementing trade policy priorities of the AfCFTA developed in coordination with continental, regional, and country partners in Africa.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7923F7410F64E388463D52C4B540C3D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy developed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall also include policy or program plans to accomplish the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H58BDD82C00B64789A3AF5EE0CE4154B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Increasing the volume and velocity of goods and services trade between African countries by improving customs operations, which may include—</text> <clause id="H3A45B0A24A864147AB74C5AF56EBA2CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing support for increased automation or online processing of customs and cross-border trade-related tasks; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1CF8530F426B49DF879BE78C3F0003B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>supporting efforts—</text> <subclause id="H7DC9D568AD154BF3AEBFEB1B4799E3A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to ensure adequate access to reliable electrical power supplies and internet access to foster digitalization where necessary; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HD1295E9A285B4E15A82E2302AF662B83"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to provide paper-based or other applicable technical alternatives at border crossings where electricity or internet access is unreliable or unavailable, including in coordination with the United States Power Africa initiative where applicable.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H295F27CA6AD74F5F9FBE618AABC3132A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Expanding trade capacities and supporting trade-related infrastructure development, prioritizing major intra-African trade corridors.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB0B6092252A04D19BC281C4014C48E7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Supporting the implementation and success of the AfCFTA and its goals as identified in consultation with African counterparts at the continental, regional, and country level, including by—</text> <clause id="HAB22C78AE6ED40A1A0C8EABCA3AD9BA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advancing African regional and intracontinental alignment of trade-related legal and administrative procedures;</text></clause>
<clause id="HCCD2B2766F4B4E9CA09CC719F15F1171"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>strengthening the technical capacity of the AfCFTA Secretariat; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD4F4F6B5B73B499C8DBB3E853363762D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promoting the development and expansion of African regional economic communities as they pertain to fostering trade, including through direct consultation and partnership with the AfCFTA Secretariat.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8B4D77171CFA49EF8D36C19A5B54AA3D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Improving the efficacy of United States trade capacity building to support the AfCFTA’s implementation, as appropriate, by preventing duplication of or incompatibility between the assistance activities of other major donors (such as nongovernmental organizations, other countries, and intergovernmental organizations) and the policies and projects included in the strategy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H54E6B183A4B5404DB277701E180BDA85"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Enabling more effective and inclusive participation of stakeholders, including those representing workers, environmental sustainability, women, youth, marginalized, or underrepresented groups, in the negotiation and implementation of the AfCFTA.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC07683DFD1C34C058D1B6C77D8134D3D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Increasing United States trade and investment to expand African regional value chains, especially as it relates to increasing manufacturing and production on the continent in industries expected to grow with the implementation of the AfCFTA.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB249F78B3EB48CE862AB36DB6C8A20E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Evaluating the industries in which the United States has a comparative advantage in Africa relative to other countries, and promote trade and investment within those industries, especially in industries expected to grow with the implementation of the AfCFTA.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2BDA5F2A2D12431CB1E51D845C111BA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prior approval and biennial updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required by this subsection may only be developed through prior consultation with, and submitted with the approval of, the Trade Policy Staff Committee established pursuant to section 242(a) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1872">19 U.S.C. 1872(a)</external-xref>). Such strategy shall also be updated biennially with such prior consultation and pursuant to such approval.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE68C22C3B024CAB9A1A2CCC13750DC7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the strategy described in this subsection, the United States Trade Representative shall, as appropriate and practicable, consult with—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1ACA6DDDD5F54177BC4878EB5C81ECDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>stakeholders in the United States and in Africa from the private sector, civil society, and African diaspora;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06994547936E4361BE3220B5E03391EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relevant African Union entities such as the AfCFTA Secretariat;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H62E50DC63A9140C6A113785C82640ADC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State, local, and Tribal governments; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC121BC166AB49FDB34558F806EFBCD3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>United States development agencies and entities not represented on the Trade Policy Staff Committee, such as the Prosper Africa Initiative, Millennium Challenge Corporation and Development Finance Corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H23259F78C71249EFBABC82A5E6F0601A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall (subject to the prior approval required under subsection (a)(3)) submit to the relevant congressional committees an initial report that includes the strategy developed pursuant to subsection (a) and an implementation plan for such strategy that includes each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9A880B295783419BA6628721E0CB7C25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The rationale, objectives, and anticipated manner of implementation of the strategy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAC026F42640C4AE49DD69E0518ABE0B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The anticipated role of each agency represented in the interagency in the implementation of such strategy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76504F43D89042D5863EA880F95ED126"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of the current trade capacity-building programs, projects, and activities of the United States in support of the AfCFTA as of the date of the submission of the report, and the relationships between such programs, projects, and activities and the objectives of the strategy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD2C5E5C331914F5AADE1B7D21934A70B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any gaps, inefficiencies, or unmet needs identified in the course of preparing the summary described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB32A681DD91B4FF0BCBCD41A660CA285"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Qualitative and quantitative goals and metrics for the implementation of the strategy, including the criteria to be used in monitoring and evaluating progress towards the objectives of the strategy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB6F13EC7FE894BC699490FA8B0DCAA51"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recommendations, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, relating to programmatic or appropriations measures that could potentially enhance the implementation of the strategy including legislative or executive policy changes for such enhanced implementation.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBD950889E9214200A7B62939C1BC095E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial update and report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the submission of the initial report required by subsection (b), and every two years thereafter for 8 years, the President shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report containing revisions and updates to the strategy required by subsection (a) and an assessment of the progress made in implementing the strategy as described in such initial report. Such biennial progress reports shall also include each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H33ADB90A30944D99932D1FC64A0AC027"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the obligation and expenditure of all amounts made available to carry out the strategy during the preceding two fiscal years, disaggregated by fiscal year, account, and activity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2B6725CE0204842AC7B69406D059DAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notable successes and challenges relating to the implementation of the strategy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFDFA31D47B9D47BA8D3C505693ACC494"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An evaluation of the progress toward achieving the qualitative and quantitative goals and metrics included in the initial report pursuant to subsection (b)(5).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3FA2AD78D984A8AAD04D5A78D56D1C5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any updates and revisions made to the criteria described in subsection (b)(5) and included in the initial report.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5E2B8D95DBF04911BA4A7A16A96C0AE0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Updated recommendations as described in subsection (b)(7).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2207612A17F443C2AB9F1A5B26A26504"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 10 years after the date of the submission of the initial report required by subsection (b), the President shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report that assesses progress over the preceding decade of the strategy. Such report shall also include each of the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HAF2F6B3BF9724841B842793900911240"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the progress made in the implementation of the strategy over the preceding decade with respect to each of the goals described in subsection (a)(3), including with respect to the qualitative and quantitative goals and metrics included in the initial report pursuant to subsection (b)(5) and using the criteria described in such subsection (b)(5).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59F062402EB846CB8C4F38B8F95EB7DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the successes, challenges, and effectiveness of the strategy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H05188103F4934D499AD2656EFC947B08"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommended legislative or executive policy changes relevant to addressing any gaps, policy or program shortcomings, or other outstanding challenges relating to the goals of the strategy, along with descriptions of prospective follow-up activities necessary to address such challenges.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD11A2C44491244428A63BC7C740E4E5D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations relating to fostering further synergies between implementation of activities, as relevant and appropriate, relating to the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3701">19 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), the AfCFTA, and any other United States trade policy initiatives towards Africa, including types of activities and expected outcomes based on the implementation of the strategy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB8C22CB76B61424A8660E34117061E5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A detailed description of the expenditure of all amounts authorized to implement the strategy throughout the 10-year period, including amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization under section 5(b), disaggregated by fiscal year, account, and activity.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7DD88D2EC47840BFAF8EAB24CA07D8E7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Each report required by this section shall be submitted in unclassified form and may include a classified annex. The unclassified portion of each such report shall be posted on publicly available websites of the Office of the United States Trade Representative.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HA1BBBD032C3B45A497D1A70876B63287"><enum>5.</enum><header>AfCFTA trade capacity building program</header>
<subsection id="H5931FD09581F4026AF3E184C5531AC52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Trade capacity building implementation</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development shall establish an AfCFTA Trade Capacity Building Program to support the implementation of the strategy required by section 4 through existing authorities granted by the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>), in collaboration with continental, regional, and country partners in Africa. In carrying out such Program, the Administrator—</text> <paragraph id="H22D75E3DBF8945E087646D6D19E2DCF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may designate the Prosper Africa Initiative to administer the AfCFTA Trade Capacity Building Program;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3EB187DFB7B04C70B8010831054D141F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may support multi-year and renewable activities with the AfCFTA Trade Capacity Building Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6819C247EA4B41AE8F432F2773D43292"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall consult with the United States Trade Representative in making programmatic decisions; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H799C366E4FD840529957AB6078E8B20E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall receive approval from the Trade Policy Staff Committee established pursuant to section 242(a) of the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1872">19 U.S.C. 1872(a)</external-xref>) for all activities for which funds are planned to be made available (including any transfers to other Federal departments, agencies, or entities) in a fiscal year from the AfCFTA Trade Capacity Building Program before the start of such fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE79562705CE42E391F4656E333396EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $200,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2025 through 2034 for the United States Agency for International Development to carry out the AfCFTA Trade Capacity Building Program described in subsection (a). Amounts so authorized—</text>
<paragraph id="HFE77A27ECDC944DFBB6347420B23760B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be in addition to amounts otherwise authorized for existing projects, programs, and activities that support the goals of such Program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79005FD4EE5D4C33B99A40B3F775B9E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may also be made available for consulting or technical services, equipment, new personnel, or other project-related administrative expenses associated with the development, implementation, and reporting requirements of the President’s strategy required by section 4(a); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF82EB0ABC2E546BA935E959BBDF7D3BD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>are authorized to be transferred from the United States Agency for International Development to other appropriate Federal departments or agencies to the extent provided in advance by appropriations Acts.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H69B0984B12FF47C28B2294FC6665512E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to—</text>
<paragraph id="H6FCB0C193AFE40379D42CB5216C82A05"><enum>(1)</enum><text>limit any authority or responsibility of the United States Trade Representative relating to the establishment or implementation of the trade policies of the United States (including under section 141 of the Trade Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/2171">19 U.S.C. 2171</external-xref>)); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDA255CEA876048A99FD785252EEE9BEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transfer any such authority or responsibility to the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HAF3D20686D1A43758A9EE02629DCB53E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD32D9239661E4C9B8DA5981634959574"><enum>(1)</enum><header>A<enum-in-header>f</enum-in-header>CFTA</header><text>The term <term>AfCFTA</term> means the African Continental Free Trade Area authorized to be created under the Agreement Establishing the African Continental Free Trade Area, adopted by its African Union signatories in Kigali, Rwanda, on March 21, 2018.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0CDF525898004EA18051DD5E5B55D565"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant congressional committees</term> means the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HA039F232844A4158B12E314CD1FC7786"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Ways and Means, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0B246958145A424F98711E0E2B9E75AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

