<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8F320B8A76B847CF8A6F02C7B0665900" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>101 HR 7247 IH: Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7247</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220328">March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Apex Project, Nevada Land Transfer and Authorization Act of 1989 to include the City of North Las Vegas and the Apex Industrial Park Owners Association, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C22AB0FB93843B9B9A42767596E6CE3" style="OLC"><section id="HDCF5489C0B854A408F801F6455DD9180" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAF2BD7AA35B54495B83C8BF9764805E6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Apex Project, Nevada Land Transfer and Authorization Act of 1989</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Apex Project, Nevada Land Transfer and Authorization Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/67">Public Law 101–67</external-xref>; 103 Stat. 168) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB04BEFD9FDD447E98E342A329C4A92E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2(a), by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEEC8331CB10642D7A98D9081F7AC74BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HDE2908EE9C6F4792AC858D0C015CADF0"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nevada’s <quote>boom and bust</quote> economic timeline demonstrates a need for economic diversity and stability in the Las Vegas Valley. In the year 2000, Nevada was the fastest growing State for 14 consecutive years and had increased its population by 1,000,000 residents since 1980. During the recession and mortgage crisis in 2009, Nevada was one of the hardest hit States, with its population facing a 20 percent increase in economic insecurity. Over the following decade, the Las Vegas Valley rebuilt, and by 2020, Nevada led in growth nationally. However, in 2021, the State experienced economic hardship at higher rates due to the impact of the COVID–19 pandemic on the travel and tourism industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7062571E977474AAC868EFA075EF0DE"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Apex Project has expanded to be one of the most promising economic endeavors in Southern Nevada, with the potential to create jobs, stimulate wages, and improve the well-being of everyone in the region—especially the citizens of North Las Vegas, the only predominantly minority population, which has been hit particularly hard by recessions and the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07B3E405C71F473CB4298856BCC92C4B"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Apex Project has evolved since 1989, but the partnership between Federal and private land owners remains unwavering. The Bureau of Land Management and Apex stakeholders have created important environmental protections and permitting procedures that are appropriate to utilize in a streamlined capacity as the Apex Project continues to take a new direction. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEC09F9639524A78898E39543A71AE3D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 2(b)—</text><subparagraph id="H9A1AEE3858034CCAB228A4A23C65628B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (8); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F81025C958E48CDA4652E56A6A1D284"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (5) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H39B375C613254031A96EA34104228205" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H01C02DAB586D4D08B551CBE412626D27"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Apex Industrial Park Owners Association</term> has the meaning given such term by the charter document for the entity entitled <quote>Apex Industrial Park Owners Association</quote>, formed on April 9, 2001, and any successor documents to such charter document, on file with the Nevada Secretary of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1B0C5633D5410194416A9E7808BC86"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>City of North Las Vegas</term> means North Las Vegas, Nevada. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8D20FFBE3D94E1DA9557C4D1B4266C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 3(b)—</text><subparagraph id="H3D26633994494EF281DDE6A5BFB21D58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Clark County for the connection</quote> and inserting <quote>Clark County, the City of North Las Vegas, and the Apex Industrial Park Owners Association, individually or jointly as appropriate, for the connection</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A43820AB1C54B6D9ACB5211BEB0B0C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Kerr-McGee Site</quote> and inserting <quote>Kerr-McGee Site and other lands conveyed in accordance with this Act</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13F04A0CB71A4FDBB3557D5D51C50943"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(or any successor maps created by the Secretary)</quote> after <quote>May 1989</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5461150BC3A04379BC3ABFA7CCFDAC7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 4(c), by striking <quote>Pursuant</quote> and all that follows through <quote>Clark County</quote> and inserting <quote>During such time as the requirements of section 6 are met, and pursuant to applicable law, the Secretary shall grant Clark County, the City of North Las Vegas, and the Apex Industrial Owners Association</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D9D7963DE184CFBB3437DFD2FEFDEC5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 4(e)(1), by striking the last sentence and inserting <quote>The withdrawal made by this subsection shall continue in perpetuity for all lands transferred in accordance with this subsection.</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAADE4D49898493CB7D6B53D3700A0ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 4(e), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H265BC222C6AF4321A2D0613E152F01B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H718C6C811B2D4A3AA765279E5215408D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the sale of mineral materials resulting from grading, land balancing, or other activities on the surface of a parcel within the Apex Site for which the United States retains an interest in the minerals—</text><subparagraph id="H5ABA4C6EB5484349BBE89240E3248889"><enum>(A)</enum><text>it shall be considered impracticable to obtain competition for purposes of section 3602.31(a)(2) of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</short-title>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H747B1642A364419CBC60907C905A5059"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such sale shall be exempt from the quantity and term limitations imposed on noncompetitive sales under subpart 3602 of such title (as in effect on the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Apex Area Technical Corrections Act</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H093009530DDB41A587C7F8B1C86E641B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 6, by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H862240A325FE48D1A46BA487F0AA6130" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7076BADAE2704CC1B81E9216883AD898"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Compliance with environmental assessments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each transfer by the United States of additional lands or interests in lands within the Apex Site or rights-of-way issued pursuant to this Act shall be conditioned upon compliance with applicable Federal land laws, including the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 and the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

