<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HF100F850BD664E51B6F8464C08DC56B7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 847 EH: Promoting Digital Privacy Technologies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 847</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To support research on privacy enhancing technologies and promote responsible data use, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HFA9A1C796E184E24B40F846328FEFEA6"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H3A38807E078049D997E867ADBF071CC5"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Digital Privacy Technologies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF88E7B4A84E04B8EB66437CF53F4491B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definition of privacy enhancing technology</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>privacy enhancing technology</quote>— </text> 
<paragraph id="HC614B4F1466A47BD83505CA33B3543FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any software or hardware solution, technical process, or other technological means of mitigating individuals’ privacy risks arising from data processing by enhancing predictability, manageability, disassociability, and confidentiality; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H607DF8AFCFBC444EB34E013DB0F03C72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE26F480A857F4F4CBFFCF68EDBAB9962"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cryptographic techniques for facilitating computation or analysis on data while mitigating privacy risks;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67E179FD00594301BFD4FCCA2BE8CEFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">techniques for publicly sharing data without enabling inferences to be made about specific individuals;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1F951BF209FA4E39ABAE467E8A32B4CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">techniques for giving individuals’ control over the dissemination, sharing, and use of their data;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCAA12C45C87E46D9B2650223DDCC6A0C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>techniques for generating synthetic data; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E822D9334E044469E9FC69CD58966D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other technology or approach that reduces the risk of re-identification, including when combined with other information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HBFAE715FAEA64F70873F1393A61DA288"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Science Foundation support of research on privacy enhancing technology</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with other relevant Federal agencies (as determined by the Director), shall support merit-reviewed and competitively awarded research on privacy enhancing technologies, which may include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB6D9CB4C146643DEA245DB563FB5691D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fundamental research on technologies for de-identification, pseudonymization, anonymization, or obfuscation to mitigate individuals’ privacy risks in data sets while maintaining fairness, accuracy, and efficiency;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H756F10545C0B465B88319418A698ABD4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fundamental research on algorithms and other similar mathematical tools used to protect individual privacy when collecting, storing, sharing, analyzing, or aggregating data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H06D037721DC4471FB1BF4F9D05878D72"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fundamental research on technologies that promote data minimization in data collection, sharing, and analytics that takes into account the trade-offs between the data minimization goals and the informational goals of data collection;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58571CCDD4874CF4BC4B1B36A029A62B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>research awards on privacy enhancing technologies coordinated with other relevant Federal agencies and programs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DADD6A9961B49E1A709170967D042FB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting education and workforce training research and development activities, including re-training and upskilling of the existing workforce, to grow the number of privacy enhancing technology researchers and practitioners;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBB3B012D9854B96A772364213FBD062"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">multidisciplinary socio-technical research that fosters broader understanding of privacy preferences, requirements, and human behavior to inform the design and adoption of effective privacy solutions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F217547F399405BBCF2D0BFCE56B4F6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>development of freely available privacy enhancing technology software libraries, platforms, and applications; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H049B890866A1405F8FC232DE4B461721"><enum>(8)</enum><text>fundamental research on techniques that may undermine the protections provided by privacy enhancing technologies, the limitations of the protections provided by privacy enhancing technologies, and the trade-offs between privacy and utility required for their deployment.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5062B0A5EFDB41899B7C4B9D8D7657EE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Integration into the computer and network security program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subparagraph (D) of section 4(a)(1) of the Cyber Security Research and Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7403">15 U.S.C. 7403(a)(1)(D)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4BAD020B4054B31AF776BD324209BA8"> <subparagraph id="HC9DC2890A553482DAF34DCFE3DFFC821"><enum>(D)</enum><text>privacy and confidentiality, including privacy enhancing technologies;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HD59B0C47EED046209443186575C8973D"><enum>5.</enum><header>Coordination with the National Institute of Standards and Technology and other stakeholders</header> 
<subsection id="HE798369F7A0E44848F6FCCDE75387A6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, acting through the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program, shall coordinate with the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, the Federal Trade Commission, and the heads of other Federal agencies, as appropriate, to accelerate the development, deployment, and adoption of privacy enhancing technologies. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HD2266E7680F34A88A95D9700A1388289"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology shall conduct outreach to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1A936DE035E542CF96A0743120BAFBB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receive input from private, public, and academic stakeholders on the development of privacy enhancing technologies; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB7EBE87D8E3488DA571E1F23EAABC58"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> facilitate and support ongoing public and private sector engagement to inform the development and dissemination of voluntary, consensus-based technical standards, guidelines, methodologies, procedures, and processes to cost-effectively increase the integration of privacy enhancing technologies in data collection, sharing, and analytics performed by the public and private sectors.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFDCCF7B98B1148E8939FA5075A97BA64"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report on privacy enhancing technology research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, acting through the Networking and Information Technology Research and Development Program, shall, in coordination with the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the heads of other Federal agencies, as appropriate, submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Subcommittee on Commerce, Justice, Science, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, a report containing—</text> <paragraph id="H6E0C5CF30005427BBEFFC5C765B2611B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the progress of research on privacy enhancing technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H786072EC09FC4B0FB8DF63E63B64DFCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the progress of the development of voluntary resources described under section 5(b)(2); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD937AB16C55149AE8A84ED88C4AF7419"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any policy recommendations that could facilitate and improve communication and coordination between the private sector and relevant Federal agencies for the implementation and adoption of privacy enhancing technologies.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HB3C330E32155453DA3734B04DEEFAA36"><enum>7.</enum><header>Protecting personal identifying information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any personal identifying information collected or stored through the activities authorized in this Act shall be done in accordance with section 690 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (relating to the protection of human subjects), or any successor regulation.</text></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220510" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 11, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

