<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H365302F2345D45598C5647FFC15ED1CA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8363 IH: Earning Experience Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8363</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a work-based learning opportunities pilot grant program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0BE08D1E870946F3BDB95B08E3E60F6A" style="OLC"><section id="H87EB6EBA1FA24CB488B8BD08971E79BB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Earning Experience Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3D0759F409504CBD9B4AD0037EE82078"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part C of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1087-51">42 U.S.C. 1087–51 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE5295F8F7AF449FFB910A86A73B80F82"><section commented="no" id="H9E12900278E04B33A67D192D39BF5D0B"><enum>449.</enum><header>Work-based learning opportunities pilot grant program</header><subsection commented="no" id="H439EFC601C294E739B70EE3933B05D41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HBDC5AE8E37B84E4C8A35EB9212B75367"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible institutions participating under this part to establish or expand a program to develop work-based learning positions.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEFD7F762B7074B938AFFB133D54BCFAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations</header><subparagraph id="H1E89C4DE816348CFAD8FA5558FA3C6E4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than 4 years, but may be renewed by the Secretary for a period of 2 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2752C938B664BE6A08E7968D1F8A64F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>A grant under this section may not be in an amount greater than $1,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H349E9591D64944F9896AA1F6176F5F27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be selected to receive a grant under this section an eligible institution participating under this part shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including a plan that describes how the eligible institution will establish or expand a program to develop work-based learning positions that will—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C613927E9494C03B4C166DA492FE039"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">benefit students with exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD97999AC3A7C4988A07508A627CE9BD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify in-demand industry sectors or occupations (as determined by the Bureau of Labor and Statistics, State departments of labor, and local workforce development boards) and develop partnerships with employers (including nonprofit organizations, for-profit firms, or public agencies) in such sectors or occupations;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4762417CDEDD4A91B0F4EEA7D5D0C926"><enum>(3)</enum><text>involve participating employers in evaluating and improving such program;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H57B459BD587540A995BB051B8F626C89"><enum>(4)</enum><text>track and report academic and employment outcomes for participating students; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF2756631A2D84B4681FE103A17FDCD03"><enum>(5)</enum><text>be able to continue after the end of the grant term.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HD0518640D25C4740ACA235B09F5545A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under this program shall be used to pay wages for students participating under this program and develop work-based learning positions that—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HADE2161197B7496EB1B61C2BA71FC640"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are for a period of at least 12 weeks;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3778AB3ADE8B40078F58DA60F95F6D03"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve students with exceptional need (as defined in section 413C(c)(2));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8A9694675D6E4B258262A6AA666CC89C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>limit administrative work to no more than 25 percent of such position;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1ED85C76ADD34EBF88E2335F6BD3CA60"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide a minimum of 15 hours of work per week during periods of enrollment and 30 hours per week during periods of nonenrollment, except such requirement may be waived by the institution in consultation with a student;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE8507D7D836F4096B97B33E474926D15"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include career coaching from participating employers (including mock interviews, résumé writing assistance, and counseling on applying for and attaining employment); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBB3831689970468BAB7AA79F1BE66F9E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide participating students with opportunities to meet with employers in fields or industries related to those of participating employers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H046453FA2AFC400CBE4B0FD3DEA1F3A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On a date that is before the date on which the period of the grant received by an eligible institution under this section terminates, such institution shall submit a report to the Secretary including—</text><paragraph id="H8961582A46654A2686619BC58FA1FC05"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the graduation rate or completion rate (as described under section 485(a)(3)) with respect to students participating in work-based learning positions under the pilot program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44C47AD342794878A76C9E282F94E2C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the results of the work-based learning opportunities program for which such institution received such grant, including—</text><subparagraph id="H0EA67BBAD1B24F95BF2C91BF676D3CAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">participating students’ satisfaction with the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD88E79F7E0A94106829173D89C7537D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the types of jobs in which participating students were employed and the types of duties performed in such jobs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC359900226A4F4F870B10B3274636CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the academic programs of the participating students;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5A6A66FC464428D852FED0FCD3C7140"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the share of participating students who worked at another job, in addition to the one under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57A3056102B9450FB75A8723D18C261F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the percentage of participating students who, during the second quarter after completing their academic program, are in education or training activities or unsubsidized employment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A559C1F14BA4257A9019BF5976CA267"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of participating students employed in the in-demand industry sectors or occupations identified under subsection (b)(2) within 2 quarters of completing their academic programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4953AF328A3B4D89906FA216910C7388"><enum>(G)</enum><text>other items as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H068D529A470F484489BC39E5EFE03B8D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reservation of funding for such program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts appropriated to carry out section 441(b) for a fiscal year and remaining after the Secretary allocates funds in accordance with section 442 for such year, the Secretary shall reserve $30,000,000 to carry out grants under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

