<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B22E7064F7A4BBC8991705893A43D7C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7745 IH: Investigate Russian War Crimes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220512">May 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support and allow funding for the investigation of the International Criminal Court with respect to the Situation in Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H945D5B1C0F524063A5E35184078FAD83" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H52F7B6125E0B4F5A9249E5DFBD92617D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Investigate Russian War Crimes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H37C5B7D457CE4B30A8FB149564C276C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to support the Investigation into the Situation in Ukraine being conducted by the International Criminal Court, including by providing material support and participating in international efforts to collect and preserve evidence that may be relevant for prosecution.</text></section>
<section id="H6F2EA23392A74AE099B9A870D216A33B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 705(b) of the Admiral James W. Nance and Meg Donovan Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 2000 and 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7401">22 U.S.C. 7401(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The prohibition under this section shall not apply with respect to amounts made available to the International Criminal Court solely for the purpose of providing material support or funding for the Investigation into the Situation in Ukraine conducted by the International Criminal Court.</quote>.</text></section> <section id="H444721A428AC4C86B6389985CC994C8B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report setting forth the Administration’s policy review of the United States position on the ICC’s Investigation into the Situation in Ukraine, including—</text>
<paragraph id="HA50BBA35BFC24A1FAD9B1D289CE9D0FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations as to the provision of material support to such investigation; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89A94DDB7CBB44D3B6CAE20F873FCA0B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national security and foreign policy benefits of formally providing material support to such investigation and other investigations.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

