<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H07320FB032CE4A6E8D8C5D92E3A96149" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7368 IH: Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7368</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220401">April 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency to develop a program to provide assistance to creditworthy borrowers with Federal student debt in purchasing certain foreclosed homes owned by the Federal Government, the Federal National Mortgage Association, the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation, and local land banks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H89DAF23EF0424905BF929F96F4B4443B" style="OLC"><section id="H8EB67D8079CF4BDBB335A41C5555584E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transforming Student Debt to Home Equity Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7E1462D0C3924CCC85554EDEF3BFA932"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H46B977ADDA8442B6828B84CDF13FCE29"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the third quarter of 2021, over 15,185,000 homes remain vacant in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC90408381414B36B1BD0D1BA8816468"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These extended vacancies depress neighborhood property values and create a downward spiral in neighborhood stability in already troubled communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB102EEA3EB4F27A1D58AEE50F293B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Meanwhile, due to climbing expenses of higher education, the total Federal student debt owed equals $1,750,000,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3479F9AF81B42BCBB075A14C32959C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>More than 44,700,000 Americans have at least one outstanding student loan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF205587F00F4B73A49DE1AD2DA81914"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Student loan repayments are forcing millions of young families to delay purchasing their first home, as they cannot afford to save for a downpayment or qualify for a mortgage while also paying off student debt.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBED3931B4A654D0C81BB574C8D54DDE4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Data from the Federal Reserve shows that non-Hispanic White households have a median net worth of $181,440, while Black households have a median net worth of $20,730 and Hispanic households have $36,180; providing innovative financial products will allow the United States to reduce the racial wealth gap and to ensure equitable access to housing and economic mobility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4286B78DEB0484AA0FD716A14A98D09"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The COVID–19 pandemic has exacerbated the racial wealth gap by increasing unemployment within already disadvantaged communities and further reducing access to homeownership and increasing the burden of student debt.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D3902EB1B8C4EA7A9F6351E95F49E03"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to a report from the Joint Center for Housing Studies of Harvard University, Black and Hispanic households are more likely to have their household income decline and to face hardship in paying rent and other monthly housing costs due to the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8A655D88C52490EA6A4A1C595202BFB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>It is imperative to create a demonstration program to design financial pathways to, where possible, systematically convert some student debt streams into equity streams through negotiation of mortgages; otherwise housing purchases will continue to be sluggish among first-time home buyers and thousands more Americans will enter their midyears saddled with student loan debt never having had the opportunity to accumulate equity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9434B117E7334D4DB9D4C44BF7258187"><enum>(10)</enum><text>It is in the interest of the Federal Government to use the resources at its disposal, including both housing properties held in trust and student debt obligations, to put reverse pressure on these downward trends.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DEE86066AF14641B7FCE3BEC6FD78DF"><enum>(11)</enum><text>By arranging financing that recalculates terms, debt-to-income ratios, mortgage interest rates, and other factors, short-term student debt could transition into longer-term home ownership.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H513A3B2D8016432F9ED58DA85E1FE188"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The goal is to connect creditworthy Federal student debt holders with housing properties for sale and held by the Federal Government and local land banks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93BFF079C9204307988B37E23D9F133E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Over time, participants can help restore neighborhoods, transform their debt to equity, and stabilize secured property values locally and on the Federal ledger by maintaining and investing in a home mortgage.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDDC45BAA6E4C42A4A2B2E03842D8A564"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program to expand access to mortgages to eligible creditworthy home buyers with federal student loan debt</header><subsection id="H4BFE3DA59F0447BDA60CCC10FE47DE17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>From amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (g), the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall establish and carry out a pilot demonstration program to—</text><paragraph id="H14026D3EF94C4D30BF8ABDBECF3D0370"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide assistance to eligible applicants in purchasing eligible properties; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D415EEC34264B3096249C3EE5EF634B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subsequently analyze the results of the provision of such assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E395614EF1E442584879B4C05024A78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In establishing and carrying out the program pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary and the Director shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H5187C245168D407C80D797276BB9E5B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director of the Consumer Financial Protection Bureau;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H464DD4A6AC1847419C25D20D0AFC468D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E5072BEBC95455588A92D1EC388B14A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Veterans Affairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD33FF117967432DAE9EF971434E0ED4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary of Education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F867ABE86804C0A920780F6CF219E40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77A6D1563540465F97A6DC43BCBACABA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text>To be eligible for the program established pursuant to subsection (a), an applicant—</text><paragraph id="H60DC4A32A20042C6BEB195577B09B2DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall have an outstanding balance of principal or interest owing on a Federal loan made, insured, or guaranteed under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DAEC75FE5EC404DA50BAF5BEA96CCFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall have an area median income at or below 120 percent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44D5B70B73FD45498B36B44FDE805EBE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not be subject to a judgment secured through litigation with respect to such a loan under title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070">20 U.S.C. 1070 et seq.</external-xref>), may not be subject to an order for wage garnishment under section 488A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1095a">20 U.S.C. 1095a</external-xref>), and at the time of application for participation in the program under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H452201D976A447FE9D922EBA101F508C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such a loan shall be in repayment status as determined under section 428(b)(7)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078">20 U.S.C. 1078(b)(7)(A)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B251F05D9D4063B1BF73F2DA4121EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such a loan shall be in a grace period preceding repayment;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B0442FF73A8444CBBD25515D9C002F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may not have owned a home during the 3-year period immediately before the applicant purchases an eligible property with assistance provided under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAE3624842B44E889935831BF205D8EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>shall complete a program of counseling with respect to the responsibilities and financial management involved in homeownership that is approved by the Secretary;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81E4530FB65347E6A9E30D112973F0BC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>shall be creditworthy, as determined by the Secretary and the Director;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00AA30A1F2974E72BEE92C9BEABB64BC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>shall agree to use an eligible property purchased with assistance provided under this section as the applicant’s primary residence for not less than the 3-year period beginning on the date of such purchase; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H864FB083A9A04BC599FD139CCB199F29"><enum>(8)</enum><text>shall be employed and earning sufficient income to repay a mortgage loan, as determined by the Secretary and the Director for the purposes of this program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20EC8E0554EE49E5A61F6FEF4FDDE58A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Types of assistance</header><paragraph id="H3D29DA2A26B0407E95DD19A81BC29C95"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A program established under this section may provide for any one or more of the following options:</text><subparagraph id="HDC15CD5086C74414AC87B9881C31F969"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A discount on the appraised value of an eligible property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA52B68B1135D4C898A08892847FBBC36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Flexibility in underwriting standards related to the purchase of eligible properties for mortgages insured under title II of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1707">12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.</external-xref>) or owned or guaranteed by the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H807194A740FD4D0AACD751B64657686A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The development of new mortgage products specifically targeted to eligible applicants.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51DB7B62BC72488BAEBC924831C87C80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Downpayment and private mortgage assistance to eligible applicants.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5ACE28DE0EE410D949DBDA48745DD56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Pre-purchase counseling including related credit and financial coaching to eligible applicants.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4E4F1B5BD3E42F4B7E351D92F93D8C2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Provision of a low- or no-interest mortgage rate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4ED4F6EE243D44DBAE37DFCC9B67154D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other assistance that the Secretary and Director jointly deem appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H679199DCB3EE473F82FE0754B232058A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Repayment integration</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program that will integrate repayment of loans described in subsection (c)(1) into a mortgage repayment schedule to allow an eligible applicant to accumulate equity in the eligible property. The Secretary shall use actuarial data and risk assessments to collateralize the mortgage provided through Federal funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8851C9B3A628447A92E8D896FFB4594B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In providing assistance described under paragraph (1), the Secretary and the Director may collaborate with—</text><subparagraph id="H5A40C8D388E744F497A19299A8148E5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community banks having less than $10,000,000,000 in total assets;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H837FB9B47D6B4A27B2035F63E15870B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>credit unions (as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24E05375F5F1457C82850C9E759A89B4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>local fair housing organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12D2BFE1F92243AD84F27F24C7C8300B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>local land banks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1898401B79D4463ABD94FD1705FD7DDB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Geographical diversity</header><text>In selecting eligible applicants to receive assistance under this section, the Secretary and the Director shall, to the extent practicable, consider the location of the eligible property to be purchased by the eligible applicant, including whether the eligible property is located in a rural or urban area, to ensure geographic diversity of such eligible properties.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC906A2727AB343719696A530628F0245"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HF942F89C8EA04B3DADFC9386482BA241"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary and the Director shall submit to Congress an interim report describing the type of assistance the Secretary and the Director shall provide under the program established under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5314F2EE6B844C95AB3B2C726A71D6FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary and the Director shall submit to Congress a final report that—</text><subparagraph id="HE20FC64194024D1D872467053451760B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluates the impact of the program carried out under this section and describes any findings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19CF0664084D4ADCA136F0FD254047B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies other types of assistance the Secretary and the Director may offer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDD8B9A07B2B46E7B269C64CF47D4147"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes any recommendations the Secretary and Director may have for improving the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62788E612BF74FDD83D19D70F1E4170E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H94245E3247F2488784C8E4525C4FBF55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30762D7B47C84A2FA85B0E948334E094"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Department of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E56AD39A5104D6694EDAEE937748F60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible property</header><text>The term <term>eligible property</term> means a property that is designed as a dwelling for occupancy by 1 to 4 families—</text><subparagraph id="H36ACBB5560834133A22AF7AD97DACC4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is safe and habitable, as defined by the Secretary and the Director;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AB88F2AFCDE40E183E037932D67165D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the occupancy of which, as determined by the Secretary and the Director, will promote community revitalization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EED964225E34152BBF6049A154234A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="HBEBCEA729D81432DA33A526C985752BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was previously subject to a mortgage loan insured by the Federal Housing Administration under title II of the National Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1707">12 U.S.C. 1707 et seq.</external-xref>) and is owned by the Secretary pursuant to the payment of insurance benefits under such Act;</text></clause><clause id="H94A068C7368D49EA81A8A3CB0615108B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a real estate owned property of the Federal National Mortgage Association or the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation;</text></clause><clause id="HFD6CA6FC24334DFE9541BB01C5618581"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is owned by a local land bank;</text></clause><clause id="H57813101495D4BB0A6F3F676EA76A0DA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is owned by the Department of Agriculture; or</text></clause><clause id="H30EBBA92AA664E2F95389177B56A0036"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is owned by the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H183DF5FD7A0A4363B181452F9BA73B6F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local land bank</header><text>The term <term>local land bank</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2706F769824249D2ACDCAA85FC00FCA2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a governmental or nongovernmental nonprofit entity established, at least in part, to assemble, temporarily manage, and dispose of vacant land for the purpose of stabilizing neighborhoods and encouraging re-use or redevelopment of urban property; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E4CEE1ED6EB44B4A95A77FCEFEF8136"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other governmental or nongovernmental entity as the Secretary and the Director may determine appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C482B82FC0E4058A9FD8893D5CF6206"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as necessary to carry out this section for fiscal years 2023, 2024, and 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

