<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC9E535961724C42A60D72AC6AD3D04E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9642 IH: Solving the Unnecessary Contracting Cliff for Enterprises to Scale Successfully Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221221">December 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program for transitioning small businesses in the construction or engineering industries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE0C4CD12255C4877828F3E4754ED200D" style="OLC"><section id="HAC38F8C753844A68A63E7F8CC2AE0401" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Solving the Unnecessary Contracting Cliff for Enterprises to Scale Successfully Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SUCCESS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA5325D51F1804B80AAD1987C1C62E107"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program for transitioning small businesses in the construction or engineering industries</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 32 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC1DE9EDA095457F904BD64AC3228B11"><section id="HD209496ABE8E46E5A5833B898CD44077"><enum>33.</enum><header>Pilot program for transitioning small businesses in the construction or engineering industries</header><subsection id="H5C40CF4A217E4BF2B00780D71D841E89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFC8CDB1C0E79450D96E2AD8C835A06B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible concern</header><text>The term <term>eligible concern</term> means a concern that has grown to exceed the size standard applicable to the North American Industry Classification System code corresponding to—</text><subparagraph id="HA366DF6D58C24F9BAE01BF36DEE540CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>commercial and institutional building construction; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87CF0816DBA747E88CE5925874CB984C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>engineering services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA492F12464EE4DE8AAF3A523A81559D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Participant</header><text>The term <term>Participant</term> means an eligible concern that—</text><subparagraph id="HE08C11152CB146F594EAA0CC3E862836"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets the criteria described in subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H754BBA5C7FA847DFBACEEE2AA044935C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>participates in the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0004BCB2E904591961877B2502E9FF4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the pilot program for transitioning small businesses established under paragraph (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92EC231174EA4E8C80643CF15809CD0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator shall promulgate regulations establishing a pilot program to foster the continued success of eligible concerns by permitting those concerns to qualify as small for certain contracts during a transitional period.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3DE2EE257A2D40A6BD9C8D62FDDE743C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Program is to assist eligible concerns in their transition from small business concerns to other-than-small and thereby increase competition in the unrestricted Federal marketplace.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF1D9A47779C84AA5BEE1A4BBA334C22A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Criteria for participation</header><paragraph id="H6285F8EE9F68498E94B80020EC8F5605"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Election</header><text>An eligible concern may make a one-time election, which shall not be changed, to participate, with respect to the primary activity of the eligible concern, under—</text><subparagraph id="HE8502001D7C64637B125A0EC0D196307"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the North American Industry Classification System Code corresponding to commercial and institutional building construction; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E6A2DD3C294885BFA6CCA790D2BBED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the North American Industry Classification System Code corresponding to engineering services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45F692C3845345F48E4D7D7E66D2EDC0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Registration</header><text>An eligible concern shall—</text><subparagraph id="H78CF5B804AB2437CB774CBFF1AF343FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>register as a Participant with the System for Award Management (or any successor system) on the date on which the eligible concern makes the election under paragraph (1) in the registry described in subsection (h); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA97FC306854A4DAFB20DA35F873CE0B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the registration of the eligible concern is current and accurate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C9904DBCA664219B480F464E8CA51A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term of the transitional period</header><subparagraph id="HA531B10EA1D44A6BA5F10B50C9F0CFD4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the transitional period, during which an eligible concern may be eligible to participate in the Program, shall—</text><clause id="H52B6D0640B95457B8EE43C486F3F979B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>begin on the date which the eligible concern first exceeds the size standard applicable to the North American Industry Classification System code corresponding to the industry elected by the concern pursuant to paragraph (1); and </text></clause><clause id="H16ED483AC7AF442CA0410D8EAA7D1586"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not exceed 7 consecutive years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H420245250F8C4CF89406429A29B8B2C1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An eligible concern first exceeding the size standard described in subparagraph (A)(i) within the 7-year period immediately preceding the effective date of regulations issued under subsection (b) shall be eligible to participate in the Program for the remainder of the 7-year period beginning on the date which the concern first exceeded the size standard.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F6DE59139284BC185C921D46947FEAD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Activity targets</header><text>The regulations described in subsection (b) shall establish non-small business set aside business activity targets that—</text><subparagraph id="H2CD03955D0214314BADBC0467C8ECC35"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are applicable to Participants during the third year and each succeeding year of Program participation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB8795225B2546ACB2AEB5CCF1F60E75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>during the period of time described in subparagraph (A), shall reflect a reasonably consistent increase in sales other than obtained through contracts set aside for small business concerns, expressed as a percentage of total sales.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2171D6AAE0CB43018E748BE340A4B2A0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cap on average annual receipts</header><text>Each Participant shall be subject to a cap on average annual receipts that is 5 times the size standard applicable to the North American Industry Classification System code corresponding to the industry elected by the concern, calculated consistent with the method in 121.104 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H747540403C904032ABC11A76E3D306B1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Certification</header><subparagraph id="H69D2590D653F4D798708DBE428CB72A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Participant shall be required to annually certify in the System for Award Management (or any successor system) as to whether or not the Participant has—</text><clause id="H9D269610283A4CED9DCA782ADCC7A00A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>met the activity target established under paragraph (4) for the preceding year; and</text></clause><clause id="H0B9933FA6CEC48DB8E5A56708E648FAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>complied with the restrictions described in subsection (e).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FCE91E0FEDB400E9E147884A30FF685"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>If a Participant certifies that the Participant has not met the applicable activity targets established under paragraph (4) for 2 consecutive years, or certifies that the Participant has not complied with the restrictions described in subsection (e), the Participant shall no longer be eligible to participate in the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H629585FC9D3040ACAA12B8781D5265FC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Participant report</header><text>The regulations issued under subsection (b) shall establish—</text><subparagraph id="H3E009B39FBCB4BFAB5C50D446FC4EA0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requirements for annual reporting by Participants to the Administrator during Program participation, to include reporting on compliance with activity targets established under paragraph (4), the number and dollar value of contracts awarded based on eligibility under subsection (f)(1), and information required for the registry under subsection (h); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B4AFE032CFF46BAAD5C366661FEC6DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reporting requirements applicable for a period of not less than 5 years after exiting the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H178DFB1DDDC746A58774D4932206142E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>No reinstatement</header><text>Upon the expiration of the transitional period, or once a Participant otherwise becomes ineligible for the Program, the concern shall not be eligible for reinstatement in the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C884C4ABC9C497B9BA2B19227DB25CD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Restrictions</header><paragraph id="H91F75D112BC14578A5C2D5313C560E81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Mentor-protégé</header><subparagraph id="HEC430B5410344011A806E56FE0A5E90A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Participant may not apply to be a protégé under a mentor-protégé program established under this Act. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94F8EB6F158D45689ED4048068FBCC97"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Existing protégés</header><text>A Participant that is already a protégé prior to registration under the Program under subsection (d)(2) may, in years 1 and 2 of the transitional period of the Program, continue to submit proposals in a mentor-protégé program established under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5693B92BF62F47C29AB3082DD6826348"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional restrictions</header><text>In addition to the restrictions described in paragraph (1), the Administrator may include additional restrictions for Participants consistent with the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D017096168742BEACD9B7E7EEA930E4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Purposes for which participants may qualify as small</header><text>Subject to the restrictions in paragraph (e), a Participant may otherwise qualify as small for purposes of the following:</text><paragraph id="H66FEAFC51C7A4F6DBF50CBBC30E3449C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Contracts that are set aside for small business concerns and assigned a North American Industry Classification System code corresponding to the industry elected by the Participant under subsection (d)(1) and—</text><subparagraph id="HDAC0B32064F641FA8B041970D6822DD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government of the United States expects to be equal to or exceed— </text><clause id="H341077945839492F830A247FBF28B3AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for commercial and institutional building construction, $5,000,000; and</text></clause><clause id="H28938624788D4B1BA7CD0E2D7169C2A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for engineering services, $1,000,000; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B2B6377C7D846B4AFA038BF51D10225"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any orders under such contracts irrespective of the value of the order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5175F6FAA9040F5882462F748175AAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Goals established pursuant to section 15(g) for participation by small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans, qualified HUBZone small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and small business concerns owned and controlled by women.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAE56911177343D5A11E27FB985B8CF8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="HF1051735649941A8B2C63C13F570174A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Program shall terminate on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7D0EE92C2F24B849A2FE6EA92784F37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continuation of participation</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), any Participant in the program as of the date on which the Program terminates under paragraph (1) may continue to participate until the expiration of the term of the Participant under subsection (d)(3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H18E60B0227534367B5FE0BC3B6E65CFE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Publication of registry required</header><text>The Administrator shall establish and maintain in the System for Award Management (or any successor system) a registry of eligible Participants, which registry shall, to the extent practicable—</text><paragraph id="HFE586208B0364AC48E2F863546362337"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include the name, address, transitional period entry and exit dates, and elected North American Industry Classification System code with respect to each Participant; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CB1FFC62BE647809971FF7FD31F5E34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be updated by the Administrator not less than annually.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE8B482097EF46D5B7EB095D44B59E7B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Additional information To be maintained</header><text>The Administrator shall maintain data regarding—</text><paragraph id="HBD8DDE1A445A49CC8FB7CA6D4ADBDB5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of Participants in the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F19923F76344DE18D100EEA9B78FCF6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of former Participants that have exited the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75EEEF9AC7EB43A18D470B2ACFC41A94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the number of former Participants that have successfully transitioned to other-than-small, under such criteria as the Administrator may establish;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4A1BAD1343D4F51BB0CA215E2E68385"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number of former Participants that have returned to being small under North American Industry Classification System code elected by the Participant under subsection (d)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8196FCA141EE4CFC9AC61A74F18A8E1D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the total dollar value of small business awards made each fiscal year to Participants by each Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0ED76F16DC8E4F4081F00ED12F0ACAD1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>GAO study and report</header><paragraph id="H316FAD325C9A49BD95B2183FFAE76978"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall begin conducting a study to evaluate the implementation of the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42188B8411584A87AABE2C2B2AD23E28"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 8 years after the date of enactment of this section, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the study required under paragraph (1), which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H1ACA0069EEB84ABCA478711F792AF580"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the feasibility and advisability of broadening the Program to include additional industries, as defined under the North American Industry Classification System;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H147210162E6245B99E8484C069D0E089"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the effects of the Program, if any, on Participants and on the industrial base;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31B808D3AF58474F9BC707C90350604F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any recommendations for improving the Program, including whether the Program should be made permanent; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5031019704B044D28A041A92CD1257FB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any additional findings and recommendations as the Comptroller General of the United States considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

