<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7388EFFA630B40C8A3660C8957EECC39" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9586 IH: Creating Low-cost, Efficient And Net-zero Emissions Resilient Buildings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9586</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the establishment of a national model building performance standards initiative, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBFEFBE43D3C04D4596C1A029B20BC9C7" style="OLC"><section id="H4343DFAE0C0944138398B8D332862F39" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H24F9EC35EBB44C45A89A9865F4324D37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Low-cost, Efficient And Net-zero Emissions Resilient Buildings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEANER Buildings Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H39A4557D97FD4ABBB53C8E460D1C048F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H4343DFAE0C0944138398B8D332862F39" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H95D946E9FBEB4EC4819D8D5A9B27D367" level="section">Sec. 2. National model building performance standards initiative.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF3F382338D534B7B86F38ACEA75CA988" level="section">Sec. 3. National model building performance standards.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB0C511DA595B477ABED3BB2ADE9DF067" level="section">Sec. 4. Federal technical assistance and support.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4AA2C17EA599454B8D85470A97B8074E" level="section">Sec. 5. Progress reports.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDA753C21112449C383035153BB89EFBF" level="section">Sec. 6. Performance standard application to existing Federal buildings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6526292071CB41AD9F3B05426D5C25DD" level="section">Sec. 7. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA4E40183178443988FEEAE45D765E911" level="section">Sec. 8. Definitions.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H95D946E9FBEB4EC4819D8D5A9B27D367"><enum>2.</enum><header>National model building performance standards initiative</header><subsection id="H8ACF7A27ECC6401296293FD98F8C7B9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary, shall establish a national model building performance standards initiative, to—</text><paragraph id="H959C783CB44348DFA5118D9053CDB8A1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist State and local governments in the development and implementation of building performance standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H021CA8005AAE45BAB0FFADB161776D16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advance knowledge about building energy and water performance and greenhouse gas emissions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BD073E382AA46B4AA033253F5A03109"><enum>(3)</enum><text>inform efforts to reduce energy and water consumption in, and greenhouse gas emissions from, buildings nationwide; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BD2859FADEF430AA5398D276AFCEB90"><enum>(4)</enum><text>achieve progress toward a 50 percent to 52 percent reduction from 2005 levels in economy-wide net greenhouse gas emissions by 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF7ED71C71CA4CBE875C646D04959816"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initiative elements</header><text>In carrying out the national model building performance standards initiative under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H5CC3A5108A6B4246A9C9B98B8FA3A4D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop national model building performance standards in accordance with section 3;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99A669DE056A4529BC5A60E9C178CFFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide assistance to State and local governments under section 4; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AFFE147522843D7958AD9DF6D8F0891" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide related information to relevant entities, including recommendations on incentives that could be provided by State and local governments to building owners and occupants for early compliance with building performance standards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65FF4DEFE1B44E2885246B7D0F389103"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination and collaboration</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator may—</text><paragraph id="H4C1DBC6D31044A4288BB09651CBAEBD2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate with all relevant program offices across Federal Government agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCE544E93ABA451589AAF12E55F364FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>collaborate with relevant stakeholders, including—</text><subparagraph id="H221CB26F97D745FFACEC5EFEB80FC52A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State and local governments, including State air quality and utility regulators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A0DEBBC3F20466798A5651188F6552B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>metropolitan and rural planning organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA58FD5B6212940219AC3E268BE991D22"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">labor union organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5869D0BF85C94377949CD3B94EFA2725"><enum>(D)</enum><text>environmental and environmental justice organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA6046BEF5BA4A799AA1724AE14A2E5B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>building developers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A0695663F0C457083E5F1D1E5B20841"><enum>(F)</enum><text>building manufacturers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H087AA285D2E74A1BADDD6B356494EE7E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>utilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF16DCFDA8BE74F21BE77148A65A9C9C5"><enum>(H)</enum><text>infrastructure providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9AE72E325204669BCF2164D34413209"><enum>(I)</enum><text>technology providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD39A66ED20AC4B63B84FAF60B229A62B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>infrastructure construction and component parts suppliers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10A6C85642104D518D19F047840780F7"><enum>(K)</enum><text>multi-State and regional entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73243B9894CA4E8AA939D4873160FAB3"><enum>(L)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">experts from academia and nonprofits;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CF4203BA63E4606A71EA9682DBD89A4" commented="no"><enum>(M)</enum><text>affordable housing providers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H085D1FCCB6494EB7BF1D1E7BB7607A00"><enum>(N)</enum><text>any other entities determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA673349366F24B19A5EB13736129D52E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Administrator shall make appropriate use of existing programs and resources relevant to building performance standards.</text></subsection></section><section id="HF3F382338D534B7B86F38ACEA75CA988"><enum>3.</enum><header>National model building performance standards</header><subsection id="HA10865723D06410291AB187BEBDEDB4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary, shall develop national model building performance standards.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1B3F1CE34BD42B39E99ED62765145C2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing national model building performance standards under subsection (a), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="HD19BD68B66454D5B934D31016E08E5BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>address data access, collection, transparency, and reporting requirements needed to implement the national model building performance standards while maintaining the protection of personal privacy through the use of anonymized data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42DBFFD232474D17A6AA45A10AAED272"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify commercial building and multi-family building property types, sizes, and occupancy rates covered by the national model building performance standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE69C2470745942FBB0F0391E4E4B740A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish metrics and calculations to determine near-term and long-term building performance standards for properties covered by the national model building performance standards that—</text><subparagraph id="H97A43C6375F74F5A89FFA0F36A26BEA8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure properties can meet initial performance targets; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H011D3E5019DC4084B21A761B8F59EDDE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be scaled up to achieve long-term energy and water consumption targets with deep greenhouse gas emissions reductions;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFEC15DBEA3B46F2803D11545C58705F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop guidelines for the development of effective dates for compliance with building performance standards, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7492DA3EA1AE44D3B593B82DFCAB4F27" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consideration of effective dates that phase in based on the size of the relevant property; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EC1042D95AA4CFFA7327CADB169EDF9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations for adequate lead time before compliance is required, to ensure that property owners can make investments to meet near-term and long-term building performance standard targets;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5B2F9E6731A41EEB804CBD770C82760"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include recommendations on exemptions or compliance period extensions for properties that—</text><subparagraph id="H1C300E89DB664019B05EE48BB1F0631B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate financial hardship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB565D2C28A1E4914B796244D8FF0A9C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are vacant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E87C1E1D5524FF494E5754DE1B97526"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are receiving a major renovation that exceeds relevant building performance standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49FBC71474F1411E8B341909E8D56163"><enum>(D)</enum><text>are pending demolition; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H572EA22EA749448DAC579947F0128146"><enum>(E)</enum><text>meet other criteria established by the Administrator;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD74BE624AE14236BAC558A6326BAEEC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>develop recommendations on non-Federal enforcement mechanisms for implementing building performance standards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D4D0294773649AAAF9E7C99641BDB48"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider any other matters necessary to develop and implement national model building performance standards, as determined by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BD8B1C365AA4D9F9F506E30C08D314E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Periodic review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary, may—</text><paragraph id="HE904C5EEFE114A75A08F33EA81911E14" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>periodically review the national model building performance standards developed under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB006ADDC9FD448BE9D45FF2103293237" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on completion of a review under paragraph (1), if the Administrator determines that significant energy and water savings and greenhouse gas emissions reductions could result, revise the national model building performance standards.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB0C511DA595B477ABED3BB2ADE9DF067"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal technical assistance and support</header><subsection id="H9A03112983FC4A6DAFFA662BC2859B6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the national model building performance standards initiative established under section 2, the Administrator shall provide relevant technical assistance to any State or local government that intends to establish building performance standards that are at least as stringent as the national model building performance standards developed under section 3, including—</text><paragraph id="H2CCBBBBE543A410E939D0E8A9891E673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assistance in the development, modification, or implementation of such building performance standards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB45E9E41997C4B3EB5273D6489D03E51" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training for using relevant Federal tools or databases for the purposes of building performance standard implementation and enforcement, including the Energy Star Portfolio Manager;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EE1DA31F1814482935FC4C33013DC4D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">education and outreach materials on building performance standards for property owners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE33D7B76FFB947F1A548135D4B3D083A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">internet-based information resources and project tracking systems and tools established and maintained by the Administrator for energy and water consumption and greenhouse gas emissions reduction management; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCED57B2A884046B5826EBF3FC462554C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">education and outreach on existing applicable Federal programs that can help property owners meet such building performance standards that are established by the State or local government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD74F6A5F43440629ACAA1FE7C3E6F4A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Financial assistance</header><paragraph id="HD614B63209A54143830E0A66780049C6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the national model building performance standards initiative established under section 2, the Administrator shall provide financial assistance to States and local governments to establish building performance standards that are at least as stringent as the national model building performance standards developed under section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE28E1C95F64BBD98B17B6F32FF6451" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish funding award limits and application requirements for financial assistance under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB494F8BA66345569BCE36F53E6C7C64"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing financial assistance under this subsection, the Administrator shall give priority to States and local governments submitting applications that—</text><subparagraph id="H58D986551AC44AF3B6F0CE43477C5B56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify environmental justice communities served or represented by the State or local government that will benefit from the development, implementation, and enforcement of the building performance standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF78904BC2BA0472085DDBA85EF34152C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include plans to ensure that environmental justice communities are included in the development, implementation, and enforcement of the building performance standards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F2A149F88254A18A84007F56B81086E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>outline the use of labor standards, such as prevailing wage standards, project labor agreements, and local hiring and target hiring provisions, that will be applicable to the implementation and enforcement of the building performance standards.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4AA2C17EA599454B8D85470A97B8074E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Progress reports</header><subsection id="H64DA61BF085C43E8AE899F17A205B6AF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report containing—</text><paragraph id="HB8BB80E8325043778C093E890664B576"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of an assessment of the assistance provided to State and local governments under section 4; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABE3304B9B14429F9236C91C726B0579"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any recommendations for modifications to the national model building performance standards initiative established under section 2 to improve the impact of such assistance on achieving full compliance with building performance standards in jurisdictions receiving such assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AD4E418E10644919BC2F9564AAC0617"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall make available on a publicly accessible website a report on State and local governments that have received assistance under section 4, including—</text><paragraph id="H058834CD26AB4493A559838A417BDC1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of energy and water consumption and greenhouse gas emissions reduction statistics; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BE87EECD67D4E26868EB84EB23D7177"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of compliance rates with building performance standards, and other trends observed.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDA753C21112449C383035153BB89EFBF" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Performance standard application to existing Federal buildings</header><subsection id="H290781529D6D489ABC257AC2F30FB039" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the national model building performance standards under section 3, the Secretary shall prescribe regulations and requirements applying such standards to existing Federal buildings, including the Capitol and congressional buildings and facilities, taking into consideration existing requirements related to Federal buildings.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35CEE2BCD14F486887A89C94FDA73E5F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary, shall adopt procedures necessary to ensure that existing Federal buildings meet or exceed the building performance standards required pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E1EA154A48E412D822F12DB68071EAE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Labor standards</header><paragraph id="H5737886833704B29945E727E628CC1AB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Davis-bacon</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor and the General Services Administration, shall ensure that all laborers and mechanics employed by a covered contractor or subcontractor are paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a similar character in the locality, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>). With respect to the labor standards specified in this paragraph, the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB92609E28C4C11A51D94C75BF45944" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Neutrality toward organized labor</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor and the General Services Administration, shall ensure that all covered contractors and subcontractors have—</text><subparagraph id="H14E6D0633FB54775A10C552712EE7B45" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an explicit policy of neutrality with regard to—</text><clause id="H7322E8847C5E44D9B34B6056F8BA4D72" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>labor organizing for the employees; and</text></clause><clause id="H22457AAAFCB74E42AF9F35F5E692EB8E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such employees’ choice to form and join labor organizations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68FA20A60D64403D8172DEC01FF7FCDC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>policies that require—</text><clause id="H9BA68690DD92498A82D9EB0D2DD355A4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the posting and maintenance of notices in the workplace to such employees of their rights under the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="HA8CD195B67A04B669392688C429B96E1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that such employees are, at the beginning of their employment, provided notice and information regarding the employees’ rights under such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD05961766DB4260862990439926FDE4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Preference for local hiring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor and the General Services Administration, shall ensure that all covered contractors and subcontractors have explicit policies that provide a preference for local hiring, consistent with applicable Federal law and subject to rules issues by the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF687C0E10ACC43ABA9AF08E7A6CE93F5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employee classification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Secretary of Labor and the General Services Administration, shall ensure that a covered contractor or subcontractor considers an individual performing any service as an employee (and not an independent contractor) of the covered contractor or subcontractor, unless—</text><subparagraph id="H13AC4529D1484A2683ACF5B5B2F49783" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the individual is free from control and direction in connection with the performance of the service, both under the contract for the performance of the service and in fact;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0A34D572C4246CF8B6BE85D789C66FA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the service is performed outside the usual course of the business of the covered contractor or subcontractor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H411ED733A28E4039A93D5717434A99EA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the individual is customarily engaged in an independently established trade, occupation, profession, or business of the same nature as that involved in such service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6526292071CB41AD9F3B05426D5C25DD"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HB973E8D6166F434EBB6E0ED9C9D4D030"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial development and administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, there is authorized to be appropriated $11,000,000 to carry out sections 2 and 3.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB17D0FD407B14DFE8ADC8AF19141C430"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2023 through 2032, there are authorized to be appropriated—</text><paragraph id="HC007D5F4C6D6497CBE92F85E0BDFCA6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to carry out section 4(a), to remain available until expended;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC19731B76FB848ACBD49C2236ED98717"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$50,000,000 to carry out section 4(b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6059794C74EA4C8A9AC6C502631F72CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to carry out section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA4E40183178443988FEEAE45D765E911" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE7E360B86C3341798E2844E8C4BC572D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H692636286BD745DFB3A6A4A717E7CCA0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anonymized data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>anonymized data</term> means data that does not reveal names, addresses, or any other information that would identify an individual or business.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06C54899A0314CCCAF225AE7E06C3070" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Building performance standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>building performance standard</term> means a performance standard applicable to aggregated energy or water usage for an entire building (including as measured by any separate meters for the building).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F0F0309570341E4AED5E29D8BD7A423" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered contractor or subcontractor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered contractor or subcontractor</term> means a contractor or subcontractor on a project for the construction, alteration, or repair of a Federal building to comply with the national building performance standards as required under section 6.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA53B8C97000F466A8D07977120AD9044" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Energy Star Portfolio Manager</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Energy Star Portfolio Manager</term> means the tool developed and maintained by the Administrator to track and assess the relative energy performance of buildings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE6FA5C05F734FEF908E61E077ACABE7" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H58C6C15C45FA486A8F319A10E3C0BBC0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carbon dioxide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4585844FBAC4E858FB689F9486FB6CB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>methane;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20FF2A193FF44857B26C9D6574939DA0" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nitrous oxide;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00E43E305ED64DA09BEE590F6EE3AFEF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>perfluorocarbons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEE5CE5265FB45C4934055AD2CDC3F21" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sulfur hexafluoride;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5F9148B822F4FFF9D3E994DA1125FAA" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>nitrogen trifluoride;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0788ADF90594FF98FEB8ABB31860C2D" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>chlorofluorocarbons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2ABB62F207542728EE1A95E6F12694B" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other anthropogenically emitted gas or particulate that the Administrator determines, after notice and comment, to contribute to climate change.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H867512E27A344654B9E7B7FECBC61443" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas emissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>greenhouse gas emissions</term> means emissions of greenhouse gas, expressed in terms of metric tons of carbon dioxide equivalent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAC3C534AB104576BB4F5485C6B7BF26" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6248A3D81E86478DBE065717A0C060AF" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0E812BC2C9954278A98C4B6B99F276F3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BE65305ADCA4DD69607E38944880EB2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEFD7CEA8A794828A4EE24CBDDAEB6F8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each territory and possession of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4FE5E2DC0C74756B103349AF4620591" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the governing body of each federally recognized Indian Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community that is recognized as eligible for special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

