<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8AB1ED2B67D542D3BC2504C1D0E5ABF5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6565 IH: Kids in Classes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6565</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220202">February 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000020">Mr. Jacobs of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an alternative use of certain Federal education funds when in-person instruction is not available.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H46327A97D3DC47E18DDA5F8698E561D5" style="OLC"><section id="H8D9C754C36674039866996F9E2297A3F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Kids in Classes Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC122B468E37248AF8BCA477EA4554E13"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H22C425835FAE4D5EB3FE4FA216C0F163"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Research indicates that children living in the poorest 20 percent of neighborhoods in the United States will experience the most negative and long-lasting effects of school closures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6EDE798B5ED44D7BF606CFFE67F9B24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Researchers predict that 1 year of school closures will cost ninth graders in the poorest communities a 25-percent decrease in their post-educational earning potential, even if that year of closure is followed by 3 years of normal schooling. By contrast, the same researchers predict no substantial losses for students from the richest 20 percent of neighborhoods.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB762BC74F6734203A0A3DA26BA908819"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Long periods of school closures during the COVID–19 pandemic deprive low-income students and students of color the equalizing force of education. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C3D37D937349E99948DBE1DCDA3F86"><enum>(4)</enum><text>School closures will widen educational inequality and the learning gaps created by these closures will persist as students progress through high school, putting their future prospects at risk.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4D5816E69A240CBA95C991B9B366A55"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Data shows that closed classrooms were disproportionately composed of disadvantaged students, as well as students with low mathematics scores, students with limited English proficiency, or students who qualify for a free or reduced priced lunch.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DF3157C31D544829178E83815D0ADC2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>School shutdowns contribute to disproportionate learning loss for disadvantaged students, compounding existing gaps.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0A725B84900D4057997A4B283E48B1DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Use of title I funds if in-person instruction is not available</header><subsection id="H81AA7CBF551E46C39A9D8704FF2DB697"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title I funds To follow eligible children</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a State educational agency shall not receive grant funds provided under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>), unless the State has provided for the allocation of those funds directly to the parent or guardian of an eligible child for qualified educational expenses (including curriculum and curricular materials, books or instructional materials, technological educational materials, online educational materials, tutoring or educational classes outside the home, private school tuition, testing fees, diagnostic tools, and educational therapies for students with disabilities) for the purposes of ensuring that funding under such title follows eligible children.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F0A290B993A404E9A79DD882312DE81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible child</header><text>In this section the term <term>eligible child</term> means a child who attends a public elementary school or secondary school that—</text><paragraph id="H07559A7FA3604DD6A1F00EEFA501FC1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receives funds provided under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE45CF731BD8546FB9BD01CA226005B34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fails for more than 3 days during a school year, for reasons related to public health emergency or collective bargaining action, to make available in-person instruction for all students who wish to attend. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

