<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EEAA377CEDE46679A4907CD4F9B7D32" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7644 IH: Pride in Mental Health Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7644</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act to ensure protections for lesbian, gay, bisexual, and transgender youth and their families.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H15CBA40933BD49F29C7B0C9CDAA0C32C" style="OLC"><section id="HF71C2DAAC1F342F8B5A86A9C44C2279F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pride in Mental Health Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H03BA105DF6CF48C28351C8EBD06E1ECD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to CAPTA</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5101">42 U.S.C. 5101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBC578C71AE2B4DDF96C201A47F36F497"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 104 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5105">42 U.S.C. 5105</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H9DB233456D784B9281BC2B5C4EFE860A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="HE9244B929F054CABBBFE4288EDCBAF9A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="HD73C7B44B4B4442281C43D299DCAF53B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (N) and (O) as subparagraphs (O) and (P), respectively;</text></subclause><subclause id="H19D2F92531FC4ED3AF68A059E28E9C5F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (M) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDE1FFD7D27E24ACFADAFEBACF1234677" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H5D030715D3CC4F80AAE75A0CB567EA4A"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">child abuse and neglect issues facing lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth and families, including—</text><clause id="H2EC1F8CA57C94EB59F8BB6F23D6FF7DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing recommendations for improving the collection of data at the Federal, State, and local levels to better identify young people who may be at risk of, or experiencing, child abuse or neglect or adverse childhood experiences because of their sexual orientation, gender identity, or gender expression; and</text></clause><clause id="H115403881F81464C8B61656D36577C6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the effectiveness of mandated child abuse and neglect reporters specific to lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth and families and the extent to which implicit bias or lack of cultural competency affect such mandated reporters;</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="H97634820BCD64249821106E373F7E93E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in subparagraph (O), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subparagraph (O)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (P)</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD0EE436827F0421AB0AEE8AC92DB5080"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>in clause (ix) of subparagraph (P), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>(including sexual orientation, gender identity, and gender expression)</quote> after <quote>sex</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HEF3EE04093E745B0B105C8D660A0B2BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>paragraph (1)(O)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (1)(P)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H790C9883696A4635987842CB7A69B0A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by inserting <quote>or lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth</quote> after <quote>children with disabilities</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C4ACBD79A33492FBF25CBE0AA6AA60E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 105(a)(1)(E) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106">42 U.S.C. 5106(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>and lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth</quote> after <quote>children with disabilities</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF36D2D81224B4C88F667B914BF60B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 106(d)(1) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106a">42 U.S.C. 5106a(d)(1)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>, disaggregated by demographic characteristics such as age, sex (including sexual orientation, gender identity, and gender expression), race, family structure, household relationship, school enrollment and education attainment, disability, caregivers, labor force status, work status in previous year, and income in previous year</quote> before the period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58EDE9BA88D44C9EBB91A2C8F6E39CF0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 107 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5106c">42 U.S.C. 5106c</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H76BAA356B3064F19B8BA4A1ACED8FDBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="H6B0E43A55C8344AA9A258E37E24EA19C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (4) and (5), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="H0776B8A0EACB43F69316BD53A6F7FBD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D622F53721B45BEB5CB6398E5545914" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2677363B665B423EA60810E6D130AA27"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assessment and investigation of cases involving lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth who are suspected victims of child abuse or neglect;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C5B16008ED84442BDB26963A330FF06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(5), by striking <quote>paragraphs (1) through (3)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (1) through (4)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4874E7DCD9454AB8993A77081533AA54"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text><clause id="H36381C08758247688D1030D0D27F981E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (G) through (J) as subparagraphs (H) through (K), respectively; and</text></clause><clause id="H590B4E5DF04D436F849E915E4CA7CD4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (F) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0228A6F9BBB94F098BA5C4F647BF498D" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H4AD86A88EF7E4AC686D32649307DA7CB"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals experienced in working with lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth and families;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C12A0554C8F4C8CBFD02464B8C10EB6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 201(b)(1)(G) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5116">42 U.S.C. 5116(b)(1)(G)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>(including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth and families)</quote> before the semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H021B61EE683446BBAC96F19DE839874F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 202 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5116a">42 U.S.C. 5116a</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HABE7BF1E87F04DAEA92385106BA31CB6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H5B9BE899973D4A0A99EFEC60CF4B93B9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>and families with other vulnerable youth, including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></clause><clause id="H6641C54000BA41458B82F1FBEB31FBEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and public sector and private nonprofit sector service providers, and parents with disabilities</quote> and inserting <quote>public sector and private nonprofit sector service providers, parents with disabilities, and parents of other vulnerable youth, including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFEBC4476E7AD41908CECDE9597A1D097"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="H4E9CEA49FBD74023828BDA5272E827FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause><clause id="H64B57807A8E74896B7F2E63E94DCCE0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HA1E3CD87689B4807BF4E7A54D46FF343"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF33B04BF80F94D7D8D5D36A02A426982" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H5A3CD80E75EA46DFBADD1A05BCEA149A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will integrate its efforts with individuals and organizations experienced in working in partnership with families with vulnerable youth, including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth, and with the child abuse and neglect prevention activities of the State, and demonstrate a financial commitment to those activities.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB06AA89F7BB14198A74CA024E8DE4336"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 206(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5116f">42 U.S.C. 5116f(4)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>and parents with disabilities</quote> and inserting <quote>parents with disabilities, and families with other vulnerable youth, including lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2D4744CF57C84F2B9506619898BE7045"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants for mental health services for LGBTQ+ youth</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part B of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-31">42 U.S.C. 290bb–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF47219ED00C94B3A823578156FBF868F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HBF0D30403EB747D8959D9697E6067736"><enum>520N.</enum><header>Grants for mental health services for LGBTQ+ youth</header><subsection id="HC5D49D4E57954FE28B11A5CB07A58673"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible entities to assess and improve lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth mental health and substance abuse outcomes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DE69A6A018E42CD9FE20C03C1CB8870"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use funds received through such grant—</text><paragraph id="HEB8DA59B020549E6A369B73A668C4BDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide mental and behavioral health resources for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth, including trauma-informed care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD96242671EA845C687C88A2795D21B3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide cultural competency training for caregivers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H846CDB8D880C4766B12C793EE121986F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and disseminate mental and behavioral health best practices and toolkits for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth, and their families and caregivers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4351960D5B774151B0BB0CD5378C2964"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop and disseminate evidence-based practices to be added to the Evidence-Based Practices Resource Center of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B9384ECBB8E44A6AA2162C8CF0BC0D5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to collect data with respect to the mental and behavioral health of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73F62F4B64FE44E8B1E1A4B767229C4D"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to issue school bullying prevention guidelines with respect to lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1499C418F0B14301A3FD15061848593D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide for the integration within school systems of mental and behavioral health services for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90DF1645D69145F791B407E350AEDE32"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to establish and implement mental and behavioral patient navigator programs for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth, and their families; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D75B6B025814EC58BBD62D937748F22"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to create and disseminate family acceptance and support models for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth, and their families and caregivers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H780E8EA08E244158B5D5A891AB75C57E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="HA2928EA30EC24B0D89D3DC6B9FB78A98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity selected to receive a grant under this section shall agree, as a condition on receiving the grant that such funds shall not be used—</text><subparagraph id="H1A9F3946463F48FE95751B307717AEF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to provide conversion therapy to any individual;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38EBDD9D1CF84955A15C32AF67D0B561"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to advertise for the provision of conversion therapy and claim in such advertising—</text><clause id="HB47BD6BF397941FBBFC255F87C09D4AE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to change another individual's sexual orientation or gender identity; </text></clause><clause id="H70D6F7469C6B48109FA7DCBD18F5BED6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender; or</text></clause><clause id="H2253BCA3FF2241EF94D7EF138181A93A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that such efforts are harmless or without risk to individuals receiving such therapy;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DFEADB6396F4AECADEDFC72586037E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to knowingly assist or facilitate the provision of conversion therapy to an individual if such person receives compensation from any source in connection with providing conversion therapy; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5332D033C1AF4310A23B1767A225642C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to promote or direct an individual to conversion therapy resources or providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD8691141B8C448790443AFB77618756"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conversion therapy defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>conversion therapy</quote>—</text><subparagraph id="H980E53A06F0F48229733F92C790754B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any practice or treatment by any person that seeks to change another individual's sexual orientation or gender identity, including efforts to change behaviors or gender expressions, or to eliminate or reduce sexual or romantic attractions or feelings toward individuals of the same gender, if such person—</text><clause id="H65AC2F405264411990882D6E573A04C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>receives monetary compensation in exchange for such practice or treatment; or</text></clause><clause id="H225B2DA642F441E7AC8AA9083037F3DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>instead of, or in addition to, receiving monetary compensation in exchange for such practice or treatment directly, receives monetary compensation in exchange for a product or service that is integral to the provision of such practice or treatment by such person, unless such product or service is protected by the First Amendment to the Constitution; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9594AF262B514D879BCAB891A6D0A84B"><enum>(B)</enum><text><editorial></editorial>does not include any practice or treatment, which does not seek to change sexual orientation or gender identity, that—</text><clause id="H199A111FE9A74B30BA5A9497B7A3C2FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides assistance to an individual undergoing a gender transition; or</text></clause><clause id="HB48D9F452D9A4BC999FD78D7AC57F17C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides acceptance, support, and understanding of a client or facilitation of a client's coping, social support, and identity exploration and development, including sexual orientation-neutral interventions to prevent or address unlawful conduct or unsafe sexual practices.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47DE1FAE0D8F40EABED22FE92DBF35E9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of reports</header><paragraph id="H746F7A5884594F8D9F76A169496DEC6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall review, and update as necessary, the reports and publications listed on the internet website of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Administration as of the date of the enactment of this section that are focused on lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08DAA41C0D11480E8590649FBFD8835F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In reviewing reports and publications under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prioritize updating older reports and commissioning new reports that fill information gaps with respect to the mental and behavioral health of lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAA2F4E703D6426F8566F06632B673ED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and conduct a Federal survey measuring serious psychological distress, mental illness, mental health, and mental health care among lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth. In developing such survey, the Secretary may consider integrating such survey as an enhanced feature of the National Survey on Drug Use and Health. </text></subsection><subsection id="H3974FF9251FD4A55BFEC0208C9A59306"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H3A0EC339CEF846F39451743A386D32A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Mental Health and the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families, commence a report on mental health, mental health care, and cultural competency in mental health care for lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, and Two Spirit youth in foster care and who are beneficiaries of other social services programs subject to Federal oversight.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA37D5648A8F442E968833C95ABFC3B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall submit the report required under paragraph (1) to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

