<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H642169A97FB9419EB983602C1E2AE560" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3952 RH: NOAA Chief Scientist Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code>
<calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 284</calendar>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3952</legis-num>
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–373, Part I]</associated-doc>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20210616">June 16, 2021</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 16, 2021</action-instruction>
</action>
<action>
<action-desc><pagebreak/></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To strengthen the role of the Chief Scientist of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration in order to promote scientific integrity and advance the Administration’s world-class research and development portfolio.<pagebreak/></official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSY00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H1D7D2525AA874614825D68C4856A73B5">
<section id="HC67728576FAC4EB595D95868AD80BC36" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NOAA Chief Scientist Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE5C86017A5784D1291F8F7CC1B404618"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendment to Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1970 relating to Chief Scientist of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration</header> <subsection id="HAF4C6768BF0E420CBAADFDD7E7ED9616"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 2 of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1970 (5 U.S.C. App) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="HA1D34BDD02184BF6AAAF49E88D7C7C40" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00">
<subsection id="HFF300CB7AD214F8F9A6E198E9AF52EDF"><enum>(d)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H45C325B48BC6462CAABDEDE18C0AE3C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>There is in the Administration a Chief Scientist of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Chief Scientist</quote>), who shall be selected by the Administrator and compensated at the rate now or hereafter provided for Level V of the Executive Schedule pursuant to section 5316 of title 5, United States Code. In selecting a Chief Scientist, the Administrator shall give due consideration to any recommendations for candidates which may be submitted by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Science Advisory Board, and other widely recognized, reputable, and diverse United States scientific or academic bodies, including minority serving institutions or other such bodies representing underrepresented populations. The Chief Scientist shall be the principal scientific adviser to the Administrator on science and technology policy and strategy, as well as scientific integrity, and shall perform such other duties as the Administrator may direct. The Chief Scientist shall be an individual who is, by reason of scientific education and experience, knowledgeable in the principles of scientific disciplines associated with the work of the Administration, and who has produced work of scientific merit through an established record of distinguished service and achievement.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC8066001CC94B56BDDDF14D9BCDAA81" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Chief Scientist shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H85884599D8694AF086CD657997C7CFA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>adhere to any agency or department scientific integrity policy and—</text> <clause id="HC27F0F71BE9E4B489100E2F33289A1B8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide written consent to all applicable scientific integrity and other relevant science and technology policies of the Administration prior to serving in such position, with such written consent to be made available on a publicly accessible website of the Administration;</text></clause>
<clause id="H915B7F2EF0754ABDA2D742DD364B1B6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in conjunction with the Administrator and other members of Administration leadership, undergo all applicable training programs of the Administration which inform employees of their rights and responsibilities regarding the conduct of scientific research and communication with the media and the public regarding scientific research; and</text></clause> <clause id="H548EB760F3244A4999A72C02BA3B56E7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in coordination with the Administrator and other members of Administration leadership, make all practicable efforts to ensure Administration employees and contractors who are engaged in, supervise, or manage scientific activities, analyze or communicate information resulting from scientific activities, or use scientific information in policy, management, or regulatory decisions, adhere to established scientific integrity policies of the Administration;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF2B9AC99450442038115C9354D08423F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide policy and program direction for science and technology priorities of the Administration and facilitate integration and coordination of research efforts across line offices of the Administration, with other Federal agencies, and with the external scientific community, including through—</text> <clause id="HA0064E583881465A9B08944D2BEF56A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>leading the development of a science and technology strategy of the Administration and issuing policy guidance to ensure that overarching Administration policy is aligned with science and technology goals and objectives;</text></clause>
<clause id="H02CEF65E8A854543A68A1C5F65844913"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>chairing the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Science Council and serving as a liaison to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Science Advisory Board;</text></clause> <clause id="HFA90871F7E824E9DBA7DF3D0067299BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>providing oversight to ensure—</text>
<subclause id="H334DAA9410414A76B7F4D0ED2D3A711C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Administration funds high priority and mission-aligned science and technology development, including through partnerships with the private sector, Cooperative Institutes, academia, nongovernmental organizations, and other Federal and non-Federal institutions; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H49B951D3B56F4020AD36F2686D53847A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>there is no unnecessary duplication of such science and technology development;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HB8318F4DE6F943A092BF9265349E9785"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring the Administration attracts, retains, and promotes world class scientists and researchers from diverse backgrounds, experiences, and expertise;</text></clause> <clause id="HA50DAE858B7E45DEB2147524415DA151"><enum>(v)</enum><text>promoting the health and professional development of the Administration’s scientific workforce, including by promoting efforts to reduce assault, harassment, and discrimination that could hamper such health and development; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HBF73091E8816449F925EBD16C22F22F1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>ensuring coordination across the scientific workforce and its conduct and application of science and technology with the Administration’s most recent Diversity and Inclusion Strategic Plan;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC0F5D61446B45C9A35B8E915C89592B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the direction of the Administrator, promote, communicate, and advocate for the Administration’s science and technology portfolio and strategy to the broad domestic, Tribal, and international communities and Congress, represent the Administration in promoting and maintaining good public and community relations, and provide the widest practical and appropriate dissemination of science and technology information concerning the full range of the Administration’s earth system authorities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7C2DE8743F6349C6BBCE9795B2FDD666"><enum>(D)</enum><text>manage an Office of the Chief Scientist—</text> <clause id="H1D0C15F1BA6140B29AD5AAFA233F1A5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which shall be staffed by Federal employees of the Administration detailed to the office on a rotating basis, in a manner that promotes diversity of expertise, background, and to the extent practicable, ensures that each line office of the Administration is represented in the Office over time;</text></clause>
<clause id="HEEB730970775482784BD21A6EC8992B6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which there shall be a Deputy Chief Scientist, to be designated by the Administrator or Acting Administrator from among the Assistant Administrators on a rotational basis, as appropriate to their backgrounds or expertise, who shall advise and support the Chief Scientist and perform the functions and duties of the Chief Scientist for not more than one year in the event the Chief Scientist is unable to carry out the duties of the Office, or in the event of a vacancy in such position; and</text></clause> <clause id="H4FEC5A418AB34B6EAE28256AFB22CAF0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which may utilize contractors pursuant to applicable laws and regulations, and offer opportunities to fellows under existing programs; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCC3B9A84B9A342009920589A10B5AFBC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not less frequently than once each year, in coordination with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Science Council, produce and make publicly available a report that—</text> <clause id="H5E371289AAD243DAAF5944335469E104"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describes the Administration’s implementation of the science and technology strategy and scientific accomplishments from the past year;</text></clause>
<clause id="H79DC66912EF8421D8853006219C5B91D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details progress toward goals and challenges faced by the Administration’s science and technology portfolio and scientific workforce;</text></clause> <clause id="H85C50C4E3CC2411AAC365AB44F963AC3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides a summary of Administration-funded research, including—</text>
<subclause id="H1B0D524162484B44BC8E1BFDE09639BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the percentage of Administration-funded research that is funded intramurally;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7E0C922ABF6C496982E9C38546C540F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of Administration-funded research that is funded extramurally, including the relative proportion of extramural research that is carried out by—</text>
<item id="HA9764DD14552448DBD9CA353A09A6ECD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the private sector;</text></item> <item id="HBD10E64E679442448FBB7D169BBB080E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Cooperative Institutes;</text></item>
<item id="H88E06C5C214743CA93675768ADE95B3E"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>academia;</text></item> <item id="H93DB1ACE4A3042F4A22ED28E1F322660"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; and</text></item>
<item id="HD714FC5440A840B6B38A5FBDD0838DFE"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>other categories as necessary; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HEB8EF0F1954A447FB3815C65B7A30949"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a summary of Administration-funded research that is transitioned to operations, applications, commercialization, and utilization; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HB3EA4AEAC6F548E5AB9446AE0B14F1A4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides reporting on scientific integrity actions, including by specifying the aggregate number of scientific and research misconduct cases, the number of consultations conducted, the number of allegations investigated, the number of findings of misconduct, and a summary of actions in response to such findings.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E6AD042E135455EB488FBBB027AA246" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed as impeding the ability of the Administrator to select any person for the position of Chief Scientist the Administrator determines is qualified to serve in such position.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HAAF40946E89B4F9E8050895B30BABF5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Saving clause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individual serving as Chief Scientist of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act may continue to so serve until such time as the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration selects such a Chief Scientist in accordance with subsection (d) of section 2 of Reorganization Plan No. 4 of 1970 (5 U.S.C. App), as amended by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <endorsement display="yes"> <action-date>June 16, 2022</action-date> <action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HSY00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc> <action-date>June 16, 2022</action-date> <action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> </bill> 

