<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6C5A755BB0654A1BB354CD1C34D0D021" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8825 IH: Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8825</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220914">September 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide authority for small cultivators of marijuana and small manufacturers of marijuana products to ship marijuana and marijuana products using the mail, and for other purpose.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8595AE929AEB433A8271DA152E5F73F1" style="OLC"><section id="HFDB1DDE91F20413AABE6A4794D6D64C0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small and Homestead Independent Producers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2D98AE8B56174FA5B21C0D8020ED78DB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority for small cultivators and manufacturers of marijuana to ship marijuana in the mail</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A small cultivator of marijuana and a small manufacturer of a marijuana product may ship and sell marijuana or a marijuana product to an individual located in that State or another State in which possession of marijuana or the marijuana product is lawful by that individual, using the Postal Service or any private or commercial interstate carrier.</text></section><section id="H1947E18659734B32B2BE010B4D0FE0BD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preemption</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act preempts the laws of any State to the extent that such laws are inconsistent with this Act.</text></section><section id="H58D12EFF0E8744638141099C6DAB9753"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA2A1E2D40FA44CB1A185C1169F8A07F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small cultivator of marijuana</term> means a person who cultivates one acre or less of mature flowering marijuana plant canopy using outdoor cultivation, 22,000 square feet or less of marijuana plant canopy using greenhouse cultivation, or 5,000 square feet or fewer of mature flowering marijuana plant canopy using indoor cultivation, inclusive of all marijuana cultivated by that person. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F5334080F2C4E58804F380FD6753FD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small manufacturer of a marijuana product</term> means a person who produces a manufactured marijuana product, including a salve, tincture, edible, or concentrate, with a gross annual revenue of less than $5,000,000, inclusive of all marijuana product manufactured by that person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFEF092E1AEB412EA6527059F37491BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>person</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1 of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A79270F7ADF41EFA52F1C2167D4003C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>outdoor cultivation</term> means the cultivation of mature cannabis without the use of artificial lighting or heating in the canopy area at any point in time, and may include the use of light deprivation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A667C813B0543D0964D7CDED1FCA71D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>light deprivation</term> means the use of any technique to eliminate natural light in order to induce flowering.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC1E5FDE76C741A296AB349C91E2844A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>greenhouse cultivation</term> means the cultivation of mature cannabis in a structure utilizing artificial light at a rate above zero watts per square foot, but no more than six watts per square foot.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42E3E0E5F25C4DC797D65E354E3F5A82"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The term <term>indoor cultivation</term> means the cultivation of mature cannabis in a structure with the use of artificial light at a rate above six watts per square foot in the canopy area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F52BE8F148148728CB012E6EF3299BD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The term <term>canopy</term> means the area that contains mature cannabis plants at any point in time.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H146A12B9E5F44B71BDE2B24EE3F6ABBF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The term <term>mature</term> means, with respect to a cannabis plant, a cannabis plant that is flowering.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H89B0A8E3CD2341149969EE2E9459C59A"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date on which marijuana is removed from the list of scheduled substances under the Controlled Substances Act and Federal criminal penalties for an individual who manufactures, distributes, or possesses marijuana, are eliminated. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

