<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F3BAD05FD2B435E87BAFC042B9BAA1F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8674 IH: Renewable Energy Jobs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8674</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Labor to carry out a pilot program to award competitive grants to eligible entities to train individuals for careers in the renewable energy and energy efficiency industries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF089128A4C19429C8B6435CA5FAF9956" style="OLC"><section id="H37E7D90DACD7444C8124D5A2ABFBCF23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Renewable Energy Jobs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H57A3BE65EEFC47B5B25F30ED07A31C10"><enum>2.</enum><header>Alternative Energy Training and Employment Pilot Program</header><subsection id="HA2694C688875413E9D88D9622FBE467E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall carry out a pilot program (in this section referred to as the <quote>pilot program</quote>) to award competitive grants to eligible entities to train individuals for careers in the renewable energy and energy efficiency industries.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC98517BC83A84460B298C22144E636FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="H49F3520CF8AA408E9EFED88A003BC647"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To apply for a grant under the pilot program, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE268116E58E5497D955E3127B727DE00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant application under this section shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7B21C6A0E8354788A077FBC6CF712796"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposal for a program to train individuals for careers in the renewable energy and energy efficiency industries. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78DA830DCFDE4C538624E18432B2ADB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the presence of such industries, and the availability of jobs in such industries, in the State in which the eligible entity will carry out the program. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F2A5E8818F841F89476A2FD2BA9A0A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the sustainability of long-term careers in such industries in such State, including a description of the growth of such industries over the 10-year period preceding the date of the application and the production output of such industries as of the date of such application.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BC323B7B06C465AA85F1E2625CDBB71"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to coordinate the efforts of the eligible entity under the program with relevant efforts of workforce development boards. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8469DF6536D74B368BDC61351629ADA8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the program aligns with the workforce plan of such State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FB10B9BBDB74475913138223551A4BA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the program will aid participants to attain recognized postsecondary credentials. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC10205C701A342FEA6AD72FB237E0BCC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration of grant</header><text>Each grant under this section shall be for a period of 3 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H04DB2EA946C84BCDAE274C52A2E0261E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may use the grant funds—</text><paragraph id="HDA50D292853546B0B779852B6380D00A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out the proposal submitted by the recipient under subsection (b)(2)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04A9F88DB87F46229BADFB63DE8AEDD3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to reimburse a primary entity for the cost of providing on-the-job training;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19E0A6EDC40541429D7B73556630E358"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reimburse a secondary entity for the cost of providing skills training (or on-the-job training if in partnership with an energy efficient employer);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H245353E728B5445AB4787269DFB74766"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to reimburse an employer for wages associated with registered apprenticeship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF802E58148BB414F9844687E59797415"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to conduct outreach to inform primary entities, secondary entities, and the public, including individuals in rural areas and Indian tribes, of eligibility or potential eligibility for participation in the program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7298F6E76DE4CFA9E6F8BD91CF84E3E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to conduct any other activities that the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H898ED2042483416ABE779F497186734D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under subsection (a), the Secretary shall prioritize grants to eligible entities that submit a proposal to carry out a program in a State that is among the 5 States with the highest installed alternative energy power capacity.</text></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7BF9F5B15C74AA39F0F89034C5060D1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of receipt of funds under this section, the Secretary shall require an eligible entity to agree—</text><paragraph id="H300EE726EA3C4CB089B4D77B7C9CED25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to repay to the Secretary any amount received under the pilot program that is not used for the purposes described in subsection (d) by the date that is 3 years after the date on which the recipient received such funds; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85E94B795B2F490FB8D5967800AF78F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to submit to the Secretary, at such times and containing such information as the Secretary shall require, reports on the use of grant funds; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6795D0399F094C03B93ECAEBD6CF6FFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure that any employer or other entity receiving funds through a program under this section pays each individual receiving on-the-job training provided by such employer or entity not less than the applicable minimum wage for the State or locality in which such training is provided.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B55724FF18E43E180E3AFB2AD722B21"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative costs</header><paragraph id="H6DA7E076AB134AC699CA50CBB0326A9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal administration</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (i), 2 percent shall be made available to the Secretary for administrative costs associated with implementing and evaluating the pilot program under this section and for preparing and submitting the report required under subsection (h).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EFB3ACFBEF24A46816D30F630EE28F7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program administration</header><text>The Secretary shall determine the appropriate maximum amount of each grant awarded under this section that may be used by the recipient for administrative and reporting costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29A47D3CE3CC45599A72EE84774D5BC7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit to Congress an annual report on the pilot program for each year of the grant period containing—</text><paragraph id="HF75F1EA4D43242B98BC01D8EF5677B69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of activities carried out under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB43EE7E30EFF41688AD6A0807C195B6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an evaluation of the pilot program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92A104FEF51E4285B37F49F245A62CDB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how many participants were employed by renewable energy and energy efficiency employers within 6 months of completing the training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85B3B0CE0A4A41E2A5A0CC72182104DF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026, for the purpose of carrying out the pilot program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD688A8AC83CE4FE686825F300AF60256"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="HCAE406887973457487E1F486DFEACDE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1BD36CDA698D4976922425D7BD06F34A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a primary entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28D9A72E64E146D3B1C7F89C950ED472"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a consortium of entities that—</text><clause id="HDD4713ED10C942C08FE85BE7F74910B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consists of one or more primary entities; and</text></clause><clause id="H003B95C9CAEE41169E3F24431E4CF229"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include one or more secondary entities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10A4FF5AF2174F64A2500605DD6ED0AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given that term in section 102 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/479a">25 U.S.C. 479a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC01A0986669D4F818C61E0B8B2EBB873"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>installed alternative energy power capacity</term> means the amount of wind, solar, and geothermal power generation, expressed in megawatts, installed in a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D320271A0AB44AF839552B163F100D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CA37E6338DE407F8CE90AA9AA3E64C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6FD2FB91E7134458A677B6E901BA038B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>on-the-job training</term> means training by renewable energy and energy efficiency employers, a labor organization, an institution of higher education, or a nonprofit organization that is provided to a paid participant while engaged in productive work that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1E3A8EE515C84AD09B3E6045FAC602B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides knowledge or skills essential to the full and adequate performance of the job;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA239F43BAA2C4E2684107497C9C4724A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides reimbursement to the employer for the costs of providing the training and additional supervision related to the training; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE9EF179678D4483C972C25E87C8939D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is limited in duration as appropriate to the occupation for which the participant is being trained, taking into account the content of the training, the prior work experience of the participant, and the service strategy of the participant, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94111BC965B7403CB4E8167816E4C27D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>primary entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H882E2BB7B0C94895889AAC33F8EF3C76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a renewable energy and energy efficiency employer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56ED36E3DC04419194FE1782DE3B505D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a workforce development board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4E16333ED7B439BA6C945A35B8FE0DE"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2EAA7B086241495B9497E3D7191CDC18"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>renewable energy and energy efficiency employer</term> means an employer that employs individuals in a trade or business in the renewable energy and energy efficiency industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFAB7CF6B1EA445D88E1128C739F9FDB"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The term <term>renewable energy and energy efficiency industries</term> means any of the following industries:</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H25962DD8A5A14DE3955C05FBA031BA12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The energy-efficient building, construction, or retrofits industry.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F5A055200364F3BBE0831F8EB831DDA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The renewable electric power industry, including the wind, solar, and geothermal energy industries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2759B84A6966499EA14D9245A1810B91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The energy efficiency assessment industry that serves the residential, commercial, or industrial sectors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDBC17F409BA42D0835DC5345DB21735"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The industries that manufacture solar panels, wind turbines, geothermal generators, and similar products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H466985F26680425CAF0A50A4F69C744B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The term <term>secondary entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H74D1BC0DDDA248139EF3D6672F146979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA32DC09D3A704B7B912E9461D7D630A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E9E64621A154EABB93C0CEB7E537678"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a labor organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H837EBDD105224FF3BAA202CDDEC4D227"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>skills training</term> means training by secondary entity that provides the knowledge and skills essential to specific jobs in the renewable energy and energy efficiency industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6C98A643604CC3A09B5F85D7D554B6"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> includes each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, the Republic of Palau, and the territories and possessions of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE6542DDC7A24D3E9B761DF68F5CC5FF"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The term <term>workforce development board</term> means a State or local workforce development board established under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3111">29 U.S.C. 3111 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

