<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5773A3253B484A77A3E560FDD1FE654F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8178 IH: Generating Resilient and Energy Efficient Network Communications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8178</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information to carry out a grant and revolving loan program to provide funding for projects to increase the resiliency and energy efficiency of communications networks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDDDB8AD562B54910A87406F8AC088401" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB6E97A3AC82444D293BDFA318DEB5DA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Generating Resilient and Energy Efficient Network Communications Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GREEN Communications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDF6FE009DA2E40BE95CDC0E0EDAAEC3B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H7AF45B01CF6343D6ABD202CAF9BA2872"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Assistant Secretary</term> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC8BF6A7A3B9646DF918B6EDEB988FE33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBC56545E1D74A539519186A90309BEF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>communications infrastructure</term> means any equipment, tower, support structure, facility, product, or technology that is essential to the operation of a communications network.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29ABC1B8A14948C08889F93DDA498D57"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Communications network</header><text>The term <term>communications network</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3286AE42E56141D1A0EEC54D3E12282B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a broadband network;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBDC915C8CBBA4F86A539F4DB1128F84A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a cellular network;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H65E5FB877B07411581FD2378ECA9DA7D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a telephone network; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DB7589E077548C987FC55099F9002FE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a cable system; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H59C807E1513646F1900C225695230C1B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a network that is primarily used for public safety or first responder communications; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9AA9938FD343448B85B1774077C03F23"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a network that provides any other communications or telecommunications service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA893B658E8194395AA817F3D9463D072"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Communications network outage</header><text>The term <term>communications network outage</term> means an outage with respect to a communications network that results in the disruption of services provided by the communications network.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25D14FCF31D94ECD9B01BB8E3A395EDD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Covered efficiency project</header><text>The term <term>covered efficiency project</term> means, with respect to action taken by an eligible entity—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCE29DA25FE2649119299E775A228C614"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purchase or upgrading of equipment or technology, including an electrical or thermal monitoring system, that is demonstrated to increase the energy efficiency of communications infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0399D081C3DF41C88F316CB72FAA8865"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the installation or upgrading of permanent solar panels, wind turbines, combined heat and power technology, or other renewable energy generators that are used in communications infrastructure, or at a data center, provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE5563B885AB458BB344721C5F163283"><enum>(C)</enum><text>entering into a partnership with an energy utility company to purchase land for renewable energy infrastructure, or to construct renewable energy infrastructure, that will be used to power a data center, an internet exchange point, or communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H866F3515514A4ABA8F350222F5438685"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the reduction of water consumption for cooling a data center, or operating other communications infrastructure, provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity, in an area that is likely to experience drought;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA8FDE176468E41FE9A8D73184C1C41FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the study of ways to make a communications network provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity, or communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity, more energy and resource efficient; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B8F6BB5A5244A45B1D6E6870AD1C3BB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the study, including through pilot projects, of green technologies to make a communications network provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity more energy and resource efficient; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF325C2CC670F4E249282CF7199499481"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other type of project carried out by the eligible entity that the Assistant Secretary determines will promote the adoption of energy efficient, renewable energy, and carbon-neutral technologies and practices with respect to communications networks, or communications infrastructure, provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H129588D94EAC4816890974CF16DF42BC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Covered resiliency project</header><text>The term <term>covered resiliency project</term> means, with respect to action taken by an eligible entity— </text>
<subparagraph id="H45670454D97648F88B7E84510413010F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the construction of communications infrastructure to be provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity in a location that is not vulnerable to projected severe effects with respect to extreme weather, natural disasters, or climate change-related events, including sea-level rise, flooding, and increased risk of wildfire;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6DF1CEC9707643328F48C4B25236F8C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the relocation of communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity to a location that is less vulnerable to projected severe effects with respect to extreme weather, natural disasters, or climate change-related events, including sea-level rise, flooding, and increased risk of wildfire;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF4923BF309E749E197A22ACB2EEF4201"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the reinforcement, hardening, or replacement of communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity in a location that is increasingly vulnerable to projected severe effects with respect to extreme weather, natural disasters, or climate change-related events, including sea-level rise, flooding, and increased risk of wildfire;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF240EECA24E0479CB6725B56B88734A3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the construction of a fortification, such as a sea wall or embankment, or the development of green infrastructure solutions, such as wetlands or drainage ponds, to protect communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity from projected severe effects with respect to extreme weather, natural disasters, or climate change-related events, including sea-level rise, flooding, and increased risk of wildfire;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H78CAAB3A7F8043E5B7784C38EECB5311"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the undertaking of research with respect to communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity to identify vulnerabilities of that infrastructure to climate change based on the best available data, analysis, and projections regarding that change, including sea-level rise projections, 100-year floodplain maps, and heat and temperature projections;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6EFFCB06A09543689D634605E86793FF"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the undertaking of research (using the best available data, analysis and projections regarding tectonic science and structural engineering) with respect to communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity to identify vulnerabilities, or the susceptibility, of that communications infrastructure to damage caused by natural disasters;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H493C067B6B9E404FBB6B5E68A90EDCB4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the purchase of renewable energy or low-emission backup generators, fuel cells, or batteries to maximize the likelihood that communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity can continue operating in the event of an electrical system outage, without regard to whether the eligible entity is required to provide such backup power with respect to that communications infrastructure;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA277E40896AB4DFEBD74D4B0C5C5F555"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the purchase of cooling equipment or insulation, or the development of green infrastructure, to protect communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity from extreme heat events;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H322A3555D6E04CD1A4202658F2734BAC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the piloting of technologies to make a communications network provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity more resilient through energy efficient and low carbon emission measures;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF0EAB61AABB4B5A862990743760C289"><enum>(J)</enum><text>in order to facilitate faster detection of, or response to, a communications network outage with respect to a communications network provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity—</text>
<clause id="H426F682A3F614C509B08183C05F2B084"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the training of employees of the eligible entity relating to such a detection or response; </text></clause> <clause id="HE47DF9E9387B40CCB5303341A473BF06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the conducting of communications network outage tests or simulations; </text></clause>
<clause id="HFFF2D10EE3AB4146A5ABF32B7D735340"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the participation in communications network outage tests or simulations, including those administered by local, State, or Federal governmental entities; or</text></clause> <clause id="HEFD8221E1283401781052B4B354EF008"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the purchase of equipment or technology relating to such a detection or response, including communications infrastructure (including deployable communications infrastructure) that can expedite the restoration of communications or telecommunications services after such a communications network outage; </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H796371E4ACAB4984824270BD88B8249A"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the undertaking of research to develop technologies that can expedite the restoration of communications or telecommunications services after an outage with respect to communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAE7D9BCBDC6C4DBB9D2E5C731928D9D8"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the construction, purchase, relocation, reinforcement, or replacement of communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity in order to minimize the risk of a communications network outage caused by an affirmative power shut-off by a utility; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H55F8F52597AC4BED8CA823FEB1BC825C"><enum>(M)</enum><text>any other type of project carried out by the eligible entity that the Assistant Secretary determines will increase the resiliency of a communications network or communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity with respect to— </text> <clause id="H7D7B1432F3C242F7A05155D95B544285"><enum>(i)</enum><text>severe weather; </text></clause>
<clause id="H5EF56D5FC51D43C69CD975C7933E61EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>natural disasters; and </text></clause> <clause id="H649FC34C253B4BE58E788AD9E35D9D78"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>climate change-related events, including extreme weather events, droughts, coastal and inland flooding, sea level rise, increased storm surge, wildfires, mudslides, and extreme temperatures.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF4E738E2853C488089E8F29C63F05641"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Data center</header><text>The term <term>data center</term> means a centralized location at which computing and networking equipment is concentrated for the purpose of collecting, storing, processing, distributing, or allowing access to large amounts of electronic data.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BBFAD64527D43608D7625D2E488A667"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any private or public entity, including a State, local, or Tribal government, that provides, operates, or owns a communications network or communications infrastructure.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD33AEE5A79244FBBA77B3D8294CAC96"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Natural disaster</header><text>The term <term>natural disaster</term> includes a natural event that is not related to climate change, including an earthquake, a tornado, a hurricane, a volcanic eruption, a solar flare, a geomagnetic disturbance, and an electromagnetic pulse.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8D0E92C659A423AADFBDB792EEB1EA9"><enum>(11)</enum><header>NTIA</header><text>The term <term>NTIA</term> means the National Telecommunications and Information Administration.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H37D64A2526AE42498DC58A6ABA7E6EC9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Financial assistance for communications network resiliency and energy efficiency</header>
<subsection id="HCF1DBC5EB8CC4EA09F8652982CCE78E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
<paragraph id="HB7B0B0B3F3FB4D2CA7F65646875A22CC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Assistant Secretary shall establish a program in the NTIA (referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>) through which the Assistant Secretary, subject to the other provisions of this section, shall competitively award grants and revolving loans to eligible entities to carry out covered efficiency projects and covered resiliency projects.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA49FD8B880DC4DB287DDAFCE79505247"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preliminary rulemaking</header><text>Before accepting applications for a grant or a revolving loan under the Program, the Assistant Secretary shall, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, and after consultation with eligible entities and the Secretary of Homeland Security, conduct a rulemaking to develop a process for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1768997F8F284FAE9871EDDB03CCCE3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying proprietary and confidential information contained in such an application; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE259FE81B5E4572AC1A036580ECB826"><enum>(B)</enum><text>handling and protecting information described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE010FA783DFF4ACA80B4775928F1D914"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application process</header>
<paragraph id="H454FCF28890744B0AF878A3E68BDBDA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), an eligible entity seeking a grant or a revolving loan under the Program shall submit to the Assistant Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Assistant Secretary may require.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB11D3896A3464C49A8F34541DE04CD94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum requirements</header><text>An application submitted by an eligible entity under paragraph (1) shall contain, at a minimum, and to the extent applicable—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8426113476AE4E1896EC625685D4B9E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a covered efficiency project—</text> <clause id="H3E1636B936FC4258BD9AD0C8B2DC0D18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an overview of the energy sourcing of the communications infrastructure or other equipment that is the subject of the project; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H5E955CDE836E4FC68410F4D9FEDB8A7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of how the grant or revolving loan sought by the eligible entity will improve the energy or resource efficiency of the communications infrastructure or other equipment that is the subject of the project; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7BCE9006244448A818666E72BFADC3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a covered resiliency project—</text>
<clause id="H0875ED917F0546BAA6C3A642B961B5D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the current, as of the date on which the application is submitted, resiliency efforts of the eligible entity with respect to the communications infrastructure or communications network that is the subject of the project; </text></clause> <clause id="H3A107380AEDB4CEBBCEC6122E067EAA1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of the specific vulnerability of, or threat of disruption to, the communications infrastructure or communications network that is the subject of the project; </text></clause>
<clause id="HE0BD7737E1E348A39DBD20E4AA0013FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of how the grant or revolving loan sought by the eligible entity will improve the resiliency of the communications infrastructure or communications network that is the subject of the project;</text></clause> <clause id="H0C228C460481440B8ABD73C1718D569A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a statement that the project meets all applicable local, State, Tribal, and Federal zoning and environmental requirements; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3271CA6F801140AAA5B2230A08C030E6"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of how the project will integrate with local or regional strategic planning efforts, if applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7842A671B37F4215A7C3000044E81720"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding prioritization</header><text>In selecting projects for which funding will be provided under the Program, the Assistant Secretary shall give priority to—</text>
<paragraph id="H8D20F5A4BA0D46C7B1E9396DD6D12AA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>covered efficiency projects that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA45B9FEE1CB245EA8EA5C5B9DAE0BA54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will be carried out in, or primarily benefit, areas in which—</text>
<clause id="H45E524F14CF6495CB6C74B3AE8945FA3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the median household income is below 150 percent of the Federal poverty level; or </text></clause> <clause id="H4A10712F3C014B878542DBF17A1C38AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a majority of the residents are members of a racial or ethnic minority group; </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0B87BB80C4A840A8B9DA2C7D3334B89D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have the greatest demonstrated impact on energy efficiency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01DAD9F2E09F47968626FB7BCCC40C63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>demonstrate the greatest overall projected reductions in greenhouse gas emissions; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H59A4D756E03C4AC2B1F62D0B54B7DE1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>covered resiliency projects that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB3E2DA2FFE354CD7B1FF86A6AC35B7DB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will be carried out in, or primarily benefit, areas— </text>
<clause id="H0CD844B476D44726BEE1942D823765A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which the median household income is below 150 percent of the Federal poverty level;</text></clause> <clause id="H67F57C71FE674527845CFC7083FA72AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in which a majority of the residents are members of a racial or ethnic minority group; </text></clause>
<clause id="HFE94978E06414C1897015763EFAFFE8E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in which rural features or sparse populations limit other investments with respect to the resiliency of communications networks; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0DB582EE8AA440FF8AC595F46E05B09D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that are highly vulnerable to events relating to severe weather, natural disasters, or climate change-related events, as determined by the Assistant Secretary after— </text>
<subclause id="H4053454AE535476987ACC604CFE80A7F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consulting with the Administrators of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, and the Environmental Protection Agency, using the best data available to those officials; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE321EF835AB14DD68C6926D2269C166F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>obtaining input from operators of communications networks regarding the types of events that are most or least impactful to those communications networks; or</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H84BFF9C46E434067A71D4682FF14DA89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>utilize green infrastructure or renewable energy solutions, including by piloting new green solutions that will affirmatively increase the resiliency of communications infrastructure or communications networks provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H993D59B73D444D7BBD026E19AADB5F7F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions on financial assistance</header> <paragraph id="HD71DBF88E8A84F1AB900976609A2C38B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered efficiency project</header><text>An eligible entity to which funding is made available under the Program with respect to a covered efficiency project shall, to the extent applicable—</text>
<subparagraph id="H38CF34FBDCFF4D2E91F95B7273F96613"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the eligible entity receives the funding, and annually thereafter until the completion of the covered efficiency project, submit to the Assistant Secretary a report that describes, for the year covered by the report, the electrical consumption, by source, of the communications infrastructure or other property that is the subject of the project, which shall identify the percentage of that consumption that comes from fossil fuels and from renewable energy sources; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64283EF01BEC4485880E1B1FF67839C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>complete a clean energy review— </text>
<clause id="HD1E1AA2025034C61B6392A9E2299D047"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the components of which shall be established by the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency— </text> <subclause id="H5BBFF3C29C664B889302FE7ED5713E9B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>through rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H8544A192CFBA48C7B1DF105AA74651A8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after developing a process, in consultation with eligible entities, for— </text> <item id="HFE5E000799F545528A18BABADD064181"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>identifying proprietary and confidential information contained in such a review; and</text></item>
<item id="H8ADD0D535E5D420C90F22E6E8FD77D94" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>handling and protecting information described in item (aa); and</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H7992B673867D46A5B7037702A0E8D518"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which shall include— </text>
<subclause id="HE1ACEA5F430C45A19A10F5C71E2B00F0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the energy consumption patterns of the eligible entity; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1C9E76BF0D9846C3995FE5649C046F52"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the steps taken by the eligible entity, or the steps that the eligible entity will take, to achieve a goal of net-zero carbon emissions with respect to the communications infrastructure, and communications networks, provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE704826E12214EC1AC3AFA657C1235B7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered resiliency project</header><text>An eligible entity to which funding is made available under the Program with respect to a covered resiliency project shall, to the extent applicable—</text> <subparagraph id="H56AB7820843F43DCB461EA0A112FB634"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning not later than 60 days after the date on which the eligible entity receives the funding, register and participate in the Disaster Information Reporting System operated by the Commission, including by subsequently reporting, during times of emergency, the operational status of communications infrastructure operated by the eligible entity; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDC5E86B9A02648F3997D5C9E2C9320E5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date on which the eligible entity receives the funding, and annually thereafter until the completion of the covered resiliency project, submit to the Commission a report that, to the extent applicable, contains, with respect to communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity—</text> <clause id="H1ECC65266F3E4CF5970CC93B32E8BD0C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number, duration, and frequency of communications network outages experienced as a result of an outage with respect to, or other failure of, that infrastructure within a certain time period, as determined by the Commission;</text></clause>
<clause id="H544677B90D4F42C88BED86A7463F47E6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the specific cause of each communications network outage described in clause (i);</text></clause> <clause id="H678ACDBE4D774AA98E90B54343900C9D" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the number of consumers affected by each communications network outage described in clause (i);</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HC6A4EFD219774457B0FDCC7F63CA8FF7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the extent to which first responders were affected by each communications network outage described in clause (i);</text></clause> <clause id="H9155B9F55D724E2AA82D0695FFE04FD6" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the total number of communications network outages annually experienced with respect to that infrastructure that are attributable to severe weather, natural disasters, and climate change-related events and the number of consumers affected by those outages;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBC0EA7C1D29341E0945DE3FCDAE5C853" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the extent of any reduction of communications network performance caused by a communications network outage with respect to that infrastructure;</text></clause> <clause id="HE2BCCB8452BC4AF2B3F5EE6E5A6E713B" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the amount of time between the start of each communications network outage with respect to that infrastructure and detection of the outage;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC6D77EC54D914B599E9058EC8CDCB960" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the amount of time between the detection of each communications network outage with respect to that infrastructure and the initiation of any response to mitigate the effects of the outage;</text></clause> <clause id="H6B20CE10601F41D3A3A8303BB6C05657" commented="no"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the amount of time required to fully restore services after a communications network outage with respect to that infrastructure; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1C54E09F264E40E2BD66F0377AE5CD79" commented="no"><enum>(x)</enum><text>any other information that the Commission determines is necessary to achieve the objectives described in section 4(a)(2); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19AEB4D1BC194D258812F05153A9FDFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>complete a communications resiliency review—</text>
<clause id="HB2D5BFDE2ECA4813AB1E0ECFCAB6E57D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the components of which shall be established by the Commission, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary—</text> <subclause id="H46774027E87A42A9960930A82C97EBC2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>through rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H3799EAA4EE4641A6940707732FF94698"><enum>(II)</enum><text>after developing a process, in consultation with eligible entities, for— </text> <item id="HDED9882FBC3C423A9DD1844640211635"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>identifying proprietary and confidential information contained in such a review; and</text></item>
<item id="H630A4047D5A843AF85B41EFA1A5BA1F5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>handling and protecting information described in item (aa); and </text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD34F7E5483854D20ADA231DBA2EB3906"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which shall include, to the extent applicable—</text>
<subclause id="H7596FC07DEE34942B1F09E1DBED31894"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the analysis of the eligible entity with respect to the vulnerabilities of communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity with respect to severe weather, natural disasters, and climate change-related events;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H290C88CCB6904CBCB278AF586923A15C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a description of steps taken by the eligible entity, or steps that the eligible entity will take, to address the vulnerabilities described in subclause (I); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H37E1691967B141939E5AE0B2917572B2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the number of projected potential users of the communications network or communications infrastructure provided, operated, or owned by the eligible entity that may be affected by the vulnerabilities described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H09060C20B18646F79A322537A9A2DE83"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation with relevant agencies</header><text>In establishing and carrying out the Program, the Assistant Secretary may consult and coordinate, as needed, with the Commission, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the head of any other Federal agency with relevant subject matter expertise.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC1D5214DE1D248C2B26C5683DD1A8226"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; minimum expenditures</header>
<paragraph id="H322FF09641F04803AE86917FEE2E3481"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Assistant Secretary $5,000,000,000 to carry out the Program, which shall remain available until expended.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63B446D2C95E465BA10443D34D91F4A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum expenditures; administrative costs</header><text>Of the amounts made available to carry out the Program, the Assistant Secretary shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HEB509C83E24B42CE81E6910972677118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use not less than 25 percent to provide assistance to eligible entities to carry out covered efficiency projects; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBA6863E25E5441B186F81F0296808146"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use not less than 25 percent to provide assistance to eligible entities to carry out covered resiliency projects; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8A20DF1CCDC646DE9299A1C17721247C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>set aside not more than 2 percent to cover costs relating to administration, research, training, and staff, including— </text> <clause id="H6538EC93F79E47F2B7E94C1C66CC9D94"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the detailing of employees from other Federal agencies; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3EA221AF4B6640C09D06C317815D7487"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the appointment of experts in the fields of infrastructure resiliency, climate science, clean energy, and energy efficiency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HFE8F2DB73A7642D89635921A5371005E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Regulatory framework</header> <subsection id="H758D8F7B6C164FF29D74DA0A22B15552"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Communications network resiliency framework</header> <paragraph id="HA2DCD15CA7DF49F28D4F949334C7DB33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Commission, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall issue rules under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, to establish a communications network resiliency framework to promote resiliency with respect to communications networks and communications infrastructure.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H90804A20BB674E8086983ECE2AF7C1AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the framework established under paragraph (1) shall be the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAA02B71BA9BD401990FAC077BC5824B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To minimize the number of communications network outages.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89CC0D7BD9BA41829FC46405BE868A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To minimize the length of communications network outages.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9E0105AEF78A4247B0326317BEAACB69"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To minimize the number of consumers affected by communications network outages.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3DE5C25F49934F3795C406BE81C46AA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To mitigate the reduction in communications network performance caused by communications network outages.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFC69B942065B468C94BB0B76B44D77D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To encourage the adoption of equipment, policies, and procedures to prepare for communications network outages.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC48B2CAE478D4C2790A7DAE74E85D438"><enum>(F)</enum><text>To promote the detection of, and response to, communications network outages in a timely manner.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1F24D21C4D9D4B8C908D2E74763690F8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>To anticipate and prepare for long-term disruptions to communications networks that are caused by severe weather, natural disasters, or climate change.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H029E816BACD842C0A9D9697A88234BE9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>To support and address the communications needs of first responders involved in detecting, managing, and responding to—</text> <clause id="H9C8DB390362346098B19AE8FC1248C4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>severe weather events, natural disasters, and climate change-related events; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0CF2D20CA9274F7F950AB3E20DE7F119"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communications network outages caused by the events described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8E9EFAFD39C41B2BFD92DAF020A599A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commission discretion</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Commission may, after providing public notice and an opportunity to comment, establish minimum performance criteria or target goals with respect to the resiliency of communications networks and communications infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H356E70A7BAEA4491BD4B6EE36C31B804"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agency responsibilities</header>
<paragraph id="H707B1995C43A442EB5DF3F19FE2DBA76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>FCC responsibilities</header>
<subparagraph id="HB9646696D31242DBB1282D71AA6983C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Resiliency mapping feasibility report</header>
<clause id="HEEFF0CB773FE447AB139957EC417E26C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall— </text> <subclause id="H94437ADFAC484A3B95596D5D180FF68C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in consultation with the Assistant Secretary and the Administrators of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency, complete a study (and submit to Congress a report regarding) the feasibility of establishing and maintaining a map that shows projected risks to communications infrastructure as a result of events relating to severe weather, natural disasters, and climate change; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H5144A71AE0AE4A82BE45E85D23699525"><enum>(II)</enum><text>include in the report required under subclause (I) recommendations regarding—</text> <item id="H1B301581F2F64C4F9441C245A645CFA6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>which Federal agency, or combination of Federal agencies, is best equipped to conduct the mapping described in that subclause;</text></item>
<item id="HCD08E886837D41ED9BB1A1BA37AC7E06"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>how the mapping described in that subclause could— </text> <subitem id="HDD064FFD2D4D41D287742D91E2EF2D97"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>incorporate the information obtained from eligible entities under the program carried out under section 3; and</text></subitem>
<subitem id="H4FE62B446EA54EBE936EFE045D4BBCFD"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>be coordinated with, and connected to, other broadband mapping efforts of the Commission; and</text></subitem></item> <item id="HEAE72617103D42079B5966A764F770AF"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>how to protect and secure any sensitive information relating to, or stemming from, the mapping described in that subclause.</text></item></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H0ABE7CDBC7BE4C95AB31EF4E92282AB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such sums as may be necessary to carry out clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6C8934D75F24658BA60548A1E0E9448" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> <clause id="H669F9E00261E4D61832D6CFA9D679FC9" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary, shall provide technical assistance and resources to— </text>
<subclause id="HD933A773B7C94DB2922E160657FD1B36" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any public or private domestic entity seeking to understand, with respect to a communications network (or communications infrastructure) provided, operated, or owned by that entity, the vulnerability or susceptibility of the network or infrastructure with respect to severe weather, natural disasters, or climate change; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEF9BEDD2586B43F893D2E23B46896A40" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any State or local government seeking to understand the vulnerability or susceptibility with respect to severe weather, natural disasters, or climate change of a communications network that—</text>
<item id="HF73F09F599BE4B56A7B4E7BE256620AD" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is located within the jurisdiction of that government; and</text></item> <item id="H5D5CFC4DF24246AF92078CF19410621B" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is not operated by that government.</text></item></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H35E32D5265A848B0A6771399D8FA7C5D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Scope of assistance</header><text>In providing the technical assistance under clause (i), the Commission shall only provide technical assistance and resources related to mitigating vulnerabilities in a communications network (or communications infrastructure) and is not required to provide technical assistance or resources on separate matters related to climate change.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H541AD551476544A1B8644FA482C371D4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>NORS</header><text>After providing public notice and an opportunity to comment, the Commission shall update the Network Outage Reporting System to include a broadband network outage as a required reporting incident.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCBA0B32226CA42CB854D5C7880CE4F2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NTIA responsibilities</header>
<subparagraph id="H78903F00925A488AABD1F7BF5DBD6039"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Energy and efficiency best practices</header>
<clause id="H6D76714011EE45E1B6281DCEF73B5DD8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with other Federal agencies (including the Commission, the Department of Energy, the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission), and after obtaining input from communications service providers and other interested members of the public, shall make available on a publicly available website a list of best practices for public and private partners to operate energy efficient and carbon-neutral communications infrastructure.</text></clause> <clause id="HDF2135ACC92C44A2AF69A9BF14F5E887"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The list of best practices described in clause (i) may include—</text>
<subclause id="HEB585DF78B2D40839596A34F55992A6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>suggested technical standards for improving energy efficiency with respect to the use and transmission of electronic data, including the implementation of more efficient compression and transmission algorithms and signal types;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2EC6078EC8834D598451C277AD5B19AC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>renewable energy sourcing guidelines; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H898A01D364F94969B1C3C44269ADFE6A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>guidelines for internet service providers to report to consumers the energy consumption of those consumers alongside the data use of those consumers.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8923EAC1A7444ADB94D93878E25FC374"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Commission, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and after providing public notice and an opportunity to comment, shall submit to Congress, and make available on a publicly available website, a report that, at a minimum— </text>
<clause id="H9F5F1502A4AD4F95B4F599DCF1170EAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contains data demonstrating, for the year covered by the report and the year preceding the year covered by the report— </text> <subclause id="H5EBB20FAA5D34273A64C5AB8AB3BA407"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of communications network outages that are attributable to severe weather, natural disasters, and climate change-related events (and the number of consumers affected by those communications network outages); </text></subclause>
<subclause id="H5B77C3FFE4B54AB6B916F91228EB7476"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any shifts in the energy consumption patterns of communications networks and communications infrastructure; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEA8638CB93D84991BC2309D3A0BC8F49"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any reduction in greenhouse gas emissions from communications networks and communications infrastructure; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H43C0F44598CC43019B2B3A2153124ACB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides the most up-to-date projected risks to communications infrastructure because of severe weather, natural disasters, and climate change-related events.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD8A99737FFF14A558771CAB840BB8DC0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department of Energy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, shall submit to Congress a report that— </text>
<subparagraph id="H5DF7DD24868049CC9C44FE016334A50F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>indicates the projected growth of electrical consumption by data centers in the United States; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF87B8667C3C3468FAB1A3BBDDF8F44B4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes recommendations for implementing energy efficiency standards for data centers that would— </text>
<clause id="H5935B2E4033D4036BA8B3455E4C2E02C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>limit the growth described in subparagraph (A) to the greatest extent practicable without— </text> <subclause id="H4F81871527244A4CBB05098D4A76C285"><enum>(I)</enum><text>reducing the rate of broadband adoption and usage in the United States; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H75901D153A9544EDB1F89EDF1C3E61F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>limiting the development of new and improved technologies or services; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA2D1C5A29718414DBEC0E31EFCC1A1D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage the rapid adoption of renewable energy sources.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

