<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBBF0BDE2E98F44868B0428945E612B0C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 6893 IH: Institutional Grants for New Infrastructure, Technology, and Education for HBCU and MSI Excellence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6893</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220302">March 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the long-term improvement of minority-serving institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF2DF9984880B44789363BD3666B506F6" style="OLC"><section id="H82719FC1068D4E21BE26A613A13B7812" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Institutional Grants for New Infrastructure, Technology, and Education for HBCU and MSI Excellence Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>IGNITE HBCU and MSI Excellence Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2242FC28FBC543259F49950C3CC9F93B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for the long-term improvement of MSIs</header><subsection id="H91523AAB3CC14FB9BA502333B841088F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities, on a competitive basis, to support long-term improvements to the facilities of such entities in accordance with this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8206BC5218C14DE9960A11908D6EA1E4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be considered for a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><paragraph id="H56D3413BCDE24978B329BCCE5B89E568" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to the extent possible, the information necessary for the Secretary to make the determinations under subsection (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H275010984D084B0B9B401424D716F819"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the projects that such eligible entity plans to carry out with the grant, and how such projects will advance the long-term goals of the entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H781520133D2440AF9D8C7647A15AFFE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how such projects will reduce risks to the health, welfare, and safety of students, staff, administrators, faculty, researchers, and guests at such eligible entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCB97391152E4B408EAB15464CF8B4E6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="HD944C3E7DC9345EEB330E42085A63CE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text><subparagraph id="H843BE1B0F40941B4A0FAA2E981A1ADDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate the greatest need to improve campus facilities, as determined by a comparison of factors identified by the Secretary, which may include—</text><clause id="H1FE8C1232C92469CA07499010046FAC9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consideration of threats posed by the proximity of such facilities to toxic sites;</text></clause><clause id="H6B388C48008B4FA28C4B221D1A517463"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the vulnerability of such facilities to natural disasters and environmental risks;</text></clause><clause id="H2C14A8D2C4CE46ADAA81D29C266AFEFC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the median age of such facilities, including the facilities that such eligible entities will use grant funds to improve;</text></clause><clause id="H571788B8E99F47E7A62CBA4DFA19E34D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the extent to which student enrollment exceeds physical and instructional capacity;</text></clause><clause id="HE0BA447F40EE47CCAAFBF429750CB70C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the condition of major systems in such facilities such as heating, ventilation, air conditioning, electrical, water, and sewer systems;</text></clause><clause id="H60E6F0040F18414F8CC5A618686FC20D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the condition of roofs, windows, and doors of such facilities;</text></clause><clause id="H9AB0BD99B0D64F94AE294303BD51A637"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>other critical health and safety conditions;</text></clause><clause id="HED6BF63249E741B789DAC8216797E2CE"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and condition of facilities in significant disrepair; and</text></clause><clause id="H555ED9253317452C9EFF6FCE6FF64903"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the total amount of deferred maintenance of such facilities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A335007ABC54530A89EF9AD13DF529E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrate the most limited capacity to raise funds for the long-term improvement of campus facilities, as determined by an assessment of—</text><clause id="H673795CAA9384D3B8990F878169ED83A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the current and historic ability of the eligible entity to raise funds for construction, renovation, modernization, and major repair projects for campus;</text></clause><clause id="H80CF2140DBB9405293A68FBDB0D2334E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the eligible entity has been able to issue bonds or receive other funds to support school construction projects; and</text></clause><clause id="H7A4AEA0FDB984B7795ED40812D477881" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the bond rating of the eligible entity;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2130F988D60246AB8CDF1B8FC831C126"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enroll the highest percentages of students who are eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>), and whose families qualify for other Federal need-based aid; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D29BE67CF464640A1DEB995BED86962"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are public institutions facing declining State support or investment; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EFFB1C9A3B54445A67AC48637811DED" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>demonstrate an effort to seek support from public and private entities for projects carried out with a grant awarded under this Act; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C22E9826C5B41B98BE70BE66F0E856B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may give priority to eligible entities—</text><subparagraph id="H97F693ED970F4937BEC9C0A6399D0B66"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that lack access to high-speed broadband and will use the grant funds to improve access to high-speed broadband sufficient to support digital learning in accordance with section 3(a)(9); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H334D593A5877490B979ACCD7753EC628"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BD3F694B3B7492F9A6A025D80AC6694" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that grants under this section are awarded to eligible entities in a manner that reflects the geographic distribution of such entities in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H81D191A97F36404BA1BBEF38F2CB3CFA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, directly or by grant or contract, may provide technical assistance to eligible entities to prepare the entities to qualify, apply for, and maintain a grant, under this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC98A33AFFE8B4C4E80D3DFB280FFE12C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Relationship to HBCU capital financing program</header><paragraph id="H1D894A9265ED4062BB1E07DEF0DFBCDD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may take into consideration whether an eligible entity has received a loan under a loan agreement made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>) when—</text><subparagraph id="H33EB0BEF1A414A92887255589995C60B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviewing grant applications under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA353F38E08DD49A0858C3B8D1ED516CC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determining priority under subsection (c); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD116DE773C384AA8AAD715F28AB9EF93" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>determining the amount awarded for a grant under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H163626885BEA472A989CCB61582DCBF4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to paragraph (1)(B), the Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="H75E4D5C2FB5241399FF7E398F952E5AC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine that an eligible entity should not receive priority under subsection (c) if such entity has received a loan under a loan agreement made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C9663015C1B4C40B03FF24665DA8293" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine that an eligible entity should receive higher priority under subsection (c) if such entity has not received a loan under a loan agreement made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC038404DE6D348CD8093F4A9EAC5DF8F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant uses</header><subsection id="H0034EFC4BF8D4D1CA19B52F36AB397C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Permitted uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), an eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall use such grant funds to carry out at least one of the following activities:</text><paragraph id="HAA73331FA32745C38DCCFD5DFCDF9FD9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Construct, modernize, renovate, or retrofit the campus facilities of such entity, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HCF32BFA435804613ACCB2F6B54EF488D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing for the improvement of existing, or the establishment of new, instructional program spaces, laboratories, or research facilities relating to fields of science, technology, engineering, the arts, mathematics, health, agriculture, education, medicine, law, and other disciplines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC59C80EE93C4F64A94E8ECAAA8D9BE0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">constructing or improving roads or other transportation infrastructure on campus, for which the eligible entity is responsible;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3C54266F0324AD9830E1A07905D63EB"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing or improving the use of campus facilities for the purpose of community-based partnerships that provide students and community members with academic, health, career, and social services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF76D47C9E83E45189D0D40FE7E444790"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">preserving facilities with historic significance, and facilities that house historic or cultural artifacts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FEBE2DFC4C34EBB8F81E3D5945C9386"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Purchase or modernize vehicle fleets owned and operated by such entity that are used primarily for the purpose of facilitating campus accessibility and student academic activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3A83A5152B5410DA2B4843BB220659F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Carry out major repairs to the facilities or other physical plants of such entity, including deferred maintenance projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA728D522782F46BC902DF124394D3AF1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acquire and install academic and residential furniture, fixtures, and instructional research-related equipment and technology in the campus facilities of such entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H583E315A400E4DD49FB3A5606DBC2A8C" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of facilitating the construction of new campus facilities funded with a grant under this Act—</text><subparagraph id="HA289469C31E345AA936F92DAE82A3A88" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase or otherwise acquire title to land to serve as a permanent site for such facilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2900EBF552134D818B863ECF1E1A8E3A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent that other public or private funds are insufficient—</text><clause id="HD8785B7F754A4F238BA7627A63BB1823"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prepare land for the construction of such facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H516F747CE31944628B8AE979FAD8DAD2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pay other preconstruction costs relating to the development of such facilities. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF11A925B3D14A5292486F7C454388AE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Install or extend the life and usability of basic systems and components of campus facilities, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HD5AC00749FD44007BCE3CB17588D1A21"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">high-speed broadband internet infrastructure sufficient to support digital and technology-based learning; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4E64D7288D64A3C8A584E64FB71235A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>high-capacity, middle-mile broadband networks, and campus-wide broadband networks, including 5G and future network generations; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C436C0F9E72412C81BE9E29F1D16A64"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fiber, cyber, and telecommunications infrastructure, including small cells;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13EDA025CCBA4161800C7DA84D0AF517"><enum>(D)</enum><text>heating, ventilation, and air conditioning (HVAC) or other indoor air quality systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H656A15AC18DA439D85AA67BB05E82B75"><enum>(E)</enum><text>support for last-mile service for rural campuses when other means of providing this support is unavailable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08A14F4D0C904A169C28BE9EB407ED74"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other infrastructure to support the success of operations and other digital and technology needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H019F9DC94D3A4FB58B49950CB61A389D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthen the safety and security of the campus of such entity by improving or utilizing design elements, principles, and technology that—</text><subparagraph id="H2CEADCE70A8A463285C3F05DBEA62C6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>guarantee layers of security throughout the such campus; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H647E1592EA8D4138AB4993F67391C6E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uphold the function of such campus as a learning and teaching environment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D5EFB91A24F41108107A28639C73619"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Reduce current or anticipated overcrowding in the campus facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EEF0F75A1B54DE5AC65834EFF9E34C7"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Ensure that the building envelopes of the campus facilities—</text><subparagraph id="HEB49F883F487492193FB370401F92E8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protect occupants and interiors of such facilities from natural elements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1DD3E721A6940FDA05C72C05E2686CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are structurally sound and secure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC98094E43B6448E597903AAD3A5565F7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Improve energy and water efficiency to lower the costs of energy and water consumption in campus facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H459729AE6BDC464F8159971DE26AAC4D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>With respect to campus facilities, reduce or eliminate the presence of—</text><subparagraph id="H76D9178088E347E7B81E77D1DA1D9B48"><enum>(A)</enum><text>toxins and chemicals, including mercury, radon, polychlorinated biphenyls, lead, and asbestos;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FC02751A341492D809F3490C38CEA3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mold and mildew;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0B8E519B0C544F2BE10C9A23965B023"><enum>(C)</enum><text>rodents and pests; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2CCB66AD1F448CBA5CEF20773845E41"><enum>(D)</enum><text>biological, radiological, and other waste related to research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D9C5221153244368357C4C9E281157A"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Ensure the safety of drinking water at the tap and water used for meal preparation in campus facilities, which may include testing of the potability of water at the tap for the presence of lead and other contaminants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF07AE2E6424F7D804E612EAB86A581"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Bring campus facilities into compliance with applicable fire, health, and safety codes and regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5059D56C4ADC42B2A1A014813E4FFD23"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Make existing campus facilities accessible to individuals with disabilities through compliance with—</text><subparagraph id="H711BD30BD0784BCA9AD72B997E89C67F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85E157B42BF6407183F11515E372159F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD00C4FF905DA4F0295AECAF111579F0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act may not use such grant funds for—</text><paragraph id="H66B840EC33AF450CBBFDFCF861B318F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>payment of routine and predictable maintenance costs, minor repairs, and utility bills; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19C7ABF6DB224FB2A18412BD17BAC8AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any facility that is—</text><subparagraph id="H8D80C3EF87264889AD47B5258FC138FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>primarily used for athletic contests or exhibitions or other events for which admission is charged to the general public; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2C95A88537740EBA29DC0B5804CE830"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">primarily used for or associated with sectarian instruction or religious worship; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40E22EE75AAF462184C3CD4EC1F5EEDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the purchase or support of any communications equipment or service (as defined in section 9 of the Secure and Trusted Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1608">47 U.S.C. 1608</external-xref>)) that poses a risk to national security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9068D5F761CC4210BC61400F72E379BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>An eligible entity shall use a grant received under this Act only to supplement the level of Federal, State, and local public funds that would, in the absence of such grant, be made available for the activities supported by the grant, and not to supplant such funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6FB4809DBAA45A9982F2B3D949BD35D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Encouraging partnerships</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage partnerships between eligible entities and public and private entities to—</text><paragraph id="H0AD0EC53D21A4BC6B678C0A47512EF97" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide additional funding; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE74D9C2FCFF4635A9D6C52D4B4867F6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist in carrying out the activities under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8C0CFC23B7D0406091A58B00EC556DA1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements for hazard-resistance and energy and water conservation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act shall ensure that any new construction, modernization, or renovation project carried out with such grant funds meets or exceeds the following requirements:</text><paragraph id="H2F6D3DFE52C34AFBA5D070CEB359E555"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Requirements for such projects set forth in the most recent published edition of a nationally recognized, consensus-based model building code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE6AA3B628E1460B8076E8B190884E42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Requirements for such projects set forth in the most recent published edition of a nationally recognized, consensus-based model energy conservation code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E2038BA79914E2DAFB52FF5D96A195C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Performance criteria under the WaterSense program, established under section 324B of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6294b">42 U.S.C. 6294b</external-xref>), applicable to such projects within a nationally recognized, consensus-based model code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H625C8BEBC0144B16819C57EEE42ACC69"><enum>5.</enum><header>Use of small business concerns</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In carrying out projects funded with a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall seek to procure contracts from small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans (including service-disabled veterans), qualified HUBZone small business concerns, small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals, and small business concerns owned and controlled by women. </text></section><section id="H2D51D45CFE8040D4BABCE26F697DE4E5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reservation for administrative and other activities</header><subsection id="H966E539630634394818294F0DFF2637C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this Act may reserve a total of not more than five percent of the amount of such grant to—</text><paragraph id="HB8F0288E4CB040A2B7692E64C792F49E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop the facilities master plan required under subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H175A556C8EA647EFB8714A703353A25B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out activities to—</text><subparagraph id="HDA1EB495631949E2BFE1303A9C38C1F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protect the health of students, staff, administrators, faculty, researchers, and guests during the construction or modernization of the campus facilities of such entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H977336D793F34BFCAB0E882AA9C447DB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigate excessive noise caused by activities carried out under this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F3A90096F83472D93878BAF92981BAA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pay personnel to carry out administrative work relating to the grant program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F5599418CB84D08B59708664DABFB9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pay other reasonable administrative costs associated with the grant program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB60D339250E400F9BB150A66A2D5D77" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Facilities master plan</header><paragraph id="H66CD2F2F9BC24C68A0E230768E9EB83F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after receiving a grant under this Act, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary a comprehensive 10-year facilities master plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE408096DB8BC4479847776D828099721" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The facilities master plan required under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the eligible entity submitting such plan, a description of—</text><subparagraph id="H5C70A0123185416F8F257292A8F56473" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the extent to which the campus facilities—</text><clause id="H1B27023488ED4239B7183FD0D45E722B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meet the educational needs of students; and</text></clause><clause id="H4D65E4829EAB4EBD9241265B023249A2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support the educational mission and vision of such entity;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF4C9B0793C345B09285340CCD2D0542" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the physical condition of the campus facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9D9B21F68F64CE89B42EBBA176721B7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the current health, safety, and environmental conditions of the campus facilities, including—</text><clause id="H0A3EEF28690941F6BE1940A00E87AC14" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>indoor air quality;</text></clause><clause id="HCDD8978450064D56B3EE13719BE2BDE4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the presence of hazardous and toxic substances and chemicals on or near such facilities;</text></clause><clause id="H791CFD3D67FD46308B93D4B45444A6CF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the safety of drinking water at the tap and water used for meal preparation, including the level of lead and other contaminants in such water;</text></clause><clause id="H8409484E1377402695278D665E979F68" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>energy and water efficiency;</text></clause><clause id="H5A22BD95D075428E8F684BE01FB82896" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>excessive noise in academic spaces; and</text></clause><clause id="HB2FDA39D4F2640F78A2311DF5DB4B399" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other health, safety, and environmental conditions that would impact the health, safety, and learning ability of students;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD14FD5919673427A83FA0F284022FEC5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the actual and anticipated impact of current and future student enrollment levels (as of the date of application) on the design of current and future campus facilities, as well as the financial implications of such enrollment levels;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D6EAEE3101F4E40986DB6CEA536175C" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the dollar amount and percentage of funds such entity will dedicate to capital construction projects, including—</text><clause id="H4FCBBDC048B24A7CB18C676751C5D370" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any funds in the budget of such entity that will be dedicated to such projects; and</text></clause><clause id="H22648AFF11FE479087C7545799FD1E8F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any funds not in such budget that will be dedicated to such projects, including any funds available to the eligibility entity as the result of a bond issue or the Historically Black College and University Capital Financing Program under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59D20934D85A439DB41D4EE983A26D58" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the dollar amount and percentage of funds such entity will dedicate to the maintenance and operation of campus facilities, including—</text><clause id="H18770CDBF5F7448AB8600B7E6CB2A62D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any funds in the budget of such entity that will be dedicated to the maintenance and operation of such facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="H87510040C5BE42B8A000EC41DD8BCBCA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any funds not in the budget of such entity that will be dedicated to the maintenance and operation of such facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93FCFCE9622C4A41809A7B1BF1C1D6B0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the facilities master plan, the eligible entity demonstrate that it conducted meaningful consultation with diverse stakeholders, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H9244AE4F129A478782BE5D5EBCBC0B77" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>staff and other institutional leaders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501CB3FA80C945E590731BBCC5849F58" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>custodial and maintenance staff;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF756EC8D5D4846C2B28564296B8272DD" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>emergency first responders;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E3B7C3932BA40D9BD7CC03CE037CB63" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>campus facilities directors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC7073C22F41489B91406FAB94F3426D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>students and families;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A44748953774F1AA4657726D30C156E" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community residents, including those directly affected by actions undertaken as a result of utilizing grant funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49A628B7CF1C4A33B9C091B1BC0FBBEB" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>government entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC24F39F5A2324B2BBEB2919B3B19B565"><enum>(H)</enum><text>local charitable foundations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FFA6A420DCB439581412DF881F6D5EE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>local employers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7A63C0D003C4CD889B7C2A72B6E5986" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Indian Tribes, as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H620317B64919488B96E016E3D25515EE"><enum>(K)</enum><text>other such individuals and entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H961D6B47124747C6B94346FA0E058CCD"><enum>7.</enum><header>HBCU capital financing loan disbursement and forgiveness</header><subsection id="H38ED71AC909648F5BF8841A0339DFB56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each time an institution of higher education receives a disbursement of a loan amount under a covered closed loan agreement, the Secretary shall repay—</text><paragraph id="H6D71E61306C24A08A402AAAF11835394"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the outstanding balance of principal, interest, fees, and costs on such loan amount (as of the date of such disbursement) under the covered closed loan agreement; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5993CB8849A64D2C95E5B7CE434032FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any reimbursement (including reimbursements of escrow and return of fees and deposits) relating to the covered closed loan agreement that are usual and customary when the loan is paid off by the institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2978FA0AB9C4E24AE0747DECC484237"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered closed loan agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term “covered closed loan agreement” means each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H89F4EE7D184E48C29E89E1D8F692CCF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A closed loan agreement—</text><subparagraph id="H6547B699978F4E9D831E229FD0887C16"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">executed before the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3AA83A644914CFD85D69999DF07F345"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made under part D of title III of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1066">20 U.S.C. 1066 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE99DDC0C2C1B469EA41B65240BFE8ED1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that provides for loan amounts that have not been disbursed as of the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7F1FBAD602A439BB6F3A6AE91C99646"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A closed loan agreement—</text><subparagraph id="H777EED553B69462F8EDFF090B1157FBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized under section 3512 of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref> note); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF04121D76B654DA98EC787F325D764E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made for the deferment of balances that have not been disbursed as of the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9F8297EF8F9A4F8BBCC3CD3C0F21BF12"><enum>8.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="H62BCD2B59FD4403B99D2F166E3AE981A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Department of Education report</header><paragraph id="HBF47763A6A28449B98073E423AFD1D86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the projects carried out with grant funds awarded under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F2631CF38804E7993F6F47FEBB1448A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H945C33188DE84BA1B0CEB90636ACB75F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to projects carried out by eligible entities with grant funds awarded under this Act, an assessment of—</text><clause id="H605764E370DC432A90BA83EDEBAE5959"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the types of such projects;</text></clause><clause id="H98E15B9B88264BBD881E1E2EF30B6042"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the square footage of the improvements made by such projects, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="H3E28B7D4F6A14103A2B5A62B991CD40B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>total square footage; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA852ADC0479845C98274EA4EDD7B8355"><enum>(II)</enum><text>square footage per each eligible entity;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H88F059B7E5974D279A5352A43E44739D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the total cost of each such project;</text></clause><clause id="HBCA130EF7A2E4A098FF8859CA1FA1354"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the cost described in clause (iii), disaggregated by the cost of—</text><subclause id="H9D7A7CE541894854A82D20B772A886AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>planning;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE4C18380437B443AB2C9B0CDC51D84AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>design;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF3BDA8F163DA4D6785713BD7FBC2B827"><enum>(III)</enum><text>construction;</text></subclause><subclause id="H1BE4051006CF4C04BFFA7982BCE63EA3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>site purchase; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6B94F7E43D364B0CA3403AE0E7882F1B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>improvements;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCF623F3686D24867A4B61D02A13009FF"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the geographic distribution of such projects; and</text></clause><clause id="H8A78CF9AB33B4C0EB1C6390A6C107513"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the demographic composition of the student population served by such projects, disaggregated by—</text><subclause id="HD9C7082208E444BBA4493D7315FA311B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>race and ethnicity; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5D5914684F4A437A8FA222CDC13E38EF"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and percentage of students enrolled at such entities who are eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a et seq.</external-xref>); </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE69EECD437F54B69BDC30F2BA28F8A7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of a sample of grant recipients, selected by the Secretary taking into account size and geographic location of each grantee, to determine how such recipients are using the grant and the effectiveness of the activities carried out with the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CFA4495D0C444A9A12ED89AAA4CE85D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an analysis of compliance with the requirement in section 3(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H519D4CDDA0D74B62942CBEE2D3480BC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comptroller General study report</header><paragraph id="H38860064BF854187A126441CFACC8659"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the implementation of the grant program under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B679BEA770647D69F623206415C96E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study conducted under paragraph (1) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HBFD2A84DAAF54DB4846AC4EABA1EFF7A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an examination of program implementation challenges; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA671125F93474D4B9058CDC2D32F3C67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of whether any changes are needed to make grants under this Act more accessible to eligible entities with fiscal challenges to help them raise capital for infrastructure projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC62DB5B3BDD24E94A8EC538D3F90C041"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>After the completion of the study under paragraph (1), the Comptroller General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the results of the study, including any recommendations to the Secretary for improvements to the implementation of the grant program under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H82B7DC70F241416194F6DD7CD94A1EAC"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H1732D8D59F0F4486B6B9AEDE5045629E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA9B661FB2D694499A01869B47B812C36" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a part B institution (as defined in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2226C69CF06C4FEA83B000E7A0A48BF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Historically Black Graduate Professional School (as identified in section 326(e) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1063b">20 U.S.C. 1063b(e)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB22C259537004BFAA5EDB77C26509792"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Hispanic-serving institution (as defined in section 502 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2B0F9E23B8B482D9E8C783EFA777CAB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a Tribal College or University (as defined in section 316 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D41FF220BFB4C9399DBFB05363F20F0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an Alaska Native-serving institution or a Native Hawaiian-serving institution (as defined in section 317(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059d">20 U.S.C. 1059d(b)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE244F99E83745ADB68B5CCFD56DDF7C"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Predominantly Black Institution (as defined in section 371(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(c)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6099B49442A64AF4BFEC91EC6BE15812"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution (as defined in section 371(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(c)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41257BD8128C44ED856713664B25F761"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a Native American-serving nontribal institution (as defined in section 371(c) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(c)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD64A04DCABC4C99A41997269613C7E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H296C8F90C44345BAA7A463A9FEE6B1EA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H501424B39ECD405D9B6C51E6A7EB7A5D"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HEC4E596BDC8144B4ACA18F4244E0CB7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this Act for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></subsection><subsection id="H95EBD48DBD004D10B58C10E1089211A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocation of funds</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated under subsection (a) for each fiscal year—</text><paragraph id="HADE164677DB84969BF57F86F93BA932B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>40 percent shall be available to award grants to eligible entities that are—</text><subparagraph id="HD2556FABCBDA47DDA14A742258E7EB92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>part B institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E22E95E6D9649E1B5233FCD7D1ACA52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Historically Black Graduate Professional Schools;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H070E1B3B0FFE450D80664D50FB4C3174"><enum>(2)</enum><text>38.5 percent shall be available to award grants to eligible entities that are Hispanic-serving institutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25666E6DDE8144FDB493B1FD86DD95DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>10 percent shall be available to award grants to eligible entities that are Tribal Colleges or Universities; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC73D6F5EF154FC2953BDC82D7A659E8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">6 percent shall be available to award grants to eligible entities that are Predominantly Black Institutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03F500278DD246F5B57E6BE5F92495AF"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">3 percent shall be available to award grants to eligible entities that are Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C2EBB989DD54725992842F92F5DB2F7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>2.5 percent shall be available to award grants to eligible entities that are—</text><subparagraph id="HF46E496815924F52B5ECA2D1B63101E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Native American-serving nontribal institutions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9038DD6502FA465D9BC20C4662294BCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Alaska Native-serving institutions or Native Hawaiian-serving institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

