<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E482F80404D4EB19B0FB530299C6575" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8593 IH: Territories Statistics Collection Equity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001204">Mr. San Nicolas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy to develop a plan to collect and publish statistics regarding the Territories of the United States in the same manner as statistics are collected and reported by Federal agencies for the several States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB9A7F95C4A164458BEF8F712E767DCCD" style="OLC"><section id="HD8FB6C42959446FC87508D1D63FB9F2D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Territories Statistics Collection Equity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H00AA4FA679174A75A7A96230D640D633"><enum>2.</enum><header>Including U.S. Territories in Federal statistical programs</header><subsection id="HAA80E1B618ED462CBB17D216B875CDF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy shall publish a list and assessment of existing Federal statistical programs that collect and publish data for the U.S. Territories comparable to the several States. The assessment under this subsection shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HF2F99F8AF7C64D129C54C9AEA240F4BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For each statistical program where a comparable program for the U.S. Territories does not exist, an explanation as to why the program does not include the U.S. Territories.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1067A7E9EBCB4E4BABCEFD02D4082055"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Impediments to data collection, analysis, and publishing with respect to the U.S. Territories.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H350B29BA33F74DFD9FBCD1E2E8F291FE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A detailed description of the level of local government participation required in Federal statistical programs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H961D9C34EDFA4CA6802CDE131C65E64E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a plan to collect and publish statistics regarding the U.S. Territories in the same manner as statistics are collected and reported by Federal agencies for the several States. The plan shall include—</text><paragraph id="H9E2CC2CE13D54A7CB359C20F7A54F732"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for including the U.S. Territories in Federal statistical programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86907E48670441CCA64957896AFDFC19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cost estimates for Federal and local governments for necessary changes to implement the recommendations under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF770A90562642EEB6907BA9C4DA8125"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 12 months thereafter until the plan is fully implemented, the head of the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H7EC41F5B28EF4777AEFB54F162CB46A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the plan developed under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A246BF3F4D447B5B2A75F86154C7DA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information on the implementation of such plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57E4E7BFA3DD446198C4AF638873B69F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the head of the Interagency Council on Statistical Policy, in coordination with the heads of appropriate Federal agencies, shall fully implement the plan developed under subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><section id="H4BA281CF1EC24DEEB23EE3FD5D352852"><enum>3.</enum><header>U.S. Territories defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the term <term>U.S. Territories</term> means American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands of the United States.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

