<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H44447B0BEFD24B2D89D3CB59C0C7767C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7156 IH: Medicaid Coverage for Addiction Recovery Expansion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7156</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220318">March 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to provide States with an option to provide medical assistance to individuals between the ages of 22 and 64 for inpatient services to treat substance use disorders at certain facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H63C2F0FE73834E978EAF386422F86EE4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H55BB22155EAF41DEA428D73C9CF13DFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicaid Coverage for Addiction Recovery Expansion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA911E1C6C361475FAF921978ED8FEC3A"><enum>2.</enum><header>State option to provide medical assistance for residential addiction treatment facility services; modification of the IMD exclusion</header> <subsection id="H130DED3B2F8A46649F096177787FFA62"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H94FCFEDF05954FFF8152D457755F9FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(16)—</text> <subparagraph id="H123C78C24C8547418934473E7E1E9B20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and, (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (B)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBF739AE38BAB40469577B350E385B458"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and (C) effective January 1, 2023, residential addiction treatment facility services (as defined in subsection (h)(3)) for individuals over 21 years of age and under 65 years of age, if offered as part of a full continuum of evidence-based treatment services provided under the State plan, including residential, outpatient, and community-based care, for individuals with substance use disorders</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA074C1EF8F342EB81200832C65D1432"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7B2E4AD5CE2241EA8AFD860883AE724E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraph (16) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(16)(A)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4FDDE0C2FD644768FE53B2877569B6D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block act-name="" id="HC656C18B9F594A68A43DBBAE6DE635B0" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H08F3474D919143DDA80ED455940C5A4E" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H0EA83ED0FF7A42CE87411C929F0A2373"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a)(16)(C), the term <term>residential addiction treatment facility services</term> means, subject to subparagraph (B), inpatient services provided—</text> <clause id="H6A355185CC344F2BA665D0B940100910" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to an individual for the purpose of treating a substance use disorder that are furnished to an individual for not more than 2 consecutive periods of 30 consecutive days, provided that upon completion of the first 30-day period, the individual is assessed and determined to have progressed through the clinical continuum of care, in accordance with criteria established by the Secretary, in consultation with the American Society of Addiction Medicine, and requires continued medically necessary treatment and social support services to promote recovery, stable transition to ongoing treatment, and discharge; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H084DD4465DE34DED832B7B51399B1868" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a facility that is accredited for the treatment of substance use disorders by the Joint Commission on Accreditation of Healthcare Organizations, the Commission on Accreditation of Rehabilitation Facilities, the Council on Accreditation, or any other accrediting agency that the Secretary deems appropriate as necessary to ensure nationwide applicability, including qualified national organizations and State-level accrediting agencies.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7AE0D71B866E411E8157047E08C5CBC4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The State agency responsible for administering the State plan under this title shall establish procedures to ensure that, with respect to any facility providing residential addiction treatment facility services in a fiscal year, the average monthly number of beds used by the facility to provide such services during such year is not more than 40.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA640AC0596814C86975FF5722D32285D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The provision of medical assistance for residential addiction treatment facility services to an individual shall not prohibit Federal financial participation for medical assistance for items or services that are provided to the individual in or away from the residential addiction treatment facility during any 30-day period in which the individual is receiving residential addiction treatment facility services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4B09F0BC7C384BF8BE2DD4C8E44ADD4C" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A woman who is eligible for medical assistance on the basis of being pregnant and who is furnished residential addiction treatment facility services during any 30-day period may remain eligible for, and continue to be furnished with, such services for additional 30-day periods without regard to any eligibility limit that would otherwise apply to the woman as a result of her pregnancy ending, subject to assessment by the facility and a determination based on medical necessity related to substance use disorder and the impact of substance use disorder on birth outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2998ACC4F7954D6DA96AC3E927153D6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2023.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HFC5DECDD3AA447A781B42ED231C2D576"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grant program to expand youth addiction treatment facilities under Medicaid and CHIP</header> <subsection id="H5ADF0F76A1294006BB63AAD11D7B5FB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="HA1C33E6CC3B84B508815CC3E554BE80D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall award grants to States for the purpose of expanding the infrastructure and treatment capabilities, including augmenting equipment and bed capacity, of eligible youth addiction treatment facilities that provide addiction treatment services to Medicaid or CHIP beneficiaries who have not attained the age of 21 and are in communities with high numbers of medically underserved populations of at-risk youth.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6229E7769B04378972C2E0D036A9642"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Grant funds awarded under this section may be used to expand the infrastructure and treatment capabilities of an existing facility (including through construction) but shall not be used for the construction of any new facility or for the provision of medical assistance or child health assistance under Medicaid or CHIP.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81E7FD7B519640E8B4E7BE5C869BB169"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Timetable for implementation; duration</header> <subparagraph id="HCC00FFAD1D54429AA7BAD31BF0D6B44A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall award grants under the grant program.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03FC0E40948942F98EAFC4BA37CE5D8C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under the grant program for a period not to exceed 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA7B2E693BB4B41E5BF857E53D6DF91DF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State seeking to participate in the grant program shall submit to the Secretary, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary shall require, an application that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8567B585F760475CA1A4BDB2A096C467"><enum>(1)</enum><text>detailed information on the types of additional infrastructure and treatment capacity of eligible youth addiction treatment facilities that the State proposes to fund under the grant program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30227979FCFF4D2C805E7D3C238A28DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the communities in which the eligible youth addiction treatment facilities funded under the grant program operate;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8BDBB742BD045DA95F2DECF61CD3764"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assurance that the eligible youth addiction treatment facilities that the State proposes to fund under the grant program shall give priority to providing addiction treatment services to Medicaid or CHIP beneficiaries who have not attained the age of 21 and are in communities with high numbers of medically underserved populations of at-risk youth; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3C74E33CF714E728C1B6F67CFFB0BF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such additional information and assurances as the Secretary shall require.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F8194AF84F14BFD8117DB8F3164C35E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rural areas</header><text>Not less than 15 percent of the amount of a grant awarded to a State under this section shall be used for making payments to eligible youth addiction treatment facilities that are located in rural areas or that target the provision of addiction treatment services to Medicaid or CHIP beneficiaries who have not attained the age of 21 and reside in rural areas.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB4861FD072A444EA773789846F081B2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H52D0260E7DF44EE3A39324EC7CCCAA02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Addiction treatment services</header><text>The term <term>addiction treatment services</term> means services provided to an individual for the purpose of treating a substance use disorder.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F82C1EE61BB43038FDD21ACA8B1451B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>CHIP</header><text>The term <term>CHIP</term> means the State children's health insurance program established under title XXI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397aa">42 U.S.C. 1397aa et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47FE847223CF4BEAA49A0B0F260EDD81"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible youth addiction treatment facility</header><text>The term <term>eligible youth addiction treatment facility</term> means a facility that is a participating provider under the State Medicaid or CHIP programs for purposes of providing medical assistance or child health assistance to Medicaid or CHIP beneficiaries for youth addiction treatment services on an inpatient or outpatient basis (or both).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E2688C1D5CF45D88DFFBF248A17B30C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><text>The term <term>Medicaid</term> means the medical assistance program established under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H896810E2D48B41528701AF6DCE255FA5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Medicaid or CHIP beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>Medicaid or CHIP beneficiary</term> means an individual who is enrolled in the State Medicaid plan, the State child health plan under CHIP, or under a waiver of either such plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0AF6DFBBCA54AEDA620243D55E43F29"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Medically underserved populations</header><text>The term <term>medically underserved populations</term> has the meaning given that term in section 330(b)(3) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4EBA300531E4C8A93B3D5E17D79E6C8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H89209C3589CE49E59FF3EA9FDDB7DDD3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 to carry out the provisions of this section. Funds appropriated under this subsection shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

