<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4AF16F62AFE451ABA7271FA390F038E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7890 IH: Defending Freedom of Conscience for Cadets and Midshipmen Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7890</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit unfair treatment of cadets and midshipmen who refuse to get the COVID&#8211;19 vaccine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBACC700F65A2493FAB48F928B33503BE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H624126E998DA4D76833BFC8C81223428" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Freedom of Conscience for Cadets and Midshipmen Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCDE8B13EE817478A9085E03A61C97B1B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD4DA9CD3887E43528931298DE1E7BBBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered individual</header><text>The term <term>covered individual</term> means a cadet or midshipman at a Federal service academy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H258E0E624C194154B8137F7C7F878028"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal service academy</header><text>The term <term>Federal service academy</term> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEF0BBD87463C4049ADB3305ED2967FD9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The United States Military Academy, West Point, New York.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H152C52F8399E4ACC877839AB47318263"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The United States Naval Academy, Annapolis, Maryland.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA9DD6AD7F3BA46F58C4666AD461681B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The United States Air Force Academy, Colorado Springs, Colorado.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F5BA1C0E1324FBBA3F843F3FA04B39E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The United States Coast Guard Academy, New London, Connecticut.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3AFAAFCF3EC24D699CCFE69C495DACC1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The United States Merchant Marine Academy, Kings Point, New York. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="HBDA801A20FF44C2586E4837429F6DE8C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on vaccine requirement for graduation from Federal service academies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A covered individual may not be required to be vaccinated for COVID–19 as a condition for graduation from a Federal service academy nor dismissed from a Federal service academy as a result of refusing to be so vaccinated.</text></section> 
<section id="HC4AE0E90A4BF4FFCAD78E43D11FE5700"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on enforcement of repayment provisions for refusal to receive vaccine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A covered individual who is prohibited from fulfilling his or her service agreement due to that individual's decision not to be vaccinated for COVID–19 may not be subjected to the repayment provisions of section 303a(e) or 373 of title 37, United States Code, or to debt repayment collections provided for under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/176">chapter 176</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, pursuant to section 7448, 8459, or 9448 of title 10, United States Code, section 1925 of title 14, United States Code, or section 51306 of title 46, United States Code, as the case may be. </text></section> </legis-body></bill>

