<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF50B447796D467C8B4713077CBB8BB2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6759 IH: Environmental Justice Air Quality Monitoring Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6759</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish a pilot program for hyperlocal air quality monitoring projects in environmental justice communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F4875E1D205411A818D4CC011D9E6D6" style="OLC"><section id="HD7250392ADD44B3E9496AB4E67AA4DE4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Environmental Justice Air Quality Monitoring Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF96157F7B1E34AA0AE6D27FAA6F3BEB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HD700B90E0A384B5B93F7E9E3182294F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>air pollution inflicts disproportionate harm on Black people, Indigenous people, and people of color;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H000A0EA72CA24477BA6B373BB0E56354"><enum>(2)</enum><text>air quality can vary up to 800 percent from block to block within a single neighborhood;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC25773FD44A5425B877F09C0185E5314"><enum>(3)</enum><text>it is possible to identify and attribute sources of pollution based on fingerprint analysis of multiple pollutants; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H797175B30F3F42BC8874C3EC72E3E767"><enum>(4)</enum><text>existing methods that are prescribed for basin-wide air quality monitoring—</text><subparagraph id="H120F55E8E4354FFABBF6AB40D3EA0D50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are cost-prohibitive for monitoring community-scale air quality; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDC549C10BBC425897AC313D709FA481"><enum>(B)</enum><text>do not, as of the date of enactment of this Act, measure the intrinsic variability of persistently poor air quality in environmental justice communities at the neighborhood block level; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D6B116FD30144EFB87214031CE776EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Environmental Protection Agency has existing authority under the Clean Air Act to address air pollutants, including greenhouse gases.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5F6391026E784837B4E7F1269E98C08E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD38B2AFE363A4D73859B435B435E8D9E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EC4C420DCD847548B37962BD9BE849A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air pollutant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>air pollutant</term> has the meaning given such term in section 302(g) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7602">42 U.S.C. 7602(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C2F48049E644E779B528CA240B8B889"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible hyperlocal air quality data provider</header><text>The term <term>eligible hyperlocal air quality data provider</term> means an organization with the demonstrated ability to deploy hyperlocal air quality monitoring systems in support of State, local, or Tribal air agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70F4F4159DF84A17B304B9F6640BF013"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, culture, natural origin, or income, in the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws (including regulations) and policies to ensure that each person enjoys—</text><subparagraph id="H1DBFC94E3B4944E0BA2DC564D04FC984"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the same degree of protection from environmental and health hazards; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9FFA1230E3B4F9892D694FF3D5C0009"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equal access to any Federal agency action relating to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws (including regulations) and policies for the purpose of having a healthy environment in which to live, learn, work, and recreate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D4BC302C3F14764BFC60B751D4EE511"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and Indigenous communities that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects, as compared to other communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2333F15FDC4F178A6A4BAAC538F3F1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Hyperlocal air quality monitoring system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>hyperlocal air quality monitoring system</term> means a method of monitoring ambient air quality and detecting the presence of air pollutants that—</text><subparagraph id="H1C3E30482E294F30BFA2D6427BEC0152"><enum>(A)</enum><text>yields frequently repeated, ongoing measurements of air pollutants at a block-level resolution; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B13BB41AF94485D9F9DC061DDCECF7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies hotspots of persistent elevated levels of air pollutants localized to, and caused by the characteristics of, a specific geographic location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3433943484A4469DBD849D9ADC47AF49"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of that Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA64D93ACADC5499CB722A888E9F5B64B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>The term <term>pilot program</term> means the pilot program established under section 4(a).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H115DFAAA7C9B45969F23E31096708064"><enum>4.</enum><header>Pilot program for hyperlocal air quality monitoring projects in environmental justice communities</header><subsection id="H240AEC3C5E9740B181F6F616B1E0AC1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall carry out a pilot program to award, on a competitive basis, grants or contracts to State, local, and Tribal air agencies, in partnership with local nonprofit organizations or eligible hyperlocal air quality data providers, to carry out projects described in subsection (b) for hyperlocal air quality monitoring systems in environmental justice communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB12598C7755C468DBBA03FB6450E41BA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Projects</header><text>A State, local, or Tribal air agency that receives a grant or contract under the pilot program shall use amounts received under the grant or contract to carry out an air quality monitoring project within a geographical region specified by the State, local, or Tribal air agency—</text><paragraph id="H0D612B84D4944D31A74AA8F37E7D8BF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to monitor air quality at a level of discreteness capable of monitoring an area that is the smaller of—</text><subparagraph id="H2EA9364D22534CB894A4C0B367EB568D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a block; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF43A7D7BDBDD433995808DEF7B23DC40"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a 100-meter radius;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08E0CB11CD4F47929112E924BFF93B78"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify areas of persistent elevated air pollution levels above a relevant background level;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3F1185C45EA43DCA61CBE43961E037C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to regularly monitor air quality using monitoring technology that meets the data quality objectives of the Environmental Protection Agency, which may, in the determination of the Administrator, include a requirement that the technology qualify as a Federal Reference Method or a Federal Equivalent Method;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F4186528CD84C2FB76CB31443EC5AB0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to determine changes in ambient levels of relevant air pollutants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H256C1C2BA4C240A4835EAEE34D991EA4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to generate equity maps by geographical area, including generating maps using such variables as demographic data relating to race, ethnicity, and income level; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B9DAA6092D742A9BB8B328DE69A0F91"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to report hyperlocal air quality data and mapping tools to—</text><subparagraph id="H227226A7B88348A8AEB106AFEA148A95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community residents through an online platform to increase public awareness and engagement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C082B1B37124171A1CEC484014A5365"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relevant local, State, Tribal, and Federal air pollution managers to inform management decisions, such as the placement or relocation of stationary air pollution monitors, transportation or land use planning, investments in mitigating air pollution sources, and other planning decisions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56D2AE147678443598AD3E3E20957038"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Project selection</header><paragraph id="HB42F3D83A3114193AA60EEEAC7B505E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>A State, local, or Tribal air agency seeking a grant or contract under the pilot program shall submit to the Administrator an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Administrator may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E7C97397D864A36B7557CF0C7EAE0C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text>In selecting projects to receive grants or contracts under the pilot program, the Administrator shall give priority to projects that—</text><subparagraph id="H5BD34B6539AC4ABDA48566A94EB0E23E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would be carried out in areas with high rates of illness associated with exposure to air pollution, as determined by the Administrator, including childhood asthma, adult asthma, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease, heart disease, chronic bronchitis, and cancer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA757DE61D134712868D484294EF580D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to identify pollution sources through multipollutant analysis when relevant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CAA4E943B1648C0B5C2C65DA4A5E9DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>would be able to assess pollution burdens on sensitive individuals who may be at greater risk of adverse health effects from exposure to the air pollutants to be monitored as compared to the general population; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32F7144C2C4A4622AF0590ADCB12E9D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>would promote—</text><clause id="HBFE7BC2A1DED43BA938C00F7DA4CF6C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>public access and transparency of data; and</text></clause><clause id="H23599CAD87EC48D2A8CAB76E16021F95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>proactive outreach for community engagement and awareness.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC3255EF597D45E3B4A28B958425C4DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Equitable funding distribution</header><text>A State, local, or Tribal air agency that receives a grant or contract under the pilot program shall ensure that air quality monitoring projects deployed using amounts from the grant or contract—</text><subparagraph id="H7F5A641CF116411F8FA511F2AD4D2FA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide full-time, salaried employment opportunities, with benefits, to local residents of environmental justice communities, which may include employment or training for positions such as—</text><clause id="HE3E2E84D466044B3875B6682A69338FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>air quality monitoring device installation, maintenance, and calibration technicians;</text></clause><clause id="HAD92D5688FFB4ADBB1CB44B49F890DF9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data scientists, atmospheric scientists, chemists, epidemiologists, and social scientists;</text></clause><clause id="HD92133F638654BBD8F2294E093556955"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>software developers, engineers, and interface designers;</text></clause><clause id="HB183DEDE202F48A7B2F7781CDE796563"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>community engagement and communications and outreach specialists; </text></clause><clause id="HADB35E78E4504B94A866DAEB7BBA349D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>air quality monitor operators;</text></clause><clause id="HE8F478C6F53142198F1338DAD693C600"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>environmental justice organizer; and</text></clause><clause id="H387834CA50B048BD88CB946D9E7C87A5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>environmental health advocate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A7CFAD485E84C3AB906CE38DD93DF6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>direct not less than 40 percent of the amount received from the grant or contract toward the employment opportunities described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8FCD392B0D847D5BE152243C2404B7A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Wage rate requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not withstanding any other provision of law, all laborers employed under projects funded directly by a grant or contract provided to a State, local, or Tribal air agency under the pilot program shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on projects of a similar character in the locality, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Davis-Bacon Act</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA5D35ED1B2074099ACB7A2AC1C64C161"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A project carried out using a grant or contract awarded under the pilot program may not exceed 5 years in duration.</text></subsection><subsection id="H88A57ED2AEE5475A9A732B07F189BED0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation metrics</header><text>To evaluate the effectiveness of the pilot program, the Administrator shall establish, based on the project requirements described in paragraphs (1) through (6) of subsection (b), metrics and reporting requirements for grant recipients.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDFD43206457B494487E1A574679DA4E3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HBBEAE948255B40C3A738019DB1CFE9B4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the end of each fiscal year in which the Administrator carries out the pilot program, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the pilot program for the previous fiscal year, which shall include, with respect to the fiscal year covered by the report—</text><subparagraph id="HB0193282EF7F4FE98F62F3FF0C81000F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of each project awarded a grant or contract under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC795E2792D614040B9FE7D4EE10126B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the evaluation metrics established under subsection (f);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CD3A00F2D9C41BA946A1415D3361E0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the results of and the insights developed from the monitoring carried out under projects for which grants or contracts were awarded under the pilot program; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DE708F8F49C4043A46C88631644901B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the Administrator proposes to continue air quality monitoring at the locations monitored by projects for which those grants or contracts were awarded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B68BB7CE4F47609E75DF883004CCF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the final project carried out using a grant or contract awarded under the pilot program is completed, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report that describes the results of the pilot program, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H1D9E8E6183364E0FB6FE392FFF4B8E97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D19FE80FF6D4AA4B432AD6C18982FCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the air quality monitoring data collected under projects that received grants or contracts under the pilot program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA550348D8704EFEB6818746DBE314AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of the effectiveness of the pilot program using the evaluation metrics established under subsection (f) and information received from the reporting requirements established under that subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44980BAAD8114419962F3E2436DA7ECE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the benefits and costs of the pilot program, including an estimate of the benefits and costs of making the pilot program permanent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF88368175EBB4CB6AF285B106D93B245"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an estimate of the cost of expanding the pilot program to monitor air quality in air basins that are adjacent to air basins for which air quality was monitored under projects that received grants or contracts under the pilot program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21373C4001204E79B9B1AE474199F23F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such recommendations for legislation, regulation, or administrative action as the Administrator considers appropriate, including recommendations for—</text><clause id="H55BF2AB89625415899D53C0583FD9AF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reducing air pollution burdens in identified hotspots; and</text></clause><clause id="HD1EF06D5B36D427D809B86F8E3943389"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>extending the pilot program or making the pilot program permanent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E46C402CF4D4D3EB8DC19F9E5BEC22F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H79BAD32E1FD34C2D93332DE15C9136BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027 to carry out the pilot program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1351528B8FE14725AEEE27F896DE7A16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Amounts made available under paragraph (1) shall supplement, and not supplant, other amounts made available to address harms resulting from air pollution.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C4F038EABED40449DB54B52A064276B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as altering, limiting, revising, or weakening existing Federal law to protect public health or welfare from air pollution.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

