<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC9DDE768101345B48FF1094CDD7BCF91" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9373 IH: To provide that the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall not issue an interim or final rule that includes an area closure in the South Atlantic for species managed under the Snapper-Grouper Fishery Management Plan until the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is complete and the data related to that study is integrated into the stock assessment.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9373</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221201">December 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall not issue an interim or final rule that includes an area closure in the South Atlantic for species managed under the Snapper-Grouper Fishery Management Plan until the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is complete and the data related to that study is integrated into the stock assessment.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6F6CA1917254BAA9AFF4C6CAF9FD74E" style="OLC"><section id="H26B700E39E0D49EE9F8B1685D65E3853" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Conditions for Rules related to certain area closures</header><subsection id="H3D1A98BBE8784F93AE60AC4EDD31C167"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6EF010F9F2E54C258C30EF41480414BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Fishing is a major economic driver in the South Atlantic. In Florida alone, recreational anglers provide $14,000,000,000 in economic output and support 119,000 jobs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A23DD29BCCF45388C2EBD620B8D0093"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Red snapper is a highly prized and sought after reef fish by both recreational and commercial fishermen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F44F1E781D442D98AE6E5B5E8CF6634"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The 6-day recreational red snapper season in 2018 added $13,000,000 to the gross domestic product of the South Atlantic region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE3B3BB51EA045F5BED9D65348F31DF9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For the last 10 years, fishery managers have successfully been working to rebuild the red snapper stock in the South Atlantic. There is currently record high abundance and strong recruitment within the stock.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FE71E947E244BF8BD421C1E48F5D158"><enum>(5)</enum><text>This record abundance has led to increased out-of-season encounters and discards which is driving red snapper mortality.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43DCCB4316B1490196E0ED2CC2C18B84"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Despite these increased discards, it is the overriding opinion of the South Atlantic Fishery Management Council’s Snapper Grouper Advisory Panel that based on members’ collective on-the-water experience, the red snapper fishery is recovered.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4665FD6B24314E59940F244FC78BBA4F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">However, options for future consideration to reduce out-of-season encounters and red snapper mortalities include shorter seasons and broad area closures for the snapper-grouper fishery in the South Atlantic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H371C20FB0B714D369360908B023BA977"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State of Florida is concerned with the economic implications of area closures for the South Atlantic snapper-grouper recreational fishery.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85773772A0CB4F7AA0367BCA022763D0"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,100,000 has been invested in independent survey data over the last three fiscal years, including $3,300,000 for the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count to estimate the number of red snapper (Lutjanus campechanus) in the South Atlantic waters from North Carolina to Florida.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCCBDBAC2DDB49289F1BE80841747516"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Marine Fisheries Service should incorporate data from this survey into the National Marine Fisheries Service stock assessments as expeditiously as possible to better inform fishery management decisions. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H675E9497321F4B8B88A8C9E32B2E3DE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Condition on issuance of rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall not issue an interim or final rule that includes an area closure in the South Atlantic for species managed under the Snapper-Grouper Fishery Management Plan until—</text><paragraph id="H2F011CF7D66F461C93A10C9D67053EF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the South Atlantic Great Red Snapper Count study is complete; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E143E3F64E542DBAAA6DE14C9277F61"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the data related to that study is integrated into the upcoming South Atlantic red snapper research track and operational stock assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

