<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H1A3AEF82ADB843B0A5D9BE7E381A9AC6" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1" star-print="first-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 496 : Ukraine Religious Freedom Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 496</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To oppose violations of religious freedom in Ukraine by Russia and armed groups commanded or otherwise supported by or acting on behalf of Russia.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H494F6D41D90A4E94A639ACF8ED13AD75" style="OLC"><section id="H9EECB25D153E44DF8771353850369786" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ukraine Religious Freedom Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB6E13131671942ACA5CD657775CF1F74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HE2A70E8141DE475EA7163ED6FBD1A06C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to never recognize the illegal, attempted annexation of Crimea by the Government of the Russia or the separation through the use of military force or recognition of independence of any portion of Ukrainian territory; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF10F8E494A7E4B89AC0D3D7D1EEAC596"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to consider any alien who, while serving as an official of the Government of Russia, was responsible for or directly carried out particularly severe violations of religious freedom in the sovereign territory of Ukraine that Russia illegally occupies, controls, or recognizes as independent, including through non-state armed groups and illegal entities it commands or otherwise supports or which act on Russia’s behalf, to have committed particularly severe violations of religious freedom for purposes of applying section 212(a)(2)(G) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)(G)</external-xref>) with respect to any such alien.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDEDF143526EE4F2DB63C293F8F423450"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of Russia as a country of particular concern for religious freedom</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of making a determination of whether to designate Russia as a country of particular concern for religious freedom under section 402 of the International Religious Freedom Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6442">22 U.S.C. 6442</external-xref>), the President shall consider any particularly severe violation of religious freedom in the territory of Ukraine that Russia illegally occupies, controls, or recognizes as independent, including through non-state armed groups and illegal entities it commands or otherwise supports or which act on Russia’s behalf, during the period of time that is the basis for the determination and designation, to be a particularly severe violation of religious freedom that the Government of Russia has engaged in or tolerated.</text></section><section id="H35FC21D971E24C11B9743C59ADE5793E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220427" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 27, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

