<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H789A6EA986B44F44980209742871CAE6" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6064 : To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine for a review of examinations, furnished by the Secretary, to individuals who submit claims to the Secretary for compensation under chapter 11 of title 38, United States Code, for mental and physical conditions linked to military sexual trauma.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6064</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220519" legis-day="20220517">May 19 (legislative day, May 17), 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine for a review of examinations, furnished by the Secretary, to individuals who submit claims to the Secretary for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for mental and physical conditions linked to military sexual trauma.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H456DCDA890784655B7CC81144461C4B3" style="OLC"><section id="HB2C7882D323B4199858C879362F5BD5A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Independent review of assessments by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs of mental and physical conditions linked to military sexual trauma for purposes of awarding disability compensation</header><subsection id="H8FBF4A64289D413193BF4E111ABD6CEA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall seek to enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (in this Act referred to as the <quote>National Academies</quote>) to perform the services covered by this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1833EB890936415594D7156BD3840AB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comprehensive review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under an agreement between the Secretary and the National Academies under this section, the National Academies shall conduct a comprehensive review of examinations, furnished by the Secretary to individuals who submit claims to the Secretary for compensation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, for mental and physical conditions linked to military sexual trauma (in this Act referred to as <quote>MST</quote>), for the purpose of assessing the impairments of such individuals arising from MST. The review carried out pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="HABDECF61BB1E4F6A9039082112971701"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination of the adequacy of tools and protocols used by the Secretary to provide examinations described in this subsection, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE5EB5025BE8C44B2A223CD3EC15B4A74"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Disability Benefits Questionnaires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2072780A42EB42DF8AE9B08D739E66D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department’s schedule of rating disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED0537771B63436BB0CC7AA45E29939E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consideration of whether certain conditions linked to MST should require referral for both a mental health examination and a physical health examination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C65AEF1C61B45579A5F9EBBBEB6C720"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the necessity of internal pelvic examinations to diagnose certain conditions linked to MST, and whether alternatives to such examinations could be considered if a veteran objects to or cannot complete such examination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7546F03B7504A52B09EA4E18604A901"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination of what credentials and training are necessary for a health care specialist or provider to perform such examinations related to physical conditions linked to MST, for men and for women, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEDFCB12E388E4137BADC37D63DC1B82D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>sexual dysfunction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41349632FB0748C2AFC8B98879292D85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pelvic pain;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07C19963B48B49E5B604A1510778D508"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pelvic dysfunction; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB5C4D3819E64262A000D9070F62B971"><enum>(D)</enum><text>musculoskeletal disabilities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97911F2AFB9142C1A69B46B8E51FCE34"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cardiovascular conditions (including stroke).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H002EF4FFDE834664AB899E6A324A74AB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination of what credentials and training are necessary for a health care specialist or provider to perform such examinations related to mental health conditions linked to MST, for men and for women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CAB7B30A28B47BF92BA95A0023A7CA2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the quality of MST training for individuals who perform such examinations, including recommendations for improvements to such training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6F05BCB191C4D82973C3981980D00F2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H4959FE3DD328457D8B71A2E9C4046B8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report of the National Academies</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date on which the Secretary enters into an agreement under subsection (a), the National Academies shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the comprehensive review conducted under subsection (b). Such report shall include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="H112B09F91BEE49F4BA65B7DAC4E8E45E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The findings of the National Academies under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46B271B36D594420BE06F640C88CBAEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations of the National Academies regarding legislative or administrative action to improve of the adjudication of claims described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB760696435D746F58A2C9373A942D731"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report of the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after submission of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the plans of the Secretary to carry out any action based on the findings and recommendations of the National Academies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220518" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 18, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

