<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0B3373F52FD149D99D250D71624C98DF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8057 IH: Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8057</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to implement policies to end preventable maternal, newborn, and child deaths globally.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H59576F6FB17C434EAF3CF74FD906C4D6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H76660FC5EC834CB4983FE32EF195DB64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEC86700501F94BB089BE6F6401EEB4E2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assistance to end preventable maternal, newborn, and child deaths globally</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end of chapter I of part I the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H699F90C9C5D34082B167B96C0A2CDF6C">
<section id="H4A46F361319846B480A84CF22A1BD463"><enum>138.</enum><header>Assistance to end preventable maternal, newborn, and child deaths globally</header>
<subsection id="HAE0948A5999C4BAD88DC337F8168843C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to implement a strategic approach for providing foreign assistance in order to end preventable child and maternal deaths globally by 2030.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD52F7A46FB8349F599D6BA8961C89B32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H96F40DDC6706463A9A95586041548B5F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF6217994B8B478FA16EAD482B5926A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H251DAA6B1BB247318D854F8019933136"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5CCC675E59844E6D98787BC77FCE8E9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H76939C66D3104215B96166F1754D5E42"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text>The term <term>Coordinator</term> means the Child and Maternal Survival Coordinator designated under subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H319210CC94B04570A9D8587C6E12A375"><enum>(4)</enum><header>International maternal and child health and nutrition programs</header><text>The term <term>international maternal and child health and nutrition programs</term> means all programs carried out using funds appropriated or otherwise made available for international maternal and child health and nutrition that are managed by the Bureau for Global Health, missions, or other operating units of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H02C37D9973334651927A2CE01A795BCE"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Most vulnerable populations</header><text>The term <term>most vulnerable populations</term> includes adolescents, populations in conflict-affected or fragile areas, indigenous populations, religious minorities, individuals with disabilities, and the poorest quintile in urban and remote locations. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB0E9985446F42F988BA4F08391778AD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Priority countries</header><text>The term <term>priority countries</term> means countries that have the greatest need and highest burden of child and maternal deaths, taking into consideration countries that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HBE32FE4A1F87481B9F15F38FCE1C074F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have high-need communities in fragile states or conflict-affected states;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F8B342DC9284EC58B0987C409CA860F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are low- or middle-income countries; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB657B39384254F28B6602239D0099F12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are located in regions with weak health systems. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDCFDA49C13746A9948ED2075B3DC462"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Relevant partner entities</header><text>The term <term>relevant partner entities</term> means each of the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H8C49DC4D33984AA2A948141B0654BD7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The governments of other donor countries.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4187EEB5B1F14C65B732670EB7675B3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>International financial institutions.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H798E08C46F5A49B9872499C25607E0A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Nongovernmental organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0145E115E4D4A99AAD178826FF40E42"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Faith-based organizations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H294D3040CC3340BA9D7F59FA4269597D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Professional organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC142E4635783475ABD5F1167E96256A5"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The private sector.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9ACE3AC6D00D476D94F1B3A0DAD88797"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Multilateral organizations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D1D7D90E0824E7190D247230AFE3161"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Local and international civil society groups.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7FFA8676E22D446AB580FAB882DE4ACF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Local health workers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE6E35DB10CF4E9ABDF56583C7D4C340"><enum>(J)</enum><text>International organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H464F74A884D0426E91BF5F86D1920FC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States, in partnership with priority countries and relevant partner entities, to establish and implement a coordinated, integrated, and comprehensive strategy to end preventable child and maternal deaths and ensure healthy and productive lives by—</text> <paragraph id="H5F3501DA5C19412199C235B5B1FD4A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>focusing on bringing to scale the highest-impact, evidence-based interventions that address the leading causes of maternal, newborn, and child mortality in each priority country;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFD07091650BA4F07BD563D9DB01E02BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring equitable access to essential health services for the most vulnerable populations, with a focus on country and community ownership;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF68AEF436C944388BF63E6516DA66FB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>designing, implementing, monitoring, and evaluating programs in a manner that enhances transparency and accountability, increases sustainability, and improves outcomes in priority countries; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H203885AE566A4F1192766DE2FE937E25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supporting the research, development, and introduction of innovative tools and approaches to accelerate progress toward ending preventable child and maternal deaths.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB8E63E28FB2453A95799BC601E4EFA6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Strategy</header> <paragraph id="H9B47FBE79AD14E92955849A6A7A07A04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2022</short-title>, the President should establish and implement a comprehensive 5-year strategy (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>strategy</quote>) to contribute toward the global goal of ending preventable child and maternal deaths by 2030 as a foundation for ensuring healthy and productive lives.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D82CF0A7D28467793D190F4AF05B424"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>The Administrator, in coordination with priority countries and relevant partner entities, shall lead the establishment and implementation of the strategy. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D80F64F377C4560B7D1440F3F82687D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy should—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1A1128E598154F3BA0BA0844F68FC26C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify priority countries in which the United States Agency for International Development will implement international maternal and child health and nutrition programs to reduce maternal, newborn, and child mortality and improve health outcomes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBAAFE1A4ADBB47C4A279544BF8342244"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to each priority country, identify the most significant barriers to maternal, newborn, and child survival and establish outcome-based targets from which progress toward addressing those barriers through international maternal and child health and nutrition programs can be tracked;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8A87C87FBEB64950AD87678EDC0AA291"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in coordination with relevant partner entities, outline how the United States Agency for International Development will implement the highest-impact, evidence-based interventions for reducing maternal, newborn, and child mortality and expand access to quality services through community-based approaches to achieve the outcome-based targets established under subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3AFBD3F51A6408E8F3342E82E89D322"><enum>(D)</enum><text>promote investments in community-based activities that empower women, support voluntarism, and provide respectful maternity care;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H869F4377D7054E228B6DCF0DFEF796F1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>describe how the most vulnerable populations in each priority country will be targeted and reached with highest-impact, evidence-based interventions to reduce maternal, newborn, and child mortality;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBA715B4330F4C9B80B405D4325498E3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>use United States Government strategies and frameworks relevant to improving maternal, newborn, and child health;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5B79B6A24B14C31A95A034B8F0666E2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>address backsliding on access to and demand for essential health services and other key challenges affecting maternal, newborn, and child survival caused by the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA861F52914B49E999CCA33D7B748113"><enum>(H)</enum><text>include development and scale-up of new technologies and approaches, including those supported by public-private partnerships, for research and innovation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H087F994282D345748CFE2F8431A5B266"><enum>(I)</enum><text>promote coordination and efficiency within and among the relevant executive branch agencies and initiatives, including the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of State, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the National Institutes of Health, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the Peace Corps, the Department of the Treasury, the Office of the Global AIDS Coordinator, the President’s Malaria Initiative, and the United States International Development Finance Corporation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA81B814A7C3D41CC83993385257E252B"><enum>(J)</enum><text>project general levels of resources needed to achieve the objectives stated in the strategy; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBE71E27E12514549803D5E705834CDDE"><enum>(K)</enum><text>support the transition to domestic sustainably financed health systems, emphasizing partnerships that seek to ensure affordability, accessibility, quality, and delivery of health services in an equitable and sustainable manner.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H333F4658DE7643F0AE55217296297ADC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Development of strategy</header> <subparagraph id="H3BDFAE4B4D43452B8208DDB5F29DF26A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consultation by Administrator</header><text>The Administrator shall consult with missions of the United States Agency for International Development in priority countries, civil society, and implementing partner organizations to inform the development of the strategy. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H98419B424EC44E4CBFAD9C8E8171DF46"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Local consultation; summary</header><text>The missions of the United States Agency for International Development in priority countries shall consult with relevant partner entities and submit to the Coordinator a summary of such consultations to inform the development of the strategy. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE09DCE0FE89C4E79A7256E5138202B26"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Establishment of Child and Maternal Survival Coordinator</header> <paragraph id="H273C41AEC8744D2FAC43F47065F58DA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President should designate an individual, selected from among employees of the United States Agency for International Development serving in career or noncareer positions in the Senior Executive Service or at the level of a Deputy Assistant Administrator or higher, to serve concurrently as the Child and Maternal Survival Coordinator. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0F00772115D3479886EE6B52120C6132"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Coordinator should—</text> <subparagraph id="HA46475E4BB704A58811A964748720746"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversee— </text>
<clause id="H0E50D6980D1E43B485319A8388390E2B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the strategy established under subsection (d)(1); and</text></clause> <clause id="HB41545CA40024B7B9D082F2E2DB06047"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>international maternal and child health and nutrition programs, including by representing the United States at international and multilateral maternal and child health and nutrition organizations;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBB84F0ACBE094F45A5D599666D976049"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have primary responsibility for the oversight and coordination of all resources and international activities of the United States Government appropriated or used for international maternal and child health and nutrition programs, as determined appropriate by the Administrator; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE5E99EB4DE24809AD392C246408A7E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>direct the budget, planning, and staffing to implement international maternal and child health and nutrition programs for the purpose of ending preventable child and maternal deaths;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H24D523C4753F4292BC9D471034551EC1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>lead implementation and revision of the strategy established under subsection (d)(1) beginning 5 years after the date on which the strategy is released;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7266DE7E9C34C87BC7DB04D264398A5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinate with relevant executive branch agencies, priority countries, and relevant partner entities as appropriate, to carry out the strategy established under subsection (d)(1) and to align current and future investments with high-impact, evidence-based interventions to save lives;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H979BFE111392452E9A4FE1BDF53A3774"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide guidance on the design and oversight of grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements with nongovernmental organizations (including community, faith-based, and civil society organizations) and private sector entities for the purpose of carrying out the strategy established under subsection (d)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7A9A5CDB6054FF0A36150687FCF468A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>report directly to the Administrator regarding implementation of the strategy established under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C45120115934C42B00E60910C73CA2C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restriction on additional or supplemental compensation</header><text>The Coordinator shall receive no additional or supplemental compensation for carrying out responsibilities and duties under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H07BE70D3CABF44FEB7239ABAAC591A29"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authority To assist in implementation of the strategy</header> <paragraph id="HF45AD2F8550D49D2AFD04CE35ECD5418"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may provide assistance to implement the strategy established under subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H29A805DC69C7489F9FE09DE29722E63A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Focus on impact</header>
<subparagraph id="H2362190E615B4525AB2D8F0AC03953BA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Targets for implementation required</header><text>Consistent with the guidelines established under section 3 of the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394c">22 U.S.C. 2394c</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/191">Public Law 114–191</external-xref>), the Administrator shall require United States Agency for International Development grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements, for the purposes of the strategy established under subsection (d)(1), to include targets for implementation of high-impact, evidence-based interventions and strengthening health systems, as appropriate, including baseline measurements from which to quantify progress.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E5742B990AF4C6184CF80837F170271"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>In exceptional circumstances for which the Administrator determines that the inclusion of targets described in subparagraph (A) is not reasonable or practicable for a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, as the case may be, should include an explanation of the omission and explicitly state how measurable impact will be targeted and tracked.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA59413E38E324820ABE298E76E45D1A8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Annual reports</header>
<paragraph id="H393E2FEF54A84D4586AC94936302B775"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Reach Every Mother and Child Act of 2022</short-title>, and annually thereafter until December 31, 2030, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on progress made to achieve the goals set forth in the strategy established under subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BA9A11BC76842A0AA8E70469B426F32"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information included in reports</header><text>Each report required by paragraph (1) should include the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HBE48CFCFEB77450C922CA4A5C16B38C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Indicators used by the United States Agency for International Development to monitor and evaluate progress of international maternal and child health and nutrition programs toward ending preventable child and maternal deaths in each priority county, such as the standard foreign assistance indicators of the Department of State and such other indicators as the Coordinator considers relevant. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F75D099D3514F75ABBB3E09CCB5DB57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Estimates of maternal, newborn, and child deaths averted as a result of international maternal and child health and nutrition programs.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H17C12C8B00E44AD6B5332066DF31AD99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Data pertaining to populations served by international maternal and child health and nutrition programs, disaggregated by gender, age, and wealth quintile.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88A704CB03FA494D89348D7B02BFD406"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A description of targets for coverage of interventions and services in international maternal and child health and nutrition programs and progress toward meeting those targets.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB34984D65FD04016BA620ED985B6D3B0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Reporting on each aspect of the strategy established under subsection (d)(1).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB88EEF04B566483F84329B07F47B8E51"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Information on funding for international maternal and child health and nutrition programs overall and for each priority country, including funding that has been planned, appropriated, obligated, or expended for the fiscal year in which the briefing is conducted and the previous 5 fiscal years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H587B96BACF6A4669AEE1C857FDF5CF0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The President shall make each report required by paragraph (1) publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC7E02D94FB534A4FAC4F3A69C2025899"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds appropriated or otherwise made available to carry out activities under this section shall be subject to all applicable restrictions under Federal law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

