<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H26702FDCF54449D8AD96F0373D9D34A5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7960 IH: Citizen Vote Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7960</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Real ID Act of 2005 to include citizenship status as part of the minimum requirements with respect to a driver’s license and identification card issued to a person by a State, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H9EFA70B68BFB42EB9B46379BBF686B73" style="OLC">
<section id="H22AA07276D0B41C1BA610D3ACD1E7FBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Citizen Vote Protection Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HEE59FE558EB14B2B96CAAD483131F947"><enum>2.</enum><header>Use of photo identification</header> <subsection id="HBEAE8F33132F4BDFA1CC9F306D74E249"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings; Sense of Congress</header> <paragraph id="HC65D3BEB815B4D66A78FEEF7B68B45A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HA3B43E050F9247FC824A01B952F62033"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Photo voter identification programs established by the States should be administered without unlawful discrimination and with an eye toward balancing appropriate access to the ballot box with election integrity and voter confidence goals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF53151D0387348A8BEF3FA7E828EB9A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>As confirmed by the bipartisan Commission on Federal Election Reform (commonly known as the Carter-Baker Commission), <quote>[v]oters in nearly 100 democracies use a photo identification card without fear of infringement of their rights</quote>.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H186B332A023F46C4B0C1B335D1AB5DFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>As confirmed by the Carter-Baker Commission, “[t]he right to vote is a vital component of U.S. citizenship and all States should use their best efforts to obtain proof of citizenship before registering voters.”.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE29675C6F08847C4BFDA9DB6339E40A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Carter-Baker Commission was correct in its 2005 report when it recommended that the REAL ID Act be <quote>modestly adapted for voting purposes to indicate on the front or back whether the individual is a U.S. citizen.</quote>.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H74BB4811B2F04AECAD30A127D8073B10"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress acknowledges the important work completed by the Carter-Baker Commission and, by amending the REAL ID Act, resolves the concerns in the Commission’s report that <quote>[t]he REAL ID Act does not require that the card indicates citizenship, but that would need to be done if the card is to be used for voting purposes</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99EDA425709B44FC977076B99F1A6E3A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Photographic voter identification is important for ensuring voter confidence in election processes and outcomes.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3DEEDF9F57D649A88772F2295E743615"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Requiring photographic voter identification is well within States’ constitutional competence, including pursuant to the Qualifications Clause of the Constitution of the United States (article I, section 2, clause 2), the Presidential Electors Clause of the Constitution (article II, section 1, clause 2), and the Seventeenth Amendment.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8F1D02A181E4D15B6BA211E6E2245CA"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fifteenth Amendment, the Nineteenth Amendment, the Twenty-Fourth Amendment, and the Twenty-Sixth Amendment, among other references, make clear that the Constitution prohibits voting by non-citizens in Federal elections.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCBEBC27967B34F7FAC0DD2A2AA610F97"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress has the constitutional authority, including under the aforementioned amendments, to pass statutes preventing non-citizens from voting in Federal elections, and did so with the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4BA1BAC66DD4BE780531DE890F26497"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress may further exercise its constitutional authority to ensure the Constitution’s prohibition on non-citizen voting in Federal elections is upheld.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB6272D889C0445449622DFBC3C040E2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the States should implement the substance of the recommendation of the Carter-Baker Commission that, <quote>[t]o ensure that persons presenting themselves at the polling place are the ones on the registration list, the Commission recommends that states [encourage] voters to use the REAL ID card, which was mandated in a law signed by the President in May 2005</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H59172526FF50432D8C252153D1001947"><enum>(b)</enum><header>REAL ID Act Amendment</header> <paragraph id="HDE2C4BF4F9F5420FAAB7BEF01310051B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202(b) of the Real ID Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/49/30301">49 U.S.C. 30301</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3A6685A2002F4FA4A6AD22FA7FD534A3" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<paragraph id="HE54ABEABCE4347B1B5AFC517661D158D"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the person is a citizen of the United States, an indication of that citizenship, except that no other information may be included with respect to the immigration status of the person.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H992605E3DD2B49E7B70020A9EF65F755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this subsection shall be effective January 1, 2026, and shall apply with respect to any driver’s license or identification card issued by a State on and after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HACADCDA63D374C4DBC225AA051B090F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section or in any amendment made by this section may be construed to establish or mandate the use of a national identification card or to authorize any office of the executive branch to establish or mandate the use of a national identification card.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

