<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAC43315E426D4FEF92E8DA621CD27776" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6728 IH: American Offshore Worker Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6728</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act to provide for an exemption to the manning and crewing requirements for certain outer Continental Shelf vessels, vehicles, and structures, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEBFFC895189E45A5ACA90962E710CC85" style="OLC"><section id="H8B2DF9180C6642B9B55FE00E53B4645B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Offshore Worker Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4F4DE511DDB14F648CBC3344F33252D3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Manning and crewing requirements for certain outer Continental Shelf vessels, vehicles, and structures</header><subsection id="H232E0177C594409599E4652DC2AA2A9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of limited exemptions from manning and crew requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30(c) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1356">43 U.S.C. 1356(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6F809D1E96974667A2CAD7A0D2F50AF8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(C), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H861DE27E3E1B42E4AF0E1C135031DED8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(c)</enum-in-header></header-in-text> The regulations issued under subsection (a)(3) of this section</quote> and all that follows through <quote>to any vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure if</quote> and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8FA4FDAB789249ADAB43FC97DFE9C53D"><subsection id="H1BFE8611B2B240A6BB245DC7A1AB1053"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><paragraph id="H7A5606AAD4544A52B95BFD2891759EFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The regulations issued under subsection (a)(3) shall not apply to any vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure if</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E7B0CA75AC94307A4E018666BB573EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H4C17F009D107447BA3EF1E2ECFA37D0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the exploration, development, or production of oil and gas</quote> and inserting <quote>exploring for, developing, or producing resources, including nonmineral energy resources,</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CC5AFD7BCA8447EA38FE08CA0FBE5E4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(2) </enum-in-header></header-in-text>to any vessel</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51FFF13486774227862A65A1334C70FC"><paragraph id="H6B135EF2DF5540318CCD56F3A2A87DCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exemption for certain foreign-owned vessels, rigs, platforms, and other vehicles or structures</header><subparagraph id="H0FF3F7A7A96948E9A439395C589B7188"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to the requirements of this paragraph, the regulations issued under subsection (a)(3) shall not apply to any vessel</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4E91F0BE15A4767B0CC04CA4BC3FE36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8356CE47968042BBA9B50D1A69D9ECFD"><subparagraph id="H9E518DD423374054A1682050E9DB59AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>An exemption under subparagraph (A) shall be subject to the condition that each individual who is manning or crewing the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure is—</text><clause id="HCBDAC313F731402C8B934E74F2212A9A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a citizen of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H1AD33569D7E444E9A7D680FA6BB24F29" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence; or</text></clause><clause id="H07423A607D994D229C53C181986F27CA" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a citizen of the nation under the laws of which the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure is documented. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD52D2557A0974438942AB8632C34EECC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An exemption under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="HCEF0EE159E554B489F75D6A9CF5F08FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall provide that the number of individuals manning or crewing the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure who are individuals described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subparagraph (B) may not exceed 2.5 times the number of individuals required to man or crew the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure under the laws of the nation in which the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure is documented; and </text></clause><clause id="H102844DAC7364B5DA7EAA23072F11D75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (D), shall be effective for not more than 1 year. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F1170C983C74BC9A321AC04B563D131"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application</header><clause id="H874657C9596544309E860A47027771C4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The owner or operator of a vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure described in subparagraph (A) may submit to the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating an application for an exemption or a renewal of an exemption under that subparagraph. </text></clause><clause id="HF325123830F14563977ACE5F6B5F2BF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application under clause (i) shall include a sworn statement by the applicant of all information required by the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating for the issuance of the exemption. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D5925917EEC425F88F4F8CA1A000E43"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Revocations</header><clause id="HDDE4EBF6585D423D9535E1B0FF6313C6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may revoke an exemption for a vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating determines that information provided in the application for the exemption—</text><subclause id="H299A392DF53A43E5B25A87DF4A9C046B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>was false or incomplete; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE1C5C11CFE3D4DD29B484F50989F3EDA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is no longer true or complete.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4EE24AB037A647B4982AD3859107B63A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Manning or crewing violation</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall immediately revoke an exemption for a vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating determines that, during the effective period of the exemption, the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure was manned or crewed in a manner that—</text><subclause id="HE4BF87EB631644F2B534221F910A13EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>was not authorized by the exemption; or </text></subclause><subclause id="H5DE0E490758D45729446126F4222B82B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not otherwise comply with this paragraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCF15DD5DB4884FC3AEC21CD7B78AE488"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall provide notice of a determination and revocation under clause (i) or (ii) to the owner, operator, agent, or master of the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F817D767F374C61993E78668B006BD7"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Review of compliance</header><clause id="H1373482EF6B14DC891BE887A58817186"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall periodically, but not less frequently than annually, inspect each vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure for which an exemption under subparagraph (A) has been granted to verify the compliance of the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure with this paragraph. </text></clause><clause id="H538A76C08E3242E08C5EC2D73D7D4086"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>During each inspection of a vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure under clause (i), the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall require all individuals who are manning or crewing the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure to hold a valid Transportation Worker Identification Credential. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF45B62313B3045EBB74E6ACA7F9F2536"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Civil penalties</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may impose on the owner or operator of a vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure for which an exemption under subparagraph (A) has been granted a civil penalty of $10,000 per day for each day the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure— </text><clause id="H6B8E243EEDBF4824AEB6F3D438117500"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is manned or crewed in violation of this paragraph; or </text></clause><clause id="H16C1FF6ECE034D6E898CD25F1CEDC008"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>operates under the exemption, if the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating determines that—</text><subclause id="H39C5F10F6BC64C439F6AF9595F80FFD3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the exemption was not validly obtained; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF0FB36CBFA9044DBBF0DDCF5DBC969D2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>information provided in the application for the exemption was false or incomplete. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2116498DD2FE468CACFEE83DA51B884C"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Notification of Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall notify the Secretary of State of each exemption issued under this subsection, including information on the effective period of the exemption.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0769B2BA8F344A52964CA7BFEC2C739C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall promulgate regulations that specify the application requirements and process and other requirements for an exemption under subsection (c)(2)(A) of section 30 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1356">43 U.S.C. 1356</external-xref>) (as amended by subsection (a)). </text></subsection><subsection id="H1DC8928DC78649AEABBA7805DAC462D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing exemptions</header><paragraph id="H98BC711C87AE438D8AA095B1FEA0258C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 120-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, each exemption granted under section 30(c)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1356">43 U.S.C. 1356(c)(2)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) before the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H177F8ED83AE24A228D4EB8F1784EB88C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall remain in effect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8EDB3EBE4194AF4B81C1C82E2EED69C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall not be affected by the amendments made by subsection (a). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B092E5810B8490798AB860333894819"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>On the day after the last day of the period described in paragraph (1), each exemption described in such paragraph shall terminate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E7B631DE104489B24E4E6B678B7718"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall notify all persons that hold an exemption described in paragraph (1) that the exemption will terminate in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2E0FD5A163546C39BA81052A5AADBC9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H607BB1126BB940639AB619558817764A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall submit to Congress a report that describes the number of exemptions granted under subsection (c)(2)(A) of section 30 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1356">43 U.S.C. 1356</external-xref>) during the preceding year. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47BD9494C2C64B998D6501B35E55E6F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall list for each vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure granted an exemption during the preceding year—</text><subparagraph id="H32699D2084A241C59F31475D6EFB2B6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and International Maritime Organization number of the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2C372182FE54870BE1257CFA9BAE1FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the flag of the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63DA46D4E9734E1B8E94D48E78641FEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the nationality of the 1 or more owners of the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC57178DA70848C7AF215A4C69E51CA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any changes to the information described in subparagraphs (A) through (C) applicable to the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure if the vessel, rig, platform, or other vehicle or structure has received a prior exemption under subsection (c)(2)(A) of section 30 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1356">43 U.S.C. 1356</external-xref>) or section 30(c)(2) of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1356">43 U.S.C. 1356(c)(2)</external-xref>) (as in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

