<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H38B8B3C5BA7B4320A1FD9F555441C85E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9190 IH: Presidential Accountability for Yearly Submission of The United States’ Budget Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9190</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221018">October 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 31, United States Code, to limit the use of Federal funds for the salaries or expenses of political employees if the President’s annual budget submission to Congress is late, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC2FC1D6FBA5F4763AB82749F877B4815" style="OLC"><section id="H2FE43021BDD342F4A5BA781CAC670BD2" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Presidential Accountability for Yearly Submission of The United States’ Budget Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PAYSTUB Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDEDFDA35E97E4CF9874EBD57AB1585D7" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limitation on use of Federal funds for political employee salaries and expenses if President’s budget is late</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2D835D91C94E4F499018F8BEC325EDB7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H0964D333B2004E8BAC045CE7FAC5DDA5"><enum>(j)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HFEE747CA0EB3422FA19F424CE20E385F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>If the budget under subsection (a) is not submitted to Congress on or before the first Monday in February of a year, during the period beginning on the first Tuesday of February of such year and ending on the date the budget is submitted, no Federal funds may be obligated or expended for the salary or expenses of any political employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE352B111F61B43F8B1D49FDA9A900BCB" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each political employee whose salary and expenses are not paid by operation of paragraph (1) shall be paid for the period the limitation under such subsection was in effect at the employee's standard rate of pay, at the earliest date possible after such period ends, regardless of scheduled pay dates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06440AA0BA3546DF9D9C7E7919FDDA01" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>political employee</quote> means any individual—</text><subparagraph id="H476A0D259D734DE09D1D9C21707E7D72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>occupying a position described under sections 5312 through 5316 of title 5 (relating to the Executive Schedule);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0604AC9E2F54B64974BD797186A0743"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serving under a noncareer appointment in the Senior Executive Service, as defined under paragraph (7) of section 3132(a) of such title; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BE9A0155B684CBCB3A2A6664EA7EF72"><enum>(C)</enum><text>occupying a position in the executive branch of the Government of a confidential or policy-determining character under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

