<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF171EAABFDB747358868FB61D7057A75" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9310 IH: Preventive Services Early Action Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9310</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to give the United States Preventive Services Task Force the authority to take early action based on scientific evidence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD1685545E53473CB0960F0648EFA05C" style="OLC"><section id="H089DD2682D1F4629B99021A93A301FCA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventive Services Early Action Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H04DCD66650474AA5B160F12E3BEFAF6F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Changes to United States Preventive Services Task Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 915(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/299b-4">42 U.S.C. 299b–4(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0ABD25EF6287405F87182E1583D632A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H8E57E8434D764F7F875DF2CD033CEC0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E9C05A0B509424D969FCDDB91428607"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F23783A2A2145CA9AABE69220FA86DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H209EEFF0F1C64513B4ED61A4D1FCC757" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H98CAABDD01DA461E838474E79CAA023C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the publication of quarterly reports on the Task Force’s website identifying—</text><clause id="H9A2D1B53F7B44462ADE01E12BD81B071"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of clinical preventive recommendations of the Task Force with respect to the scientific information described in paragraph (4)(B); and</text></clause><clause id="HE5EC55FDB10B4E4AAFBF9C6227659546"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a list of topics that the Scientific Director determines are appropriate for early action as described in paragraph (5).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5132C75A41E643B18B17A93C50A20E8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (4), (5), (6), and (7) as paragraphs (7), (8), (9), and (11), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9401886AE050496DB293CD0D5F150AE6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>after making such redesignations, by inserting after paragraph (3) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HAF48D6CA4A00426F9C6B02642124B6AA" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H8331708061934488A4594E9189551CE4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Ongoing review of scientific evidence and requests for early action</header><text>For the purpose described in paragraph (1), the Task Force shall establish and implement a process for the ongoing review of scientific evidence related to updating previous clinical preventive recommendations of the Task Force under paragraph (5) and reviewing new topics for the development of recommendations for the health care community. Such scientific evidence shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H7381C9317EC44AB7AAEE4F00E76F3899"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information from sources audited under the LitWatch process described in Appendix III of the United States Preventive Services Task Force Procedure Manual (or any successor to such process); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D9DED0D48046D29F4D80DF7A31C40F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information submitted through a public submission process, which may include evidence—</text><clause id="HDCBDEA9C6B1C4B468E6E63B094869CCB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>of the impact of clinical preventive services on populations or age groups for which such clinical preventive services do not have in effect a rating of A or B;</text></clause><clause id="H0FBD3C6C3173409DAADF39B75CCFBCEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to fill research gaps identified by the Task Force;</text></clause><clause id="H7ECD3B9B19024212B5E17E3BA4C95146"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of a new, novel screening modality or technology, preventive medication, or other preventive service not previously reviewed by the Task Force;</text></clause><clause id="HDFF70D4F247A4B3FAC6186DD51944C60"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>of health outcomes from a clinical preventive service that was previously considered but not recommended by the Task Force; or</text></clause><clause id="HEDC49265420D4CCE98F766E68D8724E0"><enum>(v)</enum><text>changes in the public health impact of a specific condition, whether in general or as such changes relate to a specific population.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC93E332EE6F4EEDA56408DC3BE135C2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Early action based on scientific evidence</header><subparagraph id="H50CAB82636C74F5BABE8931E7E129AB8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Determination by Scientific Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less than once per quarter, the Scientific Director shall determine whether the scientific evidence reviewed under paragraph (4) supports—</text><clause id="H51913A95EB63447783B1FE8DB0649A73"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">early review of a previous clinical preventive recommendation of the Task Force before the previous recommendation is subject to full review under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2); or</text></clause><clause id="H5D3EB4199C404088A2A4DADD0A4BDCD6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modification of a previous clinical preventive recommendation of the Task Force or any portion thereof before the previous recommendation is subject to full review under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33777C9D50074C068809F6CECB8D8D1B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Scientific Director shall take into consideration whether the scientific evidence involved—</text><clause id="H0307D2FF84CE4B23A0E46AD9415E9CD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes information on a new or novel intervention, modality, technology, population, or strategy not previously considered by the Task Force in the development of the previous clinical preventive recommendation;</text></clause><clause id="HBA16C71DB1D34B0297655B8CE8D6C17B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>helps to address a research gap identified by the Task Force when developing the previous recommendation;</text></clause><clause id="HCC924D7EE3CF479DA4A654C03C5DF492"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>relates to a previous recommendation for a preventive service or treatment of a disease or condition with a high impact on public health or with disparities in screening rates, incidence, or health outcomes linked to socioeconomic status or race;</text></clause><clause id="H98D5E51191E74FED8737DF2302359A75"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is based on the development of new technologies or modalities that would allow for easier disease detection or increase utilization of recommended clinical preventative services; or</text></clause><clause id="HBE092741F7D941A6B3944AD1388BDF54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is supported by additional sources of data for any subpopulations (including subpopulations based on gender, race, ethnicity, genetic predisposition, socioeconomic status, geographic location, or other risk factors) not considered in the previous recommendation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06EE4EDB7813453E9FC0956BA41E4A4D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Response by Task Force</header><text>If the Scientific Director of the Task Force determines under subparagraph (A) that the scientific evidence supports the need for early action, the Task Force shall—</text><clause id="H7EACDF36DF5C456FA874E2C5FCC6F26D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the scientific evidence in support of the determination at the next meeting of the Task Force, which shall be held not later than 3 months after the Scientific Director’s determination; and</text></clause><clause id="H42BD0D35DFCB4F4A9FC221469CA4540B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determine that—</text><subclause id="H411B093E1D8D409E8BB2E8DEE6A6DE03"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the scientific evidence does not support the need for early action;</text></subclause><subclause id="H51658E44B9344E65AF683B721B66DD31"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the scientific evidence supports the need for an early review of a previous clinical preventive recommendation before the previous recommendation is subject to full review under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2); or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB607DAD40D6E40EF9757585FC62DB826"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the scientific evidence supports the need to modify a previous clinical preventive recommendation or any portion thereof before the previous recommendation is subject to full review under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2), which may include recommending a new clinical preventive service, screening test, or preventive medication without reviewing or modifying the eligible population in the previous recommendation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884FAFEBD9A6484D833EC6A968EE24D3"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Early action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Task Force determines that the scientific evidence supports the need for an early review of a previous clinical preventive recommendation, as described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(II), the Task Force shall—</text><clause id="HD28896B9593C4B84AB31190642A07C63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allow for public comment on a draft recommendation; and</text></clause><clause id="H910C9930BB24498996703B7BE065908D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 6 months after such determination, conclude such early review and make a final recommendation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01C86D43B69A4453AA625105C24438A3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Modification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Task Force determines that the scientific evidence supports the need to modify a previous clinical preventive recommendation or any portion thereof, as described in subparagraph (C)(ii)(III), the Task Force shall finalize the modified recommendation not later than 90 days after such determination. Any modification approved under this subparagraph shall be in effect until the next review of such recommendation under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3A092D42E70426C906DF874977CA676"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Approval of clearance of certain products</header><text>Not later than 3 months after the approval or clearance by the Food and Drug Administration of a screening test or preventive medication that is a preventive strategy or modality pertaining to but not included in a previous clinical preventive recommendation of the Task Force, the Task Force shall determine that the approval or clearance of the product—</text><subparagraph id="H6727539DBC454DC0B7E8D2FF5456CA0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>does not support the need for early action;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F79F1A1FCC14125A382E033B349C0A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the need for an early review of a previous clinical preventive recommendation before the previous recommendation is subject to full review under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA78E742DBA143C7BD78A67239436912"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the need to modify a previous clinical preventive recommendation or any portion thereof before the previous recommendation is subject to full review under the 5-year review period described in paragraph (2), which may include recommending a new clinical preventive service, screening test, or preventive medication without reviewing or modifying the eligible population in the previous recommendation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H7676FFB8B79C4A4CA015828394DCB903"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (9), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92A4C4E7A9774D71B89D40CFB6FFA428" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HA9035C9438A245939BC172024D5D3B80"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><subparagraph id="HAE62E3BBEF9249FE8661566724D74D77"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>public submission process</term> means an online mechanism that allows any member of the general public to submit scientific evidence for review by the Scientific Director and the Task Force staff.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70009F8DFEC74F15981CABDD37AB2EDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>Scientific Director</term> means the chief physician, researcher, and technical advisor for the Task Force, as determined by the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H302C82EA435A419C9D364F8C5BB43D93"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (11), as so redesignated, to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H24CD8583151E41B2BB14E226FD0069AE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H0068D6A8EF634B01BCC6D2E9E18DA180"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each fiscal year to carry out the activities of the Task Force, of which such sums as may be necessary are authorized to be appropriated for fiscal years 2023 and 2024 to hire additional staff to carry out paragraphs (4) and (5).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

