<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE9337555E5AB42958E82096EFD18F028" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9305 IH: Justice for Local Communities and Workers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9305</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act to require employers who are ordering a plant closing or mass layoff to cover the cost of an economic impact study in each impacted unit of local government, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H997577D3EF294828BFDC0974B4EF8986" style="OLC">
<section id="H63ADE73BCBA94E39B044D8D90D525A75" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Justice for Local Communities and Workers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8D8511655EF34256B881CC3D18E34634"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2101">29 U.S.C. 2101(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H03E678EAC59A4A9C96EA1ED60525FD55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E6A6E97BCF941EAAE12A3C357319C98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, without regard to the number of employees employed within a single site of employment</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H023AA884BEB34A6F95F8997ADCB0684D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, without regard to the number of employees employed within a single site of employment</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD713CC3F62854E38BFBA395478438389" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC3F3337B21A74B6791FC9FE8976EFC59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>means the permanent</quote> and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H68FCA1F76BAA482889B68D9DA5BB8DD2" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8A4731E93CDB469CA6C345CD48E40FFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the permanent</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H74F3F81750B440B4951C0B8ABD0D3D3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as so designated by this paragraph, by striking <quote>50 or more employees excluding any part-time employees</quote> and inserting <quote>25 or more full-time employees or 75 or more full-time or part-time employees; or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEC7DD955909A46A39BDC58F4BD28AB3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9EB3B46B69F84A8F823E87727D001EE8" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H65C96BB55ECB42229923196F818AE439"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a permanent or temporary shutdown of a single site of employment of multiple employers, if such employers contract with a common employer of the affected employees and if such shutdown results in a combined employment loss during any 30-day period for 50 or more employees, excluding any part-time employees.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H44B5425C17544388A790CFA974534C9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(B), by striking clauses (i) and (ii) and inserting the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3D35851356134F56A4A500EACB4DD05F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HE631C80145AA42F2B40694CCF96C8001"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 33 percent of the employees (excluding any part-time employees); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HF4A036B1A2884CBFA8D139F3E0AD8566"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">25 or more full-time employees or 75 or more full-time or part-time employees.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H5EFC9115C785479A8113FEBE0A9A1936"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notification</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3(a) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H3ECDF0A6467B48D7B0CA8EA78BAAD8B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H67227DCD534A4D67B1A3F86C2808C472"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H10E00D8F03004DE1ACED29CCD7C377E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>the State representatives for such State, </quote> before <quote>and the chief</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H106F1DF3C85747298960278E859B8715"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3239877D09274435B1AF17A3D718597F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3FA5652002AB4795AA5A2ECBCC75EB96" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <paragraph id="H488CF7622D4C4A8E9D1F46C8A5918935"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to each Member of Congress representing such State or the Congressional district in which such unit is located.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDB8A9B74D2F548879B224AEE08985057"><enum>4.</enum><header>Economic impact study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H44A7E2043E9A41DB849876821B2C2D91" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H40163FCEF5AE466482CD2238B9EAFAC8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Economic impact study</header> <paragraph id="HCC7020E40D614B2C9DD4DCDD7590ED5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice served by an employer under subsection (a) before ordering a plant closing or mass layoff shall not be considered valid unless, not less than 30 days prior to serving such notice, the employer covers the cost of, and ensures that each unit of local government within which such closing or layoff is to occur completes (directly or through a contract), an economic impact study to assess the economic impact of such order during the 1-year period beginning on the first day of such closure or layoff on such unit, which shall include—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8332B875B63C4A029D65A69B7B889937"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a review of the finances of the employer to determine if the employer is financially viable (as such term is defined by the Secretary of the Treasury) to make the payments described in paragraph (2), which determination shall include whether the employer is experiencing economic hardship; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50368F21ECB947949AC19732537C3D79"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which an employer is not experiencing economic hardship, an assessment of direct and indirect financial losses (including impact on local businesses (such as downstream job and supply chain loss and decreases in customer base), and impact on tax revenue) that will be experienced by such unit. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H607C197C292F404F997C06AB8C223E77"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment by employer</header>
<subparagraph id="H50B8EE001A1F4C33A6343A510BE6D872"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an employer that is not experiencing an economic hardship and that orders a plant closing or mass layoff, the employer not later than 30 days prior to such closure or mass layoff, shall—</text> <clause id="HD1DB8E0D0C9E42779870D2ED9BDE2EC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>pay to the Impacted Workers Fund established under section 505 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (if such a Fund has been established) of the State in which each county is located that, in accordance with paragraph (1)(B), will experience financial losses as a result of such order, an amount equal to such financial losses to be dispersed in accordance with such section; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H9D675C82442C4B99B0669AC4B9B5A969" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a case in which the Fund described in clause (i) has not been established, pay to the workforce development system (as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)) of the State in which each county is located that, in accordance with paragraph (1)(B), will experience financial losses as a result of such order, an amount equal to such financial losses to be dispersed in accordance with such section.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5A20655E3E7143F787FD4E460A64E805"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>A unit of local government aggrieved by an employer that violates subparagraph (A), may sue in any district court of the United States for any district in which the violation is alleged to have occurred, or in which the employer transacts business.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A5E5A7575F54F36BFD2C7448962F52A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Guidance by the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Justice for Local Communities and Workers Act</short-title>, the Secretary of Labor shall issue guidance on conducting the economic impact studies. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3F4C03CC2F84CBA9FA8CACB56160DFE" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grants to cover the cost of economic impact studies</header> <subparagraph id="H81D70A9C6FAE4BDBA701A71858679E34" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall award grants to employers subject to the requirements of paragraph (1) the cost an economic impact study required under such paragraph.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H687FF091E914467EBF61A8D13711B303" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To receive a grant under this paragraph, an employer shall submit to the Secretary of Labor an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section id="HB0DD2ACC198747A1ADB58647A6C5D1BD"><enum>5.</enum><header>Administration and enforcement of requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5 of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2104">29 U.S.C. 2104</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HF06886F6C79D4E6EA3292538BAD9BB40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(A)(i), by inserting <quote>twice</quote> before <quote>the average regular</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H917EC5A0AF4B4780A15DE334F962B604"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>The remedies</quote> and inserting <quote>Except as otherwise provided in section 3(e)(2)(B), the remedies</quote>. </text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDBDA302E52DC461780FE34B4EDD2C969"><enum>6.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements to establish Impacted Workers Funds</header>
<subsection id="H4DF8E3D0C83242E28124BBCD711CC247"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3121">42 U.S.C. 3121 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 504 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF8CD5FF8D05A46F3BC01F19FE486BC82" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HC78FEBA40FC5400197C862E56EF2E524" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>505.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements to establish Impacted Workers Funds</header> <subsection id="HEF3D31270DB84CF1B8B65C8232B3FECA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive funds described in section 3(e)(2) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102(e)(2)</external-xref>) a State shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the Secretary under this section. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H98F2D56979FF4D5D8EB96BF3ED849FC2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperative agreement contents</header><text>A cooperative agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall require a participating State to—</text> <paragraph id="H413A51C92ECA49AFA67F17FE876B4950"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish and administer an Impacted Workers Fund (in this Act referred to as a <quote>Fund</quote>) to receive amounts pursuant to section 3(e)(2) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102(e)(2)</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H93BC7679D1604903AE0195DE98954F13"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that amounts deposited into the fund are used to support only the jurisdiction of the unit of local government for which such amounts are deposited (as determined by an economic impact study under section 3(e) of the Worker Adjustment and Retraining Notification Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/2102">29 U.S.C. 2102(e)</external-xref>)), including for workforce training, income assistance, and wage insurance. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HA8EE0F6170F945EF800E7E9CA20463E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3121">42 U.S.C. 3121</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after the item related to section 504 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6612C5030BF14E6E996CE1C4109879CD" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 505. Cooperative agreements to establish Impacted Workers Funds.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


