<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H3CBF2C586D2B4BE99BE422DB12AC48C1" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5911 : Fair Hiring in Banking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5911</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>May 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSBK00">Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Deposit Insurance Act and the Federal Credit Union Act to expand employment opportunities for those with a previous minor criminal offense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D556D063B034DA49EBF95F1E554A970" style="OLC"><section id="H1BF01CA206384BF0A3EDE45E7C5AABE0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fair Hiring in Banking Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5A3EA1E0C5B94FF28AF2BF084C19FFD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal Deposit Insurance Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 19 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1829">12 U.S.C. 1829</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1E215FFE42354EBA8689CE990B4F7A4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC98EE9130B4F495FB65FE5B68F4C2866" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H5594596284BD4E25A28635DB6ED11A37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HB206EC3E25754D7AB6C6DE67769EB65B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certain older offenses</header><subparagraph id="H64FFE641EBDA4F6396573384B29437DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an individual, subsection (a) shall not apply to an offense if—</text><clause id="HA4319F1ED1924D48A8C16746B9922879"><enum>(i)</enum><text>it has been 7 years or more since the offense occurred; or</text></clause><clause id="H58C75AD932FC4316A7AAB9C8CECF1B03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the individual was incarcerated with respect to the offense and it has been 5 years or more since the individual was released from incarceration.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FA3BDEDDB6F46588724757E73D473E1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Offenses committed by individuals 21 or younger</header><text>For individuals who committed an offense when they were 21 years of age or younger, subsection (a) shall not apply to the offense if it has been more than 30 months since the sentencing occurred.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62145CDAF6314D8CB9397E1CBF58011E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This paragraph shall not apply to an offense described under subsection (a)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H148D6C1AA9304157BF0384A0612D2615"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expungement and sealing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual, subsection (a) shall not apply to an offense if—</text><subparagraph id="H5F0CE0D60AB74F0EB08DB87EB9A10944"><enum>(A)</enum><text>there is an order of expungement, sealing, or dismissal that has been issued in regard to the conviction in connection with such offense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77FE65B895844B88AD093DB0E3943481"><enum>(B)</enum><text>it is intended by the language in the order itself, or in the legislative provisions under which the order was issued, that the conviction shall be destroyed or sealed from the individual’s State or Federal record, even if exceptions allow the record to be considered for certain character and fitness evaluation purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H413EAD2A6E484E9795F5E4E7D2C13738"><enum>(3)</enum><header>De minimis exemption</header><subparagraph id="HAD27575960BA44F9A9B167278F0A3CB8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to such de minimis offenses as the Corporation determines, by rule.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9DAE2A6F766442BB8877295FA0C4F5B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Confinement criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing rules under subparagraph (A), the Corporation shall include a requirement that the offense was punishable by a term of three years or less confined in a correctional facility, where such confinement—</text><clause id="H04915F7B3B714E47B0594CA6DDE9BD3D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is calculated based on the time an individual spent incarcerated as a punishment or a sanction, not as pretrial detention; and</text></clause><clause id="H8886F81CD2E64C6D920E62B819C7C7CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include probation or parole where an individual was restricted to a particular jurisdiction or was required to report occasionally to an individual or a specific location.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4998BCB07F144547B451414DDB748924"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Bad check criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In setting the criteria for de minimis offenses under subparagraph (A), if the Corporation establishes criteria with respect to insufficient funds checks, the Corporation shall require that the aggregate total face value of all insufficient funds checks across all convictions or program entries related to insufficient funds checks is $2,000 or less.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF5FF55C834D4F1796F66908C8A52719"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Designated lesser offenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply to certain lesser offenses (including the use of a fake ID, shoplifting, trespass, fare evasion, driving with an expired license or tag, and such other low-risk offenses as the Corporation may designate) if 1 year or more has passed since the applicable conviction or program entry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB97BAA1BB6E24EBBA9BC1F9FA18EB306"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3A22C9C97BB3454FB771E17C1DB6E733" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H9A54E62CE68544EC96ECDAA1106905CB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consent applications</header><paragraph id="HD245E49F982244A2A0EED73E1E229733"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation shall accept consent applications from an individual and from an insured depository institution or depository institution holding company on behalf of an individual that are filed separately or contemporaneously with a regional office of the Corporation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47A46324F746461F8A88F57E842ED1F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sponsored applications filed with regional offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent applications filed at a regional office of the Corporation by an insured depository institution or depository institution holding company on behalf of an individual—</text><subparagraph id="HC3DCCAC51DAC4003B76D9C67558F759C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be reviewed by such office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8D6527740A74CFC99619FF530C5F57E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be approved or denied by such office, if such authority has been delegated to such office by the Corporation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72AF8930E3E445068853286B564CDEF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may only be denied by such office if the general counsel of the Corporation (or a designee) certifies that the denial is consistent with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA90E792DC8984A029726B95DD93EA746"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Individual applications filed with regional offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent applications filed at a regional office by an individual—</text><subparagraph id="H58C48EA963504BE3890EAA4CF7E5CDF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be reviewed by such office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC87912CD19A04DCB9AED73D728FC8C58"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be approved or denied by such office, if such authority has been delegated to such office by the Corporation, except with respect to—</text><clause id="HD237F3A2EEF04CA1A9C17A3D2F09E8F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cases involving an offense described under subsection (a)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="HFFE1CF29A25F48879A42936018838696"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such other high-level security cases as may be designated by the Corporation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FBE9F4E31C34234A2472D758E44017F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National office review</header><text>The national office of the Corporation shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2343E23AC2D04883B97F5FEBEB9977D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>review any consent application with respect to which a regional office is not authorized to approve or deny the application; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E44479B3B34463BB20657693829ACF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>review any consent application that is denied by a regional office, if the individual requests a review by the national office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC39AE1220334F448F04CA12C8072ADD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Forms and instructions</header><subparagraph id="HF368D68FD53A4C8CB5BB35B81358B942"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Corporation shall make all forms and instructions related to consent applications available to the public, including on the website of the Corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4BD9CCFD514486DACC3D007ED445A40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The forms and instructions described under subparagraph (A) shall provide a sample cover letter and a comprehensive list of items that may accompany the application, including clear guidance on evidence that may support a finding of rehabilitation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H996EB00026DE469FA8F8E8331F1D0639"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Consideration of criminal history</header><subparagraph id="HD32543CE3767479598713C14050113B7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regional office consideration</header><text>In reviewing a consent application, a regional office shall—</text><clause id="HFD7F7B61240349AABB6AE7B0BDD6607E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>primarily rely on the criminal history record of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</text></clause><clause id="H31BDC34EBCE7418CA182DFFFF14148E1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provide such record to the applicant to review for accuracy.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AB73958C12D4ADC963B931B8D7584EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certified copies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation may not require an applicant to provide certified copies of criminal history records unless the Corporation determines that there is a clear and compelling justification to require additional information to verify the accuracy of the criminal history record of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF7E1997BB044BF963E26EE17BE5B7B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Consideration of rehabilitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>), the Corporation shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5D1068ABA80241BA86BB226C06004D76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an individualized assessment when evaluating consent applications that takes into account evidence of rehabilitation, the applicant’s age at the time of the conviction or program entry, the time that has elapsed since conviction or program entry, and the relationship of individual’s offense to the responsibilities of the applicable position;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD6D5BAFDDF44CD990CEDA96B5BFAEF6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consider the individual’s employment history, letters of recommendation, certificates documenting participation in substance abuse programs, successful participating in job preparation and educational programs, and other relevant mitigating evidence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8ED47A7DFFB44FB98E8050CCA57742C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider any additional information the Corporation determines necessary for safety and soundness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4600891DE074664BED1EA4409D62F21"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Scope of employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an approved consent application filed by an insured depository institution or depository institution holding company on behalf of an individual, if the Corporation determines it appropriate, such approved consent application shall allow the individual to work for the same employer (without restrictions on the location) and across positions, except that the prior consent of the Corporation (which may require a new application) shall be required for any proposed significant changes in the individual’s security-related duties or responsibilities, such as promotion to an officer or other positions that the employer determines will require higher security screening credentials.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB424246A09044249AB5F663E9AAC66E6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Coordination with the NCUA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Corporation shall consult and coordinate with the National Credit Union Administration as needed to promote consistent implementation where appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H387A334FF24F41ECAAF894AED4A25DAE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H29B1E10F1303449F8ACBBC049C135BAB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>consent application</term> means an application filed with Corporation by an individual (or by an insured depository institution or depository institution holding company on behalf of an individual) seeking the written consent of the Corporation under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF65E50694DBC46E69BF73F7F0EDE4628"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criminal offense involving dishonesty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>criminal offense involving dishonesty</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HEE5DE8171D65415D9F9AD8DBB00FC57B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an offense under which an individual, directly or indirectly—</text><clause id="H99A8BCC684D44E3C89A6BBD185EB00D5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>cheats or defrauds; or</text></clause><clause id="H418247E191434A5FAC3D52DE3C465A0E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>wrongfully takes property belonging to another in violation of a criminal statute;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EA490C2BC314051888A8F72FE74D6FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an offense that Federal, State, or local law defines as dishonest, or for which dishonesty is an element of the offense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58DCB7A1E2E54354AEF93045BC194F33"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H911AE1F5E8934C2CAB5551520CE4FC5F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a misdemeanor criminal offense committed more than one year before the date on which an individual files a consent application, excluding any period of incarceration; or</text></clause><clause id="H8F024BAE575A4A78B45089D427D3C663"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an offense involving the possession of controlled substances.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56A0EC2D3E5143349045A4F429439471"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pretrial diversion or similar program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pretrial diversion or similar program</term> means a program characterized by a suspension or eventual dismissal or reversal of charges or criminal prosecution upon agreement by the accused to restitution, drug or alcohol rehabilitation, anger management, or community service.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H0CBDDC54E68A4CADB40393DA5B07FE1A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Credit Union Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 205(d) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1785">12 U.S.C. 1785(d)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC3709428B1504878BA112E7DEF764E37" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6AA50E40D8524AD1BB3B7C3F97B72DDA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="H4B394DEF9E68451893F298605C596DAF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Certain older offenses</header><clause id="H9D2727DC529242729AA148726074BAF6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an individual, paragraph (1) shall not apply to an offense if—</text><subclause id="H66CECE1D663B4EB6BE7A663A5A64F569"><enum>(I)</enum><text>it has been 7 years or more since the offense occurred; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H59C7CDD655F2405C8C17E534EB71C498"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the individual was incarcerated with respect to the offense and it has been 5 years or more since the individual was released from incarceration.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8CAE8ECDD4444CD683F01EA00C213603"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Offenses committed by individuals 21 or younger</header><text>For individuals who committed an offense when they were 21 years of age or younger, paragraph (1) shall not apply to the offense if it has been more than 30 months since the sentencing occurred.</text></clause><clause id="H61294EE083444C7993C068C34A747E60"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>This subparagraph shall not apply to an offense described under paragraph (1)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A70911EA0AD4B709F5B7271BE3B4B37"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expungement and sealing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an individual, paragraph (1) shall not apply to an offense if—</text><clause id="H04B0F1C1F77A44BC951BE0C70CE3BA55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>there is an order of expungement, sealing, or dismissal that has been issued in regard to the conviction in connection with such offense; and</text></clause><clause id="HB3F2F007331343C8AE78598869B9EBF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>it is intended by the language in the order itself, or in the legislative provisions under which the order was issued, that the conviction shall be destroyed or sealed from the individual’s State or Federal record, even if exceptions allow the record to be considered for certain character and fitness evaluation purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6169D89DA40C4DF0A6FDEAE9F7D3F4EF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>De minimis exemption</header><clause id="H1446FA05306F472BB4D7CEAA507E491F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to such de minimis offenses as the Board determines, by rule.</text></clause><clause id="H1E1477D0F94B43929565656BD5574A9D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Confinement criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing rules under clause (i), the Board shall include a requirement that the offense was punishable by a term of three years or less confined in a correctional facility, where such confinement—</text><subclause id="H0D83D62261AD44A6979F00DDF4DA43D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is calculated based on the time an individual spent incarcerated as a punishment or a sanction, not as pretrial detention; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HBE40CB9AB934481E844B0B5C9170973F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>does not include probation or parole where an individual was restricted to a particular jurisdiction or was required to report occasionally to an individual or a specific location.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB5E1504A96634A548686DBDD92816642"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Bad check criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In setting the criteria for de minimis offenses under clause (i), if the Board establishes criteria with respect to insufficient funds checks, the Board shall require that the aggregate total face value of all insufficient funds checks across all convictions or program entries related to insufficient funds checks is $2,000 or less.</text></clause><clause id="H3DB90CA970B44924BAE3D8033BD92AB1"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Designated lesser offenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to certain lesser offenses (including the use of a fake ID, shoplifting, trespass, fare evasion, driving with an expired license or tag, and such other low-risk offenses as the Board may designate) if 1 year or more has passed since the applicable conviction or program entry.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H700CE36B0D144860B732E451018D895E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consent applications</header><subparagraph id="HA402641F2AB44506A42D7647307378CB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board shall accept consent applications from an individual and from an insured credit union on behalf of an individual that are filed separately or contemporaneously with a regional office of the Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE709342889EE44BD94683065EE8E94F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sponsored applications filed with regional offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent applications filed at a regional office of the Board by an insured credit union on behalf of an individual—</text><clause id="H53B625A046304AD28996F93D023DA7F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be reviewed by such office;</text></clause><clause id="H628F5DBDE0704FF1AB2168D358BDCBB4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be approved or denied by such office, if such authority has been delegated to such office by the Board; and</text></clause><clause id="HA2002A610F3E409497504B693751A39C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>may only be denied by such office if the general counsel of the Board (or a designee) certifies that the denial is consistent with this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB79B5B6269C44D84BA5AD81DC78CEA6E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Individual applications filed with regional offices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consent applications filed at a regional office by an individual—</text><clause id="H006C52E1315D45AE851B77A530A6F016"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be reviewed by such office; and</text></clause><clause id="H32E8F34AC8124AF09D2CA83872A03F49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be approved or denied by such office, if such authority has been delegated to such office by the Board, except with respect to—</text><subclause id="H3948E91D3CB14C47B8B152633EE4814D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cases involving an offense described under paragraph (1)(B); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4741F99D009E4BD2A55F7303AE9BBA87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such other high-level security cases as may be designated by the Board.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE9EAB68D8A14271AC71BFA2181C1A93"><enum>(D)</enum><header>National office review</header><text>The national office of the Board shall—</text><clause id="HDEED0BCFF2CA444990AC309044AE3F1D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review any consent application with respect to which a regional office is not authorized to approve or deny the application; and</text></clause><clause id="H6312690F901E46E39F36B8D2679B59EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>review any consent application that is denied by a regional office, if the individual requests a review by the national office.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CEF4E33ECE941E9B811AA431FAAA9CC"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Forms and instructions</header><clause id="HDB82D42061994DA8AC9F8F02BA120CB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Board shall make all forms and instructions related to consent applications available to the public, including on the website of the Board.</text></clause><clause id="H9AFBFD76F6774254A13DB3DCE7CA0F80"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The forms and instructions described under clause (i) shall provide a sample cover letter and a comprehensive list of items that may accompany the application, including clear guidance on evidence that may support a finding of rehabilitation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF10EC877820E4FF98AF4BEAB4895691F"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Consideration of criminal history</header><clause id="H6378D4198A4747648AA1978FFE813C52"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regional office consideration</header><text>In reviewing a consent application, a regional office shall—</text><subclause id="H25F13DA36EB34305BC8DA0DC4AE49FDE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>primarily rely on the criminal history record of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H21F42EBBBE3A45ED8B9972BBB21A2013"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide such record to the applicant to review for accuracy.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H37D60FCF24ED42B1A3D12D74B5BAF590"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Certified copies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Board may not require an applicant to provide certified copies of criminal history records unless the Board determines that there is a clear and compelling justification to require additional information to verify the accuracy of the criminal history record of the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30CA5BD2D3214128B61AEFE763FF0D1A"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Consideration of rehabilitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consistent with title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000e">42 U.S.C. 2000e et seq.</external-xref>), the Board shall—</text><clause id="H57B390339FEF4A7181CD406FB55AAC8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct an individualized assessment when evaluating consent applications that takes into account evidence of rehabilitation, the applicant’s age at the time of the conviction or program entry, the time that has elapsed since conviction or program entry, and the relationship of individual’s offense to the responsibilities of the applicable position;</text></clause><clause id="H7A651E60ECFA4B9E8EDA4FD9E4F62CAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> consider the individual’s employment history, letters of recommendation, certificates documenting participation in substance abuse programs, successful participating in job preparation and educational programs, and other relevant mitigating evidence; and</text></clause><clause id="H48756DC91F5846A4A7D937D7847F4559"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider any additional information the Board determines necessary for safety and soundness.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29B9CB5982CC42E597942AAB0682E93C"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Scope of employment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an approved consent application filed by an insured credit union on behalf of an individual, if the Board determines it appropriate, such approved consent application shall allow the individual to work for the same employer (without restrictions on the location) and across positions, except that the prior consent of the Board (which may require a new application) shall be required for any proposed significant changes in the individual’s security-related duties or responsibilities, such as promotion to an officer or other positions that the employer determines will require higher security screening credentials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD0C3F5BE78F472DAAED18F30759C547"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Coordination with FDIC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this subsection, the Board shall consult and coordinate with the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation as needed to promote consistent implementation where appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4D5D54CF6AE465189CB60F9F8F3AD03"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H62144AA31DD84ADE946D7487EE60B67B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Consent application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>consent application</term> means an application filed with Board by an individual (or by an insured credit union on behalf of an individual) seeking the written consent of the Board under paragraph (1)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1499A5727297418EA88A555F87104462"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Criminal offense involving dishonesty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>criminal offense involving dishonesty</term>—</text><clause id="H7ABCFF1B89FE43238BDADE9CAFEF5EB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an offense under which an individual, directly or indirectly—</text><subclause id="H16D557D826FE41379F625E11EA617C31"><enum>(I)</enum><text>cheats or defrauds; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF9115F59852940B5A907DE4B3D0C0695"><enum>(II)</enum><text>wrongfully takes property belonging to another in violation of a criminal statute;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3CE14EF9F57C418C9E863BD09C13E0A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes an offense that Federal, State, or local law defines as dishonest, or for which dishonesty is an element of the offense; and</text></clause><clause id="H2DE357DCBC614D529460E2CB9FFF50BC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not include—</text><subclause id="H1BA4E9BE52584081B962E1700B2A91E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a misdemeanor criminal offense committed more than one year before the date on which an individual files a consent application, excluding any period of incarceration; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF4B81D5650814A7EA8E078CBFC91C101"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an offense involving the possession of controlled substances.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA52672F585640E59E139DABF638E9F1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pretrial diversion or similar program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>pretrial diversion or similar program</term> means a program characterized by a suspension or eventual dismissal or reversal of charges or criminal prosecution upon agreement by the accused to restitution, drug or alcohol rehabilitation, anger management, or community service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC292B51ACE0E40B8A8A9EDBAB12F0B65"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review and report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 2-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the National Credit Union Administration shall—</text><paragraph id="H3ED1C821F2B14A0D84E484F9ECABF3E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the rules issued to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act on—</text><subparagraph id="H065C449AC5FA422490B0BCC9AAA1BB55"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the application of section 19 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1829">12 U.S.C. 1829</external-xref>) and section 205(d) of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1785">12 U.S.C. 1785(d)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H281B29E7BFEF41288A8176A5FC957D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of applications for consent applications under such sections; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEB15FADF68742AC8ED9DC133C9AA190"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the rates of approval and denial for consent applications under such sections;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC543E38C416E470E8A0A6D0083A32155"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make the results of the review required under paragraph (1) available to the public; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87EF583DE0E14A2C8C5EE156CD8E3ED3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a report to Congress containing any legislative or regulatory recommendations for expanding employment opportunities for those with a previous minor criminal offense.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6C306B186F79433B89AD5E5111F9C1D7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, <pagebreak></pagebreak>provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220510" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 11, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

