<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H357C0794AAAD4993BDC62B6A2330FAB6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6798 IH: Transparency for Malign Chinese Investments in Global Port Infrastructure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6798</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of National Intelligence to submit a report on Chinese investment in global port infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC6C69D1AFBB44DBB11D5FFFCAC5B7C6" style="OLC"><section id="HE26A107663C549F49EFDEE740A269651" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency for Malign Chinese Investments in Global Port Infrastructure Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5D9A7AAAC865413DBCFC23B701BEB57B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on global CCP investment in port infrastructure</header><subsection id="H740F70EB12BB4AC0B31CC5F9419B8DA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report documenting all Chinese investment in port infrastructure globally, during the period beginning on January 1, 2012, and ending on the date of the submission of the report, and the commercial and economic implications of such investments. The report shall also include the following:</text><paragraph id="HF1217A65B93C459F96DCE500D099E70E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A review of existing and potential or planned future Chinese investments, including investments by government entities, and state-owned enterprises, in port infrastructure at such ports.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D05D93D80B24DF998E30F71EBCD4AB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any known Chinese interest in establishing a military presence at or near such ports.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC03115B10B164EC2B0C2A63BBA51C478"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of China's current and potential future ability to leverage commercial ports for military purposes and the implications of such ability for the national and economic security of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB60C133EC07148D9B08B2B03469BE710"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex produced consistent with the protection of sources and methods.</text></subsection><subsection id="H26E612D852B5459B82A663EC5B6EAEDB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HAFC57D519C45440681439F28ACAD4B78"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A51C0002F144FE3A619E2DAFD077083"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

