<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5A27FFFBFC1549FE932AAB074A263958" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7492 IH: Protecting Innocence in Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7492</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220411">April 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Department of Education from punishing States, local educational agencies, or elementary schools for failure to implement or carry out certain Federal policies relating to sex education in elementary schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8D56DB8ECC84B5DB4362BBCDDA895FF" style="OLC"><section id="HCD167EE6564E444C997CA6FADB34482E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Innocence in Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9FC16275388C4D8496EFF9563D54C0C0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition of federally mandated sex education in elementary schools</header><subsection id="H12E9C5F5D3854867BDFA42E6E1219B40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition of certain actions by Secretary of Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education may not—</text><paragraph id="HA88F2A0E28D44FD1A4C7B6F577D77920"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require States, local educational agencies, or elementary schools to implement Federal recommendations, requirements, rules, regulations, guidance, or other programs relating to sex education in elementary schools; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11C6E7DA9CD94D24811771983BC6034D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">punish a State, local educational agency, or elementary school, including by withholding Federal funds or levying fines under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other Federal law, for failure to implement or carry out Federal recommendations, requirements, rules, regulations, guidance, or other programs relating to sex education in elementary schools.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4F740BD77134A01946D4569DF782244"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition of certain actions by Task Force on Sexual Violence in Education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Task Force on Sexual Violence in Education established under section 1314 of division W of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>) may not—</text><paragraph id="H941F2B6DFFA143C9A9C418956741FBC3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop recommendations for States, local educational agencies, or elementary schools with respect to sex education in elementary schools under section 1314(a)(5) of such Act or any other Federal law; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10142C4490584290913ED9A32BD212E2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 1314(a)(8) of such Act, assess the Department of Education’s ability under section 902 of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1682">20 U.S.C. 1682</external-xref>) to levy intermediate fines for noncompliance with title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) or the advisability of additional remedies for such noncompliance, in addition to the remedies already available under Federal law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D3437404D404AADB51FC4A339F0C6B8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act, the terms <quote>elementary school</quote>, <quote>local educational agency</quote>, and <quote>State</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

