<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA6F01C84F6D64FFEB54B8C10A8D8A6A3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6874 IH: American Energy for Europe Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6874</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220228">February 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a program to reduce the reliance of allied European countries on natural gas, petroleum, and nuclear fuel produced in Russia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA794ED9BDDB14AE4A4182DF5B9E5A809" style="OLC"><section id="H293F6E07979348B3B72B22052E807236" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Energy for Europe Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEF532E82B46A45C6B44F059E3231997D" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Program to reduce European reliance on Russian energy</header><subsection id="H34C9B54F797E4BCDB92CE01334BCE010"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy shall establish and carry out a program to reduce the reliance of allied European countries on natural gas, petroleum, and nuclear fuel produced in Russia by—</text><paragraph id="HC9C663E5BB0644B9AFF2B990ABE3213A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing, producing, or procuring resources, materials, or equipment that can reduce an allied European country’s reliance on natural gas, petroleum, or nuclear fuel produced in Russia;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80BC1E41CDE14DC78B90E92FDF3B702A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing to an allied European country, under such terms and conditions as the Secretary of Energy determines appropriate, resources, materials, or equipment that can reduce the allied European country’s reliance on natural gas, petroleum, or nuclear fuel produced in Russia;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB5B8E32D9464B9E9E7538A08B75C9D7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issuing grants, loans, or loan guarantees to carry out projects that can reduce an allied European country’s reliance on natural gas, petroleum, or nuclear fuel produced in Russia; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0558A691445C46A6A612D15EBE46B837"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing technical assistance to an allied European country, as the Secretary of Energy determines necessary to reduce the allied European country’s reliance on natural gas, petroleum, or nuclear fuel produced in Russia.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8565E04C19241299D8A7C10B0679A61" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy may partner with other Federal agencies to carry out the program established under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7938ECDF90024ADAA3D27BCE4EBC9886"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To enter into agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy may enter into one or more agreements directly with allied European countries and third parties under such terms and conditions as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E008631FFF14AC9AC24BC6655FC71F1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Domestic sourcing considerations</header><paragraph id="H075D8541E4EF47CC8F4102DB18B6EB2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary of Energy may only carry out an activity described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) if—</text><subparagraph id="HA3D7E7627041468D8E94C22BD30C3068"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such activity promotes manufacturing in the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF746305B4B44DB69B204C638D6A05F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such activity relies on resources, materials, or equipment that are developed or produced in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4203D575CFD74B80871BC617E46DD61F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) of this subsection shall not apply with respect to an activity described in paragraph (1), (2), or (3) of subsection (a) if the Secretary of Energy certifies that such an activity cannot reasonably satisfy subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BC43F4A6BE34A14B769642108CFBBDA" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, a report that—</text><paragraph id="H179949D830D741279320843A01E4B672" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies any resources, materials, or equipment developed, produced, procured, or provided pursuant to the program established under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E6F66380941453F967F5935037775C7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes an analysis of how such program benefits domestic energy suppliers and manufacturers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF23BB8F0A1504DD3A8F4A7224AE3648B" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><paragraph id="HA728BC5597544C05A57A8FA5DEAAE83A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy to carry out this section $500,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H789736E4BEE342DCBFE1E569993630D6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nord Stream 2 pipeline discontinuation</header><subparagraph id="H3BA3E72B08E3431EB532A746EED47C42"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><text>In addition to the amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1), there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Energy to carry out this section $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to remain available until September 30, 2024.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA0F14D408514DCD95082936CABB8CDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts appropriated pursuant to subparagraph (A) may only be expended if the Secretary of Energy certifies to Congress that the planning, construction, and operation of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline has been permanently discontinued, including as a result of United States sanctions imposed on any person or entity responsible for such planning, construction, or operation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H723A5E93D3CA4A5687E15DE82B8BB392" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Domestic energy security evaluation</header><subsection id="HB74EE2982B004B7A9AD26BA0118B87CE" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on domestic energy security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Energy shall develop and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report that evaluates the energy security of the United States, including—</text><paragraph id="H4D3A91CAACBE4D29B3B47174624E052E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of any threats posed to the supply, transmission, distribution, or use of energy in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A751D8A04684AD3A430B6C9CB7B284D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential impact of such threats on—</text><subparagraph id="H8B6E5EDBAFD840FE8A50AAFF4CB27002"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the economy of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02AABC6711CB4B719B9C8F28E1AE1C67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consumers and well-functioning and competitive energy markets in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H57EAEB69E7894BA9B62C3994603902C9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy may consult with relevant Federal, State, private sector, and other entities, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

