<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42514BDC2E9F4487A51D908498A5FF23" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6542 IH: To require the Director of National Intelligence to submit an annual report on investment by any Chinese entity in port infrastructure in the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Director of National Intelligence to submit an annual report on investment by any Chinese entity in port infrastructure in the Western Hemisphere, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBDA2E8A93CA1499CB81F6CEFAF76A455" style="OLC"><section id="H283448009EC94A84B766072A5273DE61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Director of National Intelligence annual report on investment by any Chinese entity in covered port infrastructure</header><subsection id="H158834CFC3994D2F88F649557149AC8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following for the year covered by the report:</text><paragraph id="H0FCC3A41FBF3456591A556AF74478E4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of any covered port infrastructure in which a covered foreign entity has made or maintained an investment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD9345AFEA2C49EB8FB0ACC9257FBFCF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the capability of any such foreign entity to leverage for military purposes such infrastructure, and any implications for the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C8D83325B3A4E84B79B5A79815C0F32"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7DB111BFBCAF474F869F5B63311B1739"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE836A284D56E437CB8360D0AF8422CD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H2EEBB7465D7441A9AE444F56835C852E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15F6084FE882417C99936A37642DD40D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Foreign Relations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6592955D359485A8673CCE5801CF98A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered foreign entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered foreign entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA2591BE02E234D7C850BCCBE8089BDC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Government of the People’s Republic of China; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83BACF8CCC924DFBB0C76FA0EF1706D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity partially or wholly owned or controlled by the Government of the People’s Republic of China, and any subsidiaries of such an entity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4A772547AEC403EA04D5553BD59A3F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other entity registered in the People’s Republic of China with substantial ties to the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E777438ADBB4F149CCD2C4EF30A55C8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered port infrastructure</header><text>The term <quote>covered port infrastructure</quote> means the infrastructure, including any harbor, marine terminal, or other shoreside facility of any port located in the Western Hemisphere. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

