<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H140F4C6EAEA04E2E864F283B35AF7C50" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8383 IH: To amend the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 to improve provisions relating to the development of hydropower at Corps of Engineers facilities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8383</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220714">July 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 to improve provisions relating to the development of hydropower at Corps of Engineers facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H193AC7B35AC64D23B82CB34670495D2E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2A3A29E73D294CC7A7B026767BAEEE87" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Expediting hydropower at Corps of Engineers facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1008 of the Water Resources Reform and Development Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/2321b">33 U.S.C. 2321b</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0E9BA752154543D18DAE935688E4B43E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by inserting <quote>and to meet the requirements of subsection (b)</quote> after <quote>projects</quote>;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H21E7ED054D1E49EBA56EC83DE5951AB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC21A6C6948524937A40377D5F9A3B8F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CAA249FE62D44AF87B6C89DC89409B6">
<subsection id="H9E8BA7F2DDB44151BDB049F48A2CF0FA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of policy</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="HB8A831E058204621A72DB1F8D38A724A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that the policy described in section (a) is implemented nationwide in an efficient, consistent, and coordinated manner; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0EA6CD7F9FDB4040BB23EC4AB1DA52EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess opportunities—</text> <subparagraph id="H6789DF7C6A38452C9067E83F50CA1511"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to increase the development of hydroelectric power at existing hydroelectric water resources development projects of the Corps of Engineers; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE83A2F73B2814641B7AE5343486B8FB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop new hydroelectric power at nonpowered water resources development projects of the Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H390FCF4937D24628AEEF064A7C98EB0F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2CDF79056DE0492C8D279344A23CDA50">
<subsection id="HA16D7ED78E4A42F29574A072989FBED1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program manager for non-Federal hydroelectric power development</header>
<paragraph id="H2E9C87812F1C4BCFB6DABB26DD71AE02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>The Chief of Engineers shall designate an employee of the Corps of Engineers as a Program Manager for Non-Federal Hydroelectric Power Development (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Program Manager</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4123C2B4A864B5AAA0D72B293F8A2C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Program Manager shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HAFC96F2444E64713BA9B3726E7D61EA0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not be otherwise involved in the review of any Corps of Engineers permit to develop hydroelectric power at Corps of Engineers civil works projects; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE54B1C3B80DD437D81E121C288CDAAA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be located at the headquarters office of the Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H41392C92B77444BAAF8DA381F066E57A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>With respect to the development of non-Federal hydroelectric power at Corps of Engineers civil works projects, the Program Manager shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H1DDB8C6970924F2EB975E92E236E625B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure timely and consistent review of permits across Corps of Engineers districts and levels;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBCB4F989C393429DA4952C19BF1E928C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>answer questions within the Corps of Engineers, or facilitate communication between developers and the Corps of Engineers, concerning Corps of Engineers permits;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4CD9FCBFAF5F445995C9FCD8475FF553"><enum>(C)</enum><text>answer questions from developers regarding the permitting process of the Corps of Engineers;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFBC8025AF6354996AE14D5902F0A3881"><enum>(D)</enum><text>coordinate with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission on licensing matters;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33D37957FF0F4B3A99272DAD4AD3F9D9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>facilitate timely action on all aspects of Federal permitting required for hydropower development; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H29FA0129EB54416CAA5CEE26698F0230"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ensure that new hydropower productions are designed and operated with environmentally sustainable technologies and management plans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C09D1F3153B4BF5BF3655083A7CEF00"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Chief of Engineers shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of this subsection and subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

