<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H74E5D41ADFA6450D826E29CE4298319F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8759 IH: Bureaucrats to the Border Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8759</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220830">August 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct all specified new employees of the IRS to assist with the processing through the immigration system of aliens unlawfully present in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64005ABA5060404AA82C1DB934200E38" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD3BC515A4EA341359CD74DA1CC0B60A1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bureaucrats to the Border Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H085240BB3D8E466E9174CDBE0B83C2B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>DHS Volunteer Force renamed DHS Mission Support Force</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The DHS Volunteer Force of the Office of the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security shall be known, on and after the date of the enactment of this Act, as the <quote>DHS Mission Support Force</quote>, and any reference to the DHS Volunteer Force in any law, regulation, rule, guidance, paper, map, or other document of the United States shall be deemed to be a reference to the DHS Mission Support Force.</text></section> 
<section id="HA99A3E7004BC42C2A64A82017B50D35C"><enum>3.</enum><header>New employees of the IRS to provide support at southern United States border</header> 
<subsection id="HC9132EF277C74AC7A4419C548F002AC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall require any specified new employee of the Internal Revenue Service to complete a 30-day support detail with the DHS Mission Support Force within 365 days of the date of hire of such specified new employee. </text> </subsection> <subsection id="H76150E20982744838E0542CCC3ABCEAB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA99DA5D713BD40C39D440111795C82C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Specified new employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>specified new employee</quote> means any employee who—</text> <subparagraph id="H31CDD1E83084495FB481AEE1876B5A85"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is hired as a result of the funding increase for enhancement of Internal Revenue Service resources under clause (ii) or (iii) of section 10301(1)(A) of the Inflation Reduction Act, and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF301FA75BA404665890B5A36ACC2AFB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who meets the employment standards of the DHS Mission Support Force. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7791F18AE1B44C9B89458463F83B93E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Support detail</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>support detail</quote> means a detail with either U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement for the purpose of providing assistance at the southern border with the processing through the immigration system of aliens unlawfully present in the United States.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

