<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6A0CCB5C60104CC49FAEF5C16C2752D5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7958 IH: No Federal Funds for Ballot Harvesting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7958</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Help America Vote Act of 2002 to prohibit the use of Federal funds for the administration of an election for Federal office in States which permit ballot harvesting, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HD91E3DED6D2946F09AA5FD6FD6417268" style="OLC">
<section id="HA50BB4D8F1E2430C989C7D561EE91F61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Federal Funds for Ballot Harvesting Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H9C04C59CA36B43E7B63BE587AA33D7B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text>
<paragraph id="HAA52758684E24E37A8FEAE9974301D34"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the right to vote is a fundamental right of citizens of the United States, as described by the Constitution of the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEC5FBFD762E42A59382041001A6CF43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on House Administration of the House of Representatives, which is charged with investigating election irregularities, received reports through its official Election Observer Program for the 2018 general election and the 2020 general election, as well as from other stakeholders, that individuals other than voters themselves were depositing large amounts of absentee ballots at polling places throughout California and other States, a practice colloquially known as “ballot harvesting”;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H371DE18A6BA949539DAD69217147FB5E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the practice of ballot harvesting creates significant vulnerabilities in the chain of custody of ballots because individuals collecting ballots are not required to be registered voters and are not required to identify themselves at a voter’s home, and the State does not track how many ballots are harvested in an election;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC7A7EAFAAE6406081CDFBC2B6A2E568"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in North Carolina, a congressional election was invalidated due to fraud associated with ballot harvesting committed by a political operative, and it is unlikely such activity would have been detected were it not for the prohibition against ballot harvesting in the State;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H69B28B29081E47BEA92CA6FE3F924581"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ballot harvesting invites electioneering activity at home and weakens States’ long-standing voter protection procedures, which remain in place at polling locations, creating the possibility of undue influence over voters by political operatives and other bad actors; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5E238D5383245DC837F2330790F0E44"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Supreme Court of the United States has affirmed State authority to restrict ballot harvesting (Brnovich v. Democratic National Committee, 141 S. Ct. 2321 (2021)).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HB3BF65F42FA74D3A8B8FEA9905F38F05" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal funds for election administration for States allowing collection and transmission of ballots by certain third parties</header>
<subsection id="H52FAAC57599B41A598DADBF233045BC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Help America Vote Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/20901">52 U.S.C. 20901 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3A8849539A7944BFB751B71623E0AC92" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H69829CC3E47C4CE48CE0471880F7BE62"><enum>907.</enum><header>Prohibition on Federal funds for election administration for States allowing collection and transmission of ballots by certain third parties</header> <subsection id="H02FD039826BE42FAA5E19390AF0128AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal funds may be used to administer any election for Federal office in a State unless the State has in effect a law that prohibits an individual from the knowing collection and transmission of a ballot in an election for Federal office that was mailed to another person, other than an individual described as follows:</text>
<paragraph id="H2019DFBA2ABE42BDAD1648C9B15B05DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An election official while engaged in official duties as authorized by law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D2B80AA7B4E48819C258B4085E51B12"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An employee of the United States Postal Service or other commercial common carrier engaged in similar activities while engaged in duties authorized by law.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H703F8B6D15F14ABFBE5565D4FFFA884D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other individual who is allowed by law to collect and transmit United States mail, while engaged in official duties as authorized by law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA1B55087BE84627B79AE132F056F159"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A family member, household member, or caregiver of the person to whom the ballot was mailed.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3B6E7F1AE07E45D6A60D88B9743438E3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section, with respect to a person to whom the ballot was mailed:</text> <paragraph id="HF4CAAA9B91524CD5BD944071F2F01AEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>caregiver</term> means an individual who provides medical or health care assistance to such person in a residence, nursing care institution, hospice facility, assisted living center, assisted living facility, assisted living home, residential care institution, adult day health care facility, or adult foster care home.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5ABB6BA0E6D1402ABCE0068C690916F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>family member</term> means an individual who is related to such person by blood, marriage, adoption or legal guardianship.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E98ADA162784FAA9F6D9FB0753D1044"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>household member</term> means an individual who resides at the same residence as such person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H8B25570E2A1646FF9ED58E539610D405"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents of such Act is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1AC04987E01F4D1AACAC40F52B719379" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 907. Prohibition on Federal funds for election administration for States allowing collection and transmission of ballots by certain third parties.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

