<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8D834F147E84481985C1FC7B9528AFDE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 8605 IH: Cash Refunds for Flight Cancellations Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8605</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for cash refunds for canceled airline flights and tickets.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA12AF5B3042340809148B0F02EC40AB3" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H45BEDACDB6EF433BA4B80C4F8EE11F2D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cash Refunds for Flight Cancellations Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H197BCE85AD854F969F3D564974E695BC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cash refunds for canceled airline flights and tickets</header><subsection id="HD6091567CA6840E0926304F7C656023A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/417">Chapter 417</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF33D7113DBD4CB88A2F576D332174DA"><section id="H7BB60D6C416149B9A53AADFFC22D7230"><enum>41727.</enum><header>Cash refunds for canceled airline flights and tickets</header><subsection id="H8A51D9531C7C41F5836C4D4BCFC3FD52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cash refunds</header><paragraph id="HFCD8130C42DE4BA18FD50DA0D564F077"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><subparagraph id="H6E5246FF43904E59944381DF2F631EEF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), a covered carrier or ticket agent who sells a ticket for a passenger to take a covered flight, and either such flight is canceled or significantly delayed (as defined by the Secretary of Transportation) by the covered carrier or such ticket is canceled by the passenger at least 48 hours before the scheduled departure of the flight, shall offer the passenger a full cash refund for such ticket, including any ancillary fees paid, within 30 days of the passenger making the request. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC070596FD5ED40B2A032C8D66FD99AF6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A covered carrier or ticket agent shall only be required to offer a cash refund under subparagraph (A) for 1 flight booked by a passenger on any city-pair itinerary on any given date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C358DA3FFEA4352A4F3BA5C140037C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative form of compensation</header><subparagraph id="HA491A049FD7A47459C46B70957DBF2BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered carrier or ticket agent may offer an alternative form of compensation determined appropriate by the covered carrier or ticket agent, including a credit, a voucher, or other mechanism to compensate a passenger, provided that any such offer includes a clear and conspicuous notice of a passenger’s right to a cash refund under paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B037F79013E41088784AA81007DBBC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No expiration date</header><text>An alternative form of compensation provided pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall remain valid and redeemable by the passenger indefinitely.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H809BEBE0747040A393DF02A1CA2FB798"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retroactive refunds</header><text>In the case of a passenger who—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H41C6B0494EA94C538C721F002D479102"><enum>(A)</enum><text>received an alternative form of compensation during the period beginning on March 1, 2020, and ending on the day prior to the date of enactment of this Act for a covered flight or ticket for a covered flight canceled by the covered carrier or by the passenger; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H603E2DD7F9454EE4988030ECBF6A44BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has not fully used such alternative compensation, </text></subparagraph><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="paragraph">such passenger may request a cash refund to replace the alternative compensation, or the remaining alternative compensation if the passenger has used part of the alternative compensation, and the covered carrier or ticket agent shall comply with such request within 30 days of receiving such request. </continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5F20DC976C3423EA7FA8A109CEFC851"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reimbursement to ticket agent</header><text>A ticket agent who provides a cash refund to a passenger under this section, including a retroactive refund under paragraph (3), shall be entitled to prompt reimbursement from any covered carrier for the portion of the ticket price paid to that carrier. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C2D21BE4EED4B6E87BA54C9B4E7C5B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H8ADF80BCEF024151B2C762E59CF40205"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), a covered carrier or ticket agent may use amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the commercial airline industry in any appropriations enacted on or after March 1, 2020, in response to COVID–19 to pay for the cash refunds under subsection (a), including retroactive refunds under paragraph (3) of such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7129E080346E47C7917C3A0CF5F8F6A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A covered carrier may not use amounts appropriated under section 4112 of the Coronavirus Economic Stabilization Act of 2020 (title IV of division A of the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/136">Public Law 116–136</external-xref>)) to pay for the cash refunds under subsection (a), including retroactive refunds under paragraph (3) of such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2F90D64B6CA4776BC651804DA42A293"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><paragraph id="H961AFF0E422D418E874D30F05269655D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prior to purchase</header><text>Prior to the sale of a ticket for passenger to take a covered flight, a covered carrier or ticket agent shall disclose, in writing in written or electronic communication, that the passenger has a right to cancel their ticket at any time for any reason and receive a full cash refund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D1C5B5C293426EA91262B418CA4025"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cancelled or significantly delayed flight</header><text>In the case of a covered carrier or ticket agent who sells a ticket for a passenger to take a covered flight, if such flight is canceled or significantly delayed (as defined by the Secretary of Transportation) by the covered carrier or such ticket is canceled by the passenger at least 48 hours before the scheduled departure of the flight, the covered carrier or ticket agent shall disclose, in writing in written or electronic communication, that the passenger has a right to receive a full cash refund for their ticket.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F66B8472996445FA0F19516EFE65A28"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements for disclosure</header><text>Any written or electronic disclosure under paragraph (1) or (2) shall be in a clear and conspicuous format.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD8F7DCCB49F420181894B02B9FFF07D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5AE0AC8C15B74C4B921116BC11E65574"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Air carrier, foreign air carrier, ticket agent, and United States</header><text>The terms <term>air carrier, foreign air carrier, ticket agent, and United States</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 40102.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECD541540D4149DE97A653FBF5AF5FE7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered carrier</header><text>The term <term>covered carrier</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HC652F6F2ECCA416B8CAD58662A168410"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any passenger air carrier that had an operating revenue in 2018 that exceeded $1,500,000,000 according to the Bureau of Transportation Statistics; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3D5394D2D5F4CC6AF85BA13F16EA42E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any passenger foreign air carrier operating a flight to or from the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6A58E4BEB0084A289CECFB5CE95BF696"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered flight</header><text>The term <term>covered flight</term> means a flight of a covered carrier that is scheduled to depart from, or arrive at, an airport located in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF63D4CCBA15C4FD8A28EF14352265C11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>Section 46301 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7E8AE36CC35B49F3814A9471DFC196CD"><subsection id="H395026C219204A03ADB6D3E4E9FCE6F1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Penalties relating to cash refunds for canceled airline flights and tickets</header><text>An air carrier or ticket agent that violates section 41727 shall be liable to the Government for a civil penalty of $1,000 for each violation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0BF7F5B39878405698FCC20A2B2983AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/417">chapter 417</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBB38C158D5BC47E6B4256AB013E3E9EF" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">41727. Cash refunds for canceled airline flights and tickets.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HAD61EF553F0143D2ACF54123AAAA4FB6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

