<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H96AE87F70C6F4F2290252764B2C123CA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9534 IH: Space Safety and Situational Awareness Transition Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9534</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote space safety and provide for policy, planning, and agency roles and responsibilities for the transition to a civil space situational awareness capability of certain space situational awareness activities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4167180373FE4B13AF818E7F96E369E0" style="OLC"><section id="H1C9B4B93AFE1457990D42431F262416F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H23CC5A6D8A934B02BAB0D3129629BC60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Space Safety and Situational Awareness Transition Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Space SSA Transition Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8DE719F8DDE34D7A9B7702E8A3C4A291"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H1C9B4B93AFE1457990D42431F262416F" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8CDED742790643A9ABD9C222F30A4392" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H19B4D30370714BD7B69C79DF86BE294A" level="title">Title I—Authorization of Appropriations</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDDD3023416B14D59B2FBEEA16B5235D2" level="section">Sec. 101. Authorization of appropriations for fiscal year 2024.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF70EED02DBA54E64B0288E0DA5F09003" level="title">Title II—Policy</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA5AA80C7E92C4DD6B1E808CCCBB289BC" level="section">Sec. 201. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H63C211570E2E4027B3AD411D6E7726D3" level="section">Sec. 202. Sense of Congress on United States Government responsibility.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCEC812E89EE343B79FCE0199B685651E" level="section">Sec. 203. United States policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDECCD42A74C34FF58256CD2CFA5310F2" level="title">Title III—Transition to Civil Space Situational Awareness Capability</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAA8E232AF81447B0A612831B37159BA2" level="section">Sec. 301. Sense of Congress on need for transition.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H469B31C6B3FB49D7B7DBBD2E4DFA5D61" level="section">Sec. 302. Interagency Transition Team.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H64AEF8809600417C9206C48C5E7208AB" level="title">Title IV—Agency Roles and Responsibilities for Implementation of Civil Space Situational Awareness Transition</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8EBA7AE0AA3F4BDB8B044AF46135BC52" level="section">Sec. 401. Space situational awareness services and information.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H05B4B97D37BE4A0BAFD3F6E7351D7CF4" level="section">Sec. 402. Organizational management structure for space situational awareness services and information.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H56211358A7974BFA8B2B84CCE9F49593" level="title">Title V—Research and Development</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB4C2608CE0B34694BE5592CB64002B10" level="section">Sec. 501. Informing and improving space situational awareness.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H696DF1DA59CE4026B57142C082AF6164" level="section">Sec. 502. Research strategy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEC2FF0EF12C647248BF616F78E7E56EB" level="title">Title VI—Other Considerations</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H00375DC13F42481DB03A6D2AD2EAD241" level="section">Sec. 601. Cybersecurity plan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9FA28B25A0FA4F1BB1C3EE06A0349E1B" level="section">Sec. 602. Study on international cooperation in space situational awareness.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFD8656C2AB66495685B2E860F3E9B713" level="section">Sec. 603. Report on international data sharing agreements.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7D68057399094D0B8AAFDF812FA1D30B" level="title">Title VII—GAO Review</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC8670C3F1E11440A836ECBA7A1693537" level="section">Sec. 701. GAO review.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H8CDED742790643A9ABD9C222F30A4392"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB6FB022799E24A29B787632F93BFBE8E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10101 of title 51, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58590EA086734D099FD647A2F5D8AAC4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> has the meaning given such term in section 10101 of title 51, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7815693CEC5C4270B86256A0B8633C0E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H381A08DD944E419C8A38875F9FE6C9D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>DoD</header><text>The term <term>DoD</term> means the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD220A36053547BBA344ABB2E876EE1A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>NASA</header><text>The term <quote>NASA</quote> means the National Aeronautics and Space Administration. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93AB6E96395D49E0AC886D55532B2BFF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>NOAA</header><text>The term <term>NOAA</term> means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of the Department of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB847DFFCED6C4BB98ED4F3BD22AA6256" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB5C9BE73A74312A8B26E4D3287A304" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Space object</header><text>The term <term>space object</term> means any artificial object or system, including components or pieces thereof, orbiting or passing through outer space.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3894A6EF81444BB41AA3C805DD0EC7" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Space operator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>space operator</term> means the person or entity that has responsibility for commanding operations of a space object in outer space.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01AC1C75730F4BB1B8AA14A6EBCEDC84"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Space situational awareness</header><text>The term <term>space situational awareness</term> means the knowledge and characterization of space objects and their operational environment to facilitate decisions that support safe, stable, and sustainable space activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94CA4FE595C741BBB1C0479F0A485F02" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Space traffic coordination</header><text>The term <term>space traffic coordination</term> means the planning, assessment, and on-orbit coordination of activities to enhance the safety, stability, and sustainability of operations in the space environment.</text></paragraph></section><title id="H19B4D30370714BD7B69C79DF86BE294A"><enum>I</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><section id="HDDD3023416B14D59B2FBEEA16B5235D2"><enum>101.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for fiscal year 2024</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To carry out this Act, there is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2024—</text><paragraph id="HE089AD83EB6247628209910523B273E4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the Department of Commerce, $95,000,000; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12DB058231DA4D64A97EAC9DB8B59BD7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to NASA, $50,000,000.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HF70EED02DBA54E64B0288E0DA5F09003"><enum>II</enum><header>Policy</header><section id="HA5AA80C7E92C4DD6B1E808CCCBB289BC"><enum>201.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7EA8D2531A5543358C38F2FE96B3095B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Commercial activity in space is accelerating to meet the global demand for a growing commercial space market.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE05D5E34535A420DAC88B78D30E00DC2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Space is becoming more congested, particularly in some orbital regimes, with the number of active satellites increasing significantly over the past ten years and continuing to grow.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB43DEA4215B0440D91F93749EACC2EBF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Orbital debris ranging from sub-millimeter-sized debris to large defunct rocket bodies and inoperable spacecraft threatens the safety of orbital operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A289ED832C74E7F81062BB8BA55E585"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Space situational awareness provides the foundation for understanding—</text><subparagraph id="H3E343B8F9386463087C2BE4841F537AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>where objects, both active and inactive, are located and for predicting where satellites or debris will be in the future; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B5846DD32084DDDBB67777034FD40D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the distribution of orbital debris and the risk they pose to operational satellites and crewed spacecraft.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51DC670EFD58463F9781BF241D675759" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>United States leadership in coordinating international efforts on space situational awareness is essential for the safety and sustainability of the space environment, including human activities in outer space.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92DB789B08294B6C82CF8F81C1AD5585"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Conducting safe and responsible space operations will have a major impact on the sustainability of space activities, and in turn for the prosperity and national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5057EE6695A4EC2BEA93D296933609D"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To date, the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Commander, United States Space Command, has been providing certain space situational awareness services and information to Federal Government, commercial and international space operators, and the international community, including warnings of potential conjunctions.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H63C211570E2E4027B3AD411D6E7726D3"><enum>202.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on United States Government responsibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the United States Government, in coordination with other countries and the private sector, has a responsibility to be a good steward of the space environment. It is the further sense of Congress that the United States Government should—</text><paragraph id="H75D066A0B7B44FC99ACE3049A072A75D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead in practices and policies to maintain a safe, sustainable space environment for civil, national security, and commercial use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9ACE5FD352B45AFB9685F2D993D075F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide validated space situational awareness services and information as public goods for the purposes of promoting on-orbit operational safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD0CF59A2E184F849CEA5D184959523C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a coordinated and integrated approach to improving and delivering space situational awareness services and information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE09EFF45A3ED441FA50C5E239B704764"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">leverage, to the maximum extent practicable, commercial innovation and capabilities relevant to space situational awareness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF61FBB145BE400C9BA199B9A691E9F7" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead collaborations with international and non-governmental entities, including satellite operators and space situational awareness services and information providers, as appropriate, on space situational awareness and on best practices regarding space traffic coordination that—</text><subparagraph id="HCA260096EA214CB39CCB75B761DBE477" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the growth of commerce in space and foster a competitive United States commercial space industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC129E36DB24401EBC95294DEF67CDB8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote innovation in technology and operations while improving safety;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H219650E083454162A7E7F45BFB800AFA"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead the international community in collaborations on practices and approaches that advance a sustainable and accessible space environment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB4A817A81C4072BE1BDC5C4AC90958" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transition to the Department of Commerce certain space situational awareness services and information, including public conjunction notifications, from the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCEC812E89EE343B79FCE0199B685651E"><enum>203.</enum><header>United States policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text><paragraph id="HCA727E78A9BF4BE7B02E48DB6DE28435" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make publicly and continually available, free of direct user fees, validated space situational awareness services and information, including conjunction data messages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07D2D5053A0542778E10EDFAA2A029CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continue to enhance and improve the accuracy and precision of the services and information referred to in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10DF82D761344777888B6AEA44511740"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available to governmental and non-governmental space operators space safety and sustainability tools, private sector-led voluntary consensus standards, and risk mitigation information and practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H053F4B73FED046FAA3416E16D6A3F949"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support interdisciplinary research and development to promote space safety and improve space situational awareness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94518832B5CB493A94A55D7CAC3119C3" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support mechanisms for transitioning into operational activities the research and development described in paragraph (4);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0245D3B9991473CB6C29CEE7D06D554" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support the use, where validated and practicable, of commercial technologies, data, systems, and services that can supplement and enhance United States Government-provided space situational awareness services and information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H448B1B11891048F1B58A9F062E78BE6F" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure the Federal Government remains the United States authoritative source for United States conjunction data messages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H446411A84B9F4337A16F79B19FBE032E" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote and facilitate the development and encourage the adoption of private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices for space situational awareness; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57D9BD1AD43E43B5A9E93FCB4854C2AF" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">lead international collaborations to the widest extent possible on a framework for internationally harmonized space situational awareness and best practices for space traffic coordination.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HDECCD42A74C34FF58256CD2CFA5310F2"><enum>III</enum><header>Transition to Civil Space Situational Awareness Capability</header><section id="HAA8E232AF81447B0A612831B37159BA2" commented="no"><enum>301.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on need for transition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the DoD continues to make essential contributions to the safety of the space environment by providing space operators with services and information for managing the safe operations of United States Government, commercial, and non-United States space operations, in accordance with section 2274 of title 10, United States Code. It is the further sense of Congress that the growing number of space objects has created an increasing demand for improved accuracy and precision of space situational awareness services and information for space operators, which requires personnel and resources that are not related to the DoD’s primary mission. Therefore, it is the sense of Congress that the President should provide all necessary support to plan for an effective transition to the Department of Commerce from the Department of Defense of certain space situational awareness services and information.</text></section><section id="H469B31C6B3FB49D7B7DBBD2E4DFA5D61"><enum>302.</enum><header>Interagency Transition Team</header><subsection id="H38DD74B96E574975B9AC763DC06C235F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Administrator, shall establish an Interagency Transition Team for Space Situational Awareness (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Interagency Transition Team</quote>) to lead the planning, assessment, and transition of certain activities carried out under section 2274 of title 10, United States Code, as appropriate, from the existing DoD-based space situational awareness operations to a civil space situational awareness capability under the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3FC2A32C3C45428D9DBEEBB0B7E99A08" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leadership and composition</header><text>The Interagency Transition Team established pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HDF9A34887B5247BCBC7731F44D0D4024" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be led by—</text><subparagraph id="H5128DFE188B34429B289EAE3FF60D289"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Senior Executive Service-level official (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Team Chair</quote>) appointed by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4370DA8A7A264373A866F2566EB0001C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Senior Executive Service or Flag Officer level official (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Team Vice Chair</quote>) appointed by the Secretary of Defense; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB2B42236B304B55ABBE896716570EEF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include—</text><subparagraph id="H737980D5FCD145DA88EEAEC0FC426567"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a dedicated team of Federal Government employees from relevant Federal agencies, including the DoD and NASA, with experience and expertise in space situational awareness activities, including tracking, data processing, conjunction assessment, and space operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H206D52D5046A46769A20A5991BE4FBAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Office of Space Commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84560F3D04B140AFB5D965C8D7BCFE65"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Deputy Commander of United States Space Command; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA75E7E96EAEF4E47A0EBFA5A093587A0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commander of United States Space Force Space Operations Command.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FF385154EFA4ADDB3F9DD8B845FFCD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><paragraph id="HDC9142ADB31A42389E359B8C1EDB667C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Transition Team shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9AAC04A39029455393736F89BFA8F2A4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and support a Transition Plan (as described in subsection (d)) for the planning, assessment, and transition of certain activities, including the issuance of conjunction data messages, carried out under section 2274 of title 10, United States Code, to a civil space situational awareness capability under the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97847E292E8E40FCAE4D8AF4555075C1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, standards organizations, and private industry, promote and facilitate the development and encourage the adoption of private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices for space situational awareness;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA81493C8A70442999021AB33432E1585"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish definitions for an initial operational capability and a full operational capability for a civil space situational awareness capability; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H487165E5790E4717832B7811CAADFF86" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out an assessment of—</text><clause id="HCDD6098CF6584444A8E2522F976B376B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Government and non-government space situational awareness capabilities and needs for an initial operational capability and a full operational capability; and</text></clause><clause id="H974CF5E8A448415BB06876AE0D4B8268" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal Government and non-government best practices regarding risk mitigation and collision avoidance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1926540CCD684FFA94D1F59502D490D0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency agreements</header><subparagraph id="H14F0E4FDB20445FC9F48423BACEC2C0C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>With the Secretary of Defense</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of Defense shall enter into one or more interagency agreements providing for cooperation and collaboration related to the transition of certain space situational awareness services and information in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6134C0A479D04FAD9F35CDF2397E81E1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>With the Administrator</header><text>The Secretary and the Administrator may enter into one or more interagency agreements providing for cooperation and collaboration related to the transition of certain space situational awareness services and information in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD624AF0930B43A5B433A3E4F242D7E8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Milestones</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Transition Team shall ensure—</text><subparagraph id="HF3819FC586E74B778552C2582C130ABB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demonstration of an initial operational capability by not later than September 30, 2024; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC79AF70D7D1B49F4AA48BB2B9FD7B69D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of a full operational capability by not later than December 31, 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A02D8CD95EC496EB6618521F2F22A6D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transition Plan</header><paragraph id="H93D3798B75AB4BABB7D7DECE15A86C71" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary and the Secretary of Defense shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress the Transition Plan developed pursuant to subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEC4F1AE76914F0ABD2E929AA5A6064C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The Transition Plan shall include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="H9A65D9606C794069807E2D9A00B6A368"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A definition of an initial operational capability and a full operational capability for a civil space situational awareness capability.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4E5D33E04084585B5601C053763466A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A system architecture, including requirements for an initial operational capability, and a full operational capability, including relating to the following:</text><clause id="H376B3B6C5D7E4F0FB8FF1561D84C63FD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of the Federal Government and non-government data, observations, and analytical tools needed for such initial operational capability and full operational capability, and a description of how such data, observations, and analytical tools are to be obtained.</text></clause><clause id="HD89D832DBABC42EB9150456987E67F74" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of the space situational awareness services and information to be transitioned from the Department of Defense and any additional services and information that may be provided in accordance with section 203(1) under an initial operational capability and a full operational capability.</text></clause><clause id="HA3B6283F71BC42D1ADC8BFB2F7769254" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of criteria and methods for verifying and validating non-Federal Government space situational awareness services and information, including associated data, provided by space operators.</text></clause><clause id="H4F5B86192EF640058BF62571E2975929" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of risk assessment and mitigation support services and information that may be provided.</text></clause><clause id="HCF72ADBF28604FCDAB1BAE2321E50D43"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identification of options for an information platform or mechanism to enable innovative research, development, testing, and experimentation opportunities for commercial, academic, or other entities to support and improve space situational awareness services and information, as practicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8176CEF6832461597E702B6FA35A463" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Performance measures for the level of accuracy needed for the space situational awareness services and information to be identified and provided in accordance with subparagraph (B)(ii).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A24566F4BF246888004EB55133B40F6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the milestones and timelines for demonstrating an initial operational capability and establishing a full operational capability by not later than the respective dates specified in subsection (c)(3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1D84391B33A4B0D918D51ADE5261BB2" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An estimate of the workforce, training, infrastructure, including ground-based, space-based, and in-situ infrastructure, and annual budgetary resources necessary to carry out a civil space situational awareness capability for the next five years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF62EAB526E694789A374471F24DE0EA9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In developing the Transition Plan required under paragraph (1) of subsection (c), the Interagency Transition Team shall take into consideration any agency agreements under paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA46B77EC8CAE41F4AA51C174D3E2E3A7" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Biannual reporting</header><text>The Team Chair and Team Vice Chair shall report biannually to the appropriate committees of Congress on the progress of the transition under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F533320A4844287B6D1CB8E4E147A01" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Team Chair and Team Vice Chair shall brief the appropriate committees of Congress on the Transition Plan not later than 14 days after transmitting the Transition Plan pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7BF6036ED20543D5BFE852943D9267A1" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Private sector-Led voluntary consensus standards and best practices</header><paragraph id="H5D80BDBD0CD241B2ACE05E504FF302C4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Development</header><subparagraph id="H438CF352384646C086115CD55AECEE5A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 31, 2023, the Interagency Transition Team shall review existing private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices, promote and facilitate the development of private sector-led voluntary consensus standards, as needed, and make publicly available such voluntary consensus standards and best practices for space situational awareness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CD392667C9B439A8A578FFDD7ED041F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Transition Team shall promote and facilitate the development of the private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices under subparagraph (A) in consultation with private industry and standards organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71ED50CEA9EE472DA580AF2B039850A1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>The Interagency Transition Team shall biennially through 2028 update the private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices developed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8EB33CF1CE748F5A13612383B6A34D3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices developed and updated in accordance with this subsection should include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="HAF1C398A2C6D4E8F8747134A3D6C4CF5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Space situational awareness data interoperability and data sharing protocols.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FD5F11CD3244CEB8C8D0D699A5B1619" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Criteria and methods for verification and validation of the space situational awareness services and information described in subsection (d)(2)(B)(iii).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD903A6331A1441F59F7D3A103F591819" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Content and message format for conjunction data messages.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC17DBC3AF3804E26B66BC663FD0E00AB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Emergency response protocols after a collision event, including communication between Federal Government agencies, space operators, and other relevant entities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD40DE307B24FEDA66F7328E9C4CEFF" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other matters the Interagency Transition Team determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD32BC11DE3D4CFC8A6FBDAEF6ED4A7F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Interagency Transition Team shall terminate six months after the date of the establishment pursuant to section 402(b) of an organizational management structure for space situational awareness services and information.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H64AEF8809600417C9206C48C5E7208AB"><enum>IV</enum><header>Agency Roles and Responsibilities for Implementation of Civil Space Situational Awareness Transition</header><section id="H8EBA7AE0AA3F4BDB8B044AF46135BC52"><enum>401.</enum><header>Space situational awareness services and information</header><subsection id="HCF5FF5F8B30949218DC45941333901C8" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out section 302(c)(3) (relating to the demonstration of an initial operational capability and establishment of a full operational capability), the Interagency Transition Team shall collaborate with the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE7033A49651D4CCC94458485779DAF0C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Demonstration</header><text>The capabilities referred to in subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H0F40706A994C4DDFA604112970B61C04" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">follow the Transition Plan under section 302, as appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB65558CEB67B4778B731A2D751382EA4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make publicly available and free of direct user fees space situational awareness services and information, including conjunction data messages;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA7A0B0B43044377B9BCA483F9792687" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a digital space object identification and characterization system to organize known characteristics concerning space objects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DADE8D876FE4648B2F2A108F8A17A0C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">communicate and make publicly available the private sector-led voluntary consensus standards and best practices under section 302(h);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB9B370F600541749C4E16F005862168" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support openness and transparency, to the greatest extent practicable, in space situational awareness services and information, including conjunction data messages; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29643BAFD2A54B6CA3D4ACA10C3B8056" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out testing to—</text><subparagraph id="HF5CD215B535F4E9894C538AB3828CCB5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate the interoperability of data and observations under section 302(d)(2)(B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H640F59187F9F4102AA5489AE0A478DF8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>verify and validate such data and observations, as appropriate and practicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF97C3FD903F34832B4A3B20E7ABABB6E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate the issuance of—</text><clause id="H14BECC99216449A9A95DBBB121F3046C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conjunction data messages; and</text></clause><clause id="H4CDC77068E9F4D86BCE9B6B2C2A3440D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conjunction assessments; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C3286EF01C54AD3BDF7C44E87F82370"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue conjunction data messages.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H05B4B97D37BE4A0BAFD3F6E7351D7CF4"><enum>402.</enum><header>Organizational management structure for space situational awareness services and information</header><subsection id="H18CF2E2B6D354737931B6B95CF1E6683"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proposal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the establishment of full operational capability, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Administrator, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a proposal for—</text><paragraph id="H2BDD336AD78E4826AF0F21AC7AD08821" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an organizational management structure within the Department of Commerce for managing the activities under this title;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA32DF264654DB1979DD07AA6C69830" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transitioning to such organizational management structure the functions and responsibilities of the Interagency Transition Team under section 302 after the termination of such Team pursuant to subsection (i) of such section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B2E8ABC8C3E4DC294A7FCA5A8BF2ACA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing milestones and performance measures for such organizational management structure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC577199DCB484492895C09C67A7445D0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Organizational management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than six months after the submission of the proposal described in subsection (a), the Secretary, in accordance with such proposal, shall establish the organizational management structure referred to in paragraph (1) of such subsection, and shall appoint a Director of such organizational management structure, who shall be a member of the Senior Executive Service. The Director shall establish a schedule and budgetary requirements for such organizational management structure.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H56211358A7974BFA8B2B84CCE9F49593"><enum>V</enum><header>Research and Development</header><section id="HB4C2608CE0B34694BE5592CB64002B10"><enum>501.</enum><header>Informing and improving space situational awareness</header><subsection id="HD2978600798E475A8B3D04464782A481" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text><paragraph id="H6C9D36CE51F34278966B7A7C3BEDD1DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carry out United States Government civil research and development to inform and improve space situational awareness; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BD7329095D04CB085959EEFFD531FAC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support the transition into the full operational capability of such research and development, as practicable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26688CF05BF74FB39A9BAD05402BF182" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out subsection (a), the Administrator, as necessary, shall establish research and development programs to address areas of relevant basic and applied research and development, including research and development that will support, enable, and facilitate the transition under section 302. Areas of research and development may include the following:</text><paragraph id="HCAD14BD7D3D8421B844F31FA89007576" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Analytics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E27D382B8D44DE48107058F3C7439C9" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Space object identification.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22CD53A8FF5E4724963AB6F066704E28" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Modeling, analysis, and predictions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1984F60A672437B89031BDEA6E449EF" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Space environmental conditions and impacts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A959DB985F54E3A989DC2F5708B0065" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Risk assessment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70FD50AB29584B77A5CFEEB028E9D4EB" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Post-mission disposal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB81BB389DD5C436D88005624E145EBFA" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Orbital debris mitigation, including research and development on active debris removal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E5580CAF59C4349B19EACF1BFDDB2E3" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other areas the Administrator determines appropriate, including areas to be prioritized in accordance with the research strategy under section 502.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H117363AE474D4FD6A1CCFAC26D7F6EEC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall use competitively selected grants, contracts, and agreements, as appropriate and practicable, in addition to other competitive research and development arrangements, in carrying out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H696DF1DA59CE4026B57142C082AF6164"><enum>502.</enum><header>Research strategy</header><subsection id="H137DCDD8F99144A7A3A324F5E800F402" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than three months after the transmittal of the Transition Plan pursuant to section 302(d), the Administrator shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine to develop a research strategy to inform and improve space situational awareness. Such strategy shall provide prioritized recommendations on research and the transition of research into operations and practice, and shall include measures to monitor progress on such recommendations, as well as any other appropriate recommendations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9F457B25B88945EAA2997F91B957E9FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall transmit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a copy of the research strategy under subsection (a) and a plan for implementing any recommendations included in such strategy.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HEC2FF0EF12C647248BF616F78E7E56EB"><enum>VI</enum><header>Other Considerations</header><section id="H00375DC13F42481DB03A6D2AD2EAD241"><enum>601.</enum><header>Cybersecurity plan</header><subsection id="H62FB3BD4A6EA4E4D8802E446C02BBBBC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in collaboration with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Administrator, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall develop a cybersecurity plan for reducing cybersecurity-related threats to the Department of Commerce’s provision of space situational awareness services and information.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2AFDB52670974899A9D6D7613D62082C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>In developing the cybersecurity plan under subsection (a), the Secretary should—</text><paragraph id="HB62DE4E63F9A4C0DBE57755E71E36066" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify cybersecurity risks to the provision of space situational awareness services and information, and proposed actions to prevent and mitigate such risks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD29753E6FE134961B4EB36C34DBFAFD0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify supply chain risks and proposed actions to prevent and mitigate such risks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A9AEE69B99049C690A3500FC102700E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider any other issues the Secretary determines appropriate to ensure the cybersecurity of a civil space situational awareness capability;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30D9F71C899E410E9B89DAD00FFE426E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>seek input from stakeholders, including other relevant Federal Government agencies and private industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1706170563B94C1F8536FE6AE42A91C0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include a classified appendix, if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA311E6CA334346C2B1CD4B8CC4E957A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transmittal and briefing</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a copy of the cybersecurity plan under subsection (a) and, not later than 21 days after such transmittal, provide to such committees an unclassified briefing on such plan.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9FA28B25A0FA4F1BB1C3EE06A0349E1B"><enum>602.</enum><header>Study on international cooperation in space situational awareness</header><subsection id="HB2F895CC2FC14AF28CBC69F9B3E6C42C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Administrator and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall carry out a study on international cooperation in space situational awareness. Such study shall—</text><paragraph id="HA4338A2C1CBC4D59B7E64F01B7BE23B8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine the extent to which the United States is involved in and leading international cooperation in space situational awareness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48DDF16FBB2E42E09D2850B3C06819A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider how other countries are approaching space situational awareness, including the provision of space situational awareness services and information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECD1F0F62314435F90F5ECC6707E11FE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify the formal and informal agreements that are in place to support international cooperation in space situational awareness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF77336C31A06468791959BA394BD7820" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify how United States international relations in space situational awareness can be strengthened and cooperation improved; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06494DB50529458B9553CB8C0A273EAD" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify the barriers, including technical and policy issues, to improving such cooperation and what steps can be taken to overcome such barriers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H626886E85D2041DB9A5D7D78AA23F046" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transmittal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall transmit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a copy of the study described in subsection (a), together with a Plan for implementing any recommended actions contained in such study and for coordinating with international partners and entities on standards and sharing of space situational awareness services and information, including associated data.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFD8656C2AB66495685B2E860F3E9B713" commented="no"><enum>603.</enum><header>Report on international data sharing agreements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the status and plans for international data sharing agreements relating to the transition of certain space situational services and information in accordance with this Act. </text></section></title><title id="H7D68057399094D0B8AAFDF812FA1D30B"><enum>VII</enum><header>GAO Review</header><section id="HC8670C3F1E11440A836ECBA7A1693537"><enum>701.</enum><header>GAO review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than three years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a review of the status, performance, and progress of activities carried out under titles III and IV.</text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

