<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H92725EE9B079477BA42FFA4B5026A5B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9088 IH: Protecting Access for Hunters and Anglers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9088</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000804">Mr. Wittman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001128">Ms. Conway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000129">Mr. Valadao</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000103">Mr. Rosendale</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. Rodgers of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000668">Mr. Bentz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture from prohibiting the use of lead ammunition or tackle on certain Federal land or water under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCB2A6FE2C3194DADAB2BFB26C1267BA9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA23ED55A59644146907A2F1189148E4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Access for Hunters and Anglers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB9B3096AEC604CF28EBB3A79FD5DBB76"><enum>2.</enum><header>Protecting access for hunters and anglers on Federal land and water</header> <subsection id="H181D312A070B4744A382B6E46B3B43C4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in section 20.21 or 20.108 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), and subsection (b), the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service or the Director of the Bureau of Land Management, and the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service (referred to in this section as the <quote>applicable Secretary</quote>), may not— </text>
<paragraph id="HF18F0742C83449B391779D7B1EB3EB90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit the use of lead ammunition or tackle on Federal land or water that is—</text> <subparagraph id="HDBAF9D1F5E204541A98F559603883FCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the jurisdiction of the applicable Secretary; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7FACAD0DAA3642AFB65A4E35902A75CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">made available for hunting or fishing activities; or </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25635A7DE52F4961BCAF188B45F5E971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue regulations relating to the level of lead in ammunition or tackle to be used on Federal land or water described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H824EF371268845ED8B9550676C8C6AF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to a prohibition or regulations described in that subsection that are limited to a specific unit of Federal land or water, if the applicable Secretary determines that—</text> <paragraph id="H4221D14C270F4D36B22CDF123C339E26"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a decline in wildlife population at the specific unit of Federal land or water is primarily caused by the use of lead in ammunition or tackle, based on the field data from the specific unit of Federal land or water; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA2EC70A35F8E42558EAC1AE3AB8B89B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the prohibition or regulations, as applicable, are—</text> <subparagraph id="H1C9D1A5D51764E948ACB409631BEA4E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with the law of the State in which the specific Federal land or water is located;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HADF9A17722DF444785D399665C9C0AB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consistent with an applicable policy of the fish and wildlife department of the State in which the specific Federal land or water is located; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDF5A5AB73EEC49D5AA7AC806040883A0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approved by the applicable fish and wildlife department of the State in which the specific Federal land or water is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7D5E55B67E22494DB9541EBAFDC1DC64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal register notice</header><text>The applicable Secretary shall include in a Federal Register notice with respect to any prohibition or regulations that meet the requirements of paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (b) an explanation of how the prohibition or regulations, as applicable, meet those requirements.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

