<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA316A7EA6DCE448085EFD55F06EC4989" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8879 IH: Inpatient Psychiatric Facility Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for improvements to the Medicare prospective payment system for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE7F51D8A7515476482E1CA01D2C597D4" style="OLC"><section id="HA5E2DAD3053747E39276EB3C00E499B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Inpatient Psychiatric Facility Improvement Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H4D85F57E7CD34907885ADBF558CDB4BF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Improvements to Medicare prospective payment system for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units</header><subsection id="HA9656BF3CD774EFFBBA5A6AF23F68B59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Improvements through additional claims data information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1886(s) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(s)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAA2A36F996084A649CD9EB471F8C265C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HBC2887BCE05C43D0B78303690E169701"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Additional data and information</header><subparagraph id="H7D5A7C2640004A2289DAD10C6CA4622D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall collect data and information as the Secretary determines appropriate to revise payments under the system described in paragraph (1) for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units pursuant to subparagraph (D) and for other purposes as determined appropriate by the Secretary. The Secretary shall begin to collect such data by not later than October 1, 2023.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6905C44F754A43D1A9E0946D3E6FA8B6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Data and information</header><text>The data and information to be collected under subparagraph (A) may include—</text><clause id="HF7124AA2D5234B49A52A5B8B03C56C50"><enum>(i)</enum><text>charges, including those related to ancillary services;</text></clause><clause id="H6513569D1FCC4B31880CB6471263B22F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the required intensity of behavioral monitoring, such as cognitive deficit, suicide ideations, violent behavior, and need for physical restraint; and</text></clause><clause id="H76A9DB26DFCE43A2971F4E6867456686"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">interventions, such as detoxification services for substance abuse, dependence on respirator, total parenteral nutritional support, dependence on renal dialysis, and burn care.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3026DA7E81A94F0A804F1D31323BBE22"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Method of collection</header><text>The Secretary may collect the additional data and information under subparagraph (A) on cost reports or claims.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85184C9E5FFC47BA85179D3E942D6093"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Revisions to payment rates</header><clause id="HC45703EA7AA94694822EAFD3332748BB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the preceding paragraphs of this subsection or section 124 of the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Balanced Budget Refinement Act of 1999, for rate year 2025 (and for any subsequent rate year, if determined appropriate by the Secretary), the Secretary shall, by regulation, implement revisions to the methodology for determining the payment rates under the system described in paragraph (1) for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate. Such revisions may be based on a review of data and information collected under subparagraph (A).</text></clause><clause id="HC44C2E17DCDF429CB4A0F922710C47D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may make revisions to the diagnosis-related group classifications, in accordance with subsection (d)(4)(C), to reflect nursing and staff resource use and costs involved in furnishing services at such hospitals and units, including considerations for patient complexity and prior admission to an inpatient psychiatric facility, which may be based on review of data and information collected under subparagraph (A), as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="H343C67502E874B36B2E93B4378F698C3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Budget neutrality</header><text>Revisions in payment implemented pursuant to clause (i) for a rate year shall result in the same estimated amount of aggregate expenditures under this title for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units furnished in the rate year as would have been made under this title for such care in such rate year if such revisions had not been implemented.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCCE939194D674306BBE8B9E69FB7AC69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Improvements through standardized patient assessment data</header><text>Section 1886(s) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(s)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H6E5A7B24193D4FD094DD361E8E56520B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="HB2BC64A9D0A74F67BFD79F2F635ED16A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>subparagraph (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (C) and (E)</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7165CC564D1491BB6A3CAC925EE5E92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACB84152D28A47299143DEA1A9FD679A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF4839483F3B1432B9A6673B4D7F1B73E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC521B468A4554216B1E5501710C9A2A5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Standardized patient assessment data</header><clause id="HCB2FEEA47F9741339A096BB396DF151A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For rate year 2028 and each subsequent rate year, in addition to such data on the quality measures described in subparagraph (C), each psychiatric hospital and psychiatric unit shall submit to the Secretary, through the use of a standardized assessment instrument implemented under clause (iii), the standardized patient assessment data described in clause (ii). Such data shall be submitted with respect to admission and discharge of an individual (and may be submitted more frequently as the Secretary determines appropriate).</text></clause><clause id="H006D91661A3C4298B71A4ED8DE35078A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Standardized patient assessment data described</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the standardized patient assessment data described in this clause, with respect to a psychiatric hospital or psychiatric unit, is data with respect to the following categories: </text><subclause id="H382D96981493463AB3D61A9A105FB778"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Functional status, such as mobility and self-care at admission to a psychiatric hospital or unit and before discharge from a psychiatric hospital or unit.</text></subclause><subclause id="H79B083C7E0534AF89B79E8DCB1D8FC98"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Cognitive function, such as ability to express ideas and to understand, and mental status, such as depression and dementia.</text></subclause><subclause id="H018A9C98345A495AAF0DE0C7E552A51C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Special services, treatments, and interventions for psychiatric conditions.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8C6EA483861B4DA19CF10856147B62D1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Medical conditions and co-morbidities, such as diabetes, congestive heart failure, and pressure ulcers.</text></subclause><subclause id="H849B9E9BBCAC41F0B52C12D08062F1AD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Impairments, such as incontinence and an impaired ability to hear, see, or swallow.</text></subclause><subclause id="HE41218B47B814D59A55B38AB40B105E0"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Other categories as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF6F1BCBCDDE74420983A87A90BE7BEF8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Standardized assessment instrument</header><subclause id="HD13B6EFB69A342E488AD2C88866DC56E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of clause (i), the Secretary shall implement a standardized assessment instrument that provides for the submission of standardized patient assessment data under this title with respect to psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units which enables comparison of such assessment data across all such hospitals and units to which such data are applicable.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6F77E983CDAD44219778AE0331140EAF"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide for the transfer, from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under section 1817 to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services Program Management Account, of $10,000,000 for purposes of carrying out subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96EAA405FB604B5DBBFA4D483B291D0A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), as redesignated by subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, by striking <quote>subparagraph (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (C) and (F)</quote>; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE62F414143C04A9A90B0F2FD4B17A930"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB26428CE744545869AF2AF25B250F99B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H12AD6166CBAF44E080930793F29AB16B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Additional considerations for diagnosis-related group classifications</header><subparagraph id="H2AEE09909EDD42DAAF001DC0AC7C4E34"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the preceding paragraphs of this subsection (other than paragraph (5)) or section 124 of the Medicare, Medicaid, and SCHIP Balanced Budget Refinement Act of 1999, beginning not later than rate year 2031, in addition to any revisions pursuant to paragraph (5), the Secretary shall, by regulation, implement revisions to the methodology for determining the payment rates under the system described in paragraph (1) for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, to take into account the patient assessment data described in paragraph (4)(E)(ii). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E160BFD93A6418398B0B7A4B90561DD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Budget neutrality</header><text>Revisions in payment implemented pursuant to subparagraph (A) for a rate year shall result in the same estimated amount of aggregate expenditures under this title for psychiatric hospitals and psychiatric units furnished in the rate year as would have been made under this title for such care in such rate year if such revisions had not been implemented.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

