<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H16CD8ADF7E48459CB7CEF90BBACF14AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8718 IH: Intelligence Community Coordinator for Russian Atrocities Accountability Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8718</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220816">August 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of National Intelligence to designate an intelligence community coordinator for Russian atrocities accountability, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBF7683EFEC17429A98DF0228238F4DE3" style="OLC"><section id="HD4D74912B60445EE8C29A6C1547E865C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Intelligence Community Coordinator for Russian Atrocities Accountability Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HACC6EC3A68D44FCE931DBB0946783A0A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Intelligence community coordinator for Russian atrocities accountability</header><subsection id="H21879C43BCCB4C8093A0CB74B009FAE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Intelligence community coordinator for Russian atrocities accountability</header><paragraph id="H1B4CD6AA72204CEB9B4770C289672860"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall designate a senior official of the Office of the Director of National Intelligence to serve as the intelligence community coordinator for Russian atrocities accountability (in this section referred to as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC7C7E42FC864DB3AC930EEC88A40F44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Coordinator shall oversee the efforts of the intelligence community relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H8FDBEF03F54C46B49B75EBC66258E581"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying, and (as appropriate) disseminating within the United States Government, intelligence relating to the identification, location, or activities of foreign persons suspected of playing a role in committing Russian atrocities in Ukraine.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H213BAA3441264FFE8C26E8C5653EBDAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying analytic and other intelligence needs and priorities of the intelligence community with respect to the commitment of such Russian atrocities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C10373D3E94457FB2E9253C889D42AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Addressing any gaps in intelligence collection relating to the commitment of such Russian atrocities and developing recommendations to address any gaps so identified, including by recommending the modification of the priorities of the intelligence community with respect to intelligence collection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF06C7A305364D249A99F207537C6246"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Collaborating with appropriate counterparts across the intelligence community to ensure appropriate coordination on, and integration of the analysis of, the commitment of such Russian atrocities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A888A1151354CD29D30D61BE1425444"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying intelligence and other information that may be relevant to preserve evidence of potential war crimes by Russia, consistent with the public commitments of the United States to support investigations into the conduct of Russia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D1FE98E4A3A4CC58AEEB1A99112DB9E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring the Atrocities Early Warning Task Force and other relevant departments and agencies of the United States Government receive appropriate support from the intelligence community with respect to the collection, analysis, preservation, and, as appropriate, dissemination, of intelligence related to Russian atrocities in Ukraine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HECF7D9E63F4C4A88B7577550045B94B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees—</text><subparagraph id="H680D958BAB714893803044ED39301893"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the official designated as the Coordinator pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H081D4CE655F54DEB9078F95ECC1D2408"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the strategy of the intelligence community for the collection of intelligence related to Russian atrocities in Ukraine, including a detailed description of how the Coordinator shall support, and assist in facilitating the implementation of, such strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD125B08ABCB44E08AC0B8D7AB4328722"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><subparagraph id="HB5426CAEC2AE40F59A752FA15687ED3A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than May 1, 2023, and annually thereafter until May 1, 2026, the Director of National Intelligence shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report detailing, for the year covered by the report—</text><clause id="H1D17E8B00B204ECFAF920CC195833709"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the analytical findings and activities of the intelligence community with respect to Russian atrocities in Ukraine; and</text></clause><clause id="HBE9A6083137F4CF3BB1DF61468092571"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the recipients of information shared pursuant to this section for the purpose of ensuring accountability for such Russian atrocities, and the date of any such sharing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D1F27A7DCD94ECA8DB476E510B7D9D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) may be submitted in classified form, consistent with the protection of intelligence sources and methods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91AA9C8ADE0E4A73BE5643433E02DD59" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Supplement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of National Intelligence may supplement an existing reporting requirement with the information required under subparagraph (A) on an annual basis to satisfy that requirement with prior notification of intent to do so to the congressional intelligence committees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD73CDABD50F3423193779D8FCB3A61E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H0DE8FB6B1A09420A9446807236BC7353"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Atrocity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>atrocity</quote> means a war crime, crime against humanity, genocide, or crime of aggression.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFCB27DF367F4650972BCDD25BC0DED9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commit</header><text>The term <quote>commit</quote>, with respect to an atrocity, includes the planning, committing, aiding, and abetting of such atrocity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDDEAD7C2D404847B9EF55151422987E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional intelligence committees; intelligence community</header><text>The terms <quote>congressional intelligence committees</quote> and <quote>intelligence community</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8479D5163ECF4D68AEB38EB48AFFBA5B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <quote>foreign person</quote> means a person that is not a United States person. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9065153F3C24A0782C266800A785E75"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Russian atrocity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Russian atrocity</quote> means an atrocity that is committed by an individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="H64A1F83783014F5FAB4A07AFAB0BE96A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member of the armed forces, or the security or other defense services, of the Russian Federation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC17DF94D75B442EAA144DB0E7C1B59CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an employee of any other element of the Russian Government; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC644451D67C45D9875ADA9B63073C0C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an agent or contractor of an individual specified in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B8FAF4EFEF743AC963E3EAFD1E557F4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <quote>United States person</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 105A(c) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3039">50 U.S.C. 3039</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB086C11C11D048D49DAEEB53D197C7F6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall cease to have effect on the date that is 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

