<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFFDAC0EE5275436289F3D298A8235B80" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7564 IH: Building More Housing for Servicemembers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7564</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220421">April 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to take certain actions regarding the housing shortage for members of the Armed Forces.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H602F3F6AEF4941BCB4C39118B05A4A1E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6B1C4C277E7A47E59CE7AB41AFAFA456" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building More Housing for Servicemembers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCF395EE5F53B454A80A41C024E7F7DA2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responses to the housing shortage for members of the Armed Forces</header> <subsection id="HF4412A7ABD63499893B18B46B49E86DB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report on housing shortage for members of the Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the housing shortage for members of the Armed Forces. Such report shall include the following elements:</text> 
<paragraph id="HB13243FC05A847E0A697319F8736C402"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination of the Secretary regarding the feasibility of acquiring real property near military installations that face housing shortages, to be used for the development of privatized housing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H57C42BAB3CCF4F4D8819F0A508B996EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The determination of the Secretary regarding the need for an officer or civilian employee of the Department of Defense to serve, at each military installation, as a housing manager.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEAF91A06B1714433ACA6C9ACE88DE416"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance to landlords of privatized housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prescribe guidance for eligible entities and landlords regarding acceptable housing standards for privatized housing.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4191D6E0685F4E08856FB8DF5F87CAA0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"></text> 
<paragraph id="H4301629B24134FB48565642585B7D591"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pilot program on using rental partnership programs of the Armed Forces to assure tenants for developers of privatized housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall establish a pilot program to assess the feasibility of using the rental partnership programs of the Armed Forces to assure tenants for eligible entities to secure financing to construct privatized housing.</text> <subparagraph id="HB9FD5780F80341B8B9628917A03DEBBF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretary shall operate the pilot program in no more than 10 military housing areas that each have a rental vacancy rate of less than 7 percent.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H43243D49A382472EA469B6737D88A5E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The pilot program shall terminate on the date that is five years after the Secretary establishes the pilot program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDBACA0A9CE6C4BF4AD139012A7E6F4D2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the termination of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8344A628F69A44D78B4BFBC6C6BEDFDC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint pilot program on financial incentives for developers of privatized housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, shall develop a pilot program to provide financial incentives to eligible entities to build privatized housing, or to purchase or lease existing facilities, to house members of the Armed Forces and their dependents, and low-income individuals and families, as determined by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text> <subparagraph id="H33E78BBF0ED241979BF5428FF81AB3E3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to be eligible for an incentive under the pilot program, proposed privatized housing shall ensure that a percentage of such housing is reserved for members of the Armed Forces and dependents of such members. Such percentage shall vary proportionately to the value of the incentive.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA78444681B254BAFB73239D9659DE967"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>The Secretaries shall operate the pilot program in areas that have the longest wait times for on-base housing.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H084EC478CBCA4412988877ACF3E25C6B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting eligible entities, the Secretaries shall give priority to entry-level housing and projects with greater density.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76B4BCA4D5924C86B96F92DAA98C0518" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The pilot program shall terminate on the date that is five years after the Secretary establishes the pilot program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7958F9F1D58A4B19A18B8C21BE23A388"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the termination of the pilot program, the Secretaries shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the pilot program.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48A1D0555649470BBFA0253E6B93F356"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Joint grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Housing and Urban Development may jointly operate a grant program through the Office of Local Defense Community Cooperation to build housing for members of the Armed Forces and their dependents, and low-income individuals and families. Household income limits for entities eligible to receive such a grant shall not differ based on whether a household includes a member of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H1CE995E6286C48B68C2D99271697C44B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H87805EAE55D645E88198368995F1301C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <quote>eligible entity</quote> and <quote>landlord</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 2871 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8B1FA233812B44FC897F994C31CAE67A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>privatized housing</quote> means housing under subchapter IV of chapter 169 of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

