<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H757780AB02B347299C9A728C245C721F" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1193 : Cardiovascular Advances in Research and Opportunities Legacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1193</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20211209">December 9, 2021</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20220525">May 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSHR00">Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, to establish a program under which the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall support or conduct research on valvular heart disease, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HCDCCBD0743AB4D2C829C9D0FBABE699A"><section id="HBFA228B60BCE411381E5E23E1E13A5FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cardiovascular Advances in Research and Opportunities Legacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2C6F05510524481EB9EEDE5250138DDA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for valvular heart disease research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 2 of part C of title IV of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285b">42 U.S.C. 285b et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 424C (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/285b-7c">42 U.S.C. 285b–7c</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H981B2651AF764465850C4567944F6D3A" style="OLC"><section id="H443329DB0F214E20AB12FF9D42E64157"><enum>424D.</enum><header>Grants for valvular heart disease research</header><subsection id="H213EF4F4A5CA42FF9B7B2E5B20E3EF09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the Director of the Institute, shall support or conduct research regarding valvular heart disease.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE208E177751479C9E99D369D0F884EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support guidelines</header><text>The distribution of funding authorized under subsection (a) may be used to pursue the following outcomes:</text><paragraph id="HDD809F75E8AF45AC917991A09CAB2370"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Using precision medicine and advanced technological imaging to generate data on individuals with valvular heart disease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFCC850DABC94F6D8F6A6D6E947DC350"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Identifying and developing a cohort of individuals with valvular heart disease and available data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DABCB1875D24A4DA421C9981845854C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Corroborating data generated through clinical trials to develop a prediction model to distinguish individuals at high risk for sudden cardiac arrest or sudden cardiac death from valvular heart disease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28BB3C027FFB41C5BF53F47E9C8507B8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For other outcomes needed to acquire necessary data on valvular heart disease.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEAFF53F46F0749859BB4EE9E9CA1DDBD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mitral valve prolapse workshop</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the Institute shall convene a workshop composed of subject matter experts and stakeholders to identify research needs and opportunities to develop prescriptive guidelines for treatment of individuals with mitral valve prolapse.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC36FE4E134DA49B29130E8360169E000"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7EE953913A984E8E8DA3DA8981F71ADE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Programs of Centers for Disease Control and Prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 312 the following section<italic></italic>:</text><quoted-block id="H8CDA18077B3E4A07B9B028DAB88DD9F8" style="OLC"><section id="H66908B36C94F40DD914F03A869776C54"><enum>312A.</enum><header>Prevention of sudden cardiac death as a result of valvular heart disease</header><subsection id="H868AB9E45F60418DA31558FC8CAB0963"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, may carry out projects to increase education, awareness, or diagnosis of valvular heart disease and to reduce the incidence of sudden cardiac death caused by valvular heart disease. Such projects may be carried out by the Secretary directly or through awards of grants or contracts to public or nonprofit private entities. The Secretary may directly (or through such awards) provide technical assistance with respect to the planning, development, and operation of such projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="H059483B66D774D2F83092B4CA785B16B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certain activities</header><text>Upon availability of applicable data, projects carried out under subsection (a) may include—</text><paragraph id="H1AC6A528337D4F4D8873F8C0559C98B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continuing the activities at the Division for Heart Disease and Stroke Prevention, including those related to valvular heart disease;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FF40867D5AD4094A3BF70440AA6723F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>broadening the awareness of the public concerning the risk factors for, the symptoms of, and the public health consequences of valvular heart disease; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89A77D5F3190402A8EA4179B79824424"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhancing surveillance of out-of-hospital cardiac arrests to improve patient outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFCDDA16575A34731B2740E5C182E4DB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant prioritization</header><text>The Secretary may, in awarding grants or entering into contracts pursuant to subsection (a), give priority to entities seeking to carry out projects that target populations most impacted by valvular heart disease.</text></subsection><subsection id="H489BFAC6A4DD48318EAA4C5C556BDDF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coordination of activities</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that activities under this section are coordinated, as appropriate, with other agencies of the Public Health Service that carry out activities regarding valvular heart disease.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0EB0A64CA0EA4972BD2AFB6EF4DFA932"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall—</text><paragraph id="H7E0C0951639F4B52B1C7F71FE4FABE52"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect and analyze the findings of research conducted with respect to valvular heart disease; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2D7017395364E87995E6FB4F94339D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>taking into account such findings, publish on the website of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention best practices for physicians and other health care providers who provide care to individuals with valvular heart disease.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20211208" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 8, 2021.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

