<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB096FE8493CC42CA805611B582A3515B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6375 IH: COPS on the Beat Grant Program Reauthorization and Parity Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6375</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To permit COPS grants to be used for the purpose of increasing the compensation and hiring of law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBF9D32DB393E4006A940D17B868A29C3" style="OLC"><section id="H69E82DCA3A95413E9145EC295627F7E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>COPS on the Beat Grant Program Reauthorization and Parity Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB62410D646194D0DA7C499B9CB204777"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H427A8821F93D40EEA998D2965C01D7F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5652480D93864306B9089B1D0D8F7E6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President’s Task Force on 21st Century Policing highlighted the importance of hiring law enforcement officers who reflect the diversity and values of the community, and who have both the mindset and the skills needed to engage with the community.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDB24694F1494706B2A66676C63786A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Diverse workforces can be more effective, creative, and resilient than homogenous workforces, and teams with broader perspectives result in better decision-making and problem-solving practices. Recruiting a diverse pool of candidates includes qualified individuals from different races, genders, ethnicities, and cultural backgrounds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4122685BEAA84111AB92A1B2B7BB95F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Effective law enforcement recruitment practices can help engender trust, develop good relations with their communities, and ensure that the officers they hire can best serve those communities. Recruitment efforts should start in the community, and law enforcement agencies should consider developing youth programs to attract younger generations. This could include Explorer programs, internships through local schools, cadet academies, university partnerships, and youth mentorship programs that foster relationships between young adults and departments. Not only do these programs develop enthusiasm for a law enforcement career, they can also build relationships between law enforcement agencies and the communities they serve.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BEC80B86AD6452594CF957D55B51C59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the COPS Office is uniquely suited to empower local law enforcement agencies to fulfill recommendations related to law enforcement hiring practices, including agencies being reflective of the communities they serve, both demographically and in values and vision, and possessing the mindset and skills needed to engage with the community.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB5CFAA549063487EB4E7024BFBBD1299"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reauthorization of COPS on the Beat grant programs</header><subsection id="HCEE1D1036D5D47C5A7B21EFAE532E11A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reauthorization of COPS on the beat grant program</header><text>Section 1001(a)(11)(A) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10261">34 U.S.C. 10261(a)(11)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for each of fiscal years 2006 through 2009</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2031</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCB3DA79C97A74F91BBE72DF145242B98"><enum>4.</enum><header>Rural community access to COPS grants</header><subsection id="H7B73FC804DC44FB8A0F7084B77F35BFE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Uses of grant amounts</header><text>Section 1701(b) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE88A5F37DD094747BBBA655ABAEFA558"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (23) as paragraphs (4) through (24), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1304FFF530D94795B5D17D70D43350DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5D02338DE16C498B8B5477203C7B8D63" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H50DCB5CF1EBB412C9457A1B6C14602C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of any State or unit of local government that has a median household income of less than 70 percent of the national median household income and qualifies for a reduced contribution under subsection (g)(2), to increase wages of career law enforcement officers to not more than 80 percent of the national median household income;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4F8FABE122C49D69DACF41E587286E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (23), as redesignated, by striking <quote>through (21)</quote> and inserting <quote>through (22)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D88881AE24C477283010A60B5C40EF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preferential consideration</header><text>Section 1701(c) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE4308625DC4A485D86B5E3C1FE23A69C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27AC41ECC43B4125A61877D655028726"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98BAEE591DDF4D57A84C6CA16B7D9E91"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text>Section 1701(g) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(g)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H8BAE14AC4C0E4B7883B4FFFF684CA075" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE32D8694C99A48608389786D072D06E3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><paragraph id="H73B0F8A2280C4D5C92FEAFB14986632B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the portion of the costs of a program, project, or activity provided by a grant under subsection (a) may not exceed 75 percent, unless the Attorney General waives, wholly or in part, the requirement under this subsection of a non-Federal contribution to the costs of a program, project, or activity. In relation to a grant for a period exceeding 1 year for hiring or rehiring or increasing the compensation of career law enforcement officers, the Federal share shall decrease from year to year for up to 5 years, looking toward the continuation of the increased hiring and compensation level using State or local sources of funding following the conclusion of Federal support, as provided in an approved plan pursuant to section 1702(c)(8).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D589CE3B57B46388E26F9DE14A8C1AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduced non-federal contribution</header><subparagraph id="H25169D7580194B3EB6F6C8DA52D3B085"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The portion of the costs of a program, project, or activity provided by a grant under subsection (a), in any State or unit of local government described in subparagraph (B), may not exceed—</text><clause id="H608358F99D384A23AE078874AA036D9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>90 percent for the first year of the grant;</text></clause><clause id="H86D047C896904B6A9617A36763DE289F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>85 percent for the second year of the grant;</text></clause><clause id="HFDFFDB7FE0284D65AA1BCF3CC3260C35"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>80 percent for the third year of the grant; and</text></clause><clause id="H2EA879F5F4D849BFB459D7E40A6FC779"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>75 percent for the fourth year of the grant.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0023ED335B9D420896657C913C8085B6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>State or unit of local government described</header><text>A State or unit of local government described in this subparagraph is any State or unit of local government—</text><clause id="H0CA09A38C0944031BADC5705D71030ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a median household income that is not more than 80 percent of the national median household income;</text></clause><clause id="HB6A1907C4F5C4076B6E7F3E50CF9CAE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that does not provide a single employee with compensation that is more than double the national median household income; and</text></clause><clause id="HA0B2A306083A43ADB04994010B391A0F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that is a rural State, rural community, or rural area as such terms are defined in section 40002(a) of the Violent Crime Control and Law Enforcement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)(26)(A)</external-xref>) is amended.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD30CE4F5C19C40D584965EC433CCEF24"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on hiring and rehiring</header><text>Section 1704(c) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10384">34 U.S.C. 10384(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HD1D884E70CA841F494187D0320274183" style="OLC"><subsection id="HF65CB25D4935464CBFF52E059F7FB79B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hiring and compensation cost</header><paragraph id="H52CFD3B091824FACA6A5D075659AE79C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Funding provided under this part for hiring or rehiring a career law enforcement officer may not exceed $75,000, unless the Attorney General grants a waiver from this limitation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E49BFA6314049BB8A0D9408E7576B60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reduced contribution</header><text>In the case of a jurisdiction that qualifies for a reduced contribution under section 1701(g)(2), a career law enforcement officer who is hired or rehired or whose compensation is increased under this part may not receive from any funding provided under this part compensation exceeding 80 percent of the national median household income for work performed as an on-duty law enforcement officer.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H270155AAAD6648DD9E8E4817CB397A3A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Allocation of COPS grant program funds</header><text>Section 1001(a)(11)(B) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10261">34 U.S.C. 10261(a)(11)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the second sentence the following: <quote>If funds remain available for obligation under this subparagraph in a fiscal year after all eligible and qualified grantees have been funded from the 50 percent of funding allocated for grants pursuant to applications submitted by units of local government or law enforcement agencies having jurisdiction over areas with populations exceeding 150,000 or by public and private entities that serve areas with populations exceeding 150,000, the remaining funds may be used for grants pursuant to applications submitted by units of local government or law enforcement agencies having jurisdiction over areas with populations 150,000 or less or by public and private entities that serve areas with populations 150,000 or less.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE3BEDD2DC81E473EAAFA4083C0F1EA32"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1709 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10389">34 U.S.C. 10389</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HC3536C55B60347829E2574E657481496" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0B11D7F8F8FA4C2181441895755B1CDD"><enum>(8)</enum><text><quote>Attorney General</quote> means the Attorney General, acting through the COPS Director.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HC3E0534466254F429D50BCB49FFC4112"><enum>5.</enum><header>COPS office</header><subsection id="HEDD80DC9570C49AD8664B7F1D2E736B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>COPS program</header><text>Section 1701(a) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H1B9AC274491748D78248E6AC95920C15" style="OLC"><subsection id="H73B100FA8BB64F608CBD16C1EE772A9D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>The Office of Community Oriented Policing Services</header><paragraph id="H34DC878C9EBE4AEF894181B3B3897FBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is within the Department of Justice, under the general authority of the Attorney General, a separate and distinct office to be known as the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>COPS Office</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0B2D18B3562435BB8A7D42AFE3FABBF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The COPS Office shall be headed by a Director who shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFC0AC3ED04244D9C8ADA94C91AD2A68A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be appointed by the Attorney General; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB112F0890734D07B4A41E719903CA16"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have final authority over grants under this part and any other grants, cooperative agreements, and contracts awarded by the COPS Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HF353C65B76EC484988C3735164C4399D"><enum>6.</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In fiscal year 2026 and fiscal year 2031, the Comptroller General of the United States, after consultation with the Attorney General, shall submit to Congress and make publicly available a report that provides national averages and averages for department characteristic subgroups including at least size of police and sheriff departments and urban or rural designations by jurisdiction detailing—</text><paragraph id="H075BAD6706B541B6904E011D2BBB0E77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a measure of how representative the existing workforce of the average police and sheriff departments is to the community served based on demographics which include at least gender and race;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B82F51F3774E91949EC7A4C01539D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the percentage of those employed by the average police and sheriff departments that live in the jurisdiction in which they are currently employed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89284750B5EF46CD8890F8D44D160950"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a measure of average officer pay in police and sheriff departments compared to cost of living in the jurisdiction in which they are currently employed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97369F5644A2495DBB53708F3000693F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>legislative and administrative recommendations for improving the percentage of officers that live in the jurisdiction in which they are employed and how representative the law enforcement agency is of the community it serves.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

