<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E042C8AFC104CF385119CE70D561DE2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8264 IH: Backlog Justice Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8264</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the processing of samples of sexual assault evidence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEE7A6B8B9804DFBBAAC52BF5A2CE7B8" style="OLC"><section id="HD6D876C299584499BFBBF793851CFE18" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Backlog Justice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H23D2DF3489934140B014114E7BAFFF91"><enum>2.</enum><header>National rape kit backlog database</header><subsection id="H17BACCBE5AFE4087A47806B8208C25AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance, shall establish, maintain, and update not less than biannually, a publicly accessible online database of information from inventories or audits conducted by States and units of local governments of the sexual assault evidence collection kits that are in the possession of the State or unit of local government and have been awaiting testing for more than 90 days, including an estimate of the amount of time it takes for each laboratory, with respect to which data is submitted, to test a sexual assault evidence collection kit.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8BE2110062634D94B441863FD8526BA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="H4FEBA1BD808F43F08BA810006A720169"><enum>3.</enum><header>Training analysts to test samples of sexual assault evidence</header><subsection id="H353C3CD835C7442DB9D35CEF91D6D132"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, is authorized to develop and operate training programs at the Federal Bureau of Investigation laboratory—</text><paragraph id="H27AB1E4D37E24D1086E279052485391F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for individuals hired by States and units of local government as analysts to test samples of sexual assault evidence, which may include training at the Federal Bureau of Investigation laboratory or at State and local laboratories;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB27AEA0D1A54672AE8EE46F9A26F64E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pursuant to which individuals hired and trained by the Federal Bureau of Investigation as analysts to test samples of sexual assault evidence, may be hired by States and units of local government upon completion of such training; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D2049CA13047E79F428E1A1FC6F184"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for DNA Technical Leader training, including a curriculum to host both in-person and remote training sessions for technical leaders or trained DNA examiners seeking to become technical leaders. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF425C3AECD3F4E8891F399B3BFD48791"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed to require a State or local forensic science services provider to participate in a program established under subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="H02DD1B7A13AF4BACAE270FA8F15A0ABB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="H9A5BA3F4733F448F9E54D2D86F7EE21E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Validation and technology transfer program</header><subsection id="H5D5D99D1A768451AB09F0A6B4A22531F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, is authorized to convene and coordinate, in conjunction with State and local forensic science service providers, a validation and technology transfer program, pursuant to which the Federal Bureau of Investigation laboratory, in partnership with a collaborative of State and local forensic science service providers, may research new technologies and processes for processing DNA, and provide for use by State and local laboratories related to such technologies and processes— </text><paragraph id="HE6B67C7EE84B406F9C15A7ED4E2A9370"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analytical protocols; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57E90DE7D3E54DC69DF9C2772BC4E73E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developmental validation data; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H965B8893FD10400A9D826D41C9D36AF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>model lab instrument performance verification plans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H267653ADBCED4E379B0ECD07A1B6AE9C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Validation list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon completing the research described in subsection (a), the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation is authorized to publish a list of validated technologies and processes, along with validation data and additional documentation related to each such technology or process.</text></subsection><subsection id="H77E7F4A4396740C188E2B202C3529B17"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="HD01A49AD37AD444F9EC7545E8C0467A8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increase in STOP grant funding for States that have in place electronic evidence tracking systems for sexual assault kits</header><subsection id="H1FF0A4BC0B7A4DFC8BC8B80AADB35DF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in fiscal year 2024, the Attorney General shall increase by not more than 10 percent the amount provided to a State under the part T of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10441">34 U.S.C. 10441 et seq.</external-xref>) if the State has in place an electronic evidence tracking system for sexual assault kits that complies with the requirements under subsection (b). </text></subsection><subsection id="HEAB1E2DBAD734E1B88AC3D79C566055E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tracking system requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to qualify for the grant increase under subsection (a), the tracking system shall be a website that provides information to victims of sexual assault who underwent a sexual assault kit examination and their advocates on each stage of the processing of a rape kit, including from the hospital, to a local law enforcement agency, through the analysis process at a lab, to final disposition.</text></subsection><subsection id="H93C7F9AFC9AD4D3F9AA81DE3665ECFE6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period of increase</header><paragraph id="H9B6A697A80974A80A4B2AABF39AD10ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide an increase in the amount provided to a State under the program described in subsection (a) for a 2-year period. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED9E4AC853514654B564E3A2ADA60F82"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limit</header><text>The Attorney General may not provide an increase in the amount provided to a State under the program described in subsection (a) more than 4 times.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H284A8D36AD044439BDF604C664A964FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $1,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

