<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H09C90B4DA9A54D589E8D7AA03D46287F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8342 IH: Military Interstate Children’s Compact Commission Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8342</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220712">July 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the development of recommendations to improve and fully implement the Military Interstate Children’s Compact, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H34D7DA6CF81A46239CFA83355654F5F3" style="OLC"><section id="H5EF54636025A43259B93FF1AA3ADCFC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Interstate Children’s Compact Commission Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF77BA031ACB745758714676F121AEF80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Recommendations for the improvement of the Military Interstate Children’s Compact</header><subsection id="H3A29E470904A485DBCB272914692A05D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recommendations required</header><text>The Secretaries concerned, in consultation with States through the Defense-State Liaison Office, shall develop recommendations to improve and fully implement the Military Interstate Children’s Compact.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE592C1A33D98469C85B432929CE3F0D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretaries concerned shall—</text><paragraph id="H1B94690B8F4A4EADA3A49303952B298C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify any barriers—</text><subparagraph id="H7FDB5CBF8F034488BD1B72B3B8A7CC3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the ability of a parent of a transferring military-connected child to enroll the child, in advance, in an elementary or secondary school in the State in which the child is transferring, without requiring the parent or child to be physically present in the State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2D398202825460B871A37EF9F7D84C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the ability of a transferring military-connected child who receives special education services to gain access to such services and related supports in the State to which the child transfers within the timeframes required under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C5DA55874A64004B344D77AF6EED8A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consider the feasibility and advisability of—</text><subparagraph id="H0D6AB4E370DF46B7B858C234E6F76897"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tracking and reporting the number of families who use advanced enrollment in States that offer advanced enrollment to military-connected children;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB01DD54A1934624B822F284D74B2094"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States clarifying in legislation that eligibility for advanced enrollment requires only written evidence of a permanent change of station order, and does not require a parent of a military-connected child to produce a rental agreement or mortgage statement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AB3E54F37C34107BFECDAB66AD271BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Military Interstate Children’s Compact, developing a letter or other memorandum that military families may present to local educational agencies that outlines the protections afforded to military-connected children by the Military Interstate Children’s Compact; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40827852A37B4AFB9F711879E10FA1DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify any other actions that may be taken by the States (acting together or separately) to improve the Military Interstate Children’s Compact.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A6B76523BFC4C328D6FF3CC6C56D90C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries concerned shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and to the States a report setting forth the recommendations developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE0C87359A3D84210858891D3721358CE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1CA9B9D02E3246FAA7B97CB429FCDA28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H21DBE2A5966D402285ECA97E0191768C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the congressional defense committees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8139ADC73A44AF295B5C66DE211686E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2217506ACF1E40AC8E0B1A9284B4AC22"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Education and Labor and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H791C96F984E94FD4B6DFEF5FCDDD0AF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>child</term>, <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>parent</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D0944A54B0F442AB97227D0D7EF98BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The terms <term>armed forces</term>, <term>active duty</term> and <term>congressional defense committees</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58549CA12D33466EB631BF019A4BB36D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>transferring military-connected child</term> means the child of a parent who—</text><subparagraph id="H98EC814E27EA48E3BAB651E2A4960D1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is serving on active duty in the armed forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7EA89C6D19F457BBD4B8DC8C486E20E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is changing duty locations due to a permanent change of station order; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3701357892C4E07BD8A160B55FCF109"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has not yet established an ongoing physical presence in the State to which the parent is transferring.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H959CE99929294EC8B68D736E96F98070"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Military Interstate Children’s Compact</term> means the Interstate Compact on Educational Opportunity for Military Children as described in Department of Defense Instruction 1342.29, dated January 31, 2017 (or any successor to such instruction).<italic></italic></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B4F3A09BE8D4D54999A32D59440AC78"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H56978188EC5B418CA9272A919FFB44EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Defense, with respect to matters concerning the Department of Defense; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H141E3AC401314726AC5DDC68D564046B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, with respect to matters concerning the Coast Guard when it is not operating as a service in the Department of the Navy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

