<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1AA74AB7D4BD45B8B400B2551F565506" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9225 IH: Case Backlog and Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9225</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221025">October 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000 to provide for additional rules regarding processing of immigration applications, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H308FF5FEFEF541CC8B302B2B7A4032D2" style="OLC"><section id="H8EE7831A5F8A442EA277503E9EA5C006" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Case Backlog and Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE5CE75CBE11840A482D7ACF767EAAF6B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202 of the Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1571">8 U.S.C. 1571</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA6D8B794DF5D47E9AF0E154B613367C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HBBEE1A89E5114A62BD0C0CB9F32C6003"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Immigration and Naturalization Service</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB842087A7894ED2A7528BDF6BAFA3F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>current backlog</quote> and inserting <quote>backlog</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B44FD1696F44E2B2BEDE26F7B2948E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>within 1 year after enactment of this Act</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B2C52BC5E24ECE8F44ECAF11CB075D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>Immigration and Naturalization Service</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1E072445A65D4809A7EB6DA3EBF99FD3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1572">8 U.S.C. 1572</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H386D7AAE1C474CD48C576FF092659D3C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HB4B3020CA97F4E7EBEC7BE46A8C2E3D2"><enum>203.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="H210F1F3C42EA4DA995FE3A44F27C6E92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active suspense</header><text>The term <term>active suspense</term> means circumstances in which the Department of Homeland Security cannot process an immigration benefit application due to factors outside of the Department’s control, including any circumstance in which a visa number is unavailable, or circumstances in which the Department is waiting for a response from the applicant or a third party (including another government agency).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2B7CCF696D4AA8A6BC02BDF90F8608"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Backlog; net backlog</header><text>The term <term>backlog</term> or <term>net backlog</term> means the number of immigration benefit applications that are pending before the Department of Homeland Security outside of applicable processing time goals, minus those applications in an active suspense category.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFB953AAAE5B40D4BFF48E45076FBC59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gross backlog</header><text>The term <term>gross backlog</term> means the number of immigration benefit applications that are pending before the Department of Homeland Security outside of applicable processing time goals, irrespective of whether the applications are in an active suspense category.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FB01AB20C5B4F3A8A74EEE2469E2478"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Immigration benefit application</header><text>The term <term>immigration benefit application</term> means any application, petition, or request to confer, certify, change, adjust, or extend any status authorized under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) and any other application, petition, or request for an immigration benefit, made to U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4DFE3BB738943B5A6A3C7A3B993120C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Processing time</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>processing time</term> means the time elapsed between the date on which an immigration benefit application is received by U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services and the date on which U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services approves or denies an immigration benefit application. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CEC05C9CB0746FDB110D83ED72CF862"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Processing time goal</header><text>The term <term>processing time goal</term> means the goal for a processing time established by the Department of Homeland Security as an appropriate processing time for a type of immigration benefit application. </text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H48004AF117684D7284565A9CF1B33F27"><enum>4.</enum><header>Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Account</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 204 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1573">8 U.S.C. 1573</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H424391E4E57645819442A4B2B88194B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CABF7B43F624948BE8FADA760290741"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60BFDA881C4945B6AD4374650D83A646"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2), by striking <quote>ensure that a backlog does not develop after such date</quote> and inserting <quote>prevent the recurrence of the backlog after its elimination</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD94D7DC2C6614C65B2E7A130C56D7C18"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H5E727B53F72D4D3F9B2B3EDD55A1CC9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Department of Justice</quote> and inserting <quote>Department of Homeland Security</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF174AC55EEA449DA2C5166176089485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H52CA561CA5FB44FFA4634E8CDA9DF8D1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 205 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1574">8 U.S.C. 1574</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H894A147412EB46A4AC15910F5FCDAB0B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HA48AB1BF707C490CB21E5D9DDBEC5EEC"><enum>205.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><subsection id="H76C9D77E2EA0401BAAB8AE93E8DC7FA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quarterly report</header><paragraph id="HAF78AB6194004C898C16717276CBDAE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after each of the first three quarters of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish on the Department’s website and submit to the Committees on the Judiciary, Appropriations, and Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, and to the Committees on the Judiciary, Appropriations, and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, a report concerning the backlog in immigration benefit applications as of the end of that fiscal quarter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35835A7E1B5F4461AA1D44FF1B127697"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include, as available—</text><subparagraph id="H1115F1836A08401B85A1BA015F4E2AB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of applications pending for each type of immigration benefit application, the number of immigration benefit applications in active suspense, and the number of backlog applications for each type of immigration benefit application;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7957CE8480464FA0B5AC3D8FB74FBBA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the median processing time for each type of immigration benefit application and any change in that time relative to the end of the prior quarter; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4817519795FF4DA6B2FE69E6BDD0A982"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of pending Form I–730 (or successor form) follow-to-join refugee or asylee immigration benefit applications and the number of pending Priority–3 refugee immigration benefit applications, the median length of time each application has been pending, and the number of applications that have been processed by the Department of Homeland Security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8A48332BB9B43D09358232572F4E500"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of refugee immigration benefit applications with respect to which the beneficiary has been interviewed by the Department of Homeland Security and the number of such beneficiaries whose applications are pending final adjudication, including information on the processing stage at which such applications are pending.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23AAF085B2694D9D89626FDF08A7CD3E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H30FF02C8D17E4441BCB20CC69F2FF192"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year the Secretary shall publish on the Department’s website and submit to the Committees on the Judiciary, Appropriations, and Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, and to the Committees on the Judiciary, Appropriations, and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, a report concerning the status of—</text><subparagraph id="H8A5A7107364D42DA95F9BDB034C148E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Account as of the end of the fiscal year, including any unobligated balances of appropriations in the Account;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FF95AC16A764FD59A53E757F4959C22"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the backlog in immigration benefit applications as of the end of the fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H949370F9B1A34E22B2203183032C1D66"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> requests made through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services customer service tools. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1821FF17EF08406E9AE6A9A6956B6725"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include, as available—</text><subparagraph id="H159752E5DC204A629F82468C672089C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of factors contributing to the net and gross backlogs, including a detailed assessment of the impacts of Department of Homeland Security policies on the net and gross backlogs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE085FE2C33842428933D6FD618598A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of how U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services quantitatively and qualitatively measures progress of backlog reduction measures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF2F55E6C9D24852B1D31D88790FDCD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of existing efforts to eliminate the net backlog and minimize the gross backlog;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD880E6FFF5764B3CBD937283B9A18B2C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a detailed plan to eliminate the net backlog, to prevent recurrence of the net backlog after elimination, and to minimize the gross backlog;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EBD2E9B259C4CF9B31F46650E933484"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of existing and planned quality controls for ensuring fair, accurate, and consistent adjudication of immigration benefit applications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1ABAF3212044003BE5237B977322633"><enum>(F)</enum><text>information on U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services funding, including—</text><clause id="HA2BAC3931A65477C8A69DA9C6E1012A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an assessment of how and to what extent funding, both from fee accounts and appropriations, was allocated toward backlog elimination;</text></clause><clause id="HB72D4C372C2B479988B1631EB7FEAE88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the identification of any transfers of funds between fee accounts and between Department components;</text></clause><clause id="H3A91830C07E74B0CA7F6030FC550347B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a description of whether immigration-related fees were used consistent with legal requirements regarding such use; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B7C476223D54BAFB61E7AA7D86DB17D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an estimate of the amount of appropriated funds that would be necessary to eliminate the net backlog;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E1D793E11954A55984663883824505D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>whether immigration-related questions conveyed by applicants, petitioners, beneficiaries, or authorized representatives to the Department (whether conveyed in person, by telephone, or by means of the internet) were answered effectively and efficiently;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7F05F63EAD0481B8A2524BB9DE0AB9C"><enum>(H)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4E5C3B4E8F8449ECADD9A9355231DA0F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the information referenced under subsection (a)(2) as of the end of the fiscal year;</text></clause><clause id="HA21AFFFE2D16494699E5ED7FF7A7E4E6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of any changes to processing time goals made in the two years prior to the annual report and how those changes impact calculations of the net and gross backlogs;</text></clause><clause id="HACB5C2BB1C234AA6BC6B37471BE4A8AA" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>processing time goals for each type of immigration benefit application and the percentage of applications for which the Department completed processing within each goal;</text></clause><clause id="HE9085DDB55B14338ADFAF620B2045564" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>State-by-State data on the number of naturalization applications, the number of adjustment of status applications, and the overall number of immigration benefit applications, pending for up to 6 months, 12 months, 18 months, 24 months, 36 months, and 48 months or more;</text></clause><clause id="H8A0BB19727094A8189AC09F4ED93A8D6" indent="up1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the median number of hours it takes to complete the processing of each type of immigration benefit application;</text></clause><clause id="H8B682D6FF50A48AF8EF1D5C49DEA9A58" indent="up1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of all immigration benefit applications received, and processed, by the Department, both in the aggregate and as disaggregated by type of immigration benefit application; and</text></clause><clause id="H2F152C1413A04C96B41D2283F8A622B9" indent="up1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the approval and denial rates associated with the completed applications referenced under clause (iv), disaggregated by type of immigration benefit application;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9F02E4419F34AC89CBD21865B11D849"><enum>(I)</enum><text>State-by-State data on—</text><clause id="H8BD2C1EF639A46FBA8B6E1EF05BD0D01"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of naturalization applications processed during each quarter of each fiscal year;</text></clause><clause id="H21D2ECAAFCA446D7AC8C96E61A21715E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the median processing time for naturalization applications; and</text></clause><clause id="H23FD4FF8082C4A879E0CDEF42AAD3B56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the additional resources and process changes needed to eliminate the backlog for naturalization applications; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B64BB3FA46F44AEA163F53A18EF93E7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>a status report on all other types of immigration benefit applications, including—</text><clause id="H310EB483340D47FFBAB1BC37A181BC3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>applications for adjustments of status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text></clause><clause id="H048E009C6909449D8FA7C4603E187292"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>petitions for nonimmigrant visas under section 204(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(c)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HA936C833B09148F8A212138D64F350CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>petitions filed under section 204 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154</external-xref>) to classify aliens as immediate relatives or preference immigrants under section 203 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H633238A53883485A80F2E342F390453C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>applications for asylum under section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H14E8A3C573B34C838AFCCDF167823A6B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>registrations for temporary protected status under section 244 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1254a">8 U.S.C. 1254a</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HDB66FA244CE04CA38974A03B1294D2F9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>applications for humanitarian parole, disaggregated by individual filers and referrals from a Federal agency, under section 212(d)(5) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(d)(5)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H09D3E6CAB9A845A690821ABE68CCED13"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>applications for employment authorization;</text></clause><clause id="H7A3E2F741BEA49D69859BC325C6373A7"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the additional resources and process changes needed to eliminate the backlog for all types of immigration benefit applications described in this subparagraph;</text></clause><clause id="H0C9BA46895DF4B93A812213D3D34199F"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the number of Requests for Evidence (RFE), Notices of Intent to Deny (NOID) or Notices of Intent to Revoke (NOIR) issued, disaggregated by the type of immigration benefit application with respect to which they were issued;</text></clause><clause id="H5B9E5D6CC2294B54879FA78C5DEBFEFD"><enum>(x)</enum><text>the number of immigration benefit applications, disaggregated by type of application, that received a RFE, NOID, or NOIR that were ultimately approved, denied, or abandoned by the applicant; and</text></clause><clause id="H8C3D53C25B994B43A29B602721206051" commented="no"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>the number of applicants for naturalization who applied to the United States district court for a hearing under section 336(b) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1447">8 U.S.C. 1447(b)</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31C7BD77AB6E4381ABE3AC64B9EE381E"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a status report on requests made through U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS) customer service tools, including—</text><clause id="HB3DE34C958D14F23838981E749EAA276"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of calls to the USCIS customer service phone line, including the number of calls that were completed, dropped, and resulted in escalation to a supervisor;</text></clause><clause id="H6854156AD512404FA6E19917B2581997"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the number of callbacks from USCIS that were unanswered by a stakeholder inquiring on the status of an immigration benefit application on behalf of an applicant;</text></clause><clause id="H80AF2180F1FC42D7B0D18C634BF48F28"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the median processing time for such requests; </text></clause><clause id="HD0BE03F269254241BDC5F6F9D68E23B1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of requests for local USCIS office appointments disaggregated by the issue requiring resolution; and</text></clause><clause id="H005C571BB41542C1B535EFA38F2AA8F4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of requests received through customer service online tools.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC499D4A0A8364738A80B5D3EE94B3FE3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Biennial report</header><paragraph id="HAD69A60DAAE845268E0D8ADC205386D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this section, and every two years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall publish on its website and submit to the Committees on the Judiciary, Appropriations, and Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, and to the Committees on the Judiciary, Appropriations, and Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, a report concerning the backlog in immigration benefit applications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6F370D92694478AA29AB5531C4D176A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report elements</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include, as available—</text><subparagraph id="HF6ACA57E8AAF46A0ADAFFD6BD50B4302"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the status of the net backlog, of the gross backlog, and of the overall number of pending immigration benefit applications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDC8C06664CC4A9683E691ABBEED5332"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of factors contributing to the net and gross backlogs, including an analysis of the impacts of Department of Homeland Security policies on the net and gross backlogs and an analysis of the Department’s formal processes for qualitatively and quantitatively assessing the impacts of its policies on the net and gross backlogs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3140B609F7604B6A8D9315CB5B9C7A91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an assessment of existing and planned Department of Homeland Security efforts to eliminate the net backlog, to prevent recurrence of the net backlog after its elimination, and to minimize the gross backlog;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DFE0F06F8CB4BEA9FD26DB02AA9AE47"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of existing and planned Department of Homeland Security efforts to ensure fair, accurate, and consistent adjudication of immigration benefit applications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H181F450DB3BC42D8880DB5275363E544"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations for more expeditiously processing immigration benefit applications while ensuring fairness, accuracy, and consistency in processing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE69B5A899D47492F83EBC86D7C87C6DE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Immigration functions</header><subsection id="HDF8C4983D904496DAD7B81CDEF6326E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 478 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/298">6 U.S.C. 298</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6C67973FAF7048DCB15E55B504D43645" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HF126158AAC504220A15D14F76E8398D7"><enum>478.</enum><header>Timely provision of immigration services</header><subsection id="HAA314E9306C241EEA73B7F473C90DBF2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H1435D0238DDC4395A436A287AFAA6FC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the quality and efficiency of immigration services rendered by the Federal Government should be improved after the transfers made by this subtitle take effect; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA58B328936754CFE88BE5F5A74FD4B2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security should undertake efforts to guarantee that concerns regarding the quality and efficiency of immigration services are addressed after such effective date; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72F3612E5AD245ED85DBE0CD9A1500F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security should not assign a processing time goal (as such term is defined in section 203 of the Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1572">8 U.S.C. 1572</external-xref>)) that is longer than a maximum processing timeframe set forth in section 202 of the Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1571">8 U.S.C. 1571</external-xref>), except that the processing time goal for employment authorization documents should not be longer than 90 days.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4A65395FBC9845C6805C24E613FFCDE7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Case inquiry escalation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make publicly available on the website of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services the process by which a person with a pending immigration benefit application (as such term is defined in section 203 of the Immigration Services and Infrastructure Improvements Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1572">8 U.S.C. 1572</external-xref>)) may inquire about such application after the processing time goal (as such term is defined in such section 203) or the median processing time for such type of immigration benefit application, whichever is sooner. The process developed pursuant to this subsection shall include—</text><paragraph id="H877A822233E341F994EADD7A90E5E0A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a requirement that U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services provides a substantive response to each person who inquires about an immigration benefit application pursuant to such process; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BF96F7844954036AD4B8872FE3F72E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an additional process for a person to escalate such an inquiry in the case that a substantive response described in paragraph (1) has not been provided.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H17109FBF21FE4B148C6C6F4132ACADFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/101">6 U.S.C. 101</external-xref> note) is amended in the table of contents by striking the item relating to section 478 and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8F37D6A1A8A44A338583492397FBC8D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 478. Timely provision of immigration services.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

