<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2842CC9487174BFF89C5AD5D798F14AF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8353 IH: Pay Victims Not Prisoners Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8353</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to make incarcerated taxpayers ineligible for recovery rebates, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0656FADB70494413A0583982A2485ACD" style="OLC"><section id="H33AE547D4DE14B22922BCEC90833BABC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pay Victims Not Prisoners Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H49D8E455E8FE4029982F4B16882B7783"><enum>2.</enum><header>Incarcerated taxpayers made ineligible for 2021 recovery rebate credits</header><subsection id="H35927B8DDCF04FBA9C1F04DC09F7B025" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>2021 recovery rebates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6428B">Section 6428B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsections (h) and (i) as subsections (i) and (j), respectively, by striking <quote>subsection (h)(1)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (i)(1)</quote>, and by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7A49885F48C415C8500E0A2C37E1B10"><subsection id="H6BEACBBD00BC418CB3ADA38FD2CE66E6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Special rules with respect to prisoners</header><paragraph id="HF04A9D41BAFE4BCBA2283EDF21A8E2A9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disallowance of credit</header><subparagraph id="HF8A8381CC7624FF697386B6BE935598E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), no credit shall be allowed under subsection (a) to an eligible individual who is, for each day during calendar year 2021, described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of section 202(x)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/402">42 U.S.C. 402(x)(1)(A)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8F7654B94094632A0AC1381CDD079CB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Joint return</header><text>In the case of a joint return where 1 spouse is described in subparagraph (A), subsection (g) shall be applied by treating such spouse as having failed to include the valid identification number of such spouse on the return of tax for the taxable year. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28DB3AFA6680428698E17A2310A5633A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of advance refund or credit</header><text>No refund or credit shall be made or allowed under subsection (f) with respect to any individual whom the Secretary has knowledge is, at the time of any determination made pursuant to paragraph (3) of such subsection, described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of section 202(x)(1)(A) of the Social Security Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0966C122D1A449A08C54CA2410AF084D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2020.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7B7CFB9DD22E4FF5921D89E14161468F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Disclosure of certain prisoner tax return information to Department of Justice</header><subsection id="HBFE4DA764F1A458B90593834D0F61745"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6103">Section 6103(l)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H65737A21465047868C8B0EE4D6B0EAAD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HC125D28727504FA89EEB7A1654346DB6"><enum>(23)</enum><header>Disclosure of return information to Department of Justice to carry out the Pay Victims Not Prisoners Act</header><subparagraph id="H7D5078268D4B484FB00798D9EAA9CD87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, upon written request from the Attorney General, disclose to officers, employees, and contractors of the Department of Justice the return information of a taxpayer whose prisoner commissary account may be subject to adjustment under section 4 of the <short-title>Pay Victims Not Prisoners Act</short-title>. Such return information shall be limited to—</text><clause id="HD00365FB065C4D4CB607041E4A100AB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">taxpayer identity information with respect to such taxpayer, and </text></clause><clause id="H1BBDC5028A4F4F96AE8DA9094E1A70B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to the refundable credit under section 6428B—</text><subclause id="HF2CF4261A59B4C8BB2AD20684CE30237"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount of the refundable credit allowed to such taxpayer under such section, </text></subclause><subclause id="H6D53489A8DC94B1D8A4E8F546BF35F67"><enum>(II)</enum><text>verification of whether such refundable credit was disbursed electronically or via paper check, </text></subclause><subclause id="HE747A152F001471D921277B57F4F76CC"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such refundable credit was disbursed electronically, verification of the account to which such refund was disbursed, </text></subclause><subclause id="H4ABCD76B0C1A47A3BF411DC0B934D1E8"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the date on which such refund was disbursed, and </text></subclause><subclause id="H98CE0C304E544164B2909E5790964081"><enum>(V)</enum><text>if applicable, the fact that there was no refund disbursed to such taxpayer with respect to such section. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6915EE54453A483E8D37FA4B555C6B1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by this section shall apply to disclosures made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H82A2F939F06A45EA9A5AEBFE8730C3F7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Payment of outstanding judgments against Federal prisoners using 2021 recovery rebate credits</header><subsection id="HC580B2E801C04A2D9B73B56B9F39BCE7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of prisoners who received 2021 recovery rebate credits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall identify—</text><paragraph id="HCCC503085D4C405B82E73BAD2C42C53A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Federal prisoners who received a disbursement of a refundable credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6428B">section 6428B</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, which was disbursed to the prisoner’s commissary account; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57272AFD6774426291BA6657D353920C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>of the Federal prisoners identified under paragraph (1), the prisoners who owe money pursuant to a judgment issued by a Federal court. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB992D80C7FC64443BAE21CDC78E6217B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payment of outstanding judgments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall make payments on any judgment described in subsection (a)(2) using amounts remaining in the prisoner’s commissary account from the disbursement described in subsection (a)(1). </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

