<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0D3DC85367394E84A7FAB1DC4612A3B9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7195 IH: To provide for certain whistleblower incentives and protections.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7195</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220324">March 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for certain whistleblower incentives and protections.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC230B9E20CC42A5972B21AA47769083" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7D51206905D54980AAC8C6A91348C75B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Whistleblower incentives and protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5323 of title 31, United States Code, as amended by section 6314 of the Anti-Money Laundering Act of 2020 (division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE0A2299C56144A69D43CA137DEE610E"> <subsection id="HF48403290BCD4824AB929BA150FC364C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards</header> <paragraph id="HE50D03C410D347CE9DBD21E3EA14071C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any covered judicial or administrative action, or related action, the Secretary, under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, in consultation with the Attorney General and subject to subsection (c), shall pay an award or awards to 1 or more whistleblowers who voluntarily provided original information to the employer of the individual, the Secretary, or the Attorney General, as applicable, that led to the successful enforcement of the covered judicial or administrative action, or related action, in an aggregate amount equal to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDFDDDA029F094755B9A89A002FB20163"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less than 10 percent, in total, of what has been collected of the monetary sanctions imposed in the action or related actions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1280819A5D0F4CF0B99E2FF3F2124B6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 30 percent, in total, of what has been collected of the monetary sanctions imposed in the action or related actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H871F01F77C28494D9E6EE04E23D72062"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payment of awards</header><text>Any amount paid under paragraph (1) shall be paid from the Fund established under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DAA92055275460F80FBDAA235B8E061"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Source of awards</header> <subparagraph id="H4444F8809D414B4C8465913354A89D6F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be established in the Treasury of the United States a revolving fund to be known as the Financial Integrity Fund (referred to in this subsection as the <term>Fund</term>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD30CBF09F1AF406CAA4370FD6D1DFDF1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of Fund</header><text>The Fund shall be available to the Secretary, without further appropriation or fiscal year limitations, only for the payment of awards to whistleblowers as provided in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H711FAF43401F46739E7AB2740199E4F4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Restrictions on use of fund</header><text>The Fund shall not be available to pay any personnel or administrative expenses. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HED4501226DD5422BA6EC130EE84BB358"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deposits and credits</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA0409B3DA3E04AE1887040F4AC5B9950"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There shall be deposited into or credited to the Fund an amount equal to—</text> <clause id="H6F9A139B65304431BDCC4AC63B6160AC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any monetary sanction collected by the Secretary or Attorney General in any judicial or administrative action under this title unless the balance of the Fund at the time the monetary judgement is collected exceeds $300,000,000; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H05DEFF173EB5492CB1D707E87C8F80A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all income from investments made under paragraph (5).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5BD33A82C83945D8A97EE4867355401F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional amounts</header><text>If the amounts deposited into or credited to the Fund under subparagraph (A) are not sufficient to satisfy an award made under this subsection, there shall be deposited into or credited to the Fund an amount equal to the unsatisfied portion of the award from any monetary sanction collected by the Secretary of the Treasury or Attorney General in the covered judicial or administrative action on which the award is based. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2676232DB3A44894AA6950CA715E6BCF"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Investments</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEDF070E8974647B6B58E3EE403C7F253"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Amounts in Fund may be invested</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may invest the portion of the Fund that is not required to meet the current needs of the Fund.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC3DBB11F9AE4FA6845A08562DB078C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligible investments</header><text>Investments shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury in obligations of the United States or obligations that are guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States, with maturities suitable to the needs of the Fund as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE0C1CC847C7E4596B5396C989177611E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Interest and proceeds credited</header><text>The interest on, and the proceeds from the sale or redemption of, any obligations held in the Fund shall be credited to, and form a part of, the Fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

