<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H43977920A0C34E97AAB268313187477A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>105 HR 7632 IH: Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7632</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001180">Mr. Schrader</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water on Tribal lands, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H985044FBC2DD4553ABBAEFC7680C975C" style="OLC"><section id="H46A021619ED6499989306450AE763793" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Access to Clean Water Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB19B89815C554D1E9EE797074D8B3DDC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HA72601D03F41408B8DBBD7DAE02A8E3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water is an essential human need and critical to the public health, well-being, educational attainment, and economic development of all communities in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72DD0A42B83B4F37A1C476FF063E490C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>many countries, along with the United Nations, have recognized the urgency of the need to access reliable, clean, and drinkable water by passing laws or resolutions relating to the human right to water and sanitation, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA9A4047052AA4263BCBB9D14FC9DA681"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognizing these water and sanitation needs exist among Indigenous peoples; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FAE9D5D12134EAB946701C4ED71E0BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing aggressive targets for achieving universal access to those basic services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB98A125A7757450CAFE601F0171316B6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the United States, access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water has long been a significant problem in many Native communities, such that nearly half of all households in those communities do not have access to reliable water sources, clean drinking water, or basic sanitation, and are significantly more likely than White households to lack indoor plumbing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6427C47FC218445B96B00EF2936B763C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the trust responsibility of the Federal Government to Indian Tribes requires the Federal Government to ensure the survival and welfare of Indian Tribes, and the failure to provide basic water service cannot be reconciled with that trust responsibility;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27BF166B69AC4EDA9967F0F2A5366CF8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the ongoing COVID–19 pandemic has had a disproportionate impact on Native communities due to a multitude of factors, including—</text><subparagraph id="H99CC2628266C4906B009F3CF6B7F9C53"><enum>(A)</enum><text>persistent economic disadvantages;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5BC25A810604A03AE21358FE1C315A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>racial inequity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A9739ACFC294AF096819F4B82F47523"><enum>(C)</enum><text>lack of public health infrastructure, including access to running water;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB54ED8AEA12148159E5606C0A24B3156"><enum>(6)</enum><text>on January 27, 2021, President Biden issued Executive Order 14008 (86 Fed. Reg. 7619 (February 1, 2021)), which provides that it is the policy of the Biden Administration to secure environmental justice and spur economic opportunity for disadvantaged communities that have been historically marginalized and overburdened by pollution and underinvestment in housing, transportation, water and wastewater infrastructure, and health care;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B819C28B0CB446A8CF4CFB6C1EA03B3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>through the bipartisan Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (IIJA), H.R. 3684, Congress has provided funding for the Indian Health Service and the Environmental Protection Agency to support the construction and repair of Tribal clean water infrastructure but no funding has yet been provided to assist Tribes with operation and maintenance of water infrastructure and such funding is necessary to protect the historic investment in this infrastructure and to offset Tribes’ inability to access funding sources relied upon by most municipal water providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2A0B6F5D9064EE09360559B94006F40"><enum>(8)</enum><text>technical assistance to Tribes is also necessary to ensure that they are able to access and take advantage of the new construction funding made available through the IIJA, that they develop the managerial, financial, and regulatory framework necessary for a fully functional and self-sustaining utility, and that they are able to engage appropriate outside consultants to assist as needed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21CB1A68B02B41E0A1AE990BA97581D6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>advances in water technology, including treatment, sensors, and innovative pipeline materials, can assist in—</text><subparagraph id="H499CDB91F45D41259752B2FBB523230C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accelerating efforts to provide universal access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water for all Native communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC2F64DB6C5E474FADCB5F3F445ADA13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing resilience in the face of climate change;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1EBE1E0E83041EAA98793D9634DDDF3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the COVID–19 pandemic has been a stark reminder that access to reliable, clean, and drinkable water to support basic hygiene is a matter of life or death for all individuals in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5AB96C81C0E42839EA46E7B14287C38"><enum>(11)</enum><text>it is in the interest of the United States, and it is the policy of the United States, that all existing Native communities be provided with safe and adequate water supply systems as soon as practicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2FEC7F1AB6247D9A7AA8013AFAF204C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>both appropriate funding at the level of unmet need and a <quote>whole of government</quote> approach among all Federal agencies are essential to provide a meaningful solution to the lack of access to clean water on Tribal lands.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCD4DD5F6C1294624858DED97FA57F458"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H43A5803B167B43808622F32DF5EE8BA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Indian Health Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2843BC36C0814AC882A9CD8E573D2211"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF782F374F80248C38A5F2C5BBD9C879C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Native community</header><text>The term <term>Native community</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD77E22348FF348DE86185E0914DEFB08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0507677D5604F4EABB1BA6B6F133645"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H356E66E9709B4C5B9012980755E293E5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Native Hawaiian</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Native Hawaiian</term> has the meaning given that term in section 801 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H543D6AEFD2FB4D97823E241E87959DFC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The term <term>Report</term> means the most recent annual report required to be submitted by the Secretary of Health and Human Services to the President under section 302(g) of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1632">25 U.S.C. 1632(g)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F7060369A8D431698BD539893EA1D74"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except for the purposes of section 6, the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACAD39D64DD34FA2ADB698A49AB9263F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Tribal land</header><text>The term <term>Tribal land</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H181D8BC1746241A0AD3E1E6BF4415175"><enum>(A)</enum><text>land located within the boundaries of—</text><clause id="H0B49DE72B4044442B24A8831669163BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria; or</text></clause><clause id="HF1D37A6F3FA146799429FDDF58387ACB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a former reservation within Oklahoma;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1324679929AE4E3B88635263F4A21F05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>land not located within the boundaries of an Indian reservation, pueblo, or rancheria, title to which is held—</text><clause id="H419D9C6031774E56BBB8E1ABB4BE9930"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian Tribe or an individual Indian;</text></clause><clause id="H749D1F17E9A84A0E97C8C935D155C479"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by an Indian Tribe or an individual Indian, subject to restriction against alienation under laws of the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="H0D6889C6A82A48EA86CFB94CED38F9C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by a dependent Indian community;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H969233EF92C243148596552FA4D018AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>land located within a region established pursuant to section 7(a) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1606">43 U.S.C. 1606(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF3C091145A84228B479AC8CFC43052B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Hawaiian Home Lands (as defined in section 801 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4221">25 U.S.C. 4221</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5066A7DDFC6D498B9FC172F3880ABFAE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>an area or community designated by the Assistant Secretary of Indian Affairs of the Department of the Interior that are near, adjacent, or contiguous to an Indian reservation where financial assistance and social service programs are provided to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HEAD6F892F8AA41839302A9C63B2CC363"><enum>4.</enum><header>Indian health service</header><subsection id="H23D25737859C4851AE587BDDB47CF15B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sanitation facilities construction program</header><text>The term <term>Indian homes, communities, and lands</term> for which the Indian Health Service has authority <quote>to construct, improve, extend, or otherwise provide and maintain, by contract or otherwise, essential sanitation facilities, including domestic and community water supplies and facilities, drainage facilities, and sewage- and waste-disposal facilities</quote> pursuant to <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/86/121">Public Law 86–121</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2004a">42 U.S.C. 2004a</external-xref>) includes structures that are essential to the life of the Native community and provide indispensable educational, economic, and community services, such as schools, hospitals, nursing homes, teachers’ homes, Tribal offices, and post offices.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBB7581B6DF7148B0B369518189E68ACD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is appropriated to the Secretary, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $100,000,000 for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, to remain available until expended, for the provision of essential sanitation facilities to community structures included in subsection (a) and not previously considered eligible for such service.</text></subsection><subsection id="HABC421CAD1B047A88AF4421C55F7267B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $150,000,000 for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, to remain available until expended, for technical assistance support in Native communities and for other activities authorized under section 302(b)(2) of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1632">25 U.S.C. 1632(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD7FFB4C48DFD496B86CE794B5159C2C8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance funding</header><paragraph id="H4479DF8238284D51A91FA07A3CDB1E06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $500,000,000 for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, to remain available until expended, for the operation and maintenance of water facilities serving Native communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE04109B12C54B49AEAD685B4D17EB43"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority for funding</header><text>In awarding funding for the operation and maintenance of water facilities under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall prioritize water facilities that the Secretary determines to be the most in need of assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H244AE1D30B404AF4B83EFE083A2B84CE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Future funding</header><text>For not less than 5 years after the date on which an operation and maintenance of water facilities project described in paragraph (1) is completed, to the extent to which annual appropriations are available, the Secretary shall include the completed project as eligible for sustained funding support and guidance to ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="H709B42A75A3B426C8591EBD3A37BFBD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the investments in the water facilities are adequately maintained and operated for the health and welfare of Native communities served;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6684CF3213914AB8BCCD2B431839202F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the infrastructure investment is protected; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD426440E87D442B59A2FE7E745381B4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the intended economic benefit is realized.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1F46880B29804E768606CF5910EB5DAF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Department of Agriculture rural development</header><subsection id="HC2001A4796A148569E242A84E22AF455"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary of Agriculture, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $500,000,000 to make grants under sections 306C and 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c</external-xref>, 1926d) to eligible entities described in subsection (b) to provide for the development, use, and control of water (including the extension or improvement of existing water supply systems) in eligible entities the residents of which face significant health risks, as determined by the Secretary, due to a significant proportion of the residents of the eligible entity not having access to, or not being served by, an adequate affordable water supply system.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5BF028BE39EC4D8C8D8EB8644C0DBCB1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>An entity eligible to receive a grant using amounts appropriated by subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="HF7D37B5F78CA491E9A8BF1712F2C5478"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is a Native community; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H866918749E094AF58BF5DAE1CAB09925"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a grant under section 306D of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926d">7 U.S.C. 1926d</external-xref>), includes a consortium formed pursuant to section 325 of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/83">Public Law 105–83</external-xref> (111 Stat. 1597).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H341F30CD29E54B6484FD554DEF8610E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No matching contribution</header><text>The funds made available under subsection (a) shall not require any matching contribution otherwise required by any other provision of law (including regulations).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FE8F540956F46D99A596FD07B55985B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority for funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants to eligible entities using amounts appropriated by subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture shall—</text><paragraph id="H1B86A647E36640E898362D9BF734EE1A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>treat members of an eligible entity in the same manner as individuals who reside in a colonia for purposes of subsections (a)(2)(B) and (c)(2) of section 306C of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1926c">7 U.S.C. 1926c</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA72BE0FB79B1425EA51AB8CF607D6732"><enum>(2)</enum><text>award the grants without requiring an eligible entity or the members of an eligible entity to demonstrate an inability to finance the proposed project—</text><subparagraph id="H9DBA85914ADF4A838D4229D3D6CB1C07"><enum>(A)</enum><text>from the resources of the eligible entity or members; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96F2B93FF7CD4B08AE6D91E7FE9C581F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>through commercial credit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8A3B3E861F8041E290AC2CC67BAB4819"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency collaboration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with the Director regarding agency collaboration, project prioritization, and staffing needs to ensure the amounts made available under this section are used in the most effective manner to promote access to water and sanitation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2D1D46C028004996A7D649B7EB264F20"><enum>6.</enum><header>Bureau of Reclamation</header><subsection id="H0242A00545C14D53909F5625EC8C83F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rural water supply program reauthorization</header><paragraph id="H3562A411B4704EB7ACA93C77071D9373"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Section 109(a) of the Rural Water Supply Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2408">43 U.S.C. 2408(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2032</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E961CCA817B4C8AAABD31F570A265CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>Section 110 of the Rural Water Supply Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2409">43 U.S.C. 2409</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2016</quote> and inserting <quote>2032</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41E69C2EDA454DDBA8D1941647423E12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bureau of reclamation rural water supply program</header><paragraph id="H874FFB5DF9B74737A03217A27E0180D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HD2F97001297344049F7CB5524DAE2906"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reclamation state</header><text>The term <term>Reclamation State</term> means a State described in the first section of the Act of June 17, 1902 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/391">43 U.S.C. 391</external-xref>; 32 Stat. 388, chapter 1093).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAF667164C324CF697C1D5E913CA11BF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB622DACFC90549CD9B2D974C2A6D3327"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Competitive grant program for tribal clean water access projects</header><subparagraph id="H5E0D2F29ED4743078A23194871C3E6FB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>In accordance with section 103 of the Rural Water Supply Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2402">43 U.S.C. 2402</external-xref>), the Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program under which an Indian Tribe shall be eligible to apply for a grant from the Secretary in an amount not to exceed 100 percent of the cost of planning, design, and construction of a project determined by the Secretary to be eligible for funding under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B9FB6687F1F49BF9D8B6460E7A7CF15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under subparagraph (A), a project shall, as determined by the Secretary—</text><clause id="HD018387B6AF44BBE963B736BC3F839FC"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC36C397CE1EB413E84D09473AD1EFD01"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide, increase, or enhance access to safe drinking water for communities and households on Tribal land; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H971C82B186064042A7A15886E3FAF028" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>address public health and safety concerns associated with access to safe drinking water; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB7F668DE593B4E3088A9BB53EE473D2C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be carried out in a Reclamation State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44609A5A2506477B833D99A2C20E5AAC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Priority</header><clause id="H3FEDDD08D7F04CD0AB701201AFBA634C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In providing grants under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall give priority to projects that meet 1 or more of the following criteria:</text><subclause id="H77E42E0C1DD24A0E936540A2E8861CDE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A project that would provide potable water supplies to communities or households on Tribal land that do not have access to running water as of the date of the project application.</text></subclause><subclause id="H4EBBF5DAE889457BA13031260C1431DE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A project that would address an urgent and compelling public health or safety concern relating to access to safe drinking water for residents on Tribal land.</text></subclause><subclause id="H4D302C4B64CD4650887E039EE34D44C7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A project that would address needs identified in the Report.</text></subclause><subclause id="H1C1BE492AD6445E1A2C7E4740291AD6A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>A project that is closer to being completed, or farther along in planning, design, or construction, as compared to other projects being considered for funding.</text></subclause><subclause id="H0AB63DBB39DC4745905B9DA88F6F435E"><enum>(V)</enum><text>A project that would take advantage of the experience and technical expertise of the Bureau of Reclamation in the planning, design, and construction of rural water projects, particularly with respect to a project that takes advantage of economies of scale.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7A5D97D7C6774822BEA428CD768DFFF5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>A project that would take advantage of local or regional partnerships that complement related efforts by Tribal, State, or Federal agencies to enhance access to drinking water or water sanitation services on Tribal land.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5933AD685FA44F8EAD3D9B2E76F1BA57"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>A project that would leverage the resources or capabilities of other Tribal, State, or Federal agencies to accelerate planning, design, and construction.</text></subclause><subclause id="HB4531B8324A24678A82D176C41802B06"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>A project that would provide multiple benefits, including—</text><item id="H22E023F936304524A2C2DE17D3073DC8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>improved water supply reliability;</text></item><item id="H94CB4E0437C04CB6B93EFBCF895C8559"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>public health improvements;</text></item><item id="HCE0732C4686F4EB5B976003511BCF534"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>ecosystem benefits;</text></item><item id="H21E39FCBEA1C4DF09525D5254696C0AE"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>groundwater management and enhancements; and</text></item><item id="HBB891CB99E9247B39F38F0132C4A53BF"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>water quality improvements.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HDA2108880F7442A7B586A34AC78E4FEB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In prioritizing projects for funding under clause (i), the Secretary—</text><subclause id="HF85326D6F2DF47EAA7668FD344FFE9D4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall consult with the Director; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1A849571F7CC4A6A9226107613A9BD9F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may coordinate funding of projects under this paragraph with the Director, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the head of any other Federal agency in any manner that the Secretary determines would—</text><item id="HE2CE7307454547F19993F7865199486A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>accelerate project planning, design, or construction; or</text></item><item id="H5F4B231C2F854157A0CFE0632790B5CF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>otherwise take advantage of the capabilities of, and resources potentially available from, other Federal sources.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34E23BBE0599492CAD7C0D22C585EEAE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Funding</header><subparagraph id="H9AA7C36A9781494D8E9D1F8D465EBE16"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,000,000,000 to carry out this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF895D9480F27451F825267F40E2ACD92"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administrative expenses; use of funds</header><text>Of the amounts made available under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may use up to 2 percent for—</text><clause id="H14BA6856F8404F2883D28FD2F5675A80" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the administration of the rural water supply program established under section 103 of the Rural Water Supply Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2402">43 U.S.C. 2402</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="HB310BA1C4769459FB8D4DA6640A0B811"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>related management and staffing expenses.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8937FB13850F43A1B46CC8301AE77A1F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding for Native American Affairs Technical Assistance Program of the Bureau of Reclamation</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated to the Secretary of the Interior, out of amounts in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $90,000,000 for use, in accordance with section 201 of the Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/373d">43 U.S.C. 373d</external-xref>), for the Native American Affairs Technical Assistance Program of the Bureau of Reclamation for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

