<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H6870FA4D79A44FC5B6ABFB18F17B1181" public-private="private" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 680 RH: For the relief of Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, and Vandana Kurdekar.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">VII</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Private Calendar No. 2</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 680</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–237]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210201">February 1, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>; referred to the Private Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">For the relief of Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, and Vandana Kurdekar.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F2FADB519B44E08BDD13AADBE9BDDD6" style="OLC"><section id="H06740B9502D84992A21C0DD2DE862EBE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Permanent resident status for Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, and Vandana Kurdekar</header><subsection id="HE68360DD4FDF4402A1D4C57362268C44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsections (a) and (b) of section 201 of the Immigration and Nationality Act, Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, and Vandana Kurdekar shall each be eligible for issuance of an immigrant visa or for adjustment of status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence upon filing an application for issuance of an immigrant visa under section 204 of such Act or for adjustment of status to lawful permanent resident.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF18951186DF2483FBB46C1B35CBA2C0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, or Vandana Kurdekar enters the United States before the filing deadline specified in subsection (c), he or she shall be considered to have entered and remained lawfully and shall, if otherwise eligible, be eligible for adjustment of status under section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40E4AE00F9D649B88244B120F01A5D79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadline for application and payment of fees</header><text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall apply only if the application for issuance of an immigrant visa or the application for adjustment of status is filed with appropriate fees within 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H59E788D8575A41F3B2AEB8338ADC09A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reduction of immigrant visa number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the granting of an immigrant visa or permanent residence to Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, and Vandana Kurdekar, the Secretary of State shall instruct the proper officer to reduce by 3, during the current or next following fiscal year, the total number of immigrant visas that are made available to natives of the country of the aliens’ birth under section 203(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act or, if applicable, the total number of immigrant visas that are made available to natives of the country of the aliens’ birth under section 202(e) of such Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA00E24DDB5334745A03CE3DDA12FF6EF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Denial of preferential immigration treatment for certain relatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The natural parents, brothers, and sisters of Arpita Kurdekar, Girish Kurdekar, and Vandana Kurdekar shall not, by virtue of such relationship, be accorded any right, privilege, or status under the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the Private Calendar and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

