<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9136A9A670B41AAADE6BD280FBAF049" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9541 IH: Strengthening Measures to Advance Rights Technologies Copyright Act of 2023</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9541</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="A000377">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 17, United States Code, to define and provide for accommodation and designation of technical measures to identify, protect, or manage copyrighted works, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2620C47B8237428A8DCEA1E3A9C54142" style="OLC"><section id="HB49A8C69ED7948BF84A5F85FFFCBE755" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Measures to Advance Rights Technologies Copyright Act of 2023</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SMART Copyright Act of 2023</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE40FADF928AE48B88FE26C14E459665F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of use in the marketplace of certain technical measures to identify or protect copyrighted works</header><subsection id="H41BF1F330E0046ED9C65580D3E3320B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/5">Chapter 5</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H67CF3C218BB54656A3B99D2D59878874"><section id="H822B54306F1247168C9B0CD20D9D7399"><enum>514.</enum><header>Designation of use in the marketplace of certain technical measures to identify or protect copyrighted works</header><subsection id="H2F34A3C6E70D4C2DB1B0E13899CABBD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5281654710144D31B9D1569E3B8F1EF3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered service provider</header><text>The term <term>covered service provider</term> means a service provider to which a designated technical measure applies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD02CF5AF3EE443296D2BAC8E58EAC99"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designated technical measure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>designated technical measure</term> means a technical measure that has been designated by the Librarian in accordance with subsections (c), (d), and (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F92CA5064384FE8A74AF412DAEB9B20" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Librarian</header><text>The term <term>Librarian</term> means the Librarian of Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE598DF8BF02E4B79B820F921973A059C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Proposed technical measure</header><text>The term <term>proposed technical measure</term> means a technical measure that is proposed by a person under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79874C1EF86E4F5D8F5671803A2EF504" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Register</header><text>The term <term>Register</term> means the Register of Copyrights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A9741BD0EEB482F9E6C298C53B87534" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Service provider</header><text>The term <term>service provider</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBBA04B003CB5498386AD9A2E92FD0686" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a provider of online services or network access, or the operator of facilities therefor, that—</text><clause id="H89E08BFCE00A4640803864099D2EB6E6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides storage at the direction of a user of material that resides on a system or network controlled or operated by or for the service provider;</text></clause><clause id="H937D52A8E44647FAB5DF364D505AF8B1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>refers or links users to an online location by using information location tools, including a directory, index, reference, pointer, or hypertext link; and/or</text></clause><clause id="H4999A397A83E42F6873D771E48E80518" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>provides the intermediate and temporary storage of material on a system or network controlled or operated by or for the service provider in a case in which—</text><subclause id="HEDE14A5C866C463E9B25CF1DCC258293" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the material is made available online by a person other than the service provider;</text></subclause><subclause id="H833D93AFB5A64C0FB0032E2BAE43D781" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the material is transmitted from the person described in clause (i) through the system or network to a person other than the person described in clause (i) at the direction of that other person; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB09BBDFA3588430FB409B9E37BCAD235" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the storage is carried out through an automatic technical process for the purpose of making the material available to users of the system or network who, after the material is transmitted as described in clause (ii), request access to the material from the person described in clause (i); and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339F8B0C008B45B0AB0A4ED6FFEB2D1A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term does not include—</text><clause id="H9ADCFFF2EC844BBA8A208DE12343765D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a library or archives—</text><subclause id="H948125AE227147B1A474E5EA19D9B23A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whose collections are open to the public, or are available not only to researchers affiliated with the library or archives or with the institution of which it is a part, but also to other persons doing research in a specialized field;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7FFDB4E57E214C1D8C46C0FBC5598458" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>that has a public service mission;</text></subclause><subclause id="H853063C293C74B229BC667FE52C6DFD9" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>whose trained staff or volunteers provide professional services normally associated with libraries or archives; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0BFB1F2481774EE0AA4F06A0CFBAC47C" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>whose collections are composed of lawfully acquired and/or licensed materials;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6F2FF9526CE742B7A59AAD056E5B7E09" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a nonprofit educational institution; or</text></clause><clause id="H13714464C087448D882DBA25C62B96EF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other person solely with regard to providing the services described in section 512(k) to an institution described in subparagraph (i) or (ii) in the course of providing such services to such institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDFBC38777B4457E93A49086725A268C" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Technical measure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>technical measure</term> means a technical measure that is used in commerce by a copyright owner or a service provider to identify or protect a copyrighted work.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA90DB7A3E88840DC95E1FCE103E82A66" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employment of designated technical measures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered service provider shall use reasonable efforts to employ and effectively implement applicable designated technical measures.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFA9F79F24AA9434FBDDD7EA893B0973F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority of the Librarian</header><paragraph id="HB8E793317B2C4A6F8EF2222A27CDE38A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Designation of technical measures</header><text>The Librarian may, at the recommendation of the Register, and pursuant to subsections (d) and (e)—</text><subparagraph id="H80C86209D4264EB886F238AB3B037169" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>designate proposed technical measures that—</text><clause id="H6856DFC57F2D4165A9B4A1FF81602648" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are widely used in the marketplace by service providers; or</text></clause><clause id="HA64EE465BBB0489F8E925B580CF6C933" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are widely available in the marketplace on nondiscriminatory terms and a royalty-free basis;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1743BEF127A5451AAC7538C338DE2857" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rescind previous designations of technical measures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFC72E7DDEA54E5A8C79920CCF09A906" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>revise previous designations of technical measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49A34FB7DBE1436BB20B57C548EF405A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prescription of rules</header><text>The Librarian, upon consultation with the Register, shall prescribe rules that—</text><subparagraph id="H8A372D30474848FA9D68CDFE612AD81E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>implement subsections (d) and (e); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H267F670CD7F14640944D5EA7AAC9869B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide for the protection of confidential and sensitive information provided to the Librarian—</text><clause id="H73A51D2D36F1454A8AFA3381357922B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as part of a petition under subsection (d); or</text></clause><clause id="HD886B387E15246238466A0B64CB1893B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during a rulemaking under subsection (e).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H461DFC3CD1864983A1D1098182BC39F5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Petitions</header><paragraph id="H97BC802C37484EB48E17627F0A5E6DF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>SMART Copyright Act of 2023</short-title> and every 3 years thereafter, the Librarian shall accept petitions, from owners of copyrighted works, service providers, and other stakeholders, proposing the designation of a technical measure or the rescission or revision of a previous designation of a technical measure. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34AF364C9C0C4BFE882710BE8F5C9255"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Petition requirements</header><text>In the case of a petition submitted to the Librarian under paragraph (1) proposing the designation of a technical measure or review of a previous designation of a technical measure, as appropriate, the petition shall detail with specificity—</text><subparagraph id="H0B925BD6FFAA4E5D94B5F4A016DF9FB3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the proposed technical measure, or the designated technical measure as proposed to be revised, meets the definition of <quote>technical measure</quote> under subsection (a) and the criteria for designation of such technical measure under subsection (c)(1)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05D48150D7A94D35B2CF2087344BD142" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the classes of copyrighted works, or any subsets thereof, intended to be covered; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DE9F19D8D784A86ACE0B61678FCEA6F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the types of service provider, or any subsets thereof, intended to be covered.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF3102DA426847C0A1CE7E511AF01976"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation of petition</header><text>After each deadline under paragraph (1), the Librarian shall evaluate each petition received under that paragraph and take appropriate action as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HEF4A5B01E8D5425D87060E142D86D967"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Librarian may begin a rulemaking process to—</text><clause id="HBE5D6D0D897642DF96B109C97F1BF8FD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designate a proposed technical measure; or</text></clause><clause id="H43FBFB88902346C2A2F6F1BD0036874A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>rescind or revise a previous designation of a technical measure. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBE9F004BF124FFDA9BAE4157BD3BC46"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Librarian shall reject without a rulemaking proceeding a petition that proposes the designation or revision of a designation applicable to a privately owned technical measure, unless the petition is filed or joined by the owner of the technical measure proposed to be designated or whose previous designation is proposed to be revised.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11B7AAE3184F4BF99F09BA8D6B222D32"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rulemaking process</header><paragraph id="HB68304145A7F4B168E75F141F49FF0A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public comment</header><text>For any proposed technical measure or designated technical measure for which the Librarian has begun a rulemaking process under subsection (d)(3)(A), the public comment process shall include not less than 1 public hearing convened by the Register.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5FD415A7B764549A0898529524ED0E2" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Examination by Register</header><text>For any rulemaking process the Librarian has begun under subsection (d)(3)(A), with respect to each proposed technical measure, the Register, in making a recommendation under paragraph (3), shall consider whether the criteria set forth in subsection (c)(1)(A) have been met, and, in addition, shall take into account—</text><subparagraph id="H3568013AEBEB4C119FF36933FB684F27" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the proposed technical measure imposes substantial and disproportionate costs on service providers or substantial and disproportionate burdens on their systems or networks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38271229351C409AB0D90E30EE9E40B4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether there are any intellectual property rights that need to be licensed by service providers to employ and effectively implement the proposed technical measure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE27ABE5D1AF249CAAC32218426C964FA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total amount of alleged or demonstrated infringing activity occurring over systems or networks controlled by the types of service providers described in the petition, including the volume of valid takedown notices received by the service provider pursuant to section 512, taking into consideration the scale of the platform and existing systems to identify or protect copyrighted material;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB7687AB16F24402AE4133105451F14A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the positive or negative impact the proposed technical measure may have on criticism, comment, news reporting, teaching, scholarship, research, increasing information sharing, or other relevant public interest considerations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4270E4EE8EF41679A5DEE1FD4315D38" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the proposed technical measure poses a cybersecurity threat (as defined in section 102 of the Cybersecurity Information Sharing Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref>)) to, or would create a security vulnerability (as defined in such section 102) for, the information systems of the affected service providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB7A72557FF47AFAC18F590C171BC9C" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the impact the proposed technical measure may have on privacy and data protection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA681039E228E48EF9B66014724D5667D" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the impact the lack of use of the proposed technical measure may have on unfair competition among service providers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA125D5158D404901AD3C87C9D0E08646" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>whether certain categories or types of service providers should be exempt from the subset of service providers covered by the proposed technical measure, such as corporate or not-for-profit websites that permit user comments or posts, but have never or rarely had infringing activity on their services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD2C70D7A6B044E2BCA1CEAF5AD118D6" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>whether the proposed technical measure may conflict or interfere with other proposed technical measures or designated technical measures; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECD468D443CC4C7CBCC579D0902B5551" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>whether multiple proposed technical measures and designated technical measures should be subsumed under a broader category of designated technical measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9221B9AC36D549DA828A56C6FDA20674"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendation</header><text>The Register shall make a recommendation on each proposed technical measure, and each proposed revision or rescinding of a previous designation of a technical measure, that is considered under the rulemaking process under this subsection, and after consulting with the following, as appropriate:</text><subparagraph id="HB99D02DE23EC4DBDB89ADE8398FA946F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58DED204842E4ACFA9E769424E115A3C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81BBF37006794312A7152AD2939A9FFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any relevant cybersecurity agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85854EA1FD0940E28D19EB1B55CA9ED2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Decision</header><text>If, at the conclusion of the rulemaking process under this subsection, the Librarian determines based on the recommendation of the Register that a proposed technical measure should be designated under the authority granted in subsection (c), the Librarian shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7DA6ED5BD2A744779D69CD4E13074499"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9F44FD5B1919484198F5BC3B4815D8A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for a proposed technical measure, designate the proposed technical measure; or </text></clause><clause id="HE282257F7A86415491DFEA3CDF24FCEA" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a revision of a previous designation of a technical measure, set forth the revised designation of the technical measure;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD468C028E2641529BF7524A3843277F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for a proposed technical measure or a proposed revision of a previous designation of a technical measure—</text><clause id="HF22C81F3289C481B9C323D6B8CB4A984" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>describe, as part of the designation under subparagraph (A), the classes of copyrighted works, or any subsets thereof, and the types of covered service providers to which the technical measure applies; and</text></clause><clause id="H64B35208F84C4F96A098A27E287B3C6D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include in the description under clause (i), as appropriate, any category or subset of type of service provider that is exempt from the designation, such that the requirement under subsection (b) does not apply to those service providers;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEBEA63D10E544FF8C2C7A65EF71DFC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for a previous designation of a technical measure proposed to be rescinded, rescind the designation of the technical measure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE7A4EA781B4B0AB706DD369B29610A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a proposed technical measure or a previous designation of a technical measure proposed to be revised, provide examples or a definition with specificity for what <quote>employ and effectively implement</quote> means for the technical measure, taking into account how different covered service providers to which the technical measure applies may have to employ and effectively implement differently based on their size or other relevant characteristics, provided that no such examples shall imply that a particular proprietary product must be used;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC347A57A88744A48BF3B3C0DD72D6FBC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>publish a list of designated technical measures, including the description required under subparagraph (B)(i), to be in effect after the Librarian has designated technical measures or revised or rescinded previous designations of technical measures under the paragraph in the Federal Register and publish and maintain the list on the website of the Library of Congress; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFA32A8791EE4192B32B948B459F18BA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>for a proposed technical measure or a revised designation of a technical measure, publish a deadline, which shall not be earlier than 1 year after the date of publication, by which covered service providers shall implement the designated technical measure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC03EBA7C35D4E3986148A924B9F223F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public information</header><text>To assist the public in understanding the requirements under this section, the Register shall—</text><paragraph id="H154DA140E8D94EEBAAF9DAFEA7C6DCCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish on the website of the Copyright Office an index of cases relating to the requirements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE99F48D56334AC5991BF13B017597BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update the list published under paragraph (1) not less frequently than annually.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE47E8B8DDCF4B1091E8ABE152D9E88F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H108354FB6F644589B7D676B1E31967A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text><subparagraph id="H096DA804BC364D07B7F02990F6A2D9FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$900,000 for fiscal year 2023; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5FEEEB687AC42A4812A424324F4FB4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), $700,000 for fiscal year 2024 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7651FECB1F7449C9BD08F67A47A0D700"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text>The amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1)(B) for fiscal year 2025 and each fiscal year thereafter shall be adjusted annually to reflect the change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB4E05FF541F44FA3BD04A608354CF737"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Appeal to District of Columbia Circuit</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date on which the Librarian publishes a decision regarding a technical measure under subsection (e)(4), any covered service provider to which the technical measure applies and any party that submitted a petition under subsection (d) regarding the technical measure may appeal the decision to the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEB5D496AD98B42B098229B7567532EB9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Civil Remedies</header><paragraph id="H46E333172D0B4277BE9107B9755CEE11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civil actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A copyright owner may bring a civil action in an appropriate United States district court against a covered service provider for a violation of subsection (b) for the remedies provided in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65213B05D0CA4D8095275AA680E3B312"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority of the court</header><text>In an action brought under paragraph (1), if the court finds a violation of subsection (b), the court shall enter an order on such terms as it may deem reasonable to ensure compliance by the covered service provider with subsection (b) within an appropriate time period, and, in addition, the court may—</text><subparagraph id="H7A5C34A645584FA3BC07F9A7BD02CC3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>award damages, in accordance with paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3591C58005C242C1925731E451E67D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allow, in its discretion, the recovery of costs by or against any party other than the United States or an officer of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFFCB575E9B64BCEB96709755953FBE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>award, in its discretion, reasonable attorney fees and expert witness fees to the prevailing party.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A61C8C4201F43AABE4E76EB93CA62ED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Award of damages</header><subparagraph id="H0F21ACE6C2EF4A239A0F1B100C727075" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) or otherwise provided in this title, the court may award to the copyright owner bringing a claim under paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H3F45251F5B14437298E6DDE50E45199B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>statutory damages in the sum of not less than $5,000 and not more than $500,000 for each violation of subsection (b), as the court considers just; and</text></clause><clause id="H852896F15BF24C0089A987FBAB08A485" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a separate award of statutory damages in the sum of not less than $5,000 and not more than $500,000 for each month that a covered service provider fails to comply with subsection (b) after the time period ordered by the court in paragraph (2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6857E0516AF64F5593FEC54071BAE69C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Innocent Violations</header><text>The court, in its discretion, may reduce or remit the total award of damages in any action brought against a covered service provider under paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HFC747DE27B3E4C1CB4C409B663FA515B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in which the covered service provider proves by a preponderance of the evidence that the covered service provider was not aware and had no reason to believe that its acts constituted a violation of subsection (b); or </text></clause><clause id="HBBF3B53D29E84645A21803AA87A993E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for reasons of equity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B94D1BD1DF74AA6AFF196D7C334ECA6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>No impact on safe harbor</header><paragraph id="H5013A90B05894DAF9B91E1344C0C0CD6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to alter the scope of the safe harbors set forth in subsections (a) through (e) of section 512, or to impose a condition on eligibility for those safe harbors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02A2F022C2444BEEA5E20DFA412FF862"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No defense to liability</header><text>The safe harbors set forth in subsections (a) through (e) of section 512 shall not constitute a defense to liability under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H32984C939CE94640B917EF862CBAF0B6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Limitation of liability</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (i), no covered service provider shall be held liable in a civil action on account of—</text><paragraph id="H17D8B9063A2B4947805020D7901B7CC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any action voluntarily taken in good faith under this section to restrict access to or availability of material; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A9A08F0FB54477F9DCB1052E716888B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any action taken under this section to enable or make available to covered service providers the technical means to restrict access to material described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H519057ABDB684E46BA49DE7404D7DB80"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/17/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 17, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H067AF784882F4ADD952C052EE658C34A"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">514. Designation of use in the marketplace of certain technical measures to identify or protect copyrighted works.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

