<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA7697AEEACC64570BAB62BBD6BE75792" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8911 IH: Monitoring and Investigating Nations Exploiting States Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8911</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220920">September 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior to produce a report on Russian and Chinese investments in mining and related industries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA233B02A1FE843C89B46D87ED60AFB6F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCC3839342AE048FAB2F31A4A3A88F96E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Monitoring and Investigating Nations Exploiting States Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>MINES Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H3FFEF25612604FB3BEDA1BDD4257C8F6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on investments of the Russian Federation and the People’s Republic of China in foreign mining and processing industries</header> <subsection id="H728DF6212A434637BFACBB8DE736E991"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA1C87260AAA94669B5C94C88FD687958"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the involvement of the Government of the People’s Republic of China, People’s Republic of China state-sponsored companies, and companies incorporated in the People’s Republic of China and the involvement of the Government of the Russian Federation, state-sponsored companies of the Russian Federation, and companies incorporated in the Russian Federation in the exploration, planning, development, operation, production, financing, or ownership of mining or processing facilities as identified in global investment trends by the World Mineral Outlook, and in countries identified in the United States Geological Survey’s Annual Mineral Commodity Summaries for which the United States imports minerals, metals, and materials; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAF34217D4904694B5C281D58240259D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluates strategic or security concerns and implications for United States national security and economic interests and the interests of the countries identified pursuant to paragraph (1) with respect to the People’s Republic of China’s involvement and influence in developing the country’s mining and processing industries.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H886578A5ED02401B9F6F266F2CBEBC47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be published on the respective websites of the Department of State, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Homeland Security, and the United States Geological Survey.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9BD4D4A1A40D4CBB9F37AC694BF9085B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2FA9D4CF9DA748F2A14A409B99006B21"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committee defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H76C7FD6A0ED04D009827EA095336E113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB935089E9B484336A2D6A85D9AA08E16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4DF76AFAADA1426E8D8BC0390275B335"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on mineral exploration and development in Afghanistan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7002(d)(1) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H13F9647A91C943DF97483581E66B97D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0466C6201B646DD9EA37696B6D1E871"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0B36FFF76F1B42B0904B941489960199"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3126425D329949CA8DDEA7A9BE7E4D13" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HA7DB5213071E44419660077B5EEBB76D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the involvement of the Government of the People’s Republic of China, state sponsored enterprises of such Government, and companies incorporated under the laws of such Government in the exploration, planning, development, operation, production, or ownership of mining or processing facilities in Afghanistan with respect to such mineral.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
<section id="H10AA798C7BCE4F19BECA2A7EE6602A47" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Annual review of critical mineral designations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7002(c)(5)(A) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)(5)(A)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B73250F19FC49318106FC2FDB02329F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="HBC8EE6DA6FEE402F9F6A45E5B5712FBE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretaries of Defense, Commerce, Agriculture, and Energy and the United States Trade Representative, shall review the methodology and list under paragraph (3) and the designations under paragraph (4)—</text> 
<clause id="H0C024B3EF1704229AA1CEC7CBBFFC50F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at least every 3 years;</text></clause> <clause id="H652191748C874EAD98E523AEFC69A479"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to a specific mineral, element, substance, or material, after any change in circumstances that has a substantial material effect on a factor described in paragraph (4)(A) relating to such mineral, element, substance, or material if such effect is likely to lead to a change in the listing status of such mineral, element, substance, or material under such paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE31A0BFFE5A84981A7AACE84397A895A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>more frequently as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

