<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7077 EAS: Empowering the U.S. Fire Administration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 7077</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221206">December 6, 2022.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="id8df97982c17f4bd9bc8a08ffac3c53d6" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 7077) entitled <quote>An Act to require the United States Fire Administration to conduct on-site investigations of major fires, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following: </text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="H852B74B29A7E439D896E73046A3C80CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering the U.S. Fire Administration Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H079B2BF3543A49469CE40BD5D4155FEB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fire safety investigations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Federal Fire Prevention and Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2201">15 U.S.C. 2201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4AE33ACD403D4B8791EA9A97E6F64E44" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HB6A8B0B454A74745A87E75A745A921DA"><enum>38.</enum><header>Investigation authorities</header><subsection id="HA0E00524028048B5B60CDC775C6E2E51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a major fire, the Administrator may send incident investigators, which may include safety specialists, fire protection engineers, codes and standards experts, researchers, and fire training specialists, to the site of the fire to conduct a fire safety investigation as described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H26E6245934754B52BB419CFF8B7688D9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigation required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A fire safety investigation conducted under this section—</text><paragraph id="H43C661C7253A4B75B5C2DDC0E5948DB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be conducted in coordination and cooperation with appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial authorities, including Federal agencies that are authorized to investigate any fire; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09AF06E86E134BDC85B1A782C42D6206"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall examine the previously determined cause and origin of the fire and assess broader systematic matters to include use of codes and standards, demographics, structural characteristics, smoke and fire dynamics (movement) during the event, and costs of associated injuries and deaths.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DCF1D3AAF824E8F86F2B59248023453"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="id62ADC0CF0B2B414BA5364E4835F5C3ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (2), upon concluding any fire safety investigation under this section, the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="id03C8614872CE4EFE9AF94C2B71761DF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue a public report to the appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial authorities on the findings of such investigation; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id069320BDA56448888EEC25AEE4A4DEC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaborate with another investigating Federal, State, local, Tribal, or territorial agency on the report of that agency. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5CE20E99FE9342AEA657A3C560BF6B78" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If the Administrator, in consultation with appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial authorities determines that issuing a report under paragraph (1) would have a negative impact on a potential or ongoing criminal investigation, the Administrator is not required to issue such report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idDF427280369A4636911C2D73CE0AE50C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public report issued under paragraph (1) shall include recommendations on—</text><subparagraph id="H93FBB3A52EF34782BB1BFA1F3BBE95A2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any other buildings with similar characteristics that may bear similar fire risks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F81F4A2A19D47AA8872A423707257D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving tactical response to similar fires;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66877A013F514C32A74F977AECE6DD39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving civilian safety practices; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF721DDD2126748A19CB6AC073C604050"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assessing the costs and benefits to the community of adding fire safety features; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41577099854A4CFCB5A3FC8FC15FD251"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how to mitigate the causes of the fire.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2A16FCC7CF9431CB1CAE609B3ACB582"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Discretionary authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to a fire safety investigation conducted pursuant to subsection (a), provided doing so would not have a negative impact on a potential or ongoing criminal investigation, the Administrator may send fire investigators to conduct a fire safety investigation at the site of any fire with unusual or remarkable context that results in losses less severe than those occurring as a result of a major fire, in coordination and cooperation with the appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial authorities, including Federal agencies that are authorized to investigate the fire.</text></subsection><subsection id="H28056EB8480144FFBB2B13F8C32083A3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to—</text><paragraph id="id3335240C425848FE9E6C5D06ED255975"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affect or otherwise diminish the authorities or the mandates vested in other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC3C591ED4FB5467FBE5D23540D5DD302"><enum>(2)</enum><text>grant the Administrator authority to investigate a major fire for the purpose of an enforcement action or criminal prosecution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idED4884BEF4F345DA9E62D53626882789"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require the Administrator to send investigators or issue a report for a major fire when the Administrator, in coordination and cooperation with the appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and territorial authorities, determine that it may compromise a potential or ongoing criminal investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idEAF9F6B710D143DD8B0B5B50F4843ABA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Major fire defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>major fire</term> shall have the meaning given such term under regulations to be issued by the Administrator.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 

