<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCB155DEB6069448EB01F73B02BD11E3B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6797 IH: Strengthening Citizenship Services for Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6797</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services to facilitate naturalization services for noncitizen veterans who have been removed from the United States or are inadmissible.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5ED9F0D105D9416DA8CBB1D4EDC2830F" style="OLC"><section id="HF73754F9BCA84EF88604066B89E8477E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Citizenship Services for Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF2B83DF3D61B45AB841E26AB68D08C53"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HAB482AF67B0B41C58E08B26956E642C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biometric collection</header><text>The term <term>biometric collection</term> means the biometric collection described in section 103.2(b)(9) of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations, during which the applicant provides information, including by providing fingerprints, photographs, or signatures, to confirm his or her identity and to satisfy any requirement for background and security checks in connection with an application to become a naturalized citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F9E3C9554C34E31BA41C5887940F508"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible veteran</header><text>The term <term>eligible veteran</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H1633E925211345B2904710B890BEF265"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a veteran who is a noncitizen; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9BAB4240B504B94929D500555EB2287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes any veteran who—</text><clause id="HB0AE2E3D5638459A95FA8D0EA5EE1178"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was removed from the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="HFA4844092D7445A59626D82CC7B52A29"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not in the United States and is inadmissible under section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC30A8E6522AD451986927D3275FAE550"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Naturalization examination</header><text>The term <term>naturalization examination</term> means the English and civics test that each noncitizen is required to pass (unless exempted) pursuant to section 312(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1423">8 U.S.C. 1423(a)</external-xref>) to become a naturalized citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F73E3B27D04C76ADBE402EDB5E3E68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Noncitizen</header><text>The term <term>noncitizen</term> means an individual who is not a citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68CD65582A354769B6D6C0B10A18165F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Oath of allegiance</header><text>The term <term>oath of allegiance</term> means the affirmation and ceremony necessary to become a naturalized citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H350C4EDE46674B35975712E28259A36C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2652D6B730F44592999FEBFFB62815F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Naturalization examinations and biometric collection for eligible veterans</header><subsection id="H1C63CB826F7F48FF9409DAAA77EBA6FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall ensure that the naturalization examination for each eligible veteran is conducted at—</text><paragraph id="HC2A8D585E22A454D8732509DA333869D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a United States port of entry that is accessible to the veteran; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD0003107C4640ABABFFA8C55F7BA962"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a United States embassy or consulate in the country in which the veteran resides.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H414EB2E3FEA745C4B8311C15ACF7F6F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Biometric collection</header><text>The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall ensure that biometric collection is made available for each eligible veteran at—</text><paragraph id="H13FA1DD53F51456B98F09D970C09F93E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a United States port of entry that is accessible to the veteran; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78BDF208A9094CB199A3A7AF89F2D0B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a United States embassy or consulate in the country in which the veteran resides.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE0EAC6BF1064C9DBC7F6654D87C3811"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Oath of allegiance</header><text>The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall ensure that the oath of allegiance for each eligible veteran is conducted at—</text><paragraph id="HFD84EB1E5AEB441CB5146A77EF88A2C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a United States port of entry that is accessible to the veteran; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3D13251BFD64F348E304CC5E32A94A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a United States embassy or consulate in the country in which the veteran resides.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2E869444DF0445449AAFB6C2E4EE01CC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Joint guidance from the secretary of homeland security and the secretary of state</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall jointly issue guidance regarding—</text><paragraph id="H5F4FB5E1FC5E4F3C9715E0D45B1567AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the methods used by the Department of Homeland Security to conduct biometric collections, naturalization examinations, and oath ceremonies for eligible veterans at a United States port of entry, embassy, or consulate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D0EEE269F7B4344ADEA3AD6B8DA9AAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the methods used by the Department of State to facilitate available space for the activities described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD243C69A57714F4D8F03455DDDC5B20A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>quality assurance mechanisms to ensure eligible veterans are able to complete the naturalization process at a port of entry, embassy, or consulate.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0BCEF2E958394B68913AF2FD972490E1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H16698E39B57441D7A2578FE8D4F3C897"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall jointly submit a report to the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate, the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives that contains an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H9FE043951B494F398A03DFC4181CE450"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the implementation of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69CD31000C214440B2ECA38C1C814A94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the effectiveness of the guidance issued pursuant to section 4.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A5B370608D5425A8328221E826651FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updated guidance</header><text>Not later than the last day of the 90-day period beginning on the date on which the report is submitted pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of State shall jointly update the guidance required under section 4 to the extent any shortcomings are identified in the report.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3AEC67AC8A414E65970BABC9DA7001F2"><enum>6.</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall promulgate regulations to implement this Act.</text></section><section id="HD39430BA6C974752A965E641BCF11876"><enum>7.</enum><header>Effective date; applicability</header><subsection id="HF2423A63EAFB491FBAE0D2AD9AA7D543"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2888DC8A20FE4FD7AA5D7A087EDEB239"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The requirements under this Act shall apply to all naturalization examinations involving eligible veterans with a pending naturalization application as of the date of the enactment of this Act or who submit a naturalization application after such date of enactment, regardless of the date on which the veterans were discharged from the military or exited the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

