<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54E2D359DFEA442A8CC1D82B637A6756" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8916 IH: Access to Reproductive Care for Servicemembers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8916</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220920">September 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish leave policies of the Armed Forces for a member to seek an abortion.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5CEDB2B86A3B4CEC9C77B4F992D10855" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H261107B72E80486FA460EE9138BC4412" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access to Reproductive Care for Servicemembers Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HEF658CA19E4A40FBAE07CF4D10F9590B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H2AA56BD15ECD447694C53263C26D852D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the Supreme Court’s decision to eliminate the right to abortion, States across the country are moving swiftly to ban abortion access, leading to even greater barriers to care for military families.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7707645E3A314173B49CCC413C66923E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Access to abortion care is essential to a person’s health and central to their economic and social well-being. Bans and restrictions on abortion delay access to abortion care and therefore increase costs for members of the Armed Forces seeking care. The consequence of these delays and barriers could mean that a person is forced to carry a pregnancy against their will.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE35AB636798D4AB782A48C30010A5194"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Armed Forces have a large presence in many States poised to ban or restrict access to abortion, many of which also neighbor States that would likely ban abortion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H19464CC7806F47E585673861C9BC6A91"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Members of the Armed Forces seeking care off-base may be limited in their ability to do so due to restrictions on leave or travel restrictions imposed by their unit.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE090B88B77B454F987D92DE1A79734F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Restrictions on receiving approval to take leave for abortion care interfere with a member of the Armed Forces’ health, well-being, and right to access the care they need. The decision to terminate a pregnancy should not depend on the discretion or judgment of a military commander.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87EEC2AC26BA4E0E87CAB3D0F51ABE06"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Army has recognized that abortion is a time sensitive-procedure and access should not be delayed for members or military families.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE48F0D8DE4DA4CADABE8B72C3F4DA9B6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When a member of the Armed Forces decides to obtain an abortion, it should be available, affordable, private, and free from punishment, reprisal, or judgment by the member’s chain of command.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE534E83C701245A3AB6AE35C7D660F09"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The harms of abortion-specific restrictions fall most heavily on people who already face barriers to accessing health care including people with low incomes, such as junior members, and Black, Indigenous, and people of color, immigrants, young people, people with disabilities, the LGBTQI+ community, and those stationed in rural and other medically underserved areas.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F63F82C54554F96950EB94892D53F42"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Equal access to abortion care, everywhere, is essential to social and economic participation, equality, reproductive autonomy, and the right to determine a person’s own life.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC076BB1E1BC74B4DB2C9B6368B11A85D"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The denial of leave for an abortion or any other reproductive health service violates the rights of members of the Armed Forces. Access to care for military families should not be determined by the personal beliefs of others.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA3996A95A6FB4BD9B8D3CA654C272A1A"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to the health and well-being implications for members of the Armed Forces and their families, the failure to address these issues will contribute to the challenges that the Armed Forces faces in attracting and retaining personnel, thereby negatively affecting military strength and readiness.</text></paragraph> </section> <section id="H5C420A92BC8741B88F0452CDCBB6CB24"><enum>3.</enum><header>Leave for a member of the Armed Forces for abortion</header> <subsection id="H527ABE92BC754B25AEB3997936D09117"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned (as such term is defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code) shall, with regards to abortion care for a member of the Armed Forces—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2BCD433A6AC0468FA63AD4F0411D03F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider such care to be time-sensitive and therefore approve leave for such abortion care; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDAA103045B7F4980A7EE559BCC100674"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not require the member to disclose to a commanding officer the time-sensitive care or procedure being received during such leave.</text></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H13593126C62645CEACCB6BD1B9D65B08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reimbursement for travel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a jurisdiction where abortion is prohibited or inaccessible, the Secretary concerned shall reimburse the member for costs incurred by the member to travel to a different jurisdiction for an abortion.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAA6443DDD62B4F9EB1D7C615E8AD7C58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Privacy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Health care providers of the Defense Health Agency and commanding officers shall, to the greatest extent practicable, protect the privacy of a member who takes leave under this section, including when such member makes a request for such leave and when such member returns to duty.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5448D1B40FD478182E7EDD789DF9BF4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No member of the Armed Forces may be subject to any adverse action for requesting or taking leave under this section.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

