<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD278E15B7D324638B1AD625D136210C4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6491 IH: Salmon Focused Investments in Sustainable Habitats Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6491</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220125">January 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the identification of salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD3FE659DA5EB4AE3ADFC389623533124" style="OLC"><section id="H971CB226D7BE44288ED44555F09221D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Salmon Focused Investments in Sustainable Habitats Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Salmon FISH Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H1F7BD0D45E2548FEADEEAA7111B73D0E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4E5345DECBCA4CC69E49BB4DB737ADB3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pacific and Atlantic salmon are important for food, culture, ecology, and the economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39389A2C16104B56B59E3D37BEDA2009"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Salmon are especially important to Indian tribes, many of which consider salmon to be sacred and central to their culture, ceremonies, and subsistence.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5F1A04EF7B46EEB584AED5827AAA92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such Indian tribes have significant leadership and expertise with respect to salmon.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H512E502579D8414C88CC221FF1E63160"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HE338A900A73046959F3DFABFA1F1F65C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4(e) of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304(e)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H677215D959A043A1A266288EDF7DDE83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Salmon</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>salmon</term> means any of the wild anadromous Oncorhynchus species that occur in the Western United States, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6A49A07B3C554777A27AC40CB75A0E6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Atlantic salmon (Salmo salar);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08CE8FE1BA4D480DA2D3B5E071D6F31E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>chum salmon (Oncorhynchus keta);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE69B2B3F0324C96B71037A873105F4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>pink salmon (Oncorhynchus gorbuscha);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC83E13956E4F4404A19FC197AF8AB468"><enum>(D)</enum><text>sockeye salmon (Oncorhynchus nerka);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35B96C7A619141FBADDFA73CBCD4C495"><enum>(E)</enum><text>chinook salmon (Oncorhynchus tshawytscha);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5FC9900CF8E48E8918442A371A1F65C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>coho salmon (Oncorhynchus kisutch); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H380F76F9B3F74EBF80ED4BB9474435CA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>steelhead trout (Oncorhynchus mykiss).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H944156E395294BD0A6D161FA5513B724"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Salmon conservation area</header><text>The term <term>salmon conservation area</term> means a watershed, a portion of a watershed, mutliple watersheds, or other defined spatial unit that—</text><subparagraph id="H2CC7304F7DA04CF9A0FE6CE84977F8EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is identified as a salmon conservation area under section 4(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2316FAE590D245138D50EBB870A59BFB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of the identification described in subparagraph (A), meets the biological criteria (as identified by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service in coordination with the relevant Federal agency with jurisdiction over such salmon conservation area) for abundance, productivity, diversity (genetic and life history), habitat quality, or other biological attributes important to sustaining viable populations of salmon throughout the range of such salmon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58818F38217C4A4AAE7E07F4C997541B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is regionally significant for the conservation of salmon.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05CC7B0608FA493EBDB2D691DC1EE006" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Salmon stronghold</header><text>The term <term>salmon stronghold</term> means a salmon conservation area that—</text><subparagraph id="HCC27A515062D4B30955D438F8804DE06" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is identified as a salmon conservation area under section 4(b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED69D7E494FB4429B7074B6288B8D516" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of the identification described in subparagraph (A), has—</text><clause id="H864AD80EE85F49C3874FA11EEE805444" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relatively high anadromous salmonid abundance, productivity, and diversity (life history and run timing), as well as habitat quality or other biological attributes important to sustaining viable populations of wild salmon throughout the range of such salmon;</text></clause><clause id="H60C58B8344EB4FE59C577B572B39EC09" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>populations of salmon that are strong and diverse; and</text></clause><clause id="HE7CE2FCEBAA440F096593C22C2C26186" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>salmon habitats that have a high intrinsic potential to support a particular species or suite of species. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H277CCFAF1E724AE9A39C53B5EA7A3C29"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant Federal ageny</header><text>The term <term>relevant Federal agency</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD21FF147C3B146E0B16609A9BCEFEBA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Forest Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C26753AB6DE47D3AC8673115C2EB260"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau of Land Management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FA280B7F4C642F597A1758686BCA840"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Park Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H140D172B750942BA83211F90A1D46575"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Affairs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H18DCABDCF1C14EC484CEDD83C75F4F2A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Identification of salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds</header><subsection id="H390BBBF45C8B4647AFB8743A1803748B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service shall jointly issue guidance on the process and biological criteria required to identify salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H57DCDB8D92664754A2F766062288594C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication</header><paragraph id="H284944043AD44F519782F440A7C0F77B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, in cooperation with relevant Federal agencies shall publish a list of salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFF82DC70CFE4638AD4A8D123037A78F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, in cooperation with each relevant Federal agency shall not less frequently than once every 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, revise the list under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H2A121C65E72E4E2394796996C9E6E07A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to add subsequently identified salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds in accordance with subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF82EA77C27CD4CB4B1DA64C54E6D5DE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to remove from such list any areas that no longer qualify as salmon conservation areas or salmon strongholds. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F42B7D201C546629C26614F5274AEAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In identifying salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds under subsection (b), the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, in cooperation with each relevant Federal agency—</text><paragraph id="HB25CA5FDB9194074B0A894000E5B6919"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H9BF6D4DA77B0468AB6D34BBA251371F0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State in which such a salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold under consideration are located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F7C8AB1DB1F407AAAFC188EBC152CE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Indian tribes that have land, fishing rights, or cultural ties to the area in which the salmon conservation area or salmon strongholds will be prospectively located; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FA63375A2C94008B63EADB4D5F5A974"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H30F25043A8A047B29062795616BF6067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>nongovernmental organizations; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8735DBDB344480D9A21C7893ACA1C1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>non-Federal scientists; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D0E360F784D461C9FF120118D24866E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>members of the public. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CD5023B2DD342D6A3D32D5AB5F5E5DE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subsequent identification and revision</header><paragraph id="H089DF69C092041DA956FC13975875755" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date described in subsection (b)(1), an entity described in paragraph (1) or paragraph (2) subsection (c) may nominate to the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service a salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold for identification under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAC79D2717CB408B90C2EA9989F89FBF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a nomination described in paragraph (1), not later than 180 days after receiving such nomination, the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service shall jointly determine if the nominated watershed is a salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold and provide to the entity that provided the nomination under paragraph (1) a written explanation with respect to such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF785D45BDBB34F40AD1083EFD4D188AF" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Watershed management and restoration identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, in cooperation with the Secretary of Agriculture shall use watershed evaluations conducted under the Watershed Condition Framework under section 304 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6543">16 U.S.C. 6543</external-xref>) and other relevant watershed analyses to support the identification of salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds under this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="H4513D8E67A204419A43BBEC55E1F8F6C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Essential fish habitat</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service shall use the analyses conducted by the Administrator under section 305(b) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1855">16 U.S.C. 1855(b)</external-xref>) to identify, map, and designate essential fish habitat to support the identification of salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds under this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="H2B9445360BD648A18579E0D4CCB05635"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effect of identification</header><subsection id="HB8DD0AB6BA4348CD84B06E1181041022" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Priority for forest road decommissioning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture—</text><paragraph id="H6F8AF244D0CC4D22823420AF052C3CCA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall give priority to forest road decommissioning (as defined in section 212.1 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations) and fish passage projects within or directly affecting a salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB53677BB4305422BB2D27E551F254C75" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not carry out the forest road decommissioning or fish passage projects described in paragraph (1) unless the Secretary of Agriculture has, with respect to ensuring that the habitats of salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds are not degraded, consulted with the—</text><subparagraph id="H7FCD3379295A44B693FF9ACFD96AD757" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entities described in paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 4(c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H274359DC344041DE9BC64661B7E5A08E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, acting through the Administrator of the National Marine Fisheries Service; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F3B4259498A4BEF86B96FB8A25ECC57" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service;</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D2B11E4C234C96877219504E997AB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transboundary pollution</header><paragraph id="H0EDDF37CE1174C5592E6D28DF7519F73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notification of Secretary of State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold is determined by a Federal agency to be negatively impacted by transboundary pollution or other international actions originating in Canada, the head of the Federal agency shall notify the Secretary of State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD300CA34A5BD4927AC0E19441B5D4CB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a notification under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall consult with representatives from Canada to resolve the issue for which the Secretary of State was notified under such paragraph. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE2FA36958342C5AAD6CC399E3E2777"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Referral to International Joint Commission</header><text>If the issue for which the Secretary of State was notified under paragraph (1) is not resolved on a date that is 6 months after the date of notification under such paragraph—</text><subparagraph id="H367BAFF8F5024751A399181B1347DDA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of State shall request to submit a joint referral to the International Joint Commission with Canada to research and provide recommendations to resolve such issue; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AB9BF061AA5481BA47FFB303316E45B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if a joint referral under subparagraph (A) is not submitted, the Secretary of State shall refer such issue to the International Joint Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8B4B649050B84CB38026B69D91920D81" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Watershed management and restoration program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of the Healthy Forests Restoration Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/6543">16 U.S.C. 6543</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6A3EC99FABC941F084371470841D37CD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8999AB09393E4155ACF002D9DAC3CE73" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H5980EBF10EE740F991B4E09CD232FBFD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section and the purpose described in paragraph (2), $40,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each of the 4 fiscal years thereafter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H819F5BEE969A449493E11C24DCB031DA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preserve salmon habitat watersheds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use a portion of the funds appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) to provide funds to programs that preserve watersheds that are salmon habitats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H989109F8510F493986A51ED6DE46B6AC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional watershed permissible</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary may use funds appropriated under this subsection to identify additional priority watersheds in each National Forest if such watersheds, or portions of, are determined by the Secretary to be salmon conservation areas or salmon strongholds (as such terms are defined in section 3 of the Salmon FISH Act).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H19088FC23BDD4DAF80BFF8FD03CD12B4"><enum>7.</enum><header>Grant program</header><subsection id="HCD1DC7EF76064DB7A73C26A56102F090"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><paragraph id="H8AF2908F75FB4C49A0AF5EE8A65B7F1D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service shall, in collaboration with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, carry out a grant program, to be known as the <quote>Salmon Conservation Area Grant Program</quote>, to make grants to carry out the purposes described in subsection (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31CB4605448046DAA4C8A123B79733C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall have a duration of not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84036BD955DA403E8E7D2C7E5C0EB08D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making grants under this section, the administrator of the grant program shall give priority to an eligible entity that demonstrates that the eligible entity—</text><subparagraph id="H0469CACDB2594935AC0EE35D05E86737"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will carry out a project under this section on a salmon stronghold; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD663FA07516247D2A52248DF9CBA1386"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has considered the durability of the project and how the project contributes to the long-term conservation of salmon;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96B4193490904DFEA3D389F5DAF845CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has coordinated with other stakeholders to carry out the project; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H907D770F0C524384AB7748D481378038"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has considered how the project will work with other salmon restoration projects. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8097620CEA6D44D5820D4F4D6C17E57E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><subparagraph id="H0CF0E1B80149429FB0171E8E8AC6DC15" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall provide, in cash or through in-kind contributions from non-Federal sources, matching funds to carry out the activities funded by the grant in an amount equal to not less than 25 percent of the cost of the activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB9721F8215C416282861FCB2859F3D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><clause id="HD313F41F86A4401AB4BBD72764150993"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Indian Tribes</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an eligible entity that is an Indian Tribe.</text></clause><clause id="H041FA2197A1041EF93C84E77361C244D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Discretionary exceptions</header><text>The administrator of the grant program under this section may reduce or waive the matching requirement under subparagraph (A) if—</text><subclause id="H5BA5DA4B8C634065815ECCA5040D4FFE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an eligible entity submits a written request to the administrator for a waiver with a justification as to why the eligible entity cannot meet the matching requirement; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC22D533EC2914C9B89F6A90F7ACC383E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the administrator determines such justification is sufficient to waive such requirement.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01261F423558414C96542840E63E19A0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Administration</header><subparagraph id="H5925BA6C2B3745499A8CC8D81855789F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service may enter into an agreement to administer the grant program with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation or a similar organization that offers grant administration services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFD6C16B249D4F1F96B970EEE9DF9E9B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service enters into an agreement under subparagraph (A), the organization selected shall—</text><clause id="HF4E1FE92A36449379BAF2D5CDA8459AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for each fiscal year, receive amounts made available to carry out this section in an advance payment of the entire amounts on October 1 of that fiscal year, or as soon as practicable thereafter;</text></clause><clause id="HF39868AAF36B4C429361B76CEE20D439"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>invest and reinvest those amounts for the benefit of the grant program; and</text></clause><clause id="HFC09F85ED7614BD0A2219C99D7788EDE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise administer the grant program to support partnerships between the public and private sectors in accordance with this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DBCBF135C404F7B9F430F58BB96F430"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>If the Secretary enters into an agreement with the Foundation under subparagraph (A), any amounts received by the Foundation under this section shall be subject to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>), excluding section 10(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3709">16 U.S.C. 3709(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA447202FC747474EBA03143CE07385EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the grants under this section are—</text><paragraph id="H58C5093763A1408BA0C9E0722346C9EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to protect or maintain salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold features and projects that are focused on conservation and restoration within salmon conservation areas or salmon stronghold; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9576667154D4446813DDBAB8E9AFCAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to carry out at least one of the following: </text><subparagraph id="HB40098F77CE6407B8A1CE17D43D2A5B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To address factors threatening to limit abundance, productivity, diversity, habitat quality, or other biological attributes important to sustaining viable salmon populations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA85774FD124A4056B4CECCE86AF7E0D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To restore or maintain ecological functions and processes related to salmon productivity and diversity at watershed or subwatershed scales.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H135E88A3AAEA442CAED227785D8B7BDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To improve the resilience of salmon populations in response to acute events such as fires, landslides, and earthquakes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54450377978E40AFB65433ABF7725828"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To improve the resilience of salmon populations to climate change and prepare populations for other future changes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC1950459365474E8BBDFBBE4631F29A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To provide co-benefits to fish and wildlife, in particular where salmon can be used as indicator species for habitat quality.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8F1B3D8EB3745AB995882620473495A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>To implement focused, prioritized protection and restoration in watersheds.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D34AA903DAC43B68B4267C3556307D7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>To improve conservation area or salmon stronghold resilience both downstream and upstream.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H07D628C61F66418791E7E981720CA8D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the administrator of the grant program at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as such administrator may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4881F2BAB2284F7D81AB318241EF996E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H7A5DE01558914CAF8F6E4426BBB1A724" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to carry out activities consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b), which include— </text><subparagraph id="HD25ECB9FD5034AB399060FB28C7B7495" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subsection (e), land acquisition, conservation easements, and land exchanges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF970D164E738486894EFE15F3AF58163" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purchasing mining rights;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCAB19CFE3274607874AAA33DA982E7D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the improvement of fish passages and removal of fish passage barriers and dams;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H156B24A9D9044EBFAE5669C443801BAD" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>habitat restoration and rehabilitation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ABDA7163067453995CA1323236C9A2B" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>outreach and local engagement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B3C80C944034C86993B77ABA04A4033" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">purchasing water rights related to leasing, consumption, and use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA3FD6E108B04AF09B16FF489A28BDF4" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>groundwater recharge projects (including ponds and forbearance);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6712BD07B12140FAB5031300769E6B09" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>water efficiency projects;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H12A139B053164A3FB4F4DBFE2F3777DB" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional planning or development of a focused, prioritized protection and restoration action plan for the watershed; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4950E382ADF49D8B199FBA123A22197" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitoring and research, including monitoring the status of salmon populations in watersheds within conservation areas before and after the removal of a dam.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7594F16819DB432F86B53B01643DAF9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>None of the funds made available under this section may be used—</text><subparagraph id="H1F79CA33F0214DFC9519D5AE1D20B6AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to carry out litigation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC403E45FBA34F829EDC1016CBCC1EC6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out lethal intentional takings. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDE454C20C7342CE8C021007267002CC" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Acquisition and transfer of real property interests</header><paragraph id="H52C7A4149CCE4DB6A341E65C81C6AEA1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of real property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No project that will result in the acquisition by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, a relevant Federal agency, or eligible entity of interest in land, in whole or in part, may receive funds under this section unless the project is consistent with the purposes of this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3F37C8149C0424E9874BA938F0CB527" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private property protection</header><text>No Federal funds made available to carry out this section may be used to acquire any real property or any interest in any real property without the written consent of each owner of the property or interest in property. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6791F1286BB4472690AAEE838A2BE6EB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transfer of real property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No land or interest in land, acquired in whole or in part by the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, a relevant Federal agency, or eligible entity with funds made available under this section may be transferred to a State, other public agency, or other entity unless—</text><subparagraph id="HBB5412798A364B7FB32018C1CB48CEB5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation, the relevant Federal agency, or eligible entity with jurisdiction over such land determines that the State, agency, or other entity is committed to manage, in accordance with this section and the purposes of this section, the property being transferred; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1812EA077C9F4242A313462172A1E334" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the deed or other instrument of transfer contains provisions for the reversion of the title to the property to the United States if the State, agency, or entity fails to manage the property as a salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold in accordance with this section and the purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7065264B519E49709F900805F6AF175F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any real property interest conveyed under paragraph (3) shall be subject to such terms and conditions as will ensure, to the maximum extent practicable, that the interest will be administered in accordance with this section and the purposes of this section. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H025DA9908D144F60A3FE5D3B5755DADA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date on which the first grant is made under this section, the administrator of the grant program shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives that includes—</text><paragraph id="H0CF8991BC6624AD8ADA75D38266215D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of the results of each project with recommendations on strategies and approaches focusing on salmon conservation actions projected to have the greatest positive impacts on abundance, productivity, or diversity in salmon conservation areas and salmon strongholds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6718FEAAD3F4077B2629C9F39205938"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conclusions and recommendations on appropriate metrics to measure and evaluate the efficacy of salmon conservation efforts, including key indicators for habitat and aquatic health and recommendations on quantifying such benefits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52CFC55F310540D3B4CCACF05298E4F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of the status and trends for wild salmon abundance, diversity and productivity in each salmon conservation area and salmon stronghold; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A80B4080D484158B784618C1A179B7D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an analysis of the social and economic effects resulting from salmon conservation area and salmon stronghold conservation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H912B7C2E7C614552B210C61C54806413"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of threats imposed by changing ocean conditions on marine survival.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4A740EE09E0430D9D6AC21FDE21ECC2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Eligible entity defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an Indian tribe, nongovernmental organization, State or local agency, or institution of higher education (as defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) that has approval to carry out a project with respect to a salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold under this section from each entity that has jurisdiction over such salmon conservation area or salmon stronghold.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9C567BCBE8AF4A4EBA6010B65E5BCBEC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each of the 4 fiscal years thereafter.</text></subsection></section><section id="H36B2DF7537C44D52981B8988532A8777" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Limitations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, and no action to implement this Act, may be construed—</text><paragraph id="HCA93E62264E84108968A8D8668726868" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to create a reserved water right, express or implied, in the United States for any purpose, or affect the management or priority of water rights under State law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H689A9BD620934F81A9C052CCA9804947" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to affect existing water rights under Federal or State law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF58A79CBC78493CB5B409B4F946B95C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to affect any Federal or State law in existence on the date of enactment of this Act regarding water quality or water quantity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A3071D75ABA455EA1C5ADBCBD38E5A0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to abrogate, abridge, affect, modify, supersede, or otherwise alter any right of an Indian tribe under any applicable treaty, or Federal or tribal law or regulation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F8636333DCB453AA63BB00BD4E03D23" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to diminish or affect the ability of the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the Director of the Fish and Wildlife Service, or head of a relevant Federal Agency to join the adjudication of rights to the use of water pursuant to subsection (a), (b), or (c) of section 208 of the Department of Justice Appropriation Act, 1953 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/666">43 U.S.C. 666</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9676EEDDE35A407093E33A6BD6BEE9FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to diminish or affect any program or activity by an Indian tribe that does not impact salmonid habitat.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

