<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBBA03EF5BCB54DD2BEEECDA1A269FA52" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8813 IH: Assuring that the Fact-Finding Examination Continues to Track Human Rights in Venezuela Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8813</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000581">Mr. Vicente Gonzalez of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the United States Government to support extending the mandate of the Independent International Fact-Finding Mission on Venezuela which is set to expire in September 2022.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD88FE30599314382BDD4DACCB08C3279" style="OLC"><section id="HE0B11B9381C34472BD3A1D50ECAF3336" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assuring that the Fact-Finding Examination Continues to Track Human Rights in Venezuela Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AFFECT Human Rights in Venezuela Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF27974954855424FB841F7AD8E8BFE62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H54ACB80BC2344526B19363B57A0154C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In its Resolution 42/25 adopted on September 27, 2019, the United Nations Human Rights Council established an independent fact-finding mission, the Independent International Fact-Finding Mission on the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fact-Finding Mission</quote>) <quote>to investigate extrajudicial executions, enforced disappearances, arbitrary detentions and torture and other cruel, inhuman or degrading treatment since 2014 with a view to ensuring full accountability for perpetrators and justice for victims</quote>. The mandate of the Fact-Finding Mission was extended by the United Nations Human Rights Council on October 6, 2020, for an additional two years, until September 2022, through its Resolution 45/20.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63EBE63B54C94669BC820884DD92D358"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Fact-Finding Mission has identified specific incidents and patterns establishing reasonable grounds to conclude that violations of international human rights and criminal law have been committed in Venezuela, according to its September 2020 report.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0EC54A2BE34957AFE8ED0695BCBAE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Fact-Finding Mission has faced several constraints, including lack of access to work in-country, travel limitations due to the COVID-19 pandemic, disrupted interviews due to electricity and internet failures, and limited ability to secure witness statements and key documents. Despite these challenges, the Fact-Finding Mission was able to carry out its investigative and analytical work and generate reports that serve as an invaluable resource for victims, civil society organizations, and international accountability mechanisms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E0A72868DB449D096FCE037D4E28774"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has historically used its voice, vote, and influence at the United Nations to address human rights abuses around the world and to seek to hold perpetrators accountable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFD2C2599FC44F7591B7C9C31BA2CB9C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Marta Valiñas, Chair of the Fact-Finding Mission, reported at the 49th session of the Human Rights Council that the Venezuelan people <quote>have endured a decade of deepening economic, humanitarian and human rights crises, as well as the breaking down of State institutions, all of this exacerbated, most recently, by the impact of COVID-19. The clearest showing of this are the more than six million people who have had to leave the country.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5D556F513AA846C0BFCE1FC4C4E31494"><enum>3.</enum><header>Actions relating to the Independent International Fact-Finding Mission on the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela</header><subsection id="HA52EE9A78D2B401EB716D92D6035E466"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Support To extend mandate</header><text>The Secretary of State shall take such actions as may be necessary to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States in the United Nations Human Rights Council (UNHRC) and the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA) to seek to—</text><paragraph id="H2BAB653542374FA097F8C69EA6049D78"><enum>(1)</enum><text>extend the mandate of the Independent International Fact-Finding Mission on the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela (in this section referred to as the <quote>Fact-Finding Mission</quote>) by two years beyond September 2022, as previously outlined and determined by UNHRC Resolutions 42/25 (September 27, 2019) and 45/20 (October 6, 2020), to conclude in October 2024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25A34927827041E99B29860432FFAA4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage international support among member states of UNHRC to empower the Fact-Finding Mission to thoroughly conduct its stated purpose of investigating gross violations of human rights perpetrated in Venezuela since 2014; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9A8ED4E5764754878CB82C433738CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide investigative and technical assistance to the Fact-Finding Mission as requested and as permitted within United Nations rules and regulations and within United States law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC761241A90BB446B920307AC049CED12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support for further action</header><text>The President is authorized to direct the United States Permanent Representative to the United Nations to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to urge the United Nations to provide greater action with respect to human rights violations in Venezuela by—</text><paragraph id="H1FBE79FC11994D4F863CAF7AA394A067"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">urging the UNGA to consider a resolution condemning the Venezuelan regime’s use of political prisoners and wrongfully detained foreign nationals, including Americans, as leverage to extract concessions from its adversaries consistent with UNHRC Resolution 42/25;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72D49F0B547B4765A6274A91798B83AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assisting efforts by the relevant United Nations Special Envoys and Special Rapporteurs to secure the release of all political prisoners and wrongfully detained foreign nationals in Venezuela, promote respect for human rights, and encourage dialogue towards a peaceful and democratic transfer of power;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB40872F1EE241FE8859E8FAA18BB7D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>urging the United Nations and specialized agencies to address the humanitarian needs of the people of Venezuela, including vulnerable Venezuelan refugees and migrants in third countries through direct assistance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCE92288557243FB804B754D031BF03E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>supporting access for humanitarian actors, independent media, and credible international legal and judicial entities, including future United Nations Fact-Finding Missions and similar investigatory mechanisms, to people residing in Venezuela and to the growing Venezuelan diaspora.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2E79FDBA09548888473EE238B4B4E30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Due consideration of fact-Finding mission reports</header><text>The President and Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph id="H40127AE7E33A4A0A8DC4904F3A8E696B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriately review all past and future reports presented by the Fact-Finding Mission to the UNHRC, including the Detailed Findings published on September 25, 2020 (A/HRC/45/33) and September 16, 2021 (A/HRC/48/69); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF273F376D7F4BFAAB654E48655D36B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give due consideration to the Fact-Finding Mission’s reported conclusions in developing and executing the foreign policy of the United States with respect to Venezuela.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDAAA8B54CF5C43C78EA0D210C8F80D61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the expiration of the official mandate of the Fact-Finding Mission, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the implementation of the actions described in subsections (a), (b), and (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB27F73A3C5044519B17B3D6EB53FB57F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H4D7B6DE1007D4C4E8E592664B7EA0D25"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59394BAF3EFB425699A593001BD7F4A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

