<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7E5F64038257456D81DF9EA059B2301A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7315 IH: Transparency and Effective Accountability Measures for Veteran Caregivers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7315</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to formally recognize caregivers of veterans, notify veterans and caregivers of clinical determinations relating to eligibility for caregiver programs, and temporarily extend benefits for veterans who are determined ineligible for the family caregiver program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7BBF262B3E454F6F9F666C280C531E41" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE2D34CFCA16E4E28AB583DA01517AAA6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency and Effective Accountability Measures for Veteran Caregivers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TEAM Veteran Caregivers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H8B1CF2FDA9BF43F5ADA968E882BE4B93"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification of administration of caregiver program of Department of Veterans Affairs</header> <subsection id="HEB875C73B5DE4DFE9E20989C45DA385A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Official designation of caregivers</header> <paragraph id="H1A4E7EDF4D9641879CD487AF0915CD0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall formally recognize all caregivers of veterans by identifying any caregiver of a veteran in the health record of the veteran.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF1EE6E28BDC4B3784C9C413EB51B989"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>Caregivers recognized under paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F42CE3E000E49FC97F0B6DE875E164F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>family caregivers participating in the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers under subsection (a) of section 1720G of title 38, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H535EA4C30F1B47BE887405799C4A7973"><enum>(B)</enum><text>caregivers participating in the program of support services for caregivers under subsection (b) of such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2D1E6094EF4E414CA93CCE0B465746AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification letters regarding clinical determinations</header> <paragraph id="H6E80999D0CBF45449F00A3A0215A2A98"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, using a standardized letter, shall notify veterans and caregivers of veterans regarding any clinical determinations made relating to claims, tier reduction, or termination of assistance under, or eligibility for, a caregiver program under subsection (a) or (b) of section 1720G of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H69ADD6E9FACF4528B92AA8966AA15213"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Notifications under paragraph (1) shall include the elements required for notices of decisions under section 5104(b) of title 38, United States Code, to the extent that those elements apply to determinations under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2FE10BC4DED542F9B99C34C7F57DCDF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Temporary extension of benefits for family caregiver program</header> <paragraph id="H3FAF9C25BA6D4D3AB4BE64980A738463"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon determining that a veteran who was receiving services under the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers under section 1720G(a) of title 38, United States Code, is no longer clinically eligible for purposes of such program, the Secretary shall extend benefits under such program, including stipends under paragraph (3)(A)(ii)(V) of such section, for not less than 90 days after the date of notification under subsection (b) that the veteran is no longer clinically eligible.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A4848B06E4148D1B7408996F5BFFDEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to the termination of caregiver benefits—</text> <subparagraph id="H0E057D478E2B4E389389EC1EC71E03E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines that the family caregiver committed fraud or abused or neglected the veteran;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA4727B7F24449ACB5870A211EFF84B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the family caregiver was designated under section 1720G(a)(7) of title 38, United States Code, as the primary provider of personal care services for the veteran and another primary provider is designated within 90 days after the date of termination, in which case benefits for the terminated primary provider will terminate the day before the date on which the new primary provider is designated;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FBFC07B69D2439EBDCDCEDEB8D8E71D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if another individual is designated to be a family caregiver within 90 days after the date of termination, such that there are three family caregivers assigned to the veteran, in which case benefits for the terminated family caregiver will terminate the day before the date on which the new family caregiver is designated;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D443008F77949A69C0A8A5D29566F34"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the terminated individual had been living with the veteran and moves out, or the terminated individual abandons or terminates his or her relationship with the veteran; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5453160990B4FD79E9DEE294C7BEEA0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>upon request of the family caregiver or the veteran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

