<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3EE9A1B506F8498698746CF7AEB1F266" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6924 IH: Pandemic Payroll Tax Suspension Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6924</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220303">March 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To suspend payroll taxes for 2021 and 2022.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1120608DE2564517ACF2C8DC79BCBBF8" style="OLC"><section id="H48C15A3C3AAB4D218891FDE2A8CF5BE9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pandemic Payroll Tax Suspension Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H53F325BEFF6E4F12ACEF7778672044E7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Suspension of payroll taxes for 2021 and 2022</header><subsection id="HB6955D50581A44058A1F8CEB59999E2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text><paragraph id="HE932F92BF4684A0DB6C2F7A73BDD42BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to any taxable year which begins in the payroll tax suspension period, the rates of tax under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1401">section 1401</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be 0 percent,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H320907C942CE4DE8A8353CE8ADCA8813"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to remuneration received for pay periods ending during the payroll tax suspension period, the rates of tax under 3101 of such Code shall be 0 percent (including for purposes of determining the applicable percentage under sections 3201(a) and 3211(a) of such Code), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC81F6DC84C04B7A9DBC658558EEE357"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to remuneration paid for pay periods ending during the payroll tax suspension period, the rates of tax under section 3111 of such Code shall be 0 percent (including for purposes of determining the applicable percentage under section 3221(a) of such Code).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA43F7E642144F70B4F436C3E09F7859"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Payroll tax suspension period</header><text>The term <term>payroll tax suspension period</term> means the period beginning on January 1, 2021, and ending on December 31, 2022.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCDC6FA93371F432B9DE33BC781AB5105"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employer notification</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall notify employers of the payroll tax suspension period in any manner the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE4018B608FE4DEB9DEC03848F7B2826"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transfers of funds</header><paragraph id="H20D5E3BBF92745D28B4B619D67624197"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Transfers to Federal old-age and survivors insurance trust fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby appropriated to the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund established under section 201 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401</external-xref>) and the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1817(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395i">42 U.S.C. 1395i(a)</external-xref>) amounts equal to the reduction in revenues to the Treasury by reason of the application of subsection (a). Amounts appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be transferred from the general fund at such times and in such manner as to replicate to the extent possible the transfers which would have occurred to each such Trust Fund had subsection (a) not been enacted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0D28AE3F92241ED97901ED5F14AE4AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfers to social security equivalent benefit account</header><text>There are hereby appropriated to the Social Security Equivalent Benefit Account established under section 15A(a) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/231n-1">45 U.S.C. 231n–1(a)</external-xref>) amounts equal to the reduction in revenues to the Treasury by reason of the application of subsection (a). Amounts appropriated by the preceding sentence shall be transferred from the general fund at such times and in such manner as to replicate to the extent possible the transfers which would have occurred to such Account had subsection (a) not been enacted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80D469F4C4004F19B621B6914D4ECA99"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with other Federal laws</header><text>For purposes of applying any provision of Federal law other than the provisions of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, the rates of tax in effect under section 3101 of such Code shall be determined without regard to the reduction in such rate under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

