<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H755DDF61024D461B88241EC155348733" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>103 HR 7132 IH: Safe Connections Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7132</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To preserve safe access to communications services for survivors of domestic violence and other crimes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H258D4AD510D94AE1BE2272E2A135EDB3" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HE2CFFECC304B4246A4C099C6B9A19A65"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safe Connections Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFF0ED1431FD043BCA463505AC6B4DDEA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, terms used in this Act that are defined in section 345(a) of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act, have the meanings given those terms in such section 345(a).</text></section><section id="HF76379BDF4FD4651BE746210E83AF0B7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H67623D3012314234AA1C87F479FDFB8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, sexual assault, human trafficking, and related crimes are life-threatening issues and have lasting and harmful effects on individuals, families, and entire communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AC0A22DBCE54E21A06BA8A3C886737F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Survivors often lack meaningful support and options when establishing independence from an abuser, including barriers such as financial insecurity and limited access to reliable communications tools to maintain essential connections with family, social safety networks, employers, and support services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C012D46151541CC9942C50FA26BD69F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Perpetrators of violence and abuse described in paragraph (1) increasingly use technological and communications tools to exercise control over, monitor, and abuse their victims. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E36254C7E2B4A5FAEEA5706CD80E629"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Communications law can play a public interest role in the promotion of safety, life, and property with respect to the types of violence and abuse described in paragraph (1). For example, independent access to a wireless phone plan can assist survivors in establishing security and autonomy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB71664BC97894A8895A900ADB82D79BC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Safeguards within communications services can serve a role in preventing abuse and narrowing the digital divide experienced by survivors of abuse.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1A83C8D0B91347C99318FA1C8F76E4E4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of domestic violence survivors within communications services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part I of title III of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/301">47 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFE6AFDE7F1AC497687D2CB0AF50D9DCE"><section id="HCC34E03C3C3149CD8A2004159E2F4764"><enum>345.</enum><header>Protection of survivors of domestic violence, human trafficking, and related crimes</header><subsection id="H4B5B0948F9104669AAB5640457F99F60"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA617584C1E6D40889500B4667F5B24BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Abuser</header><text>The term <term>abuser</term> means an individual who has committed or allegedly committed a covered act against—</text><subparagraph id="HBB213EC400394B3981E59C15F01EEC4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual who seeks relief under subsection (b); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD598A4937AFA4DD2B433FD28A11249E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an individual in the care of an individual who seeks relief under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC856C1C7972A44FD977975D32E7CF04C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered act</header><subparagraph id="H74E0A46314EE4851A85FCF349536B391"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered act</term> means conduct that constitutes—</text><clause id="H88867FDAB84747D18E6FB8DCF18AAEF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a crime described in section 40002(a) of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291(a)</external-xref>), including domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, and sex trafficking;</text></clause><clause id="HFD595857A3564BE2AE42EC458F993E28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an act or practice described in paragraph (11) or (12) of section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>) (relating to severe forms of trafficking in persons and sex trafficking, respectively); or</text></clause><clause id="HBF501792F7D64EDCB388E29CAA9299CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an act under State law, Tribal law, or the Uniform Code of Military Justice that is similar to an offense described in clause (i) or (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2FD160F3D004DF796A9C3D7899D68A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conviction not required</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to require a criminal conviction or any other determination of a court in order for conduct to constitute a covered act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90FE1A3735EF4E578948F5FEFC199ADD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered provider</header><text>The term <term>covered provider</term> means a provider of a private mobile service or commercial mobile service, as those terms are defined in section 332(d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FB0E397919F4EEAB5E13692C1F5EEAB"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Primary account holder</header><text>The term <term>primary account holder</term> means an individual who is a party to a mobile service contract with a covered provider.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C218F8C969643E1A0D35A9A08B10BFC"><enum>(5)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Shared mobile service contract</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>shared mobile service contract</term>—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF21347D45B374FA2A13ACD6BF59F0F85"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a mobile service contract for an account that includes not less than 2 consumers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A0E6E0584A84C60837C14CC543BE055"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include enterprise services offered by a covered provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2672FFDEAFAE4BEB8C68637F30CEACF8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Survivor</header><text>The term <term>survivor</term> means an individual who is not less than 18 years old and—</text><subparagraph id="H000EF5CB4BBA4361947406316B769D88"><enum>(A)</enum><text>against whom a covered act has been committed or allegedly committed; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6EEA91FEFFC4133B5CF61BC5104778E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who cares for another individual against whom a covered act has been committed or allegedly committed (provided that the individual providing care did not commit or allegedly commit the covered act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2BB2CC3B1094675BBBBE8DA4F53C0A7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Separation of lines from shared mobile service contract</header><paragraph id="HD981E2BBEF6C48F1B680B2EE00C48E36"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 business days after receiving a completed line separation request from a survivor pursuant to subsection (c), a covered provider shall, as applicable, with respect to a shared mobile service contract under which the survivor and the abuser each use a line—</text><subparagraph id="H0D105B44AE5F425BAE4539D6E1B9DDFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>separate the line of the survivor, and the line of any individual in the care of the survivor, from the shared mobile service contract; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8B8543FDB9D428999240A54080AC460"><enum>(B)</enum><text>separate the line of the abuser from the shared mobile service contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B35D7BB95894F33816299445E2C4BCE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations on penalties, fees, and other requirements</header><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (5) through (8), a covered provider may not make separation of a line from a shared mobile service contract under paragraph (1) contingent on any requirement other than the requirements under subsection (c), including—</text><subparagraph id="H0079661973DE423184843158BAE353AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>payment of a fee, penalty, or other charge;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFACA85445E2472B9D70F71FEA604EF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintaining contractual or billing responsibility of a separated line with the provider;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04AAB17F410C4E56BC98C302857FDB80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>approval of separation by the primary account holder, if the primary account holder is not the survivor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCA8B69D0A9E4A6093E168483FD1CFAC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a prohibition or limitation, including one described in subparagraph (A), on number portability, provided such portability is technically feasible, or a request to change phone numbers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EF8509D67C242B1B0E5A45783A786BB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a prohibition or limitation on the separation of lines as a result of arrears accrued by the account;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4106166EFCF14BA4931D14CF5CF0A29E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an increase in the rate charged for the mobile service plan of the primary account holder with respect to service on any remaining line or lines; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF71B960D7B44C2B970B9228FB952741"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other limitation or requirement not listed under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88D92BCBAE0440D08643B973DCEF40A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (2) shall be construed to require a covered provider to provide a rate plan for the primary account holder that is not otherwise commercially available. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5741DCFEDAF04229889D86790DB8E673"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Remote option</header><text>A covered provider shall offer a survivor the ability to submit a line separation request under subsection (c) through secure remote means that are easily navigable, provided that remote options are commercially available and technically feasible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A58445C32E042B295A29297BD60FB18"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Responsibility for transferred telephone numbers</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), beginning on the date on which a covered provider transfers billing responsibilities for and rights to a telephone number or numbers to a survivor under paragraph (1)(A) in response to a line separation request submitted by the survivor under subsection (c), unless ordered otherwise by a court, the survivor shall assume financial responsibility, including for monthly service costs, for the transferred telephone number or numbers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97560682CBC246CA8A7D88A5BD4C4F42"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Responsibility for transferred telephone numbers from a survivor's account</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), upon the transfer of a telephone number under paragraph (1)(B) in response to a line separation request submitted by a survivor under subsection (c), the survivor shall have no further financial responsibilities to the transferring covered provider for the services provided by the transferring covered provider for the telephone number or for any mobile device associated with the telephone number.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD8028600D914D399FD365F11650DBFC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Responsibility for mobile device</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), beginning on the date on which a covered provider transfers billing responsibilities for and rights to a telephone number or numbers to a survivor under paragraph (1)(A) in response to a line separation request submitted by the survivor under subsection (c), unless otherwise ordered by a court, the survivor shall not assume financial responsibility for any mobile device associated with the separated line, unless the survivor purchased the mobile device, or affirmatively elects to maintain possession of the mobile device.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE53449618D6487DBAFC107441F5C809"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Notice to survivor</header><text>If a covered provider separates a line from a shared mobile service contract under paragraph (1) and the primary account holder is not the survivor, the covered provider shall notify the survivor of the date on which the covered provider intends to give any formal notice to the primary account holder.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD08D7DB9C5824A81BEC0418BF8FC30D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Line separation request</header><paragraph id="HCAB2786FE44E490EA99C779C4B1C03DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A survivor shall submit to the covered provider a line separation request that—</text><subparagraph id="H74935415979C473F9C3F4B6550EB15D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>verifies that an individual who uses a line under the shared mobile service contract has committed or allegedly committed a covered act against the survivor or an individual in the survivor’s care, by providing—</text><clause id="H4F6382EC888541939C26D169B8B1A028"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of a signed affidavit from a licensed medical or mental health care provider, licensed military medical or mental health care provider, licensed social worker, victim services provider, or licensed military victim services provider, or an employee of a court, acting within the scope of that person’s employment; or</text></clause><clause id="H0880A6280AEF4E8789A1380524938285"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a copy of a police report, statements provided by police, including military police, to magistrates or judges, charging documents, protective or restraining orders, military protective orders, or any other official record that documents the covered act;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E4FB5458DA44E99AC55D077BDA4DC72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of relief sought under subsection (b)(1)(A), with respect to—</text><clause id="H7BEE9954DC964E6592080D2E2EE4EDA7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a line used by the survivor that the survivor seeks to have separated, states that the survivor is the user of that specific line; and</text></clause><clause id="H41A20B6CECB147A1B006B8AE86B5140A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a line used by an individual in the care of the survivor that the survivor seeks to have separated, includes an affidavit setting forth that the individual—</text><subclause id="HF159D14E25954A6BAEF22A5D057A3FEC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is in the care of the survivor; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H716BD50A93974CA981F76A741C6FD46C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is the user of that specific line; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84DFF5E082A145B6A232BCB785116350"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requests relief under subparagraph (A) or (B) of subsection (b)(1) and identifies each line that should be separated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EB00BFBEF0543B690EEE41C4C00830C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communications from covered providers</header><subparagraph id="HF445F87681BF4383A5912B3DF53E0A6E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered provider shall notify a survivor seeking relief under subsection (b) in clear and accessible language that the covered provider may contact the survivor, or designated representative of the survivor, to confirm the line separation, or if the covered provider is unable to complete the line separation for any reason, pursuant to subparagraphs (B) and (C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H512B4CE1EB4B4CDFB6F8F0187D0BDDB6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Remote means</header><text>A covered provider shall notify a survivor under subparagraph (A) through remote means, provided that remote means are commercially available and technically feasible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H125F86E0B6124F3D8A42FC8BEC14971D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Election of manner of contact</header><text>When completing a line separation request submitted by a survivor through remote means under paragraph (1), a covered provider shall allow the survivor to elect in the manner in which the covered provider may—</text><clause id="H1CD0BD9AB17140F593BAC59C56637535"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contact the survivor, or designated representative of the survivor, in response to the request, if necessary; or</text></clause><clause id="H6E48335815714C4DAE7322A172E61434"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notify the survivor, or designated representative of the survivor, of the inability of the covered provider to complete the line separation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50434199E9094FDBB6C75B95F8D9401A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Enhanced protections under State law</header><text>This subsection shall not affect any law or regulation of a State providing communications protections for survivors (or any similar category of individuals) that has less stringent requirements for providing evidence of a covered act (or any similar category of conduct) than this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC8BE1FCBCF94D899BD2A0DB10ED7C1F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Confidential and secure treatment of personal information</header><paragraph id="H40F1305521A64E9E8E42F209653EDA94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 222(b), a covered provider and any officer, director, employee, vendor, or agent thereof shall treat any information submitted by a survivor under subsection (c) as confidential and securely dispose of the information not later than 90 days after receiving the information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A13B05891D94DA0A5D3C25314A186D8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall be construed to prohibit a covered provider from maintaining, for longer than the period specified in that paragraph, a record that verifies that a survivor fulfilled the conditions of a line separation request under subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49C08EE4668B413CA76ED74EA58965FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability of information to consumers</header><text>A covered provider shall make information about the options and process described in subsections (b) and (c) readily available to consumers—</text><paragraph id="HA6D089B999CE459AA19F0068659B5825"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the website and the mobile application of the provider;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H621C0E3F2A60438790DA3B9CB0A23065"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in physical stores; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H160E44F0D0EC42C6A1DCD3368341A7C7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in other forms of public-facing consumer communication.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H316BE55064F34133854CB0427F79A8D9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Technical infeasibility</header><paragraph id="HD497B2B9BFE2429181C529B028AD7CEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirement to effectuate a line separation request pursuant to subsection (b)(1) shall not apply to a covered provider if the covered provider cannot operationally or technically effectuate the request.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6042401346B943D990A95FC8A0270B92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If a covered provider cannot operationally or technically effectuate a line separation request as described in paragraph (1), the covered provider shall—</text><subparagraph id="HAEDD2D87FFA3427D9614EA3EA47B627F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the survivor who submitted the request of that infeasibility—</text><clause commented="no" id="H468FAA466120452B9AD930054916131B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>at the time of the request; or</text></clause><clause id="H8917E25206864FBA997550C77152E618"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a survivor who has submitted the request using remote means, not later than 2 business days after receiving the request; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5DBA32FC1F74448B176DE444A59DE0B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the survivor with information about other alternatives to submitting a line separation request, including starting a new contract. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5576F0977C2A49A482BAA63B8187D009"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Liability protection</header><paragraph id="HC8FE5B17B3234AA38CC5B52BD4AD33C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered provider and any officer, director, employee, vendor, or agent thereof shall not be subject to liability for any claims deriving from an action taken or omission made with respect to compliance with this section and the rules adopted to implement this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA72B418256154CB390D4DD8C2D316B36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission authority</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall limit the authority of the Commission to enforce this section or any rules or regulations promulgated by the Commission pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H857F9954AC2F48B4BD35B2017E12379B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Rulemaking on protections for survivors of domestic violence</header><subsection id="H563FFD8A25084D63BF33C2BED60E9FA4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H292608E294714BA28F0E7C3995C5613D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Affordable Connectivity Program</term> means the program established under section 904(b) of division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>), as amended by section 60502 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>), or any successor program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91B7226D7B8C4668B03C0F29DCCBC628"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H535DB84946524438A29F0C251E65AC13"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Communications Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65A0B710826A40C987D77D29810D8394"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>covered hotline</term> means a hotline related to domestic violence, dating violence, sexual assault, stalking, sex trafficking, severe forms of trafficking in persons, or any other similar act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E42E45B8EA42B6B95DCB0E018B99C9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>designated program</term> means the program designated by the Commission under subsection (c)(3)(A)(i) to provide emergency communications support to survivors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF8A9700E17496BA73E8A645510BD1B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>Lifeline program</term> means the program set forth in subpart E of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB7BBE9CC58742B081F199000B91EAAF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the term <term>text message</term> has the meaning given the term in section 227(e) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/227">47 U.S.C. 227(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CD104C14E81421E9627C46A1716EC59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemakings</header><paragraph id="HBE1ABBD8B62041DF9CDDCFC1672F630C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Line separations</header><subparagraph id="HEF6015C01E7740DDACDC557C9FD831FA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall adopt rules to implement section 345 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB18217FD37F4AA3BB88BEB419949631"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In adopting rules under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall consider—</text><clause id="H1C9A79B2240F463AACD198DC136184CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>privacy protections;</text></clause><clause id="H854D6017E4C7483D940108FF9A4F76A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>account security and fraud detection;</text></clause><clause id="H06F6D921C3834EA8BE2E855D067522EF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>account billing procedures;</text></clause><clause id="HCE1652726F7E4515A1499A0E295805D8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>procedures for notification of survivors about line separation processes;</text></clause><clause id="H98E3C63AA12E4DB4BE978AF401E1DBF2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>notice to account holders;</text></clause><clause id="HDF4FEAC72EA14FDABD793C76749E3450"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>situations in which a covered provider cannot operationally or technically separate a telephone number or numbers from a shared service plan such that the provider cannot effectuate a line separation request;</text></clause><clause id="HCD0D0D905BB3444FBFD7C1CEDEE6BDD5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the requirements for remote submission of a line separation request, including how that option facilitates submission of verification information and meets the other requirements of section 345 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act;</text></clause><clause id="HBE072F7FE4164910A3FC323D5C78FEDB"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>feasibility of remote options for small covered providers; </text></clause><clause id="H32F56B432A814AFE9F28E5FD86C2E3A4"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>implementation timelines, including those for small covered providers;</text></clause><clause id="H7AF1704A12164057BD353CF4F3F9956F"><enum>(x)</enum><text>financial responsibility for transferred telephone numbers; </text></clause><clause id="H9E3E34AD599149E8910BEBAB1D5FCE98"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>whether and how the survivor can affirmatively elect to take financial responsibility for the mobile device associated with the separated line; </text></clause><clause id="H420E83C3AFD940FCB79B9938453727E8"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>compliance with subpart U of part 64 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulations (relating to customer proprietary network information) or any other legal or law enforcement requirements; and</text></clause><clause id="HCC24A06E93B8402A984D8783D6D3A440"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>ensuring covered providers have the necessary account information to comply with the rules and with section 345 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA66A998CF8D14B8792CD4BD2AE192B05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Emergency communications support for survivors</header><subparagraph id="HA448422E0ED047BC8ACE7AA4D055CBD8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, or as part of a general rulemaking proceeding relating to the Lifeline program or the Affordable Connectivity Program, whichever occurs earlier, the Commission shall adopt rules that—</text><clause id="H17C8580979774FD6ADA6F908724716E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>designate a single program, which shall be either the Lifeline program or the Affordable Connectivity Program, to provide emergency communications support to survivors in accordance with this paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H1ED3EA938F384286BB3F2A06045F9068"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>allow a survivor who is suffering from financial hardship and meets the requirements under section 345(c)(1) of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act, without regard to whether the survivor meets the otherwise applicable eligibility requirements of the designated program, to—</text><subclause id="H38BF2246DDC94030B06122AF04263C1D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enroll in the designated program as quickly as is feasible; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H11F36B0E19C842689518E714F1E44E1D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>participate in the designated program based on such qualifications for not more than 6 months.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9E3F131E50041D58433968925DC5675"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In adopting rules under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall consider—</text><clause id="HBB4EEA4EA4A1469DAB16FED609BA061D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how survivors who are eligible for relief and elected to separate a line under section 345(c)(1) of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act, but whose lines could not be separated due to operational or technical infeasibility, can participate in the designated program; and</text></clause><clause id="HA1B5E3F6C47640288B0024880C67E41B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>confidentiality in the transfer and retention of any necessary documentation regarding the eligibility of a survivor to enroll in the designated program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD1A71189FC54D639AF84FC6C0BF8808"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 2 years after completing the rulemaking under subparagraph (A), the Commission shall—</text><clause id="HA320BF9D917C4F738D0321F7B1DB5363"><enum>(i)</enum><text>evaluate the effectiveness of the Commission’s provision of support to survivors through the designated program;</text></clause><clause id="HBDF592D7502F4B8E9F3941A482AEB559"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assess the detection and elimination of fraud, waste, and abuse with respect to the support described in clause (i); and </text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1582295911C2417085B21EAF3C42CD12"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the evaluation and assessment described in clauses (i) and (ii), respectively.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABB2B53CF89E4FC08A8373C9CDD87A80"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit the ability of a survivor who meets the requirements under section 345(c)(1) of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act, to participate in the designated program indefinitely if the survivor otherwise qualifies for the designated program under the rules of the designated program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E7593626EAC4F5485048A8D885144BA"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>A provider of wireless communications services that receives a line separation request pursuant to section 345 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act, shall inform the survivor who submitted the request of—</text><clause id="H4D6967EE2A2845E58ECD48922E92B57B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the existence of the designated program;</text></clause><clause id="H85B9F2EFE2E941F8AC12DD1639B8E026"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who qualifies to participate in the designated program under the rules adopted under subparagraph (A) that are specially applicable to survivors; and</text></clause><clause id="H67B1F9D3D7504E70B2D870CF3B0733B9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how to participate in the designated program under the rules described in clause (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF78337D24F1F4335ACD7999A30A6F2FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Hotline calls</header><subparagraph id="HEC2171015EE9442BA4638EF7F0773283"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall commence a rulemaking proceeding to consider whether to, and how the Commission should—</text><clause id="H650D14DE6E6245AC981B2C9C3444C313"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish, and update on a monthly basis, a central database of covered hotlines to be used by providers of wireless communications services or wireline voice services; and </text></clause><clause id="HDADBB627F2F04A2A9072D0B862C51416"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>require providers of wireless communications services or wireline voice services to omit from consumer-facing logs of calls or text messages any records of calls or text messages to covered hotlines in the central database described in clause (i), while maintaining internal records of those calls and messages.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7017A5EE92B94E9EB3B6A87FAD8E528E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The rulemaking conducted under subparagraph (A) shall include consideration of—</text><clause id="HF28D0E76468042FA81792D399C24DD91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ability of law enforcement agencies or survivors to access a log of calls or text messages in a criminal investigation or civil proceeding;</text></clause><clause id="H7A5AEEB370BC4C1FBB374958707997CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the ability of providers of wireless communication services or wireline voice services to—</text><subclause id="H313EF9EEBFA54EBEA17959881795C36F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>identify logs that are consumer-facing; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H03F365CAD4BD4D769E4C9233967B4980"><enum>(II)</enum><text>omit certain consumer-facing logs, while maintaining internal records of such calls and text messages; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF45C8F75EEAE4804A850CBB6FCDD3F64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other factors associated with the implementation of clauses (i) and (ii) to protect survivors of domestic violence, including factors that may impact smaller providers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H544096ABF24742CA8F0F39F4B01DC16F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No effect on law enforcement</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (A) shall be construed to—</text><clause id="HBCC7DA6D7A05459CAAFB57BF615DDF2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>limit or otherwise affect the ability of a law enforcement agency to access a log of calls or text messages in a criminal investigation; or</text></clause><clause id="HDD1700825A61411FAE3028E1C5193A1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>alter or otherwise expand provider requirements under the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/414">Public Law 103–414</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 4279) or the amendments made by that Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD52C968D39C341C99B468429161E1531" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text>If the Commission establishes a central database through the rulemaking under subparagraph (A) and a covered provider updates its own databases to match the central database not less frequently than once every 30 days, no cause of action shall lie or be maintained in any court against the covered provider or its officers, employees, or agents for claims deriving from omission from consumer-facing logs of calls or text messages any records of calls or text messages to covered hotlines in the central database.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF332ED0DD5B44139869E0241B4E0E106"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements under section 345 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by section 4 of this Act, shall take effect 60 days after the date on which the Federal Communications Commission adopts the rules implementing that section pursuant to section 5(b)(2) of this Act.</text></section><section id="H922A7C7F732D4A1EAD6150B4A16FD563"><enum>7.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to abrogate, limit, or otherwise affect the provisions set forth in the Communications Assistance for Law Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/414">Public Law 103–414</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 4279) and the amendments made by that Act, any authority granted to the Commission pursuant to that Act or the amendments made by that Act, or any regulations promulgated by the Commission pursuant to that Act or the amendments made by that Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

