<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E31B2325C39491F9CC6CA51EE0BC84D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7838 IH: Paycheck Protection Program Fairness for Engineering Services Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7838</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that no cost reduction or cash refund is due under certain transportation cost-reimbursement contracts on the basis of the forgiveness of certain covered loans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H15244457D6714AF5BBD38879B6179369" style="OLC"><section id="HEDA505AC61CF4C1FB55B598E314AF900" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Paycheck Protection Program Fairness for Engineering Services Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC350B6D374A5457AAB46C2F0584F762C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Treatment of paycheck protection program loan forgiveness of payroll costs under highway and public transportation project cost-reimbursement contracts</header><subsection id="H27A821E18DA54D74B86BB53929950F0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding section 31.201–5 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), for the purposes of any cost-reimbursement contract awarded in accordance with section 112 of title 23, United States Code, or section 5325 of title 49, United States Code, or any subcontract under such a contract, no cost reduction or cash refund (including through a reduced indirect cost rate) shall be due to the Department of Transportation or to a State transportation department, transit agency, or other recipient of assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/23/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of title 23, United States Code, or <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, on the basis of forgiveness of the payroll costs of a covered loan (as those terms are defined in section 7A(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636m">15 U.S.C. 636m(a)</external-xref>)) issued under the paycheck protection program under section 7(a)(36) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)(36)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1507ECFEE81440C7A17014965E37D2E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Saving provision</header><text>Nothing in this section amends or exempts the prohibitions and liabilities under section 3729 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF3038084973A43FEA891F02F67C7580C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This section ceases to be effective on June 30, 2025.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

