<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF393065F19A46239CE017494190852A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8038 IH: Formula Shortage Reporting Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8038</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220613">June 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Food and Drug Administration to require manufacturers of infant formula to warn about a discontinuance or interruption in the production of infant formula, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H39AC283EB6C94AECBA78A36844062D47" style="OLC"><section id="H71F08CB3C7CC41F8A26627958805D337" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Formula Shortage Reporting Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB75BD757D6EE409FBF0F47BDB55B2470"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement to warn about discontinuance or interruption in the production of infant formula</header><subsection id="H5F205531B73D49CA83996293E9E07F36"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 412 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/350a">21 U.S.C. 350a</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H442D20F35C044D4C8AD7C8417D350C6B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7DBD321077334902BD22DF0BA2F29459"><enum>(j)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC3D4EC6064C34D0691AF670E8F0C11B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A manufacturer of infant formula shall notify the Secretary, in accordance with paragraph (2), of a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of the infant formula or an interruption of the manufacture of the infant formula that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of that infant formula in the United States, or a permanent discontinuance in the manufacture of an infant formula component or an interruption in the manufacture of an infant formula component that is likely to lead to a meaningful disruption in the supply of the infant formula component, and the reasons for such discontinuance or interruption. Notification under this subsection shall include disclosure of—</text><subparagraph id="H65B0A773CD5C4518BA6F6D92C65353DD" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reasons for the discontinuance or interruption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86C0BFDD5E0D4D048F40AC9ECDCEDC95" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if an infant formula component is a reason for, or a risk factor in, such discontinuance or interruption, the source of the infant formula component and any alternative sources for the infant formula component known by the manufacturer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80C7C18A80E1453EA24BA128A6B70DCA" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether any associated device used for preparation or administration included in the infant formula is a reason for, or a risk factor in, such discontinuance or interruption;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24C00805ACCC4324B40CED91C16E3FB4" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in the case of an interruption, the expected duration of the interruption; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H043BCA8AB89D40EA93A671C9D9AF14DE" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A66125A6D874AEA827DF321E81EF744" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A notice required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted to the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H28EB91AC009842F3B4108403F7A65B9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at least 72 hours prior to the date of the discontinuance or interruption; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5C607033AB44E86909496A3FFDA3805"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if compliance with subparagraph (A) is not possible, as soon as practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A946D9C6F58453097C1FABC53E6175B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a manufacturer of infant formula determines that compliance with paragraph (2)(A) is not possible, the manufacturer shall submit such determination in writing to the Secretary and the justification for such determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5EED3EB319F4E0FB4ECAD370B168D29" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall distribute to health care providers who treat pregnant women and children under the age of 2, and make publicly available on the website of the Food and Drug Administration, information on the discontinuance or interruption of the manufacture of the infant formula described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53F9E3BF3E3045FB845229B0F5986A99" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed as authorizing the Secretary to disclose any information that is a trade secret or confidential information subject to section 552(b)(4) of title 5, United States Code, or section 1905 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EAFE5C3501747CBADD21C4FB6A97651" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary shall find a manufacturer of infant formula to be in violation of this section if—</text><subparagraph id="H25B2797B9D3A45B287A50DCAA1F0FDD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that—</text><clause id="HE1DE754857EB4B5CB2E17636784557E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the manufacturer has failed to submit the notice required by paragraph (2) and the determination and justification required by paragraph (3); or</text></clause><clause id="H4C3BB0BE277E461B8C7888AD6931151F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the determination and justification submitted by the manufacturer are insufficient;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB259C549FF75489FBF285F67EE291AD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary issues a letter to such manufacturer—</text><clause id="H2B227C5463F94048A676AC71032111A1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>informing such manufacturer of such failure or insufficiency; and</text></clause><clause id="H1BEB13CF31AD44F0827F224FC5A2D031"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>giving such manufacturer a period of not more than 30 calendar days to correct such failure or insufficiency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC24614836B8C43EBA304428090F2FCB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines such manufacturer has failed to correct such failure or insufficiency by the end of such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C269BFC179541389A335472092392B2" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HF2B381E8A3D342FBB89D19E5EB635E2D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>infant formula component</term> means a raw or in-process material, ingredient, container, or closure used in the manufacturing or processing of infant formula;<italic></italic></text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54C4EE7746D24E44BAA9277E0C3A6D10" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>infant formula shortage</term> or <term>shortage</term>, with respect to an infant formula, means a period of time when the demand or projected demand for the infant formula within the United States exceeds the supply of the infant formula; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA3E7D5FFED64D9FB8D15BC1A9CE05B9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>meaningful disruption</term>—</text><clause id="HCA8BBBDD8FAB4AA087C76BDE26BAF346" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a change in production that is reasonably likely to lead to a reduction in the supply of an infant formula by a manufacturer that is more than negligible and affects the ability of the manufacturer to fill orders or meet expected demand for its product; and</text></clause><clause id="H5D4D178F356E46E0BF08543033057163" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include interruptions in manufacturing due to matters such as routine maintenance or insignificant changes in manufacturing so long as the manufacturer expects to resume operations in a short period of time.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC90271A7D9A749788FF990D993680A0A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/331">21 U.S.C. 331</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA08DC15DC42C4750952C8949DD2F3FFD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA5E9AB2456BE49888CF6F27253AC53EE"><enum>(fff)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The failure by a manufacturer of infant formula, with respect to a notice of discontinuance or interruption, to make a correction as required by section 412(j)(6)(C).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

