<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA05A6705976B42BD8544BD0A468BEEF9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6420 IH: Sex Trafficking Demand Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6420</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220118">January 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001159">Mrs. Rodgers of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 relating to determinations with respect to efforts of foreign countries to reduce demand for commercial sex acts under the minimum standards for the elimination of trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5518BEFD6A07423B979D5238E91EBD52" style="OLC"><section id="H133EBA44993E4A94926707A6D8FFBB3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sex Trafficking Demand Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9E30D0ED4511455BB16BE33E7A486336"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H94166C5ABF134FA89828D6555C541731"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It has been the longstanding position of the United States to reduce the demand for sex trafficking victims. There is also a wide international consensus on the necessity of demand reduction in order to prevent human trafficking. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A96842E74F741B29064DBE3CFEA5812"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United Nations Protocol to Prevent, Suppress and Punish Trafficking in Persons, Especially Women and Children, Supplementing the United Nations Convention Against Transnational Organized Crime of 2000 (also referred to as the <quote>Palermo Protocol(s)</quote>) expressly addresses the requirement that nations make serious efforts to reduce demand for trafficked persons. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95752335A43843658482B64DB89ED232"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Article 9, addressing prevention of human trafficking, specifically directs that, <quote>States Parties shall adopt or strengthen legislative or other measures, such as educational, social or cultural measures, including through bilateral and multilateral cooperation, to discourage the demand that fosters all forms of exploitation of persons, especially women and children, that leads to trafficking.</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23535880F9A54E688060A3568EC502E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United Nations Protocol, the Europe Convention on Action against Human Trafficking, and the 2011 European Union Directive of the European Parliament and the Council on preventing and combating trafficking in human beings also specifically address the need to prevent human trafficking by reducing demand for trafficking victims. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9310D5F59E9449D87324CDF0453382A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Research has shown that legal prostitution increases the demand for prostituted persons and thus increases the market for sex. As a result, there is a significant increase in instances of human trafficking. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DE2C324E9B540C0B83DCF18F86BF1A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2012, researchers Seo-Young Cho, Axel Dreher, and Eric Neumayer published their findings in World Development establishing that, <quote>The scale effect of legalized prostitution leads to an expansion of the prostitution market, increasing human trafficking … . On average, countries where prostitution is legal experience larger reported human trafficking inflows.</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC3337DEC4FF4562948DBCA56D7F8B9B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2005, a study focused on 11 European Union countries requested by the European Parliament’s Committee on Women’s Rights and Gender Equality and performed by Transcrime found that stricter prostitution laws are correlated with fewer human trafficking victims. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA978D9E412CE4F55A467B7F0331C762B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Case studies published by researchers Niklas Jakobsson and Andreas Kotsadam support the possibility of a causal link between harsher prostitution laws and reduced human trafficking. Jakobsson and Kotsadam found that trafficking of persons for commercial sexual exploitation is least prevalent in countries where prostitution is illegal and most prevalent in countries where prostitution is legalized. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB89DEA306424114BD320EE68B10CAEA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Further data have demonstrated the correlation between the adoption of legislation that criminalizes demand and reductions in sex trafficking.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7DDD03B1200A485F89D11CCD39E469D2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Modifications to factors for consideration for minimum standards for elimination of human trafficking</header><subsection id="H64A56B7052454A57BC367CEE2843CA44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (12) of section 108(b) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7106">22 U.S.C. 7106(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6FF86296F3534BFAA229A1E821257125" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8AAB0DD24B3F4557A1E9AD16069C694C"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the government of the country has made serious and sustained efforts to—</text><subparagraph id="HE87DB4C81E64487F9B217E078477C063"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prohibit the purchase of commercial sex acts, to the extent such prohibition is within the authority of such government, or implement a policy against the purchase of commercial sex acts, if such prohibition cannot be instituted; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02DADEA909ED4FCFB74BE0F48421934F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate buyers of commercial sex on how traffickers exploit prostituted persons for human trafficking; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ADFA6DFB66C44C6871E90AA0529B51C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reduce demand for participation in international sex tourism by nationals of the country, including through arrests, prosecutions, and convictions; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H281706915D034691A73CF9080236399B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that anti-trafficking-in-persons training and provisions are incorporated into codes of conduct for the staff of the government, to the extent that such ability is within the authority of the government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB86EB2465A7C4AF9B4A2ED9C9A31D5C0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) takes effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and applies with respect to determinations under subsection (a)(4) of section 108 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 that are made on or after such date of enactment.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

