<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Placed-on-Calendar-Senate" dms-id="HE217DC365A5C4802B963332AD876B4B7" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3807 PCS: Relief for Restaurants and other Hard Hit Small Businesses Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 387</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3807</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc> Read the first time</action-desc></action><action><action-date date="20220525">May 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 to increase appropriations to the Restaurant Revitalization Fund, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAFDE70A286564B11AAFD6E58537F30D9" style="OLC"><section id="HF75A31D0E48C48F6A1CCCF59441D53C9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Relief for Restaurants and other Hard Hit Small Businesses Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0FDDC7F0527046F8A39C7C577C3E6A3D" commented="no" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Restaurant Revitalization Grants</header><subsection id="H945327DF071943ABA070FBFCDC7352BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appropriation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5003(b)(2) of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8B072AFE5D404E37B112A2583CA4A4FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subparagraph id="HC27FFD674C3B4F0A884475C4D8582F86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$28,600,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$70,600,000,000</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H724138DC77EC4002A5545FFA88BACCD6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, of which not more than $420,000,000 shall be for administrative expenses to carry out this section, and of which $7,500,000 shall be for the Inspector General of the Small Business Administration, $7,500,000 for the Department of Justice for investigative and prosecutorial activities related to fraud and abuse, and $7,500,000 for Pandemic Response Accountability Committee, for audits of grants under this section to investigate fraud and to identify improper payments and ineligible recipients, and for other necessary expenses</quote> before the period at the end; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C949607997C4279946D572954822511"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i)(II), by striking <quote>$23,600,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>any remaining amounts not used for a purpose authorized under subparagraph (A) or clause (i) of this subparagraph</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAA2FE837C6D412B9F46140BF0D70F00" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Insufficient funding</header><text>Section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H102C9DD4C5104EC8B60D68F3D65CE27E"><subsection id="HBA3F398FB244451F9EAAA75E076F4CAA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Insufficient funding</header><paragraph id="H6E259C5C717A4FA385E82CFC0BA723C2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Administrator determines that the amounts made available to carry out this section are insufficient to make grants in the amount provided in subsection (c)(4) to each eligible entity that has submitted an application in accordance with the program guidelines in effect on the day before the date of enactment of this subsection, but has not received an award as of such date, the Administrator shall make grants with the available amounts to each such eligible applicant—</text><subparagraph id="HEBD214FF7B924B5E94CD6FFA3CE15972"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such that the amount of the grant that each such eligible entity would have otherwise received under this section is reduced by an equal percentage; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H772FCA305AA142F2A45ECF215D310580"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by establishing a maximum amount for a grant made under this subsection to ensure that smaller eligible entities still receive grants in the amounts provided under subsection (c)(4); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H305B04F592534C14BBCD7B1AD6C4B5D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by providing full awards in the amounts provided under subsection (c)(4) below a certain threshold (as the Administrator may establish) and reducing grants above that threshold by an equal percentage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED63A50508214DC4B94F526CF7799A37"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reserving funds</header><text>Nothing in paragraph (1) shall prevent the Administrator from— </text><subparagraph id="H90B9ADAADC364E2EA897E9D24D7F460D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reserving funding for applicants that may be determined to be eligible for a grant under this section upon reconsideration; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A438D65673046CEB4A069F7A05A9F51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>making partial awards to eligible entities on a preliminary basis until the amount of funding required to fund grants to all eligible applicants is established, upon the completion of the reconsideration process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4C7C80933F0A4341AA0C9E6B7897FBAA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reports; reconsideration; verification of business type</header><text>Section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (b), is further amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFEF0396E54364FC9B9CD24CED80618FA"><subsection id="HFFDABD3283F24519A5BDCF97D9CF0901"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="HD7A048874CF9487698FD91141252E8F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on a biweekly basis until the amounts made available to carry out this section are fully expended, publish data that shows, for the period beginning on the date on which the Administrator began making grants under this section and ending on the date on which the information is published—</text><subparagraph id="HB48FA429768A4507A1527E960E046F52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to applications for grants under this section, the number of those applications—</text><clause id="H079077EDB178487CBA56D6DBF2CB1B31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the Administrator has received;</text></clause><clause id="H7405845F1CBE420CAF6788D8F546784F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the Administrator has reviewed or is in the process of reviewing; and</text></clause><clause id="HD86B958DA12B4412B3C826847468B76F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to which the Administrator has made a decision; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56756D7FC0E644E9B64B0C3601A0818C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and dollar amount of grants under this section—</text><clause id="H3673921D8DCC45818AAF4904C03F5ABD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that have been awarded; and</text></clause><clause id="H7113402D5605416097636FCEFC8F1DE1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that have been disbursed; </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E2444FF5D1240ACA411C55D1C40CE8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on a weekly basis until the amounts made available to carry out this section are fully expended, publish, with respect to the period beginning on the date of enactment of this subsection and ending on the date on which the information is published—</text><subparagraph id="H2E94A04EBFA94075A321781994803949"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to each eligible entity to which a grant is made under this section—</text><clause id="HA8BD7F0D09A04F60A4DE5CCE2997C6DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name of the eligible entity, including the name or names under which the eligible entity does business if that name is different from the name of the eligible entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H41D1C6100D534E6ABC73B445797CA280"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the address of—</text><subclause id="H7A8ED177A98F41DE9513D68D5D238F56"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the eligible entity; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1792C2A2BC7F4EFF97D0263365B1ED3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the physical location or locations for the eligible entity listed on the application, if different from the address of the eligible entity;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C8D5597458D425D81462D76C41FEF61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of each grant described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11BB87F2CA444D028DB5AAF46E1948AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the business category listed in subsection (a)(4)(A) to which the eligible entity belongs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7BE7B42541A84AE88F9AC33CF94E789E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reconsideration</header><paragraph id="HC7AC2BF2ECA646E3B8F4F823C7A37626"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Explanation for denial</header><text>With respect to an applicant that applies for a grant under this section and is denied by the Administrator, the Administrator shall make available to the applicant a brief explanation identifying the reason why the Administrator denied the application of the applicant, which shall include, where applicable, a citation to the statutory, regulatory, or guidance provision with which the applicant failed to comply and that was the basis for the denial.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EDEC087D7E949BC83CCCF45F0322CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish a reconsideration process through which the applicant may—</text><subparagraph id="HB3F2B54A717445CA99685009EB24E31B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Administrator additional information the applicant determines to be relevant to whether the applicant is eligible for the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA258E4EFA1CD4AD9A8ECB3B47A5BA2D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>receive a review of the application and such additional information submitted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63039215C4B74442A51A72669B8E9B12"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Verification of business type</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Administrator verifies that an applicant for a loan under section 7(a)(36) of the Small Business Act is not an eligible business type for a grant under this section using credible information other than information obtained from the application of the applicant for such loan during 2020, the Administrator may reject the application solely on those grounds.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA14FA63EA0EB4E4F939D719168700761"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirement of continuing operation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any application for a grant under section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>) that is pending on the date of enactment of this Act or for which the applicant has received an award notice but the Administrator has not disbursed amounts under the grant, the Administrator may not disburse amounts under the grant unless the applicant submits a statement to the Administrator indicating the applicant is still operating, or intends to reopen within 6 months after the date of the statement is submitted, the place of business for which such applicant is seeking such grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A640E7933504DE3A716C0140BFD646E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Oversight and audits</header><text>Section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (c), is further amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A6DC679D6D14C72830B0A14A5877318"><subsection id="H990CC226530146619ADAC832653484FC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Oversight and audits</header><paragraph id="H1A5B92F06C204CC0BA918F948327EB8F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall institute an oversight and audit plan with respect to eligible entities receiving grants under this section, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H342BDF4F96F445F0A86A7BC3405BE6A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>documentation requirements that are consistent with the eligibility and other requirements under this section, including by requiring an eligible entity that receives a grant under this section to retain records that demonstrate compliance with those requirements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59EA347C62274DCE99D121B32CDB8835"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reviews of the use of grants made under this section by eligible entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F69111867DA4E93BFDA277BD5DD3108"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of plan</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives the plan required under paragraph (1), which shall describe—</text><subparagraph id="HD6532FEDEFA84963B7F7B99F9F2BBD3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the policies and procedures of the Administrator for conducting oversight and audits of grants made under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E749CCD73564EB79124C1D4AE4684F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the metrics that the Administrator will use to determine which grants made under this section will be audited under that plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H655382E97E5442AA8CCCC0D00C1B7155"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this subsection, and once every 30 days thereafter until the date that is 180 days after the date on which all amounts made available to carry out this section have been fully expended, and upon request thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the oversight and audit activities of the Administrator under this subsection, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HBD7DD9CE6BA8474D8BFF0BD246C1D208"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of grants approved and disbursed under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194196CC6BF9426B8512D44D3871B25D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount of each grant received by each eligible entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA602C6A0F6A44756AF4AA3F3EFB4E074"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of active investigations and audits of grants made under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC39BC0AD366343DFAA34DF942D16F0A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of completed reviews and audits of grants made under this section, including a description of—</text><clause id="H50DDF16FCDC040DDB6AB9CD72F90295F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any findings of fraud or other material noncompliance with the requirements of this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H998F038404B14C7E8C575A8749B59B0D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the total amount recouped from ineligible recipients; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF2C3E241606433EAE4828BB265C192B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of any substantial changes made to the plan required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DAFA031A3E84520960E14661B49B890"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Retroactive application</header><text>This subsection shall apply to grants and decisions made under this section before, on, or after the date of enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H612637F3AA784B0F91E50955031A1AC4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Hard Hit Industries Award Program</header><subsection id="HB9773140019A4CF7BFDEA4899D6FDFF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC2DD0E767B9A4BC194F79D77D95A4F22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AB21DAA29AF4FE4B05CB2DA2F4911AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Affiliated business</header><text>The term <term>affiliated business</term> means a business in which an eligible entity—</text><subparagraph id="HC300C31785F441C69F51B7E1646FDBB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has an equity or right to receive not less than 50 percent of the profit distributions of such business; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE235CF622AA49D0950E528D76621870"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has, on or before March 13, 2020, contractual authority to control the business.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BAD4B9ADCEE4339BD3B3F887A37AB37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Award</header><text>The term <term>award</term> means a financial assistance payment that an eligible applicant receives directly from the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73C647E241C3478EBCB5ED0FF4C555D0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered period</header><text>The term <term>covered period</term> means the period beginning on February 15, 2020, and ending on the later of—</text><subparagraph id="HF54F4E59396A49F3A471F3BD3DE918C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>March 31, 2023; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H081111C84D5141EAB5F674B947BCBF7F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a date to be determined by the Administrator that is not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2EEC6BFC0EB4A329D20268D4C71B9BA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H622AF3BF1E634ECC99CEC9E4A18A465C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a small business concern that—</text><clause id="H36ACBE007FDC4E63938DCACADA2D8E0F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employs not more than 200 employees; and</text></clause><clause id="HB8B580BCBB6E41C297C66BE3151CDC0D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>suffered a pandemic-related revenue loss of 40 percent or greater; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6E8D03F4AE24CC0B004C8175459E793" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include a small business concern that—</text><clause id="H932D6D1EEF764167B7873A02DFDE2DC5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a State or local government-operated business;</text></clause><clause id="HC79589A12BA24725A0021802BD4DAE96" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has received a grant under—</text><subclause id="H43392AAD1F8542F288FFC74DC37CC8A0" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 324 of the Economic Aid to Hard Hit Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Venues Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009a">15 U.S.C. 9009a</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause id="HED41DABBDBD64E35904186D969F3A1FE" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H656C7F274CFF47F1892E05BED9625354"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a publicly-traded company; </text></clause><clause id="H16B925EBD21642E3BA69EA3415BD2FC0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is an entity that is owned or operated by a private equity fund; or </text></clause><clause id="H8E019E1A83F04CCEBC2F90CA036A70B8"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a wage violation at the time of application.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4388A86E17BD422196AEF454520FA360"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible self-employed individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible self-employed individual</term> has the meaning given in section 7002(b) of the Families First Coronavirus Response Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/1401">26 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref> note). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD614F47E2ED74854920FC3789FFDDC0D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Exchange; issuer; security</header><text>The terms <term>exchange</term>, <term>issuer</term>, and <term>security</term> have the meanings given those terms, respectively, in section 3(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F28B6DDCA7F4AAD97D0180B847FC9AB"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Pandemic-related revenue loss</header><subparagraph id="H078D1E39CE024A349AEB97A940BCAE4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>pandemic-related revenue loss</term> means, subject to subparagraph (B) and with respect to an eligible entity—</text><clause id="H2C5E95F371AB45E8B313C0391839E8C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">except as provided in clauses (ii) and (iii), the average annual gross receipts during 2020 and 2021, as established using such verification documentation as the Administrator may require, of the eligible entity subtracted from the gross receipts of the eligible entity in 2019, if such sum is greater than zero;</text></clause><clause id="H2CAED0C4A6214CDB8F81678C8E86B99C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the eligible entity was not in operation for the entirety of 2019—</text><subclause id="HD187B9E0D6B3433D99AF243B9A732930"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the difference between—</text><item id="H59E123512A874564A93FC480D12222BD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the product obtained by multiplying the average monthly gross receipts of the eligible entity in 2019 by 12; and</text></item><item id="H6642063B313A48DA9489CC4476BD9584"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the product obtained by multiplying the average monthly gross receipts of the eligible entity in 2020 and 2021 by 12; or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H1D42A198086C4685A99AEA54E0CA226A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an amount based on a formula determined by the Administrator; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC72FE2C8D0994D9AA890E9A48F60B8D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if the eligible entity began operations during the period beginning on January 1, 2020, and ending on the day before the date of enactment of this section, an amount based on a formula determined by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H129F3165F64343B5BED6269841E7BE9A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reduction</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the pandemic-related revenue losses for an eligible entity calculated under subparagraph (A) shall be reduced by the sum of—</text><clause id="H49776F54D6E741E697A21636CA990AFE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amount received from a covered loan made under paragraph (36) or (37) of section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>) in 2020 or 2021;</text></clause><clause id="HA9DD8AE568F04D1199104C1AAA37FAA3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amount received as a grant under section 1110 of the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009">15 U.S.C. 9009</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H7F3FFB8AAAF3429994BF512155F84C29" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any amount received as a grant under section 331 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Venues Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009b">15 U.S.C. 9009b</external-xref>). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D1FA55744DC42FABDCD1F6C3B927B77" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Percentage determination</header><text>For the purposes of determining the percentage of pandemic-related revenue loss under this subsection, the percentage shall be equal to—</text><clause id="H9E4ED198A5F24673B8A83DA86229FE31" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity for which subparagraph (A)(i) applies, the product obtained by multiplying—</text><subclause id="H5A6ACA33F02A48529FEACD3E2A69646B" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quotient obtained by dividing the pandemic-related revenue losses for such eligible entity by the gross receipts of the eligible entity in 2019; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD3D30463FADA4DEA8B9C24C91A3642CB" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>100;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF7A4644CD56F41DB82213B9E7997141B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity for which subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) applies, the product obtained by multiplying—</text><subclause id="H7A22FE3B24C247FABB17FDF6CAA82B6C" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the quotient obtained by dividing the pandemic-related revenue losses for such eligible entity by the product obtained by multiplying the average monthly gross receipts of the eligible entity in 2019 by 12; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HFAC34C11B41D48E686A17B75FDD50376" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>100; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA320818455CD42C9A316BC595F94C6F1" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of an eligible entity for which clauses (ii)(II) or (iii) applies, an amount based on a formula determined by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC924226E4A6E4DCC8FE263E41F1B6A00"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Payroll costs</header><text>The term <term>payroll costs</term> has the meaning given the term in section 7(a)(36)(A) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)(36)(A)</external-xref>), except that such term shall not include—</text><subparagraph id="H90BEF15496FE4E169971069F402D6C26"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified wages, as defined in section 2301(c) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/3111">26 U.S.C. 3111</external-xref> note), taken into account in determining the credit allowed under such section 2301; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6DD5BDA4979461A8AB4ECA59F965AA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>premiums taken into account in determining the credit allowed under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6432">section 6432</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C938BB1A8B14C69AD36026410D4F32E"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Private equity fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>private equity fund</term> has the meaning given the term in section 225.173(a) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E8B265BDE04000A725F9AE9603305F"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Publicly-traded company</header><text>The term <term>publicly-traded company</term> means an entity that is majority owned or controlled by an entity that is an issuer, the securities of which are listed on a national securities exchange under section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BD8EBBFACD04A75B242D2E9475B99CE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Small business concern</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>small business concern</quote> has the meaning given under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>) and includes—</text><subparagraph id="H9B1E0E30BC5D4DCDA2729CDAFC2E50F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals who operate under a sole proprietorship, as an independent contractor, or as an eligible self-employed individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6E53D09A25E4A53AD2B4579DD85BF4C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">small business concerns described in subparagraphs (B), (C), and (D) of section 31(b)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657a">15 U.S.C. 657a(b)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7095056A4E114464AF38D7CB144E3FA5" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Small Business Act definitions</header><text>The terms <term>covered mortgage obligation</term>, <term>covered operations expenditure</term>, <term>covered rent obligation</term>, <term>covered supplier cost</term>, <term>covered utility payment</term>, and <term>covered worker protection expenditure</term> have the meanings given, respectively, in section 7A of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636m">15 U.S.C. 636m</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84AEA36D6B71444093E1E2B9DAB3564D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Awards to eligible entities</header><paragraph id="HE09799DA4C7C4FE98F59C5D52E50D410" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts made available under this Act, the Administrator shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Hard Hit Industries Award Program</quote>, under which the Administrator shall make awards to eligible entities that submit an application under paragraph (2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAADC1E8F4C842A0B21490A8FF061122"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="HC48A781F2E494F81BEF20C8AE948C676"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>An eligible entity shall submit to the Administrator an application for an award under this subsection. In such application, the eligible entity shall make a good faith certification that—</text><clause id="H029DBC85AC9B405B8CED601803B422B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the uncertainty of current economic conditions makes necessary the award request to support the ongoing operations of the eligible entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H88107EE209C14EA3A8F0C1C2DA90AD8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the eligible entity has no pending application for and has not received a grant under—</text><subclause id="HA4BB21B1347F41F09DDAF6E3E8188EAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 324 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Venues Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009a">15 U.S.C. 9009a</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H53A50EE840F5441484031525C20AEE1B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61A5B414F85B427FBB7F440343A05A87"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Verification</header><text>The Administrator shall use tax records or other reliable sources, such as certified accounting statements, with respect to an applicant for an award under this section to determine—</text><clause id="H83B7C2A0DB2A4C6FA6D897AD6DA65BC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the eligibility of the applicant for that award; and</text></clause><clause id="H9966BCED50FF48DC91C92258506B0B5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount of that award to the applicant.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC75C7F5BB83440E2BF2AFA5E1754DF04"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Acceptance of applications</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall begin accepting applications for an award under this subsection. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7491BAF61034736ADE805DF989CB604" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Priority</header><clause id="HCB15DB41DACB483DAD95F81475D70207" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall prioritize eligible entities that have experienced significant pandemic-related revenue loss to receive an award under this section as follows:</text><subclause id="H5EAF5A72622946DE9553459D4A001C89" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">First priority to eligible entities that experienced a pandemic-related revenue loss of at least 80 percent.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD41182B5D1FB456695926EF6244D72B9" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Second priority to eligible entities that experienced a pandemic-related revenue loss of at least 60 percent.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFC71CCE6C16844AF9DE7237BACA89D2C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Smaller entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within each category of eligible entities described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (i), the Administrator may prioritize awards to eligible entities with 50 employees or fewer.</text></clause><clause id="HCC42BEFE2AAC4FD69AEE3FA370FE7810" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Additional priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within each category of eligible entities described in subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (i), the Administrator may prioritize awards to eligible entities that did not receive a covered loan made under paragraph (36) or (37) of section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>) in 2020 or 2021.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36C705A72BDF4778983C7F898B5DACF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Award amount</header><subparagraph id="HBE2B58A884DD4F138B550F1C67056269"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Aggregate maximum amount</header><text>The aggregate maximum amount of awards made to an eligible entity and any affiliated businesses of the eligible entity under this subsection may not exceed $1,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H721399AF96084CDDA29B3F6E7D44115C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination of award amount</header><clause id="H779D7BBA3D5C47508DE9679AA396BEEE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this paragraph, the amount of an award made to an eligible entity under this subsection shall be equal to the pandemic-related revenue loss of the eligible entity.</text></clause><clause id="H05E51F3756024ABDBA05644065793A1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Return to Treasury</header><text>Any amount of an award made under this subsection to an eligible entity described in clause (ii) or (iii) of subsection (a)(8)(A) that is greater than the average annual gross receipts of the eligible entity in 2020 and 2021 shall be returned to the Treasury.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H502ADDF3E0CC4B6EA1400EB41F03FE53" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Insufficient funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After selecting award recipients in accordance with paragraph (2)(D) and before disbursing any awards under this section, if the Administrator determines that the amounts made available under this Act for making awards under this section are insufficient to make awards to each eligible entity that submits an application under paragraph (2) in the amount described under subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Administrator may make awards with the available amounts such that the amount of the award that each eligible entity would have otherwise received under those subparagraphs and in accordance with paragraph (2)(D) is reduced by a percentage, except that the Administrator may establish an aggregate maximum amount for awards made under this subparagraph and in accordance with paragraph (2)(D) to ensure that smaller eligible entities receive awards in the amounts provided under those subparagraphs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D3556358ECD4AC7BAAC1CAA6C2BD791"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>During the covered period, an eligible entity that receives an award under this subsection may use the award for the following expenses incurred as a direct result of, or during, the COVID–19 pandemic:</text><subparagraph id="HB317B2F8939547D2AB450DE982E66B1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Payroll costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BCEA5F9EBE34F0797C5405280947933"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Payments to independent contractors, as reported on Form 1099–MISC, except that each such payment may not exceed $100,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE7E630F3CA2473B89734896E6F0757F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Scheduled payments of interest or principal on any covered mortgage obligation (which may not include any prepayment of principal on a covered mortgage obligation).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA63788846FC0422089F20F9C77669037"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Payments on any covered rent obligation and common area maintenance charges under a lease agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66DD6D4F0AC44F35B40FCBA881D05349"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Covered utility payments.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF01BCE36F8294C24B751251BAE51577D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Maintenance expenses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D11AD298BF147148636D46D9A99A203"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Covered worker protection expenditures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A669A9F217F480C9AE922BB4CE1197D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Supplies, including protective equipment and cleaning materials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8C8DFCA1F7B4C7D85BEC5E7CB14B68A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Expenses that were within the scope of the normal business practice of the eligible entity before the covered period.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D28225402C64FF3B650ACFFC6F633A0"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Covered supplier costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC87DB0FF9954A069E5F1EFC7BCC1F21"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Covered operational expenses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7E0E86C64F645CF830D24F08FCC1FD5"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Paid sick leave.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7669E03A56CF44C8A72F09F9E8E1E478"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Capital expenditures (or expenses required under any Federal, State, or local law) relating to implementing social distancing measures.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82CEC9C19831410CADB111944C9957F0"><enum>(N)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other essential expenses of the eligible entity, as determined by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47724375C81E49C39E5EA0993C983989"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Returning funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an eligible entity that receives an award under this section fails to use all of the award on or before the last day of the covered period or permanently ceases operations on or before the last day of the covered period, the eligible entity shall return to the Administrator any funds that the eligible entity did not use for the allowable expenses under paragraph (4).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BA61F10AB4541599D9CDE7364CEE785"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data transparency and customer service</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H3E5C247519B0428EBF664C63B04C0DF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in carrying out this section, maintain regular communication with applicants and representatives of such applicants, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H7486E7C3603F47D5BC95E1FBF48CAD69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hosting regularly scheduled information sessions with those persons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC181363FAACB4E479072893A6AEF2DC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing opportunities to those persons to submit and receive answers to questions regarding awards made under this section;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D1C1AE4B1844E2AB8BD886D156E71DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on a weekly basis until the amounts made available under this section are fully expended, publish data that shows, for the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the information is published—</text><subparagraph id="HEBC55CBA3A25428792F5B0D1043D9699"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to applications for awards under this section, the number of those applications—</text><clause id="H38184F37B910458598C6330C9F56D15D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that the Administrator has received;</text></clause><clause id="H5F24A7E4356D40738FBA3D596D2116F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the Administrator has reviewed or is in the process of reviewing; and</text></clause><clause id="H1AEC5CFDC0184ED08024A374D2AD6727"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to which the Administrator has made a decision; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7ADE9A8AEF24AE1A8C9C813AF4EA984"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number and dollar amount of payments awarded and disbursed under this section;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H601F5D38BEFA44F59A755A96EBC4B8EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on a weekly basis until the amounts made available to carry out this section are fully expended, publish, for the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the information is published—</text><subparagraph id="HD0EC27322C1848B3A17A42D70EBEAB8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and location of each eligible entity to which an award has been made under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H554D4746D2F04D5EBE0BEDA06473FA43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount of such award;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ADC5CEE98C2413CACAF2F16B3751E1C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>with respect to an applicant that applies for an award under this section and is denied by the Administrator—</text><subparagraph id="HE3C1CE05F6D043B3BFA7DED17C181AD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make available to the applicant a brief explanation regarding the denial which shall include, where applicable, a citation to the statute, regulation, or guidance with which the applicant failed to comply and that was the basis for the denial; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA2B0D6CED5846079558622D5D197620"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establish a reconsideration process through which the applicant may—</text><clause id="HEDBD0D6958074F0CA856B63243680700"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Administrator additional information the applicant determines to be relevant to whether the applicant is eligible for the grant; and</text></clause><clause id="H7625299615774C23BDAE28EB099D01C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receive a review of the application and such additional information submitted under clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78186D1883784CD5A6B8A7690D3403EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Tax treatment of awards</header><paragraph id="HF0EEE6D3916B4E929BA4254759F9929E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purposes of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986—</text><subparagraph id="H4B509722068F4C93B5719A21446A4301"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no award made under this section shall be included in the gross income of the eligible entity that receives an award;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16B8D633C32149269542E635235EB1E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no deduction shall be denied, no tax attribute shall be reduced, and no basis increase shall be denied, by reason of the exclusion from gross income provided by subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H457450AD65AC4FF79EB98213DACE750D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case of a partnership or S corporation that receives an award under this section—</text><clause id="HDE171D83E2714531B91E56D0764FBD36"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any amount excluded from income by reason of subparagraph (A) shall be treated as tax exempt for purposes of sections 705 and 1366 of such Code; and</text></clause><clause id="H67D4C99B21474C5F8F75F62FF71A3B81"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary’s delegate) shall prescribe rules for determining a partner’s distributive share of any amount described in clause (i) for purposes of section 705 of such Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E985D2457B542CBA5543075ED1C0DC8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall apply to taxable years ending after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE21AFB3103B046C5855958C0D7CD6408"><enum>(e)</enum><header>System for Award Management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not require any eligible entity that applies for an award under this section to use the System for Award Management (or any successor system) with respect to that award.</text></subsection><subsection id="H44E720EF9D8A4D4B820276A3D94EEA8E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Application processing</header><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget may, on an emergency basis and in order to expedite the processing and approval of applications for awards under this section, waive the requirements of part 200 of title 2, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations) with respect to an award made under this section, if—</text><paragraph id="HB581D40F1CD94BA688BDB2A49DD24479"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Director finds that such a waiver will prevent eligible entities from failing or suffering undue hardship; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A27165BFA3246578DC889E536E18CDE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>each eligible entity that receives an award under this section is still required to submit to the Administrator ongoing reports regarding the use by the eligible entity of the award amounts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CB252C6D9D24687BC801102F38538E1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Oversight and audits</header><paragraph id="HFC89DB7BC3B54D3EBC40EBAB034F1C91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In cooperation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator shall establish an oversight and audit plan with respect to eligible entities receiving awards under this section, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H8A35240E1FC04D92803B950EBF281573"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">documentation requirements that are consistent with the eligibility and other requirements under this section, including a requirement that an eligible entity that receives an award under this section retains records that demonstrate compliance with the requirements of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32C6A4ABEB6D424B9707313F193AA1D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reviews of the use, by eligible entities, of awards made under this section to ensure compliance with the requirements of this section, which shall include—</text><clause id="HA68FA9D12AF944A8A11DDFB943745438"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a review and audit by the Administrator of awards made under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H15BB9722045A4DADA06167150D300D99"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of fraud or other material noncompliance with respect to an award made under this section—</text><subclause id="HBC66693D621A472481156D9271330FF4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a requirement that the applicable eligible entity repay to the Administrator the amount of the misspent funds; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7D1781B4BA534E5F9D276BA1978E1151"><enum>(II)</enum><text>legal action by the Administrator to collect the misspent funds.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EF85EB568494FDA81593778442D2D8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of plan</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives the plan required under paragraph (1), which shall describe—</text><subparagraph id="H20F4859D0E7E4C479021F8E7FBF7E30B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the policies and procedures of the Administrator for conducting oversight and audits of awards made under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H332A7F825E6043348E60775D4189A218"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the metrics that the Administrator will use to determine which awards made under this section will be audited under that plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD5777293C9C4338AC741437B7AA2C2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, once every 30 days thereafter until the date that is 180 days after the date on which all amounts made available to carry out this section have been fully expended, and upon request thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the oversight and audit activities of the Administrator under this subsection, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC688CE3882BA4814B23B8D3D1AE0B964"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number of awards approved and disbursed under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H099A7918B77D4D3FA997264C08F5387A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total amount of each award received by each eligible entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F037B3BD697476096FDCE805EFB2851"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of active investigations and audits of awards made under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE60AECE070A84585B86DAB6FBF19E818"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of completed reviews and audits of awards made under this section, including a description of any findings of fraud or other material noncompliance with the requirements of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F4E2117E4294878BDBCB0F37CB3286B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a description of any substantial changes made to the plan required under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD551E7E388C74F3B8FE0013278738A9F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue rules to carry out this section, without regard to the notice requirements under section 553(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA31E7F21E7C5480AA888698412BA556D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $13,000,000,000, for the Hard Hit Industries Award Program established under this section, to remain available until expended, of which not more than $380,000,000 shall be for administrative expenses to carry out this section, of which—</text><paragraph id="H11C2AA6FEA7046D8B5C1816A99C32D11" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,500,000 shall be for the Inspector General of the Small Business Administration to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse with respect to funding made available for the Hard Hit Industries Award Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1274BCF0FB8C4499982D83A8A40FDFCE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,500,000 shall be for the Department of Justice for investigative and prosecutorial activities related to fraud and abuse, with respect to funding made available for the Hard Hit Industries Award Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE349AE83D1B940E887A2C7861B33C966" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$2,500,000 shall be for shall be for the Pandemic Response Accountability Committee with respect to funding made available for the Hard Hit Industries Award Program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA85A62733DB94346A92F1D5E73DC80A4" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Funding for the Restaurant Revitalization Fund and the Hard Hit Industries Award Program</header><subsection id="HD8F4E1C17C144788A878BCDBE348C0F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any unobligated covered funds are hereby transferred to the Administrator of the Small Business Administration for purposes of carrying out section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>) and the Hard Hit Industries Award Program established under section 3 of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H107352726FA24E1B9BC49A10E0F4EBE7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered funds defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered funds</term>—</text><paragraph id="H5FB8F5F2A238464AAA820BFDC4BA64C1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means any and all funds recovered, seized, reclaimed, or otherwise returned to the Federal Government received pursuant to—</text><subparagraph id="H0C41AF07907446E18CA3146137698012" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">paragraph (36) or (37) of section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H202FFAA3BAED447BACBE4F4F51DB02B2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 7(b)(2) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(b)</external-xref>), with respect to a loan made under such section in response to COVID–19 during the covered period (as defined in section 1110(a) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009">15 U.S.C. 9009(a)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0336C7F07CEE4EF28DE8AAFA13F5594D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 1110(e) of the CARES Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009">15 U.S.C. 9009(e)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A93A3702CB4A9B9933D026B11F7E66" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 331 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Venues Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009b">15 U.S.C. 9009b</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1A507AE25AC42C7A5B2B494E07CA6DD" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 324 of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Venues Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009a">15 U.S.C. 9009a</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F696E484AC447E48E4B21792AC862F1" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB2D56BFC1D746519E652F07F4306BEE" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 3 of this Act;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5C882CDDD4B43649A7DD8DE9591868B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes any funds that as of December 31, 2022, are unexpended under section 5003 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009c">15 U.S.C. 9009c</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D2A3627CE3A435B9BD54733B99610E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include funds paid by person to the Federal Government for the purposes of tax obligations, servicing of loans, or standard payment of fees.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7E0AB154BF8C42BAAC0558D89D153463"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants for shuttered venue operators</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 324(d) of the Economic Aid to Hard-Hit Small Businesses, Nonprofits, and Venues Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/9009a">15 U.S.C. 9009a(d)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFA6171E5EE2A478398FC46C20ED564AA" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0FCC86A6059E49EF865AF2184F183C18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="H53C574F748E54E53968B78E9E46D161C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Expenses incurred</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received under a grant under this section may be used for costs incurred during the period beginning on March 1, 2020, and ending on March 11, 2023 (or a later date, as determined by the Administrator).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F8D8512CD0D4BD68928CA6A65B71F60"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Expenditure</header><text>An eligible person or entity shall return to the Administrator any amounts received under a grant under this section that are not expended on or before April 15, 2023 (or a later date, as determined by the Administrator), with respect to costs incurred during the period described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220407" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 7, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220525">May 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Read the second time and placed on the calendar</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

