<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99DAC99E018D40779CA13A4EEB15C441" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9085 IH: Cybersecurity Clinics Grant Program Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9085</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program carried out by the Department of Homeland Security to fund university-based cybersecurity clinics at junior or community colleges, historically Black colleges and universities (HBCUs), Hispanic-serving institutions (HSIs), and other minority-serving institutions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD6A4D1A31E443B48E24580601C954B9" style="OLC"><section id="H6B8D3518A6FD44F0985C3EEF987A1E18" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cybersecurity Clinics Grant Program Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF2633AA07C4C46629B477626FBF47363" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cybersecurity Clinics Grant Program</header><subsection id="H20F4A5D49F4D426085F2CC73A0178084"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Cybersecurity Clinics Grant Program</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>). Under the Program, the Secretary shall make grants to fund university-based cybersecurity clinics at junior or community colleges, historically Black colleges and universities (HBCUs), Hispanic-serving institutions (HSIs), and other minority-serving institutions to allow such colleges, universities, and institutions to—</text><paragraph id="H1A137DF087114FC49526F0007504452B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop interactive, personalized workshops to provide education on the importance of protecting devices, data, and identity from physical and digital compromise;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9412DEA8E3140A09AB0B964A7EACF86"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop experiential cybersecurity curriculum to provide education relating to how to increase cybersecurity resilience in organizations and defend against digital threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EA075F258F144398F109BC1E3DD7C9D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer high-potential paths to increase the number of experienced cybersecurity professionals by creating a talent pipeline of students with practical experience, and appropriate certifications, interested in joining the cybersecurity workforce; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC794C02384DC4C10B8612290B2F59DB3"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help civil society organizations, State and local government agencies, critical infrastructure providers, small and medium-sized businesses, and other under-represented and under-resourced public interest organizations develop their cybersecurity workforces.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA74A420B5236493A8F492C58F209F65A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cybersecurity curriculum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, shall develop the experiential cybersecurity curriculum referred to in subsection (a)(2) to carry out the Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3237C8EA160E465E8F61F939C8D31A5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, shall annually submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report containing information on the expenditure by each grant recipient of grant funds made under the Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF188132C5DA449BC849D7DD13FB14C89" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency, shall issue guidance regarding the development of experiential cybersecurity curriculums described in paragraph (2) of subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="H8183AFD02FE14B56B9676A5090278E37" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out the Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2136EB7953C84EC08531E4BF92117D2E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE83B807538EE40B886FCF94C5871BA26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hispanic-serving institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Hispanic-serving institution</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 502 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H170B9C68360B44618BBF2D693B928A2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historically Black colleges and universities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>historically Black colleges and universities</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE4800F12C944002A88FDE0B8E8DF237"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD45F8C690C469CBB0E8F73EE531028"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Junior or community college</header><text>The term <quote>junior or community college</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 312(f) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9E37A9E894C44C285327CEDC86949F7"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>minority-serving institution</quote> means an institution of higher education described in section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

