<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA70F624C0BD84C84A075B6419F546E7F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6660 IH: First Rhode Island Regiment Congressional Gold Medal Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6660</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000396">Mr. Kahele</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000015">Mr. Neal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To award a Congressional gold medal, collectively, to the First Rhode Island Regiment, in recognition of their dedicated service during the Revolutionary War.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB73B0A16E59A4BA99D5A06E74670E554" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HAC39A4CECD68445C962CAF76560519D6"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>First Rhode Island Regiment Congressional Gold Medal Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1D5A272F760342B8A5C126B5E909CD52"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HD468B2C5EC0940DDA0DA0771C26AB6A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During the winter at Valley Forge, from 1777–1778, the Continental Army had difficulty recruiting the necessary quotas of men set by the Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A72EFBEEA0B49DEA659C2DE809F2C55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At the same time, the State of Rhode Island was ordered to supply two battalions while faced with the occupation of the City of Newport by the British.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H663A85F3E1A84E2A9A5A7BE1F8717A65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In January 1778, at the urging of Brigadier General James Varnum, General George Washington wrote to Governor Nicholas Cooke of the State of Rhode Island requesting assistance recruiting men for the Continental Line.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48BE9EADFCF343C49BE402D330E27B61"><enum>(4)</enum><text>On February 14, 1778, the Rhode Island General Assembly voted to allow the enlistment of <quote>every able-bodied negro, mulatto, or Indian man slave</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A56E9D70A514466993240E45ACD5748"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In addition, the Rhode Island General Assembly provided that any enlisted slave <quote>upon his passing muster before Colonel Christopher Greene, be immediately discharged from the service of his master or mistress, and be absolutely free as though he had never been incumbered and be incumbered with any kind of servitude or slavery.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7764D73DD2AC4EB7A27A7FB6BBC8A4F1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a result, between February 1778 and June 1778, Colonel Christopher Greene, Lt. Colonel Jeremiah Olney and Major Samuel Ward recruited almost 200 men of African heritage and Indigenous descent who formed the core of the First Rhode Island Regiment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0BCF9B0C43C4D38B4536DFC6AE20AE2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The First Rhode Island Regiment became among the first units in American History in which men of every race and ethnicity were recruited to serve.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6273E8AA525241AE87BD3A39FD119EDB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>On August 28, 1778, at the Battle of Rhode Island, following an attempted siege of British-occupied Newport along with the newly allied French fleet, the First Rhode Island Regiment acted heroically in holding back Hessian forces and causing them to retreat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3254CB2845084A7EB05DA30F4C359BF6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>During the Battle of Rhode Island, the First Rhode Island Regiment’s losses included three killed, nine wounded and eleven missing soldiers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E547ABF4832434CA887CD198C66AEB5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>For an additional 5 years, the First Rhode Island Regiment fought bravely to win American independence including at Fort Oswego, Saratoga, and Yorktown.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F59B763EE2E438D97C5B669569CFA62"><enum>(11)</enum><text>On June 13, 1783, at Saratoga, the First Rhode Island Regiment was demobilized.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3FC1B89C84F4F8795CFFC65478AE7C6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Their commander, Colonel Jeremiah Olney, praised the Regiment for <quote>faithfully preserving in the best of causes, in every stage of service, with unexampled fortitude and patience through all the danger and toils of a long and severe war</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H629E63AAAC084EF5BA21CDD8FE4D0EEB"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Afterwards, some veterans of the First Rhode Island Regiment had to consistently resist efforts at re-enslavement and fought for back wages from the Rhode Island General Assembly.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F4BA36163314F619E0EC10A82C0AB05"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the Rhode Island State Archives, the First Rhode Island Regiment included at least the following soldiers: Babcock, Priamus (Primus); Bent, Prince; Bours, Cato; Brown, Priamus (Primus); Burk, Africa; Burroughs, John; Carpenter, Cudgo; Champlin, Dick; Champlin, Jack; Champlin, July; Champlin, Newport; Champlin, Sharper; Champlin, York; Clark, James; Coddington, Jack; Fones, Jack; Gardner, Cuff; Gardner, Hercules; Gardner, Minkl; Gardner, Preamus (Primus); Gardner, Rutter; Gray, Ebenezer; Green, Cuff; Greene, Cato; Greene, Jack; Greene, Pero; Greene, William; Hammond, Prince; Harriss, Cesar; Hazard, Backus; Hazard, Jabin; Hazard, Jacob; Hazard, Peter; Hazard, Peter; Lefavour, Thom; Mason, Warsen; Mawney, Cyrus; Minturn, Jack; Mowrey, Pero; Nichols, Thomas; Perry, Ganset; Phillips, Philow; Pierce, Titus; Potter, David; Randall, Prince; Rhodes, Bristol; Rhodes, Priamus; Rhodes, Richard; Rhodes, Samuel; Richmond, Ebenezer; Robinson, Mingo; Rodman, Isaac; Rodman, Mingo; Rodman, Prince; Rose, Cesar; Saltonstall, Brittain; Saunders, Sampson; Sheldon, Cesar; Slave; Slave; Smith, Juba; Sweeling, Query; Talbot, Sigby; Tanner, Quam; Tillinghast, Cuff; Updike, Cesar; Updike, Moses; Vaughan, Prince; Vernon, Cato; Watson, Fortune; Wells, Cesar; Wickes, Nat; and Willbour, Boston.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCB5D1929EED34FB39D27112C9E7A5E1D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Congressional gold medal</header><subsection id="H39A4386332BE4A7AADFBA7EC1CBF0EAF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Award authorized</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate shall make appropriate arrangements for the award, on behalf of the Congress, of a single gold medal of appropriate design to the First Rhode Island Regiment, collectively in recognition of their dedicated service during the Revolutionary War.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD5CE9BDA10A8430D8748DFC2644EB955"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Design and striking</header><text>For the purposes of the award referred to in subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall strike the gold medal with suitable emblems, devices, and inscriptions, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCD831E1007264CB59854E0CAA7111F4B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rhode Island State Library</header><paragraph id="HB55DB6005BAC45C8B25DDB7B6F4ED374"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Following the award of the gold medal in honor of the First Rhode Island Regiment of the Revolutionary War under subsection (a), the gold medal shall be given to the Rhode Island State Library, where it will be displayed as appropriate and made available for research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H099DAEE371C6499984419276CE478EBA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Rhode Island State Library should make the gold medal received under paragraph (1) available for display elsewhere, particularly at other appropriate locations associated with the First Rhode Island Regiment of the Revolutionary War.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H419E8C94BEF84219B1C33E984DC4F7E7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duplicate medals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Under such regulations as the Secretary may prescribe, the Secretary may strike and sell duplicates in bronze of the gold medal struck under section 3, at a price sufficient to cover the costs of the medals, including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, and overhead expenses.</text></section><section id="H8CCF01E9CA2144F6A18468A940290EF9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Status of medals</header><subsection id="HF983499AD8234906B5D5986A48C627AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National medals</header><text>Medals struck pursuant to this Act are national medals for purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/51">chapter 51</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0ACF5C1C610E4904A7C2181CDD792173"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of section 5134 of title 31, United States Code, all medals struck under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA3F9B5171B654DFEAA6348FC51E883C5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to use fund amounts; proceeds of sale</header><subsection id="H4883105CBD15475395E13BBE3B8D0357"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To use fund amounts</header><text>There is authorized to be charged against the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund such amounts as may be necessary to pay for the costs of the medals struck under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE390F62B0E4421EA0C6BFAA831B495F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Proceeds of sale</header><text>Amounts received from the sale of duplicate bronze medals authorized under section 4 shall be deposited into the United States Mint Public Enterprise Fund.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

