<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9BB0FC04F525426DB882BFE06167914E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9298 IH: To direct the Secretary of Labor to conduct a study on implementing a process through which a State or business may apply for an exemption from enforcement of certain occupational safety and health standards on the basis of economic hardship, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9298</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221115">November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Labor to conduct a study on implementing a process through which a State or business may apply for an exemption from enforcement of certain occupational safety and health standards on the basis of economic hardship, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DB495C0CEE142E08FC7AF019AFB714F" style="OLC"><section id="H6ED50A463C7A4E30A7F0C17B8705D5D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study on certain exemptions from occupational safety and health standards</header><subsection id="H53EFBECA5FA74E61838B0828BF991372"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor shall conduct a study to develop recommendations for implementing a process through which a State or business may apply for an exemption from an occupational safety and health standard in effect under section 6(a) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655(a)</external-xref>) on the basis that such standard causes a significant economic hardship to such State or business, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H2DD2FB15F340427890F9ED1163F4F743"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Legislative actions necessary to implement such process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB79AB8079B8149D2A0C8F5530B39492D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Other actions necessary to implement such process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3A1E4F36A934454B9B7A263004D2361"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Speaker of the House and publish in the Federal Register a report containing the results of the study.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

