<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36B3E321FF0B445FBBD14C68119BC7D4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8860 IH: Tracking and Reporting Absent Community-Members Everywhere Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8860</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220915">September 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to include certain additional information in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2AE86790B4684ED8A16BED5D740B768B" style="OLC"><section id="H3F6390EB410C4F79985D311E16CC197D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tracking and Reporting Absent Community-Members Everywhere Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TRACE Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HEAA527A0CAF94309AA71F9E22BC4A87E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Information to be included in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall include in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System the following data fields:</text><paragraph id="H64302CEA39A4427F8D3F39DEF7E8602D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any initial search, rescue, or recovery mission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72ED2BA69D334350AA3AC0E7D82EEF41"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of any ongoing search effort.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B61373EF3FF4CEFBABF71A0A9EA0F99" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In the case that remains of a person are found, the cause of death determined by a coroner or forensics investigator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9181519066F64ADA828CE0CF3FB0156C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the last known location of the missing person was confirmed or was suspected to have been on Federal land. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FCBBDBC4A5643F18D90C8BC13C7CCB4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For missing persons whose last known location was confirmed or was suspected to have been on Federal land, the following additional data fields: </text><subparagraph id="HBD9DABEE14F04AD49391A65831D278BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The activity in which the person was engaged or suspected to have been engaged at the time of their disappearance, including any known or suspected destination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAF679DF6BD74FB6AFA0E7343D61FBCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of any belongings of the person that were recovered, and the location of recovery of each such time.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64AA03B6EE0E4092B36FB326D946EE6F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the last known location of the missing person is controlled by the Bureau of Land Management, the Forest Service, the National Park Service, or the United States Fish and Wildlife Service. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD6368ED3AA948278735F47083A08BF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any additional information, including any specific location details, about the unit of Federal land that was the last known location of the missing person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8307CBCAD8924411B8EB3EB25709FB77"><enum>3.</enum><header>Inclusion of open and archived cases</header><subsection id="H30C3CC7D11684A46BC5845752273802B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Open cases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretaries, in consultation with Federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies, as appropriate, shall each include in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System the information described in section 2 for each missing person the last known location of whom was confirmed or was suspected to have been on Federal land, and the case of whom is open on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB8337B4538CE43AEA76C69736CF3B845"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Archived cases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the completion of the requirement under subsection (a), the Secretaries, in consultation with Federal, State, or local law enforcement agencies, as appropriate, shall each include in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System the information described in section 2 for each missing person the last known location of whom was confirmed or was suspected to have been on Federal land, and the case of whom was archived. </text></subsection><subsection id="H669E7DF2CE7E42E1B63FB18DC628DC15"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of the Secretaries under this section apply in each case with respect to which the Federal land is under the administrative jurisdiction of the applicable Secretary, regardless of whether another Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency that is not under the applicable Secretary’s jurisdiction is the lead law enforcement agency investigating the case.</text></subsection></section><section id="H50E5C7DB298F455B9B964B41523F7CA3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning in the second calendar year that begins after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, on January 15th, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall submit to the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate a report that contains, for the previous calendar year, the following information:</text><paragraph id="HF60AB66CA77C4ED49AB80F2665BD38A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of open cases in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE23B698EC474C9DA5C4003422CC62BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of cases in the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System that were archived.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5281A9852F4A808BCFD40130C793F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of archived cases entered into the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System under subsection (b). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H964E05995E8E48CEA75D617D477B24E8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of cases for each of paragraphs (1) and (2) where the missing person’s last known location was confirmed or was suspected to have been on Federal land.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H97502FE3513C4D4FB67951265BEBDEBA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph id="H06B0B49E288942C0AF6D32A72BB4E5D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>Federal land</term> means land owned by the United States that is under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior (except land held in trust for the benefit of an Indian Tribe), or the Secretary of Defense only with respect to land and water resources projects administered by the Army Corps of Engineers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D46C319D74D4CE08BA8161032AFD83B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>open case</term> means an active case and a case that is unsolved but not being actively investigated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C946084EC344D23B42B635B7A1734AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretaries</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA84A2A3D64564FC6BFAC8885A9A1565C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture with respect to land and water under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B40CD68A9024CBF999EF4730C94C148"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior with respect to land and water under the administrative jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior (except land held in trust for the benefit of an Indian Tribe); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE52FA31F6B1147CA9F72B365741AE2C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense only with respect to land and water resources projects administered by the Army Corps of Engineers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

