<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H702CB214B6C04C2E825F2A2F83012FC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7349 IH: Validate Prior Learning to Accelerate Employment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7349</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001135">Mrs. Steel</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act to identify or develop assessments to measure the prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences of an individual, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B8BD61CC84E4CF3AAB6100DFE739A98" style="OLC"><section id="H4C2EF459D52448FD9E4DB78A783DE237" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Validate Prior Learning to Accelerate Employment Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0AAA1BD662DE470D98E1ED72B17822C6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Assessments to measure the prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences of an individual</header><subsection id="H9FA28838991D410F9FABFEDDD5414060"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statewide employment and training activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 134(a)(2)(B) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(a)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA8DA01EE216245D19FBEB41029F317AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (v)(VI), by striking the <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H360C4463C3C445BDBDE1A14EB975EBC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (vi), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9DD5B012F6E427490C1DD315B519B11"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H96454B15F6CC4AE2AAED616A8D78ADB9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HCCB85237479B4703B0CDD3BCA848FAB9"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating with industry organizations, employers (including small and mid-sized employers), training providers, local boards, and institutions of higher education to identify or develop assessments that—</text><subclause id="H1F8F1330FBCC4CF4901AC34FF51D74B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are a valid and reliable method of collecting information; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC4C3BCD4BAE4406883CDA70973498ED3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>measure the prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences of an individual for the purpose of—</text><item id="H3DE37410DCE64E049FB8AEAD717327C1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>awarding postsecondary credit toward a recognized postsecondary credential aligned with in-demand industry sectors and occupations in the State;</text></item><item id="HC97F4A9F3D7B468B84B056D67FE22F43" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>awarding a recognized postsecondary credential that is used by employers in the State for recruitment, hiring, retention, or advancement purposes;</text></item><item id="H4FFD087C45B54EC98C2465512A15C378"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>developing individual employment plans that incorporate the prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences of an individual to identify skills related to an in-demand industry sector or occupation and any upskilling needed to secure employment in such sector or occupation; and</text></item><item id="H3DF53E5FF8A249E2862D6B1B7F77BB80" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>helping individuals communicate their prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences to prospective employers through skills-based profiles or portfolios; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H3D89526D04304D65BBB91A7AA027A54F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disseminating to local areas information relating to the assessments identified or developed pursuant to clause (vii), including—</text><subclause id="H428CDD63DD3046A188328EBECE6800D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any recognized postsecondary credential awarded through such an assessment; </text></subclause><subclause id="H21A5E32B356A4760A035940038DE57DA" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the industry organizations, employers, training providers, and institutions of higher education located within the State that recognize the prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences of an individual validated by such assessments; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD4F62484AF9F4851B41AB0E30AEECA69"><enum>(III)</enum><text>how such assessments may be provided to, and accessed by, individuals through the one-stop delivery system. </text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF37A3AB590E94D71B044106E99058352"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allowable Statewide employment and training activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 134(a)(3)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5119B16FC1EE40048FB80A3A9D330637"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (xiii), by striking the <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E27730EE6D7418695C8CC75F7500742"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (xiv), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D7995ED94E24124AF6F1D301702554B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF7680635B1E74D658777C658D187ECE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H48918B16C52D44209631BB055A2DBBA2"><enum>(xv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying and providing to employers information relating to best practices on the use of assessments, including such assessments developed or identified by the State pursuant to paragraph (2)(B)(vii);</text></clause><clause id="H44044316A02B49CD8F85DD702382DA51"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to employers seeking to use such assessments for hiring, promotion, or upskilling of employees; and</text></clause><clause id="HE5DC97610F95406B8141BAD41E3E875A" commented="no"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting employers in the State seeking to implement a practice of hiring individuals based on their prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences as an alternative to relying on postsecondary degree requirements in the hiring process.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E4F4E2A7B904F52930ACB144A0F7342"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized local employment and training activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 134(c)(2)(A)(iii) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(c)(2)(A)(iii)</external-xref> is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H60DEA1A8CC054B3BA18061DCFAEAF45A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H5C506E9A4EB74F088CF3131A9D8AF445"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">initial assessment of skill levels (including literacy, numeracy, and English language proficiency), aptitudes, abilities (including skills gaps), and supportive service needs, and a determination (considering factors including prior work experience, military service, life experience, or education history, and in-demand industry sectors and occupations in the local area) of whether such an individual would benefit from an assessment identified by the State pursuant to subsection (a)(2)(B)(vii) to measure the individual’s prior knowledge, skills, competencies, and experiences to accelerate the individual in obtaining employment that leads to economic self-sufficiency or career advancement; </text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF591753FF72F42D597BA09E0C519A612"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Permissible local employment and training activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 134(d)(1)(A) of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3174">29 U.S.C. 3174(d)(1)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9100935940914E76A8F6375D89BFF172"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (xi), by striking the <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3282286147BD46EDBAA43C563AFF03F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (xii), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H039E2935D97C4F18B6180FFB137D7716"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H55A2308BC2BB48BA99E9199E22EE59BF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HD700339CD9FF4576B50C84A2BE6AC4FD"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessments for individuals upon initial assessment of skills (pursuant to subsection (c)(2)(A)(iii)) or completion of training services or other learning experiences; and</text></clause><clause id="HB07BE93CD85142ABB76C8D625D96D596"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>providing technical assistance or other support to employers seeking to use such assessments for hiring, promotion, or upskilling of employees.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

