<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H19BF052033B641F7B67FFF0FC1D5C83D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>103 HR 2641 RH: Pacific Northwest Pumped Storage Hydropower Development Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 463</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2641</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–644]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210419">April 19, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 to authorize pumped storage hydropower development utilizing multiple Bureau of Reclamation reservoirs.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D41C1A763534806A5C542128C1AB6BD" style="OLC"><section id="H94907C28E43C49F3AE496BE5FC7A0858" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pacific Northwest Pumped Storage Hydropower Development Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H882323C57BA24D49B75AC989B023423F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Authority for pumped storage hydropower development using multiple Bureau of Reclamation reservoirs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9(c) of the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/485h">43 U.S.C. 485h(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1C2BC9E83F4045EC8884A92DA0F6ADD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), in the fourth sentence, by striking <quote>, including small conduit hydropower development</quote> and inserting <quote>and reserve to the Secretary the exclusive authority to develop small conduit hydropower using Bureau of Reclamation facilities and pumped storage hydropower exclusively using Bureau of Reclamation reservoirs</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02095183DBF04FA694764A980C97AC6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>has been filed with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission as of the date of the enactment of the Bureau of Reclamation Small Conduit Hydropower Development and Rural Jobs Act</quote> and inserting <quote>was filed with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission before August 9, 2013, and is still pending</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7E0ED0A963DB4789BA2052D5D483B1DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitations on issuance of certain leases of power privilege</header><subsection commented="no" id="HC0C9B5BD71A441B2AEDEACE9C6ED5E99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H7B774A54A74C440DA386D550D118390B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDEC8DE6F3A7244C4A9D74D66E57F72EF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Hearings and Appeals.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H826D04487E5641A0B796F6A895F385D6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Office of Hearings and Appeals</header><text>The term <term>Office of Hearings and Appeals</term> means the Office of Hearings and Appeals of the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDB474EDDCED749BEBA31AC10A1CC3F25"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Party</header><text>The term <term>party</term>, with respect to a study plan agreement, means each of the following parties to the study plan agreement:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9D1631F2D49848CF9CCF302062B69B66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The proposed lessee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3AB296CFE1342609596EA6AD89CCED9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H724479EB34B34F2B831A296A064700F5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Project</header><text>The term <term>project</term> means a proposed pumped storage facility that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H53E0EBE3C45D4F849A553C917577BF9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would use multiple Bureau of Reclamation reservoirs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H76E46C6A23F74EA19288FA32E6B5D5CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of June 1, 2017, was subject to a preliminary permit issued by the Commission pursuant to section 4(f) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/797">16 U.S.C. 797(f)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H66739FD2BF9A4E6EA26E4F4724BAFFAE"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Proposed lessee</header><text>The term <term>proposed lessee</term> means the proposed lessee of a project.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF224A89214FE4BAAA6C67DAC564ABED1"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC377200E03624AF2839DE1D51E8C0517"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Study plan</header><text>The term <term>study plan</term> means the plan described in subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6B2EC299A7334AB799997DEA1447A1DC"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Study plan agreement</header><text>The term <term>study plan agreement</term> means an agreement entered into under subsection (b)(1) and described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB5CFE581D70A43B2BF2771A534D2AFDE"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Tribes</header><text>The term <term>Tribes</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E30FEC01BDA4086B4D478E7173567E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Confederated Tribes of the Colville Reservation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HABBFD87B522B4E45B482E14D3E78E145"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Spokane Tribe of Indians of the Spokane Reservation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9F4E037637343DE8446BE2E2EDC394B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement for issuance of leases of power privilege</header><text>The Secretary shall not issue a lease of power privilege pursuant to section 9(c)(1) of the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/485h">43 U.S.C. 485h(c)(1)</external-xref>) (as amended by section 2) for a project unless—</text><paragraph id="H5E282E8DA85E49598DEF1691219D1528"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the proposed lessee and the Tribes have entered into a study plan agreement; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H791CA823C68A4C898F985381FCAF027D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary or the Director, as applicable, makes a final determination for—</text><subparagraph id="HB6622DAA80EA4B8EA049DB18E965B5AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a study plan agreement under subsection (c)(2); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4151B5FB244647CCA5E1E513581B2638"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a study plan under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B91CF10B83945498AEFDFCEAD51634F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study plan agreement requirements</header><paragraph id="H49CD8EFF984343A9ADF9BDC25162FDCE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A study plan agreement shall—</text><subparagraph id="H083578D3A499427F8367C5C7E5D813B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish the deadlines for the proposed lessee to formally respond in writing to comments and study requests about the project previously submitted to the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3442DEABA4E3408196E77A718C74B4F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>allow for the parties to submit additional comments and study requests if any aspect of the project, as proposed, differs from an aspect of the project, as described in a preapplication document provided to the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H127A3FA955DA4CA7B4A14486307C8BC8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>except as expressly agreed to by the parties or as provided in paragraph (2) or subsection (d), require that the proposed lessee conduct each study described in—</text><clause id="HAE2601723BDB4523A9EDF500D8074533"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a study request about the project previously submitted to the Commission; or</text></clause><clause id="H276F8643B9D748A5A5519695EAE70784"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any additional study request submitted in accordance with the study plan agreement;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC91F84BFFB24BE0837C18E5F005473E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require that the proposed lessee study any potential adverse economic effects of the project on the Tribes, including effects on—</text><clause id="H3A3E1582BE154399A0CB005D77B9CD23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>annual payments to the Confederated Tribes of the Colville Reservation under section 5(b) of the Confederated Tribes of the Colville Reservation Grand Coulee Dam Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/436">Public Law 103–436</external-xref>; 108 Stat. 4579); and</text></clause><clause id="HDB592F90A0E24639AA8F19D3096066E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>annual payments to the Spokane Tribe of Indians of the Spokane Reservation authorized after the date of enactment of this Act, the amount of which derives from the annual payments described in clause (i);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE555E13261904AB1B8831A40CDB93B23"><enum>(E)</enum><text>establish a protocol for communication and consultation between the parties;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE16464C693684941A061B151DB320C3F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provide mechanisms for resolving disputes between the parties regarding implementation and enforcement of the study plan agreement; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9963234C0D342079331C4ABC5B10D71"><enum>(G)</enum><text>contain other provisions determined to be appropriate by the parties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3BFCA9992314AA2A7A1FACD961E4E74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disputes</header><subparagraph id="H4A39DBCA28F047C092F4E289279A1E5F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the parties cannot agree to the terms of a study plan agreement or implementation of those terms, the parties shall submit to the Director, for final determination on the terms or implementation of the study plan agreement, notice of the dispute, consistent with paragraph (1)(F), to the extent the parties have agreed to a study plan agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D361510F2214522B82314B5608B3CE0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>A dispute covered by subparagraph (A) may include the view of a proposed lessee that an additional study request submitted in accordance with paragraph (1)(B) is not reasonably calculated to assist the Secretary in evaluating the potential impacts of the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB935A6FA844440259F66B3755F41EE33"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Director shall issue a determination regarding a dispute under subparagraph (A) not later than 120 days after the date on which the Director receives notice of the dispute under that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65806FE18E9F4CB699A92FA489C27EEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study plan</header><paragraph id="H1663F1B029424214A511CE26DA8B4A61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The proposed lessee shall submit to the Secretary for approval a study plan that details the proposed methodology for performing each of the studies—</text><subparagraph id="H21E6F9148B6243FEA191430274792670"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identified in the study plan agreement of the proposed lessee; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2DAE19508C8A41B08D55EC2F5DDEFF83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determined by the Director in a final determination regarding a dispute under subsection (c)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE81162D3A44D40589C4F343227A9A65C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial determination</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary receives the study plan under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make an initial determination that—</text><subparagraph id="H81567C0C5D1D445098211492DCE5828C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>approves the study plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F3DC37C9C814C3C9B55B5A68F3FDD45"><enum>(B)</enum><text>rejects the study plan on the grounds that the study plan—</text><clause id="H699920DCBB914665A9713195938648F9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lacks sufficient detail on a proposed methodology for a study identified in the study plan agreement; or</text></clause><clause id="H78DF43186C78459FB5BB8119158AADCD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is inconsistent with the study plan agreement; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CDDC832422042ABA797331A3C496CCF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>imposes additional study plan requirements that the Secretary determines are necessary to adequately define the potential effects of the project on—</text><clause id="H3597AF1788FD4A15ADB22C7B9A0A944D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the exercise of the paramount hunting, fishing, and boating rights of the Tribes reserved pursuant to the Act of June 29, 1940 (54 Stat. 703, chapter 460; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/835d">16 U.S.C. 835d et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H03490C0593F349FC9852841B13AE7E48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the annual payments described in clauses (i) and (ii) of subsection (c)(1)(D);</text></clause><clause id="HFBDCD683B733478187216E52BA0CAACF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Columbia Basin project (as defined in section 1 of the Act of May 27, 1937 (50 Stat. 208, chapter 269; 57 Stat. 14, chapter 14; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/835">16 U.S.C. 835</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="H663C033152D3496BA01439F9225BB296"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>historic properties and cultural or spiritually significant resources; and</text></clause><clause id="HEB4D18B4BA6C489EBB2B842DD0A26916"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the environment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF1DD8008BB48A6B63DA7F956508B52"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Objections</header><subparagraph id="H3EC04D42A3B04EADB6FBB3417EC172D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary makes an initial determination under paragraph (2), the Tribes or the proposed lessee may submit to the Director an objection to the initial determination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H087A8415E52C49FB8294C3721583EA5C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final determination</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date on which the Director receives an objection under subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</text><clause id="H364A72AC3D8A49A4BBE06C843EFA6338"><enum>(i)</enum><text>hold a hearing on the record regarding the objection; and</text></clause><clause id="HBE47CF0E932A498086859D6334F776B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make a final determination that establishes the study plan, including a description of studies the proposed lessee is required to perform.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABD0C39CA82746A8BA6F7022C7702240"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No objections</header><text>If no objections are submitted by the deadline described in paragraph (3)(A), the initial determination of the Secretary under paragraph (2) shall be final.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3ADE256E2D8147FA9635058D3291C242"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conditions of lease</header><paragraph id="H613A9D4A20F54805B5C8326B3FC33451"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consistency with rights of Tribes; protection, mitigation, and enhancement of fish and wildlife</header><subparagraph id="H44E7540CCC13462AB2DBC46A43FCDADB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any lease of power privilege issued by the Secretary for a project under subsection (b) shall contain conditions—</text><clause id="HB6E6D6F9D9764EB19F5CF08C44F81CDB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to ensure that the project is consistent with, and will not interfere with, the exercise of the paramount hunting, fishing, and boating rights of the Tribes reserved pursuant to the Act of June 29, 1940 (54 Stat. 703, chapter 460; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/835d">16 U.S.C. 835d et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="HE537D84C90CF42DE8B621AF86604D2D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to adequately and equitably protect, mitigate damages to, and enhance fish and wildlife, including related spawning grounds and habitat, affected by the development, operation, and management of the project.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF815773CAB784DD5AA49DC85AE16BDE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Recommendations of the Tribes</header><text>The conditions required under subparagraph (A) shall be based on joint recommendations of the Tribes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C6C8645080B4086A2447E767FACC62E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Resolving inconsistencies</header><clause id="H4F578F9DD7E64429846EB9DABC3DB99E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary determines that any recommendation of the Tribes under subparagraph (B) is not reasonably calculated to ensure the project is consistent with subparagraph (A) or is inconsistent with the requirements of the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/485">43 U.S.C. 485 et seq.</external-xref>), the Secretary shall attempt to resolve any such inconsistency with the Tribes, giving due weight to the recommendations and expertise of the Tribes.</text></clause><clause id="HCDCC47D9C9BF43C1ADEC3008B8D804CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Publication of findings</header><text>If, after an attempt to resolve an inconsistency under clause (i), the Secretary does not adopt in whole or in part a recommendation of the Tribes under subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall issue each of the following findings, including a statement of the basis for each of the findings:</text><subclause id="HDAE0F94D99A44286A3CB0431B0CFB115"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A finding that adoption of the recommendation is inconsistent with the requirements of the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/485">43 U.S.C. 485 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="HD933D599898B4AB9B168CCBDE8C93B4E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A finding that the conditions selected by the Secretary to be contained in the lease of power privilege under subparagraph (A) comply with the requirements of clauses (i) and (ii) of that subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H334B6B88B60940BDBD7197DF6C2A1252"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual charges payable by licensee</header><subparagraph id="HE879E48A84E840BBBD5D8765B55B60DF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), any lease of power privilege issued by the Secretary for a project under subsection (b) shall contain conditions that require the lessee of the project to make direct payments to the Tribes through reasonable annual charges in an amount that recompenses the Tribes for any adverse economic effect of the project identified in a study performed pursuant to the study plan agreement for the project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74C19905804949FFA60F6D678A9071AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agreement</header><clause id="H778BA2EB7D654D7E8148FAB78D3C88F4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amount of the annual charges described in subparagraph (A) shall be established through agreement between the proposed lessee and the Tribes.</text></clause><clause id="H4CD2EA3BA09740AE93DFDB53928A9DB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>The agreement under clause (i), including any modification of the agreement, shall be deemed to be a condition to the lease of power privilege issued by the Secretary for a project under subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED443426DB644C368F3D4745A1801821"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Dispute resolution</header><clause id="HC8696A3E67E04BD692807815CFED606F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the proposed lessee and the Tribes cannot agree to the terms of an agreement under subparagraph (B)(i), the proposed lessee and the Tribes shall submit notice of the dispute to the Director.</text></clause><clause id="HAE1116B9BF384B80AEEE74A3CA26FCE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Resolution</header><text>The Director shall resolve the dispute described in clause (i) not later than 180 days after the date on which the Director receives notice of the dispute under that clause.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07BA69BAF069490888893914A9CEB69E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional conditions</header><text>The Secretary may include in any lease of power privilege issued by the Secretary for a project under subsection (b) other conditions determined appropriate by the Secretary, on the condition that the conditions shall be consistent with the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/485">43 U.S.C. 485 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0CBD817F41648C6AB3CBB5C7B32D189"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In establishing conditions under this subsection, the Secretary shall consult with the Tribes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEDAA99E342943DFB250849E9BEC4D06"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>The Secretary or any officer of the Office of Hearing and Appeals before whom a proceeding is pending under this section may extend any deadline or enlarge any timeframe described in this section—</text><paragraph id="HB0AFC1345DD7483D92817AA0858F285B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at the discretion of the Secretary or the officer; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C2AD9FEB7BA4144B3AE4B841C11247B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on a showing of good cause by any party.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6BF8D6C531A4423E9A2C407B0403B340"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Any final action of the Secretary or the Director made pursuant to this section shall be subject to judicial review in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCE8985F5350E41868B33D79F255E2D4A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect on other projects</header><text>Nothing in this section establishes any precedent or is binding on any Bureau of Reclamation lease of power privilege, other than for a project.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc> Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

