<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H3DDC010C84E443779950F27828EC3D48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1082 EH: Sami’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1082</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the unauthorized sale of ride-hailing signage and study the incidence of fatal and non-fatal assaults in TNC and for-hire vehicles in order to enhance safety and save lives.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H8CD39F17FDA246899810D2DB5E118264" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7C5DFF727DCC4782B07B8810EC3954D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sami’s Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H83393E74C0B74907863BE0D871B72045"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H266A6B77BE5248D9BF879E584C958331"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Passenger</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>passenger</quote> means an individual who is matched with a TNC driver through a TNC platform.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H477405E4AE8D4E2ABD93753C1B6C7658"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tnc driver</header><text>The term <quote>TNC driver</quote> means an individual who contracts with a transportation network company and provides transportation services facilitated through a TNC platform in exchange for compensation or payment of a fee from a passenger.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC895B88588BA4BC98EAADB1712545F03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tnc platform</header><text>The term <quote>TNC platform</quote> means an online-enabled application or digital network made available by a transportation network company to connect passengers to TNC drivers for the purpose of a TNC driver providing prearranged transportation services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9CCF4D6B555E4A37BB1600D73B87EEC9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tnc vehicle</header><text>The term <quote>TNC vehicle</quote> means a vehicle (also known as a <quote>ride-hailing vehicle</quote>) that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F8589FB9487495BB23289966CC61AB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>owned, leased, or otherwise authorized for use by a TNC driver; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A1A196BA6524175BB0CEEB34A3DC2A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>used by the TNC driver to provide to passengers prearranged transportation services facilitated through a TNC platform.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52529227B6DE4903A1F5CBAD66F95CBC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transportation network company; TNC</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3BE9793897C54A1EAA19CC6DFAF810A0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The terms <quote>transportation network company</quote> and <quote>TNC</quote> mean a corporation, partnership, sole proprietorship, or other entity that makes available a TNC platform to connect passengers to TNC drivers in exchange for compensation or payment of a fee in order for the TNC driver to transport the passenger using a TNC vehicle.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09CF68E50B464606956AFF6C0E847051"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>transportation network company</quote> and <quote>TNC</quote> does not include—</text> 
<clause id="HE3AA32C1E1E64DFCB59586B64FCD9AB5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a shared-expense carpool or vanpool arrangement that is not intended to generate profit for the driver; or</text></clause> <clause id="H6DD418E8837D40A88993173DAB23B878"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>microtransit or other dedicated services provided exclusively on behalf of a government entity, a nonprofit organization, or a third-party commercial enterprise.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H5EA7C452E96E492DBD1C3C2AD4DDEB1C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on sale of ride-hailing signage</header> 
<subsection id="H0E4DE36EE6FE40F5BF385AA80B332190"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), it shall be unlawful for any person to sell or offer for sale any signage that—</text> <paragraph id="HB6F1881A27D94EB3965274FCBC90130E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is designed to help a passenger to identify a TNC vehicle; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C2A64452B734F02905706CA83AED7CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>either—</text> <subparagraph id="H1D778B97A40E42ED822E8030F9D74115"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contains a proprietary trademark or logo of a transportation network company; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9A0A08913F2E41F49272021D4406F7E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>purports to be signage of a transportation network company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9ED14BC785D845E3B9D04518BB333328"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not apply to any person authorized by a transportation network company to sell or offer for sale signage of the transportation network company described in that subsection.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H808C1114BB3A433380679B4102F7FAFC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<paragraph id="H303D9EA9826E49B6B66884E9D7FABB58"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A violation of this section shall be considered to be a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5748E75F0A3A474CA99E2D895A2EDB1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Action by FTC</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) are incorporated in this Act.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1F25F4DBD7F44869B4D9585E4EA46807"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment</header><text>Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties, and entitled to the privileges and immunities, provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDDC7B7FB152C473C89BFA1DD2B2A38B1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this section limits the authority of the Federal Trade Commission under any other provision of law.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H2078E5FB537F4D07B2CA9C6A7F008E1F"><enum>4.</enum><header>GAO study on incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical and sexual assault of passengers, TNC drivers, and drivers of other for-hire vehicles</header> 
<subsection id="HB50D2E6842F24DA69B113B6607AE54A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GAO Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes the results of a study regarding—</text> <paragraph id="H95C88D55A5A1410581E9F440279C9609"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical assault and sexual assault perpetrated in the preceding 2 calendar years (starting with calendar years 2019 and 2020 for the first study)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC5E2866F68BE4AAFA5FC7CC8A4DA02A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>against TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs) by passengers and riders of for-hire vehicles; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC06B1C97F16445E9834FF4D4B3BD78A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">against passengers and riders by other passengers and TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including the incidences that are committed by individuals who are not TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles but who pose as TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H25CBD31BD5444C52946C72A22CD4D65B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nature and specifics of any background checks conducted on prospective TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including any State and local laws requiring those background checks; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E92257826114D6EAB5AC70C7B808976"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the safety steps taken by transportation network companies and other for-hire vehicle services (including taxicab companies) related to rider and driver safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC08527E353FA44C893702878877063A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sexual assault defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>sexual assault</quote> means the occurrence of an act that constitutes any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H55EF1197967C469891496EC68078F611"><enum>5.</enum><header>Budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20221214" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 14, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


