<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H2A170B62162E4642A7B574F3C8CDCF73" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6450 RH: SCORE for Small Business Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 187</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6450</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–257]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000396">Mr. Kahele</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to reauthorize the SCORE program, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H7FDEDE0B123344C1A0918832AA26014F" style="OLC"><section id="H7DD69330580C4442B79A54EABB7FFC08" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SCORE for Small Business Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE53CBB533FE04A5E869F930F6715373B"><enum>2.</enum><header>SCORE Program provisions and requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H32DCB7771CF44725A73D28D740A44ACA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(1)(B)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB5FB8339D7A04FCFA7088DF7F30F338F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE)</quote> and inserting <quote>the SCORE program described in subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H10BDF0089CE94AC58F132BB04AF6768E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>SCORE may</quote> and inserting <quote>the SCORE Association (as defined in subsection (c)) may</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H258A67C42D164737BAB218E6CD1A390D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDB62446EC96942B7BBDF913583152C1F" style="OLC"><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3351F9C47C3E4830AA402998DE4EE96F"><enum>(c)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">SCORE program</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F3CEF672B7C435EB4699B7B0E328DCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H971C512799E54EF6A8FE0EB166F820F3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>SCORE Association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>SCORE Association</term> means the Service Corps of Retired Executives Association or any successor or other organization that enters into a cooperative agreement (as described under paragraph (2)) with the Administrator to operate the SCORE program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF49D98401F1843A5A7F91AF3FC637021"><enum>(B)</enum><header>SCORE Foundation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>SCORE Foundation</term> means an organization with a mission to support the SCORE Association and volunteers of the SCORE program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7C2385C8F2C4BA1B765A0D7628D3088"><enum>(C)</enum><header>SCORE program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>SCORE program</term> means the SCORE program authorized by subsection (b)(1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F58EC75C7714B909254443798D70F1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Cooperative agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall enter into a cooperative agreement with the SCORE Association to carry out the SCORE program, which shall include the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H41287249C80F4762AC639A247F41AC3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Administrator duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text><clause id="H4B4B88553B114E6E99B9FCBDCC34203A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">every 2 years, conduct a financial examination of the SCORE Association to ensure that any costs paid for with Federal funds are allowable, allocable, and reasonable;</text></clause><clause id="H004443F6FC974B97AA89F2FD1CC3E4A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review and approve contracts entered into by the SCORE Association to provide goods or services for the SCORE program of a value greater than an amount determined by the Administrator;</text></clause><clause id="HD44328626BB742459329796170B464C7" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain a system through which the SCORE Association provides documentation relating to such contracts; and</text></clause><clause id="HAF5D14580FEE42008821E6B84C3AEFBA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">within 30 days of the receipt of a quarterly report on the achievements of the SCORE program submitted by the SCORE Association, reconcile differences between such report and the performance results of the SCORE program reported in a management information system of the Office of Entrepreneurial Development.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBE0723B09167498AA33B74653B62F08D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>SCORE Association duties</header><text>The SCORE Association shall—</text><clause id="HAD74D8C7D9D341DEA8FFF7704E86DDFB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>manage nationwide chapters of the SCORE program;</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2E290AC9C0364E53BE639D46F67D83B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide annual training to employees of the SCORE Association on generating and using program income from the SCORE program;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF113169C0D72424FA70DFCFA7F8BBD6C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>submit documentation to the Administrator verifying such annual training is completed;</text></clause><clause id="H4B7A27D2FF98443A98686A8ABB8BEC8C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separate funds donated to the SCORE Association from program income and funds received pursuant to a cooperative agreement; and</text></clause><clause id="HEE0D066D97F7402287908497A81E078D"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain and enforce requirements for volunteers participating in the SCORE program, including requirements that each such volunteer shall—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA44F07FFDA9846A58CADE98EBADC3B1F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>based on the business experience and knowledge of the volunteer—</text><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA81A3102F96A4F81B4CCFAF99CA90296"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>provide personal counseling, mentoring, and coaching on the process of starting, expanding, managing, buying, and selling a business at no cost to individuals who own, or aspire to own, small business concerns; and</text></item><item commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC47E4E4F0934434BC8F3E34632FA652"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>facilitate free or low-cost education workshops for individuals who own, or aspire to own, small business concerns; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6B53B4B122341DEAE4365B8CE4CC4D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>as appropriate, use tools, resources, and expertise of other organizations to carry out the SCORE program.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A118BDF75A489B801F0FF6AB00E610"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Joint duties</header><text>The Administrator, in consultation with the SCORE Association, shall ensure that the SCORE program and each chapter of the SCORE program—</text><clause id="HF25F8BB768F348F8BEB2FA9BFB666C75"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and implement plans and goals to effectively and efficiently provide services to individuals in rural areas, economically disadvantaged communities, or other traditionally underserved communities, including plans for virtual, remote, and web-based initiatives, chapter expansion, partnerships, and the development of new skills by volunteers participating in the SCORE program; and</text></clause><clause id="H7DAC331FA79340349045A68E5BAA1AA6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reinforce an inclusive culture by recruiting diverse volunteers for the chapters of the SCORE program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF16E279C7DD6453DAD760F45D78CEFC6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Online component</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to providing in-person services, the SCORE Association shall maintain and expand online counseling services including webinars, electronic mentoring platforms, and online toolkits to further support entrepreneurs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F298B2FD31E4E8F89CF56088B2C765E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Accounting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The SCORE Association shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7CBCBE2712484F289E5ED6E01CEC6B7C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintain a centralized accounting and financing system for each chapter of the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCAFF43989434E7D84BB990818C9F35A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain a uniform policy and procedures to manage Federal funds received pursuant to a cooperative agreement described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8591CA26FCC947E99B86D316359137F3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maintain an employee of the SCORE Association to serve as a compliance officer to ensure expenditures of the SCORE program are fully compliant with any law, regulation, or cooperative agreement relating to the SCORE program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC07B9134E05740FA951F8A52DF31B49B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Compensation</header><subparagraph id="H7B06D073F95E4801B0DF82805C3A322A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Salaries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The salary of an employee of the SCORE Association may not exceed the equivalent of the maximum rate of pay allowable for an individual in the career Senior Executive Service employed at the Administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08B2C4D06F6E420793086F758A41E300"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Performance awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The SCORE Association may spend up to 5 percent of the aggregate salaries of employees of the SCORE Association on individual performance awards to employees of the SCORE Association, to be disbursed before the last day of the fiscal year, if not later than 60 days before such disbursement the SCORE Association submits to the Administrator a report on the number and amount of such awards to be disbursed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE44E40DC7B9A4C94A3F6A20D64B22E2E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>SCORE Foundation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Board of Directors of the SCORE Association or an employee of the SCORE Association may not simultaneously serve on the Board of Directors of, or receive compensation from, the SCORE Foundation without written approval from the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20B8995468DC4C4787E9043FCCB82018"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Whistleblower protection requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The SCORE Association shall—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4AA55D6E97D94611B844E653CA0DE012"><enum>(A)</enum><text>annually update all manuals or other documents applicable to employees and volunteers of the SCORE Association or the SCORE program to include requirements relating to reporting procedures and protectors for whistleblowers; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBBACC929FFF421BB229B3B5FE4FFEA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct an annual training for employees and volunteers of the SCORE Association or the SCORE program on the requirements described in paragraph (1) and encourage the use of the hotline established by the Office of the Inspector General of the Small Business Administration to submit whistleblower reports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC115B5B72C3F41F090415CA331C104ED"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Published materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The SCORE Association shall ensure all published materials include written acknowledgment of Small Business Administration support of the SCORE program if such materials are paid for in whole or in part by Federal funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD14B1C066D684A39B123F01567841D58"><enum>(8)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Privacy requirements</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H63C7E32C898D41AAAB605EECB94B5292"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Neither the Administrator nor the SCORE Association may disclose the name, address, or telephone number of any individual or small business concern receiving assistance from the SCORE Association without the consent of such individual or small business concern, unless—</text><clause id="H47ED3F316EB64EB396AB3137F2C67A37"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Administrator is ordered to make such a disclosure by a court in any civil or criminal enforcement action initiated by a Federal or State agency; or</text></clause><clause id="H1A02E7C6C3DF4CA5951F8A3607C34454"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator determines such a disclosure is necessary for the purpose of conducting a financial audit of the SCORE program, in which case disclosure shall be limited to the information necessary for the audit.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9F38C6CE347A4BC58940710734B91474"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administrator use of information</header><text>This paragraph shall not—</text><clause id="H9A59F478779D49EEAC2781CA2E8F22AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restrict the access of the Administrator to SCORE program activity data; or</text></clause><clause id="H90F8483DD658488B86EB23C384D3791A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent the Administrator from using SCORE program client information to conduct client surveys.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBC6C42D89C984F57B088D3E824EEC8FF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Standards</header><clause id="H51393D810F6A4D4F8820012CBB7F38E9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall, after the opportunity for notice and comment, establish standards for—</text><subclause id="H04EA4AD550004CA6B645EC1F95B7F4D1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>disclosures with respect to financial audits described under subparagraph (A)(ii); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H891D2FFAFAEA47FA875EF619020B4A6B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conducting client surveys, including standards for oversight of the surveys and for dissemination and use of client information.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H194A99333C8C46A1B5763DC25A6B8425"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Maximum privacy protection</header><text>The standards issued under this subparagraph shall, to the extent practicable, provide for the maximum amount of privacy protection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C5C816149ED43A4899584195DBDCB60"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report on the performance and effectiveness of the SCORE program, which may be included as part of another report submitted to such Committees by the Administrator, and which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H12185FAD6F6B4FC7AE9ACB2CAD140402"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total number and the number of unique clients counseled or trained under the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC444027FAB0B47A4AAF35A499D73F7F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of hours of counseling provided under the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FB5237254C047F68AE6C876CB9B0878"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of local workshops provided under the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF070639703C84F45B224514CDF992891"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of clients attending online and local workshops provided under the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5E072D53B444E999AB666A530A621DB"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, the demographics of SCORE program clients and volunteers, which shall include the gender, race, and age of each such client or volunteer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61E9CBE8F3F648EBBB92CB14C2AB2D38" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to businesses assisted under the SCORE program, the cost to create a job, the cost to create a business, and return on investment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8641F561AC44FD7A5644C013F71864A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of referrals of SCORE program clients to other resources and programs of the Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7C8FF91DD6F4EDEB0A5FFED34F86BE9"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of SCORE program clients receiving financial assistance, including the type and dollar amount, under loan programs of the Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7712CFAFB0D04170B4133468FB57CF34"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the results of SCORE program client satisfactory surveys, including a summary of any comments received from such clients;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3E80BD2982A443B878254B83174DA5F"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of new businesses started up by SCORE program clients;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD98E385EDE8F4C13AD83002541BBE9FB"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the number of such new businesses realizing revenue growth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC7178CD2264D2E8EE61B95FBA98F89"><enum>(L)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, the number of jobs created with assistance from the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BEE0BEFF58E4C42B2D424F724D68999"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the total cost of the SCORE program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34C60756236343D1A4836CDA4F43151E"><enum>(N)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Administrator to improve the SCORE program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC627CFD3871945A1BC46EB9F33D960B8"><enum>(O)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an explanation of how the SCORE program has been integrated with—</text><clause id="H264B2FC30D3E4299BD47BA567C3AF626" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>small business development centers;</text></clause><clause id="H99FF50952ADC43D9AF6EBACE954AB2D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>women’s business centers (described under section 29);</text></clause><clause id="HAA31D8C1E0F7426DB44ED7DBDEB8A23A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Veteran Business Outreach Centers 20 (described under section 32);</text></clause><clause id="HF5F62E09E3334FB08A2AE64AA54318BF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other offices of the Administration; and</text></clause><clause id="HC3EB5C9854704EEEB3C927235033B2C4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other public and private entities engaging in entrepreneurial and small business development.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H47B2D3DA078E4259A27FA7A9107D62B8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for the SCORE program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 20 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9BBB7B6F7B0F4B408D6B6D9500E92BED" style="OLC"><subsection commented="no" id="HF105A815EB7C4761B03A46854E0A6BE0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>SCORE program</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out the SCORE program authorized by section 8(b)(1) such sums as are necessary for the Administrator to make grants or enter into cooperative agreements in a total amount that does not exceed $13,500,000 in each of fiscal years 2022 and 2023.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H9D1AC3FCF07F45779AB56B6ED6216509"><enum>4.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="HCEF59C96EF804825813770B29E6CFD84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and report on the future role of the SCORE program</header><paragraph id="HD2EA685D0AA74293B4D40703975082B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The SCORE Association shall carry out a study on the future role of the SCORE program and develop a strategic plan for how the SCORE program will meet the needs of small business concerns during the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, with specific objectives for the first, third, and fifth years of such 5-year period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D5AA624A7694A09BC1602A0178E9189"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 6-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the SCORE Association shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report containing—</text><subparagraph id="H4F0198F1DD3A4B138ACDAAAEFBF032AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all findings and determination made in carrying out the study required under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD176066BCD4E38A4429150E76C4986"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the strategic plan developed under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79D897AA38BC483BAA729FBAAE344794"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an explanation of how the SCORE Association plans to achieve the strategic plan, assuming both stagnant and increased funding levels.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F7D7E095E17493E82DA12B2583A1DE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrator report on leased space</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report containing an assessment of the cost of leased space that is donated to the SCORE Association.</text></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H82157961E7A34E6692640BAF541F8F02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Online component report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 months after the last day of the first full fiscal year following the date of the enactment of this Act, the SCORE Association shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report on the effectiveness of the online counseling services required under paragraph (3) of section 8(c) of the Small Business Act, as added by section 2 of this Act, including a description of—</text><paragraph id="H1FB9AD5337794BE88C196153118C8C03"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how the SCORE Association determines electronic mentoring and webinar needs, develops training for electronic mentoring, establishes webinar criteria curricula, and evaluates webinar and electronic mentoring results;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B0165E4AEEF4361B70FCADDBCA5A5DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the internal controls that are used and a summary of the topics covered by the webinars; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E9363D50CA14FF2A2790D2DB3F31269"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performance metrics, including the number of small business concerns counseled by, the number of small business concerns created by, the number of jobs created and retained by, and the funding amounts directed towards such online counseling services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2EA6F04E00F749269FCCB8EAD4FB11E4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><subsection id="H78C76197CFE847309DFAFE320EFEB242"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Small Business Act</header><text>The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3DCA8D2CFFF9463482C2D90F9E22C6B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0C47656FED0843388DBF590313985175"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(12)—</text><clause commented="no" id="H880EE75FB0824B74861365173A7D6AE1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">program</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">SCORE</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H3CE4FD9EC6D84569B97C3C39627492EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C2D78FD294C4FC0BF2DD55D023CAE4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (m)(3)(A)(i)(VIII), by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC8CA99707104D7099AA4CED7FD81831"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 22 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/649">15 U.S.C. 649</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HA80A44ACA1EA40039C32D17EA960FB9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="HD9FD7CF810544F1CA9F9379662903369"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HDDA603C7CFBB40B7B428B1D60505FBAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5EB9BE63AEB64E6F88FB86D55614983B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(12), by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE2D31D243F24B74911F588A49203F51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other laws</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HFF307DBB1FEC48DEA99670267218D89E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Small Business Reauthorization Act of 1997</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 707 of the Small Business Reauthorization Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE) program</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program (as defined in section 8(c)(1) of the Small Business Act)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1334C91A280F41719CC1FDD1454AB77F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Veterans Entrepreneurship and Small Business Development Act of 1999</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 301 of the Veterans Entrepreneurship and Small Business Development Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>Service Core of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HFFD9EA8DF5BE4D0A9D9988AC8B86505D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Military Reservist and Veteran Small Business Reauthorization and Opportunity Act of 2008</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(5) of the Military Reservist and Veteran Small Business Reauthorization and Opportunity Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>the Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>the SCORE program</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7CDB6E13EFB4F43898F7D71F43099A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Children’s Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009</header><text>Section 621 of the Children’s Health Insurance Program Reauthorization Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657p">15 U.S.C. 657p</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H8AE1E8C5B2554A8881A13780687DDB6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H133F33E9C2DA4DAD8A7F048D7993823B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HA5A558EB05C14D0683B9C7E1F3C495EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>SCORE program</term> means the SCORE program authorized by section 8(b)(1)(B) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81B5C14CDCB04DDEBDAC78EDC508BC74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(4)(A)(iv), by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA1C87F9217140F0AB100DD91C809206"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Energy Policy and Conservation Act</header><text>Section 337(d)(2)(A) of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6307">42 U.S.C. 6307(d)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Service Corps of Retired Executives (SCORE)</quote> and inserting <quote>SCORE program</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8464BF8C4D33496BA95E08C4B4A4FFC0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H6DE7ADB0AC694A0A92F234C128889A76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration; Administrator</header><text>The terms <term>Administration</term> and <term>Administrator</term> mean, respectively, the Small Business Administration and the Administrator thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H947E82FD2B484CA0AB4FB0371A0FE9A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>SCORE Association; SCORE Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>SCORE Association</term> and <term>SCORE program</term> have the meaning given those terms, respectively, under section 8(c)(1) of the Small Business Act, as added by section 2 of this Act.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

