<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6AD316CAF6B54741BD23BCCDB66AA26B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6819 IH: Compact of Free Association Host Communities Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6819</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220222">February 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001204">Mr. San Nicolas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000396">Mr. Kahele</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address the growing unreimbursed economic impact costs on communities that receive and host Compact migrants from the Freely Associated States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H21F775B9533E48E7958272A6FE9BF205" style="OLC"><section id="H8657179BCC304C46B2B2085DDDD7A540" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Compact of Free Association Host Communities Support Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H8F5F6D765DA84155AE7414396E0508F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Waiver of matching funds requirement</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A Federal department, agency, independent agency, office, or instrumentality may waive any requirement for local matching funds (including in-kind contributions) otherwise required to be provided by an affected jurisdiction for any Federal grant requiring matching funds.</text></section><section id="H1D268D1D59DB49DBA9E15E9C8880A815" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reconciliation of unreimbursed impact expenses</header><subsection id="HD49D02C0B31A45D18DEAC6312119FE12" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To address previously accrued and unreimbursed impact expenses, at the request of the Governor of an affected jurisdiction, the President may reduce, release, or waive all or part of amounts owed by the Government of an affected jurisdiction (or the government’s autonomous agencies or instrumentalities) to any department, agency, independent agency, office, or instrumentality of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6058742BFB8849F6AD135E6D91325B5C" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><paragraph id="H668B0BBBA09E48B9A4E7DAC7806CA488" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Substantiation of impact costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Governor of each affected jurisdiction shall submit to the Secretary a report, prepared in consultation with an independent accounting firm, substantiating unreimbursed economic impacts to the affected jurisdiction of receiving compact migrants from 2004 through 2021. Upon request of the Secretary, the Governor of the affected jurisdiction shall submit to the Secretary copies of all documents upon which the report submitted by that Governor was based.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B5749FA5DBC4ABBB55BA2B59F6A6E3E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional review and comment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reduction, release, or waiver under this Act shall not take effect until 60 days after the President notifies Congress of the President’s intent to approve a request of the Governor of each affected jurisdiction. In exercising his authority under this section and in determining whether to give final approval to a request, the President shall take into consideration comments the President may receive after Congressional review.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5E06186F5B64EDA984C1D46AD607C21"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual limit</header><text>The President may reduce, release, or waive, under subsection (a), amounts totaling, in the aggregate, not more than $100,000,000 annually.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD0C95E8419534987830B7CA358452310" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This authority of the Secretary under sections 2 and 3 shall terminate on that date that the Secretary certifies that all the unreimbursed economic impact costs to affected jurisdictions have been reconciled and repaid to those affected jurisdictions.</text></section><section id="H3D079B249F3F4234AE53796961F1FD9E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="HB68EBADE3FF14A8C98E2FB37C36895BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Affected jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>affected jurisdiction</term> means any State, territory, or possession of the United States that receives and hosts a Compact migrant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5B46ADBAF794FC7A3202D8605FDBE60"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compact migrant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>compact migrant</term> means a person, or their children under the age of 18, admitted or resident pursuant to section 141 of the U.S.–RMI or U.S.–FSM Compact, or section 141 of the Palau Compact who, as of a date referenced in the most recently published enumeration is a resident of an affected jurisdiction. As used in this subsection, the term <quote>resident</quote> shall be a person who has a ‘residence,’ as that term is defined in section 101(a)(33) of the Immigration and Nationality Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39EE7042E4964EC6AFD4B952A808DF75"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

