<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H82BC6F99021C4F0A8E8DA49A83835F3B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8194 IH: Civil Justice for Victims of International Fentanyl Trafficking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8194</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to strip foreign sovereign immunity of certain foreign states to secure justice for victims of fentanyl overdoses in the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5A2E8AEB99CF4FCA8645740B70A166E7" style="OLC"><section id="HEEDD956323FA4C02BAC89CCECEE02625" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Civil Justice for Victims of International Fentanyl Trafficking Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H5D7DD607E07B43AA8E4F9DE8BA744915" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responsibility of foreign states</header><subsection id="HC11EDEBC25CD453CABF8298BFF8EB26F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsibility</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/97">Chapter 97</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1605B">section 1605B</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA24D95E15F584362BB9170888E49D9C0"><section id="H0C7B11D544D249CAB1CCA922C3960B35"><enum>1605C.</enum><header>Responsibility of foreign states for death or injury from international fentanyl trafficking in the United States. </header><subsection id="HDD5D48AC64644E268ADC4D6002FF75C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsibility of foreign states</header><text>A foreign state shall not be immune from the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States in any case in which money damages are sought against a foreign state for death or physical injury to a person caused by fentanyl use or exposure that occurs in the United States following any reckless action of a covered person, that caused or substantially contributed to the unlawful trafficking of fentanyl from the foreign state into and within the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H938894523282432692CE4A5D37AFB0E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered person defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered person</quote> means— </text><paragraph id="H6E904E7A8B074437ADB217299CA9E427"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an alien who is unlawfully present in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H882D9F94C8E849F6B6F67976CD5FF561"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a foreign opioid trafficker, as identified in the report submitted under section 7211(a) of the Fentanyl Sanctions Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF8E0C80093847EDBF1A87CE075C0739"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a significant foreign narcotics trafficker, as identified in the report submitted under subsection (b) or (h)(1) of section 804 of the Foreign Narcotics Kingpin Designation Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2ADE803B722B4A0689FFA75904C2B698"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>A foreign state shall not be subject to the jurisdiction of the courts of the United States under subsection (a) on the basis of an omission or act that constitutes mere negligence.</text></subsection><subsection id="H84498FA0F7FB43FB80EAA41A7A7593B8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusive jurisdiction</header><text>The courts of the United States shall have exclusive jurisdiction in any action in which a foreign state is subject to the jurisdiction of a court of the United States under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD991323A7BE84B49A6E5BB1E1879A40F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Intervention</header><text>The Attorney General may intervene in any action in which a foreign state is subject to the jurisdiction of a court of the United States under subsection (a) for the purpose of seeking a stay of the civil action, in whole or in part.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4D88765FBFCA4B87B79184B75A3FBE15"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Stay</header><paragraph id="H5C1153AC63284B41868B0966824717F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A court of the United States may stay a proceeding against a foreign state if the Secretary of State certifies that the United States is engaged in good faith discussions with the foreign state defendant concerning the resolution of the claims against the foreign state, or any other parties as to whom a stay of claims is sought. In exercising its discretion under this subsection, the court shall balance the interests of the United States with the interests of the plaintiffs in a timely review of their claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB99E5D3779E7432CAF4911C0E5B1A794"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><subparagraph id="H5DE2C627601E46068C6322CC15E4E52D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A stay under this section may be granted for not more than 180 days.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D25A4CD5D15419CBD452D57BD44DA27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header><clause id="H482BFF37AACF4817930C3B19247624EE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may petition the court for an extension of the stay for additional periods not to exceed 180 days.</text></clause><clause id="HA37A1C80969B4016B705E4BE1A4AB0DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Recertification</header><text>A court may grant an extension under subparagraph (A) if the Secretary of State recertifies that the United States remains engaged in good faith discussions with the foreign state defendant concerning the resolution of the claims against the foreign state, or any other parties as to whom a stay of claims is sought. In choosing whether to grant an extension, the court shall balance the interests of the United States with the interests of the plaintiffs in a timely review of their claims.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA31CB159E0E448F8445028DC37C8760"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enforcement by state attorneys general</header><text>Any State, on its own behalf or on behalf of the citizens or residents of the State, may bring a civil action in a district court of the United States under the circumstances described in subsection (a). Nothing in this Act may be construed to prevent a State from exercising its powers under State law.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3997667603784C7DA6336019BEAB0D34"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 1605C of title 28, United States Code, as added by such subsection (a), shall apply to any conduct occurring before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA879BF013246441F8A0EADB08274D20C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/97">chapter 97</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/1605B">section 1605B</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H20B5C8FFE7704DB1A92BD77B176B9547"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H0C7B11D544D249CAB1CCA922C3960B35">1605C. Responsibility of foreign states for death or injury from international fentanyl trafficking in the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

