<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HA2C39239C8AF4E4B808C5E0E06A68669" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7153 EH: Department of Veterans Affairs Principles of Benefits Automation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7153</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to submit to Congress a plan to modernize the information technology systems of the Veterans Benefits Administration, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE64925E5022C4B29A7BCF4FCB56929D9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC488ACFD903C49FD9A06F711F784D39E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Veterans Affairs Principles of Benefits Automation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5925AAEEA9754E5E8FC408B1281660B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should increase automation in the processing of claims for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary in accordance with the following principles:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9360BC398BF24CAD95B56478ACC722C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The purpose of automation should be to increase the speed and accuracy of claims processing decisions. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C695A2572264A459F5CCEF064BE7348"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Automation should be conducted in a manner that enhances the productivity of employees of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H19028688BCA2477F97BAB05185964864"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Automation should be carried out in a manner that achieves greater consistency in the processing and rating of claims by relying on patterns of similar evidence in claim files.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92475B442FEC4CFF9CA2A20A28C70AEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To the greatest extent possible, automation should be carried out by drawing from information in the possession of the Department, other Government agencies, and claimants for benefits.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC578B8E798694134A92D6E1DBCFC6EE5"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automation of any claims process or determination should not be end-to-end.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EACFAE7C8A6483E8369BA57BC40D6DD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Employees of the Department should continue to make decisions with respect to the approval of claims and the granting of benefits.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75B9277BE6CD427EBA00C04606A8180E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Automation should not be carried out in a manner that reduces or infringes upon—</text> <subparagraph id="H09CC3D04218E494D8E83E23EAA3CD6BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the due process rights of claimants for benefits under the laws administered by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD297FB6945A548289E135A3406B641F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the duties of the Secretary to assist and notify claimants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38DFA4E371AD44979CEA39965E288ED9"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automation should be carried out while taking all necessary measures to protect the privacy of claimants and their personally identifiable information.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD3DD7942018C4DC4944556D9BED5E4E1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Automation of claims processing should not eliminate or reduce the Veterans Benefits Administration workforce.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF1EBA84C31764B3A8D709F5AF9990F36"><enum>3.</enum><header>Plan for modernization of Veterans Benefits Administration information technology systems</header> <subsection id="H6D6F83AC934B47798AF171B107A821DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit to appropriate congressional committees a plan for the modernization of the information technology systems of the Veterans Benefits Administration. The plan shall cover the first fiscal year that begins after the date of the enactment of this Act and the subsequent four fiscal years and shall include each of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H127A41747FF94ADF9EFE1EA0131EFEC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An identification of any information system to be modernized or retired, if applicable, during the period covered by the plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F206683137E4802860262B3FB3E6C5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the Secretary intends to incorporate the principles referred to in section 2 into the modernization of such information systems.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A6ED2C5EB85439CB2BE6648181F6CAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of targets, for each fiscal year, by which the Secretary intends to complete the modernization of each information system or major component or functionality of such system identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3AC67FBBBD1143FA96EC8044B9BED50F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Cost estimates for the modernization of each information system identified under paragraph (1) for each fiscal year covered by the plan and in total.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7370D6A3C0BC4E0EB93B545584C903C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <paragraph id="H84EAF5661B764F3286A351D409619C71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Subcommittee on Military Construction, Veterans’ Affairs, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBABE3F67D32E48AFAC9CB44FA209460B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs and the Subcommittee on Military Construction, Veterans’ Affairs, and Related Agencies of the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220517" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 17, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

