<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H37D6874E0E51493DB8B03513BDCE639B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6786 IH: Increasing Consumers’ Education on Law Enforcement Resources Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6786</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal Trade Commission to conduct an education campaign to inform the public about the resources available when their safety and security has been violated online, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF9B183FE897D49A6B4E8B8AD906C3AAE" style="OLC"><section id="H3B2591576B0C4445A8AD16BD0DED7FD1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing Consumers’ Education on Law Enforcement Resources Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDF71EAB1B606477A855E095CCB68F5E7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consumer education on law enforcement resources</header><subsection id="HAA7CE8B427EE4FB493B619D3258D9037"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Education Campaign</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission, the Attorney General, and the head of any other appropriate Federal agency, shall develop an educational program and related resources to inform the public about the resources the public has when their safety and security has been violated online.</text></subsection><subsection id="H52D4987BF53A4293A5677B41E6EB7D92"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing and implementing the consumer education program and related resources under subsection (a), the Commission and Attorney General shall consult with State attorneys general, State and local law enforcement entities, technologists, technology industry representatives, academic researchers, and consumer advocacy groups.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC6EB93CD717B46289DCD2EF1FCF21142"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Commission and Attorney General shall ensure that such program and related resources are available to and readily accessible by the public on the website of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE29EC256A9314F169D04A8C564A60849"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Education campaign</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the Commission and Attorney General have developed the educational program and related resources required by subsection (a), the Commission and Attorney General shall carry out an annual education campaign to inform the public about the resources the public has when their safety and security has been violated online.</text></subsection><subsection id="HADB48AE1A10A4C969024CFCC6E2920AA" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission and Attorney General may use, or authorize for use, funds available to carry out this section to pay for the development, production, and use of broadcast and print media advertising and internet-based outreach in carrying out campaigns under this section. In allocating such funds, consideration shall be given to advertising directed at non-English speaking populations, including those who listen to, read, or watch nontraditional media.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

