<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H45F32B91499B492AA4933375769380BA"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8385 IH: To require the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness to conduct a study on the benefits of licensure reform for the hiring of military spouses.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8385</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220714">July 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness to conduct a study on the benefits of licensure reform for the hiring of military spouses.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H12271DB2FB114D82B9A98A0F0D544003"><section id="HD12F407C775845148A40E3C0EF66B924" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study on portability of licensure for military spouse hiring</header><subsection id="HF54F095496ED4E5D848924AA268C2A0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness to conduct a study on the benefits of licensure reform for the hiring of military spouses.</text><paragraph id="H218A501C51CB42308DAF0E2F80232B62"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Such discussion shall include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="H48015D53CBBB47EFB9D56CDC19737391"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The value of, and opportunities to, private entities that hire military spouses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF970E9193D7D4B77A8DF9AE254AD0FA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Career opportunities for military spouses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39AE93FD79564A4C9E9F79128D9A836E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Understanding the challenges that military spouses encounter in the labor market.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3088210A0F9447AB8D914C284ED1791F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Gaps and opportunities in the labor market for military spouses.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AFEFEA67C8141B483E1C1540C9879EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The benefits of portable licenses and interstate licensure compacts for military spouses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0543A7F60D994461A97958464820C1C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To develop recommendations to facilitate better data collection on the benefits of occupational licensure reform for military spouses.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E706C2F42964934B292961823D416A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial Briefing</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness Comptroller shall brief Congress on the initial results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCD5707E17295407F9159A5ACF931F196"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final Report</header><text>Not later than 240 days after the date on which the briefing required by subsection (b) is conducted, the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel Readiness shall submit to Congress a final report setting. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

