<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D5A42A37BFB4768BF9DCCF772FA6BE3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7468 IH: Security of the Economy, Climate, and other U.S. interests with Recent and Existing Food alternatives Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7468</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of National Intelligence to submit to Congress a report on the effects of increased production and consumption of alternative proteins on the long-term national security interests of the United States.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCBDB2A3A4A8647CA8B3CF269AE5A37CD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1B03AB668FF44C6E9AEB99F670B7AADF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Security of the Economy, Climate, and other U.S. interests with Recent and Existing Food alternatives Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SECURE Food Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H4B44A101174A4F76BCBB0AEB9626EAFC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on the effects of increased production and consumption of alternative proteins to national security</header> <subsection id="H9DA5584035FA4858BB31E551AA1DD168"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in consultation with the heads of other departments and agencies of the Federal Government that the Director determines appropriate, shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on the effects of increased production and consumption of alternative proteins on the long-term national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEFB02569C4914B398738BA102EB5B110"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HEF55161278B74613BDCB643D3DFD9E82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of how the increased production and consumption of alternative proteins affect—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8DC15BE7538B45859CA908522DFDE3BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>biosecurity, food security, climate security, and water security;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB21C322B383B43B38BD4F0F7160B31A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the environment, including with respect to reduced land use and reduced deforestation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF92585C7230B4953AEB35AF49540846A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public health, including with respect to pandemic risk reduction, air and water pollution reduction, and antibiotic usage reduction; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C5530B96E0241D984749313FC5411EB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the economy, including with respect to job creation and new markets for agricultural products of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F6896555AC5402490B52655962B5241"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A detailed explanation of whether, and to what extent, progress in the production and consumption of alternative proteins made by foreign countries constitutes a competitive threat to the economic interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4A223AEFD731459487DD0F2DE5FB783B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29997C49DFA7466DBFC0E57DB8A86C57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H237831003F7747DA9191A295FBF55820"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alternative proteins</header><text>The term <term>alternative proteins</term> means food proteins produced from plants, fungi, or animal cell cultivation that share sensory characteristics with conventional animal proteins.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC04FF58534A4D0E8B68898E1DAAD860"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional intelligence committees</header><text>The term <term>congressional intelligence committees</term> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

