<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1CCB3D8C17A94AE2838E6326FD0B231B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8258 IH: Federal Interior Land Media Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8258</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide exceptions from permitting and fee requirements for content creation, regardless of distribution platform, including still photography, digital or analog video, and digital or analog audio recording activities, conducted on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H240998FED1E64147B411927DB34074E6" style="OLC">
<section id="H55A5BD729E054410A7880D9EF4705C0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Interior Land Media Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FILM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9741FCCD3F264687BA9DB3A46F71D479"><enum>2.</enum><header>Filming and still photography within the National Park System and on other Federal land</header> <subsection id="HF4EBA9C84A934C8AB5A731DEB3BD2CE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filming in national park system units</header> <paragraph id="H80F86B2526794557B95DD8257F3C4DA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1009">Chapter 1009</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking section 100905 and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05B8AEF99D9F4960837CFCF395042A66">
<section id="H6D2545B5AB2A46889E71CAF12CF124E7"><enum>100905.</enum><header>Filming and still photography in System units</header>
<subsection id="HE6980CE093D742838E47687A148A7AAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filming and still photography</header>
<paragraph id="HB77F3C8275B54A49A4DAC576929201D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that a filming or still photography activity or similar project in a System unit (referred to in this section as a <quote>filming or still photography activity</quote>) and the authorizing or permitting of a filming or still photography activity are carried out consistent with—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D7B7A513A75477CA163645241394199"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the laws and policies applicable to the Service; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52BA4D362E504B2489D87653253849CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an applicable general management plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF05CF07DC3D42D796E8FC8A3D7B0788"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No permits required</header><text>The Secretary shall not require an authorization or a permit or assess a fee, if a fee for a filming or still photography activity is not otherwise required by law, for a filming or still photography activity that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD283057340E842A0BAAA769166E5596F"><enum>(A)</enum>
<clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HEC8B6E72E7044FA38D268414D9E27A3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves fewer than 6 individuals; and</text></clause> <clause indent="up1" id="H45BF42C5576145588E82A95892376062"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets each of the requirements described in paragraph (5); or </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0392B789E4D6476FAF19B8F7A4B0B568"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is merely incidental to, or documenting, an activity or event that is allowed or authorized at the System unit, regardless of—</text> <clause id="H1E6A76BC42B14D2B8DA34BDB249BF739"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of individuals participating in the allowed or authorized activity or event; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H05F31BB2879B41769DCA9592F5BAD6EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether any individual receives compensation for any products of the filming or still photography activity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8A7AFE8240624CFF8FE9514A1DAE000A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Filming and still photography authorizations for de minimis use</header> <subparagraph id="H4572BA7EB8864BB7B2555BCA164C6CBB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a de minimis use authorization for certain filming or still photography activities that meets the requirements described in subparagraph (F).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6869B01002264D898DE23D25CE278A74"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>For a filming or still photography activity that meets the requirements described in subparagraph (F), the Secretary—</text> <clause id="HF187E94F94FC428DB22C042B3D22AE6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may require a de minimis use authorization; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HEDB90A31DEE34EBE8C2461BC609CF05F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not require a permit.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0709EA42A6B847CABC98F86DA8EE56D9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No fee</header><text>The Secretary shall not charge a fee for a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC48511B5407C4EC6AF3B028447BA1452"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary shall enable members of the public to apply for and obtain a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph—</text> <clause id="H8E875085E1AD44439AEEE67CDE1CE7D2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>through the website of the Service; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HAD768402FE994C7B96F2F38AA4C1C4DD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in person at the field office of the applicable System unit.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB895E3E0935348A99048D4CD0E52F4A9"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Issuances</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text>
<clause id="H1CD6EEC13405421DBD0FD5D90F0B8C32"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish a procedure—</text> <subclause id="H8CD3A235C0954666ABCE575B70046666"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to automate the approval of an application submitted through the website of the Service under subparagraph (D)(i); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H239E004CCA2343B79B4D27822CAD9BC7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to issue a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph immediately on receipt of an application that is submitted in person at the field office of the applicable System unit under subparagraph (D)(ii); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H452B52F3A08946439E742CFE2CCFC30F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if an application submitted under subparagraph (D) meets the requirements of this paragraph, immediately on receipt of the application issue a de minimis use authorization for the filming or still photography activity.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFA24AA1A28FB4BF4835EF6707A291B21"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall only issue a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph if the filming or still photography activity—</text> <clause id="H3941E037B95049BA9EAB226E52D541F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves a group of not fewer than 6 individuals and not more than 8 individuals;</text></clause>
<clause id="H9CCB5DB3063E41B49627640BBA0F8733"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets each of the requirements described in paragraph (5); and</text></clause> <clause id="HEDDCB274EC54498E8EC1DDF31D4E26BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is consistent with subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE9482F1779D84FA6BF736063719D844B"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A de minimis use authorization issued under this paragraph shall list the requirements described in subparagraph (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9ACE44CD3AF447A7BCB7FEFB36992BC3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Required permits</header> <subparagraph id="HA5EAC807AE6C42DF9B07D9F44CFDC7FA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary may require a permit application and, if a permit is issued, assess a reasonable fee, as described in subsection (b)(1), for a filming or still photography activity that—</text>
<clause id="H9D3648E6F4B64355A1EB2E58005BD85E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves more than 8 individuals; or</text></clause> <clause id="H40823A313CFF4723AE2DA703D7607C90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not meet each of the requirements described in paragraph (5).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCEB68859896C4AD38F9942B57CE6510F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Wildernesss Act clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision of this subsection is intended to or shall be construed to conflict with the provisions of the Wilderness Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBBAEAE35D3A04050931EEBEDB34C2EC8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements for filming or still photography activity</header><text>The requirements referred to in paragraphs (2)(A)(ii), (3)(F)(ii), (4)(B), and (7)(C) are as follows:</text>
<subparagraph id="HFC73F857C29348E4B1A3EC44CA46EF4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A person conducts the filming or still photography activity in a manner that—</text> <clause id="H9A25E21D05D7488D836FFDDA6A7A1E72"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not impede or intrude on the experience of other visitors to the applicable System unit;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0C006B1FAFEA48FF82EC3254F81C7A25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except as otherwise authorized, does not disturb or negatively impact—</text> <subclause id="H809BBC236F0C4A66ACBC15A84C3C268A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a natural or cultural resource; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HAAF51CF08A9A4E51ACD9B3D4F08B2E9A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an environmental or scenic value; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H37490BD451C64AAFA35835317C11888B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allows for equitable allocation or use of facilities of the applicable System unit.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCDD1451C97544E4892FFC9A64E6ED210"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The person conducts the filming or still photography activity at a location in which the public is allowed.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H710E273365B14A5693F36A0EE5FC318F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity does not require the exclusive use of a site or area.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H680D17A82DF8421D93D8A35FF95DAE7D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The person does not conduct the filming or still photography activity in a localized area that receives a very high volume of visitation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A2F193721984E29825B5CC5DB00D0FA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity does not use a set or staging equipment, subject to the limitation that handheld equipment (such as a tripod, monopod, and handheld lighting equipment) shall not be considered staging equipment for the purposes of this subparagraph. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H954435BC4FB04A37AA7F1A86A30B5F42"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity complies with and adheres to visitor use policies, practices, and regulations applicable to the applicable System unit.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C8A736E690143C9B22492861101BDC0"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The filming or still photography activity is not likely to result in additional administrative costs being incurred by the Secretary with respect to the filming or still photography activity, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8DC72F18BA8541209E6D7A4202F6C4C4"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity complies with other applicable Federal, State, and local laws (including regulations), including laws relating to the use of unmanned aerial equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0CA2F21532F49189209BF8E87003F45"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Content creation</header><text>Regardless of distribution platform, any video, still photograph, or audio recording for commercial or noncommercial content creation in a System unit shall be considered to be a filming or still photography activity under this subsection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H562170FF93AE4ECA90BFE65501AA6A89"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effect</header>
<subparagraph id="H26695262840548DFA889EAFAA91A8503"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Permits requested though not required</header><text>On the request of a person intending to carry out a filming or still photography activity, the Secretary may issue a permit for the filming or still photography activity, even if a permit for the filming or still photography activity is not required under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5ABB9A0580D341D482AFC454B3A7536B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No additional permits, commercial use authorizations, or fees for filming and still photography at authorized events</header><text>A filming or still photography activity at an activity or event that is allowed or authorized, including a wedding, engagement party, family reunion, or celebration of a graduate, shall be considered merely incidental for the purposes of paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H218C80B23DAC467DBAE4AD415FCDC68E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Monetary compensation</header><text>The receipt of monetary compensation by the person conducting the filming or still photography activity shall not affect the permissibility of the filming or still photography activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6B92C7AA11AE47A1A1BFBD54F10B6224"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fees and recovery costs</header> <paragraph id="H2C629DD21BF245B8804C74E3204D9878"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The reasonable fees referred to in subsection (a)(4) shall meet each of the following criteria:</text>
<subparagraph id="HD22E25D66A6B44B586C8E94B18134DF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The reasonable fee shall provide a fair return to the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2AB452B0E0543D1AAD23CC0AF049830"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The reasonable fee shall be based on the following criteria:</text>
<clause id="H348EFBFFC3114A29A87D07205D45C86A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of days of the filming or still photography activity.</text></clause> <clause id="H171D1A2583F8499B9C100C3EFD78180E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The size of the film or still photography crew present in the System unit.</text></clause>
<clause id="H64FB45702F514393BF1A4F050A7480AE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The quantity and type of film or still photography equipment present in the System unit.</text></clause> <clause id="HF80E69B00BF3475A9085DD404CE88707"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other factors that the Secretary determines to be necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF2C3A2C351314AB8874E885B8D93D996"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recovery of costs</header>
<subparagraph id="H442C8B8C026B4421AD0391DA1797453D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall collect from the applicant for the applicable permit any costs incurred by the Secretary related to a filming or still photography activity subject to a permit under subsection (a)(4), including—</text> <clause id="H75EDDEB9D1494704918EDDDCFECA3E98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the costs of the review or issuance of the permit; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA5F96CA4C3734DFC8EEC4FC354DC3342"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>related administrative and personnel costs.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C2135F9892F42BA918FFFB296652155"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect on fees collected</header><text>All costs recovered under subparagraph (A) shall be in addition to the fee described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9BA9BA3DB6C749AC9EE3C856C37FA552"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of proceeds</header>
<subparagraph id="H01CAFC0BB7B84366AEAE518AF2A132F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>All fees collected under this section shall—</text> <clause id="HD34EE6372D144375B39BC46CB9B392E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be available for expenditure by the Secretary, without further appropriation; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H1A81837A578A40638055A49217F74E68"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remain available until expended.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD204CE150D4842B2B5483933FD94FF4B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>All costs recovered under paragraph (2)(A) shall—</text>
<clause id="H41E141B1A9F74FAA996D5F2CA4884BCC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be available for expenditure by the Secretary, without further appropriation, at the System unit at which the costs are collected; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2A5141BC3526419B9691BE953D149466"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remain available until expended.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H83F3995845E44074B39A022E69068E33"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protection of resources</header><text>The Secretary shall not allow a person to undertake a filming or still photography activity if the Secretary determines that—</text> <paragraph id="H684C14ED8F5B468584BAFCEFACE80EDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there is a likelihood that the person would cause resource damage at the System unit, except as otherwise authorized;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF04A9D792F8A4FD6874895303B55BAEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the person would create an unreasonable disruption of the use and enjoyment by the public of the System unit; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08128AF3B853481C92C02932AD449788"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the filming or still photography activity poses a health or safety risk to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDA896FC15831421A8A64868B337CBB5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Processing of permit applications</header>
<paragraph id="H5A624F124B334F7385DCFF934E4984EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process to ensure that the Secretary responds in a timely manner to an application for a permit for a filming or still photography activity required under subsection (a)(4).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83B96BB54A0B4A80B04BE78ED3AA6140"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>If a permit is required under this section for 2 or more Federal agencies or System units, the Secretary and the head of any other applicable Federal agency, as applicable, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate permit processing procedures, including through the use of identifying a lead agency or lead System unit—</text>
<subparagraph id="H6CA817B634794BC7B34A35D55841D446"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to review the application for the permit;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80BE76E9A4304370ACA55445D865C499"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to issue the permit; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6D4CF1B3AD964BDB919BD1CA1AFB6822"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to collect any required fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7CC36C13214404D8A446AE056F71CCC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/1009">chapter 1009</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 100905 and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5734C3810A344FF975255B2F7CEC048">
<toc>
<toc-entry level="section" bold="off">100905. Filming and still photography in System units.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF1AB1E32D3C74201BD9235B723895972"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Filming on other federal land</header><text>Public Law 106–206 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/460l-6d">16 U.S.C. 460l–6d</external-xref>) is amended by striking section 1 and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H480EEBB0E7F24B14B740D5CF48DB7B7D"> <section id="H4D0CABDA37EE4E838FAAF41640387DA4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Filming and still photography</header> <subsection id="HCE0BB4CFB18B418A84BDD8C7AD57AB6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Filming and still photography</header> <paragraph id="H16B0872E050D4608848A4BD83FBD6DED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall ensure that a filming or still photography activity or similar project at a Federal land management unit (referred to in this section as a <quote>filming or still photography activity</quote>) and the authorizing or permitting of a filming or still photography activity are carried out consistent with—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC0345B3E40234635A5A6679A32B4CC54"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the laws and policies applicable to the Secretary concerned; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE334EF9B7C9A4FF2A7380E9E11B6B2C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an applicable general management plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5F33942B39E04CA0996F3DC58654C879"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No permits required</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not require an authorization or a permit or assess a fee, if a fee for a filming or still photography activity is not otherwise required by law, for a filming or still photography activity that—</text> <subparagraph id="H0CB9BE14309E4F078928D8B71F2BCA3D"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H244AFC5C3A0B4CC68C2C948FBC300367"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves fewer than 6 individuals; and</text></clause>
<clause indent="up1" id="HB70D14922FFF460BAEDF0C4F9B912662"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets each of the requirements described in paragraph (5); or </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97CA747B1500438183FDA5F4E7BED455"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is merely incidental to, or documenting, an activity or event that is allowed or authorized at the Federal land management unit, regardless of—</text>
<clause id="H99DED5FFFB2143A7BD4ACD5028015570"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of individuals participating in the allowed or authorized activity or event; or</text></clause> <clause id="HAB7D2B70948C4FC3BB7A056FBCE04AF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether any individual receives compensation for any products of the filming or still photography activity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBAAF151907D1440594983F5F94790551"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Filming and still photography authorizations for de minimis use</header>
<subparagraph id="H96DD5225FA824671B653A5DA5F2CDDC8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall establish a de minimis use authorization for certain filming or still photography activities that meets the requirements described in subparagraph (F).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39FD8DB9B5F4494287D783F0EBFB6F6F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>For a filming or still photography activity that meets the requirements described in subparagraph (F), the Secretary concerned—</text>
<clause id="HF68C865C7F8B4706B2502CAA886CF6E9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may require a de minimis use authorization; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9DE66B04EAAB41AC85562D8C6C4FADFB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not require a permit.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6CEC282C298C444CBF173DCBBD809F1E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No fee</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not charge a fee for a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEF26B7755085429D93D6CB405A108DE1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall enable members of the public to apply for and obtain a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph—</text>
<clause id="HEACFB9318F70468AAF467BD3CC32964F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>through the website of the Department of the Interior or the Forest Service, as applicable; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7C87CFCFE1AA4C69801FCA52388A055C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in person at the field office for the Federal land management unit.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0391C12E8ED24E44B763905EF7320F64"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Issuances</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall—</text> <clause id="H4A9EBA452F6546D39038F4344684A26F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish a procedure—</text>
<subclause id="H0701E608FE504A5DB95E52A3D209C1E6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to automate the approval of an application submitted through the website of the Department of the Interior or the Forest Service, as applicable, under subparagraph (D)(i); and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF586BCCD58414B1DA329E94057EB97DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to issue a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph immediately on receipt of an application that is submitted in person at the field office for the Federal land management unit under subparagraph (D)(ii); and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H8143EC5D4C314ADBB01A4D47ECBE0CE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if an application submitted under subparagraph (D) meets the requirements of this paragraph, immediately on receipt of the application issue a de minimis use authorization for the filming or still photography activity.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAD7703BA96C14E758BCC0D1E9435F1E3"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall only issue a de minimis use authorization under this paragraph if the filming or still photography activity—</text>
<clause id="HDEAA206D0FFE4E628FD07888899A7EBF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves a group of not fewer than 6 individuals and not more than 8 individuals;</text></clause> <clause id="H362986E89306460DA2AAB9306C2B61E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets each of the requirements described in paragraph (5); and</text></clause>
<clause id="H2CB4718350E94CBDA01FAD0D89521534"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is consistent with subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD138B2BCE78B47D49FC87819F27890F7"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A de minimis use authorization issued under this paragraph shall list the requirements described in subparagraph (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1B1528BEA88146F5806417F8B9397011"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Required permits</header>
<subparagraph id="H2F99E82280844EA49CDB63A7AE466C17"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2)(B), the Secretary concerned may require a permit application and, if a permit is issued, assess a reasonable fee, as described in subsection (b)(1), for a filming or still photography activity that—</text> <clause id="H9302E91E6C224A27944172E9E384404A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves more than 8 individuals; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H2EF3EF3E77184D67BAAD77E0D5126E30"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not meet each of the requirements described in paragraph (5).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE21E9F6A1C92482B8A6D71C25A261FCE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Wildernesss Act clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No provision of this subsection is intended to or shall be construed to conflict with the provisions of the Wilderness Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE3FCB92E1B44385BA794012AA4B7268"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements for filming or still photography activity</header><text>The requirements referred to in paragraphs (2)(A)(ii), (3)(F)(ii), (4)(B), and (7)(C) are as follows:</text> <subparagraph id="H0B9969E28FA0418FAC2888276C5602E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A person conducts the filming or still photography activity in a manner that—</text>
<clause id="HC597EABA96B847A5A93BCEB71F501222"><enum>(i)</enum><text>does not impede or intrude on the experience of other visitors to the Federal land management unit;</text></clause> <clause id="HDCBC5FCC5CE94556B7940D1E64C96727"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except as otherwise authorized, does not disturb or negatively impact—</text>
<subclause id="HE65D3A473A814F6F8DD9FCBF0091975C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a natural or cultural resource; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF7504632CF2A4D2DAA93454F059C8C25"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an environmental or scenic value; and</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H6493EBE9E6764B11830D53CE86358412"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allows for equitable allocation or use of facilities of the Federal land management unit.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1702E8213A7C4669B8EF85C3E0F7A7D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The person conducts the filming or still photography activity at a location in which the public is allowed.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0E8A4844CB3245BA807FE9ADBDD9F338"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity does not require the exclusive use of a site or area.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA202D714E5B7497FB620541F6B24276A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The person does not conduct the filming or still photography activity in a localized area that receives a very high volume of visitation.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H299B43BC1B1A45F3B210B4CC8DE156E7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity does not use a set or staging equipment, subject to the limitation that handheld equipment (such as a tripod, monopod, and handheld lighting equipment) shall not be considered staging equipment for the purposes of this subparagraph. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H86F82E4BD102494792DA2A854634E5C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity complies with and adheres to visitor use policies, practices, and regulations applicable to the Federal land management unit.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H97175D9BD680478684AE602CB8D17114"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The filming or still photography activity is not likely to result in additional administrative costs being incurred by the Secretary concerned with respect to the filming or still photography activity, as determined by the Secretary concerned.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F7D2189D97E460496262A28CF1CE4D0"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The person conducting the filming or still photography activity complies with other applicable Federal, State, and local laws (including regulations), including laws relating to the use of unmanned aerial equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2324D99F771049B39988AC902C167884"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Content creation</header><text>Regardless of distribution platform, any video, still photograph, or audio recording for commercial or noncommercial content creation at a Federal land management unit shall be considered to be a filming or still photography activity under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H723C9909F5294262AD5A8D9181AD31EE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Effect</header> <subparagraph id="H6079483918904321ADF16C5CD32D361C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Permits requested though not required</header><text>On the request of a person intending to carry out a filming or still photography activity, the Secretary concerned may issue a permit for the filming or still photography activity, even if a permit for the filming or still photography activity is not required under this section.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA4070E0B89FB49D38599DEB685F9AA34"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No additional permits, commercial use authorizations, or fees for filming and still photography at authorized events</header><text>A filming or still photography activity at an activity or event that is allowed or authorized, including a wedding, engagement party, family reunion, or celebration of a graduate, shall be considered merely incidental for the purposes of paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H775A907490624DE398C4E168CB532648"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Monetary compensation</header><text>The receipt of monetary compensation by the person engaged in the filming or still photography activity shall not affect the permissibility of the filming or still photography activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC386F6CB094E47C8AB6CF8CF286B1C3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fees and recovery costs</header>
<paragraph id="H3955376548A54BDE9EC14D8E35C5D216"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The reasonable fees referred to in subsection (a)(4) shall meet each of the following criteria:</text> <subparagraph id="HF9C2709832C24046A3E0842C991E54BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The reasonable fee shall provide a fair return to the United States.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H01A2FFEF933A437883E8AEE02FC9A40F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The reasonable fee shall be based on the following criteria:</text> <clause id="H00D023CA52494CF68E2459F38C72C06A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of days of the filming or still photography activity.</text></clause>
<clause id="H3C4EF89D52DE440FBD05E450A4F3C2B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The size of the film or still photography crew present at the Federal land management unit.</text></clause> <clause id="H2EB2F0F2FBD74837BE459918CECE0BF9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The quantity and type of film or still photography equipment present at the Federal land management unit.</text></clause>
<clause id="H4591B27B42E2408DAC0C047E6E80D310"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any other factors that the Secretary concerned determines to be necessary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0520EA4703949C5A55F7ED94DB8A86B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recovery of costs</header> <subparagraph id="HD0B8937C95E341269E073A632458E9A9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall collect from the applicant for the applicable permit any costs incurred by the Secretary concerned related to a filming or still photography activity subject to a permit under subsection (a)(4), including—</text>
<clause id="H8A1E8348C4CA4C8CA3125D53DAB9A109"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the costs of the review or issuance of the permit; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9E8CE2745BF442BE83DE01BD2593126A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>related administrative and personnel costs.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H471DCF311E124D04AE121AA891493071"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect on fees collected</header><text>All costs recovered under subparagraph (A) shall be in addition to the fee described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4FA5ACC1929B4462BAA550897616C0DF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of proceeds</header> <subparagraph id="HD2C2DF9862E84C4B9BE2F36F496DD96C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>All fees collected under this section shall—</text>
<clause id="HE5F592781C6749D59CBCB41D13ABEA02"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be available for expenditure by the Secretary concerned, without further appropriation; and</text></clause> <clause id="HAE8FF8012E904D02A9672C7FB577943A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remain available until expended.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFB8229B9087741A3AC1C45D48B751A51"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Costs</header><text>All costs recovered under paragraph (2)(A) shall—</text> <clause id="HDC3AD753F1574A40820572AF3C951719"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be available for expenditure by the Secretary concerned, without further appropriation, at the Federal land management unit at which the costs are collected; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H702B4CA038274B7785AE39C1831D8986"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>remain available until expended.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H12BEA3C7E0BF4FF986761AE1786D2584"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protection of resources</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not allow a person to undertake a filming or still photography activity if the Secretary concerned determines that—</text>
<paragraph id="H3E9DC7568C2342C18874B4E68A5BCAC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>there is a likelihood that the person would cause resource damage at the Federal land management unit, except as otherwise authorized;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H192A853917B74BCCBDA247B2B1C742D9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the person would create an unreasonable disruption of the use and enjoyment by the public of the Federal land management unit; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H39C4E2B71C8C43B3A779FB108FECB22A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the filming or still photography activity poses a health or safety risk to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H312056B6A23E4F6A85A950F7C376D7F4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Processing of permit applications</header> <paragraph id="H2B42FCD1EC354A7AA49330DA6F738F37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall establish a process to ensure that the Secretary concerned responds in a timely manner to an application for a permit for a filming or still photography activity required under subsection (a)(4).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35ADFF738B53457E8479A3128824C843"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>If a permit is required under this section for 2 or more Federal agencies or Federal land management units, the Secretary concerned and the head of any other applicable Federal agency, as applicable, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, coordinate permit processing procedures, including through the use of identifying a lead agency or lead Federal land management unit—</text> <subparagraph id="H2411297349464043B42C6B323123CC32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to review the application for the permit;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0D0C17D9DBB54362A0530A72573051FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to issue the permit; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F2BB42E395F4E158BED0CAFF9738FC4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to collect any required fees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H2E0A9C8909734BA5B3BB1D6749872F7B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H5961952B25D24D199513115DF92AC047"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal land management unit</header><text>The term <term>Federal land management unit</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H43D29D72BAC1468ABD5FF5981A67FF34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal land (other than National Park System land) under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DBA7A48742D46C9943D6BA563DF6A7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>National Forest System land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0E72257A07334F2E8ED19FA3EA361EA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H03B0A9FD70B24A15838EBC614A85FE4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to land described in paragraph (1)(A); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H633607C110BC4D7594EE51925AF83C87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to land described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

