<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC79328D7BE84929AAC89D388AD929CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7920 IH: Stealthing Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7920</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220531">May 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create a civil action for non-consensual sexual protection barrier removal, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0F10390F495F4901979CFEEB3DD85A2F" style="OLC"><section id="H46DF4D123B8349748C9002DF9DEB4716" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stealthing Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBD2A66434F0F4BBAA308F98C96252BDC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HBA986770F9804BBB85EBCD84878B6695"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stealthing is a type of sexual violence used to describe non-consensual condom removal during sex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C41963607FB4C7B9125EA5CBE31FF22"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In October 2021, California became the first State to outlaw stealthing at the State level. This law creates a civil remedy so that victims of stealthing can sue for damages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H813BFDDCFE7F4DE0BC62122891CD68DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A 2019 study from Health Psychology reported that almost 10 percent of male participants reported engaging in non-consensual condom removal since the age of 14 years, with an average of 3.62 times and a range of 1–21 times.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49405D4F4A5041ED8058CF3671D8C232"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A 2019 study from the Jacobs Institute of Women’s Health found that 12 percent of women have experienced stealthing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD7747A0DAE04791B60A2C13BC4C326F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A 2018 Australian study from PLoS ONE found that one in three female respondents and one in five gay male respondents have experienced stealthing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8C7E8FEAF674B8AADF3C22700265EF7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stealthing is a grave violation of autonomy, dignity, and trust that is considered emotional and sexual abuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H817CAAC2A85344209FC324A2D3531965"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Stealthing exposes victims to physical risks including pregnancy and sexually transmitted diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7729DED127849FF826060FD46F5F112"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">People engaging in sexual intercourse have the right to make decisions about whether to use a condom or other sexual protection barrier. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H49A67C5B3A06408580305436D0C09D66"><enum>3.</enum><header>Non-consensual sexual protection barrier removal</header><subsection id="H68FC6A2AE2CC45E7B34F77DF599F2CA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Civil action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person may commence a civil action against a person who, in a circumstance described in subsection (b), engages in non-consensual sexual protection barrier removal.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC083EC5962784691B6BB8F6420AE8E49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Circumstances described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text><paragraph id="H0DF5E262C94348B9A7C49810A98A7A18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the defendant traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42267AD15CA449E58334188B998AEA2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the defendant used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9B1A61BD7564C5B848296133FAFEF43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BE2DCFC18D24051B2EFE225A089C87F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the defendant transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9719BC0DB8410B9E6DB10A249AED56" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any sexual protection barrier described has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce and was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65F977E826C940E1B3E30A5F1EB4D777"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC1AF215035549318AC0C80201C32996"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A57DD96A87A4AB4AACA5C4AFD4F3C50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person bringing a civil action under subsection (a) may recover compensatory and punitive damages, injunctive and declaratory relief, and such other relief as a court may deem appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9C0C3C18DF75441A98467DB5DC2DAFCC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H39134EC300D143C6B5AC0B3E0F4A2772"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Non-consensual sexual protection barrier removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>non-consensual sexual protection barrier removal</quote> means removal of a sexual protection barrier from a body part, including the genitals, or an object being used by a person for sexual contact with another person without the consent of each person involved in such sexual contact, causing sexual contact between the body parts, including the genitals, or objects being used for sexual contact, and the body of any person engaged in such sexual contact. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22FCA575B5C34BADB4919E6DA222A042"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sexual protection barrier</header><text>The term <quote>sexual protection barrier</quote> includes a condom, including an internal condom, a dental dam, or any other barrier against sexual fluids during sexual contact. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

