<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HACEF13E2D5064F0383437858A52357B1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8156 IH: Oligarch Assets for Ukrainian Victory Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8156</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220621">June 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Attorney General to transfer the proceeds of certain forfeited property to remediate the harms of Russian aggression towards Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H09C2CBD87EAF4860832846ABE4A87FF7" style="OLC"><section id="HE0C915E787514EC8B797505D1F3BC642" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Oligarch Assets for Ukrainian Victory Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H966C1404007743D5824527E9A086EBC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Attorney General authority to transfer forfeited Russian assets to assist Ukraine</header><subsection id="H5EB86CB67EDD4A9789DD17780AC32495"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may transfer to the Secretary of State the proceeds of any covered forfeited property, for use by the Secretary of State to provide assistance to Ukraine to remediate the harms of Russian aggression towards Ukraine. Any such transfer shall be considered foreign assistance under the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H39174930B99D49579C832BE748EF402F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State, shall provide a semiannual report the appropriate congressional committees on any transfers made pursuant to subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="H1457F7834D0B473791CEBA41E257F105"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA3DAB5EA0AA94BC4A2685EB023FB3291"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered forfeited property</term> means property seized by the Department of Justice under chapter 46 or section 1963 of title 18, United States Code, which property belonged to or was possessed by a person or entity designated by the Secretary of the Treasury or the Secretary of State, pursuant to Executive Order 14024, as subject to sanctions. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DAF8CC6C4624CFEB2A0D46A9B2A6EF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H442F301A95E948A78437D02761875374"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committees on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE04A40DB01C24025A414B23C158AB294"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61A56C978FE249AC885D989C81114A21"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H599996EF527440E98BD37E840D2FBDF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD33CFBC6CFB74CE98FAC10277375BE54"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority under this section expires on May 1, 2025. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

