<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1ACCDB0D772A47BF831849048281BB00" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6416 IH: Banning Surveillance Advertising Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220118">January 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit targeted advertising by advertising facilitators and advertisers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC9855E912FB3495AB4AEE7EAF864D880" style="OLC"><section id="HF5B6144A959B43748F9817052BBC9006" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Banning Surveillance Advertising Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8D6D32DA9C6F4C799D1DA442B25229CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on targeted advertising</header><subsection id="H5C8C9A2DB10944FFACF55DEBF7C6CD63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on targeting by advertising facilitators</header><paragraph id="HFE64CAE90BAA4263BAF7BED7595D06D1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An advertising facilitator may not—</text><subparagraph id="HF14BD31F63F34024B9A332B74D1E0D56" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">target the dissemination of an advertisement; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D4B8413542043108CF16AC09822AF01" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">knowingly enable an advertiser or a third party to target the dissemination of an advertisement, including by providing the advertiser or third party with—</text><clause id="H7EE3105C3B6A4E27BF25F2F56B7AEF6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a list of individuals or connected devices;</text></clause><clause id="HF6C51378FB61432699A5236568983A18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contact information of an individual;</text></clause><clause id="H673328FB8BCE49859DE89872EF94D987"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unique identifier that may be used to identify an individual or a connected device; or</text></clause><clause id="H388A7F1040884579946D1FAA4C32E5AE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other personal information that can be used to identify an individual or a connected device.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48588ED5241B43C4970BF897BC0CF464" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contextual advertisements</header><subparagraph id="H19065ECBD8A440B8AD381C015D465454"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), an advertising facilitator shall not be considered to target the dissemination of an advertisement, or to knowingly enable an advertiser or third party to target the dissemination of an advertisement, to an individual (or a connected device associated with an individual) if the advertisement—</text><clause id="HCD98316F97DC4E66A27910320135138A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is disseminated based on information—</text><subclause id="H9140E06210844D32B8DCE4ED6C161AA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the individual is viewing or with which the individual is otherwise engaging; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE32A0E9020E44257BF16EA5DCF53BC4D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which the individual searched; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H619AED365ECF45B99B1358CC2CEFAC46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is displayed or otherwise disseminated in close proximity to information described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7673626E9206442DA676FA49BAFA5E1E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on further use of information related to the delivery of contextual advertisements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information collected in connection with the dissemination of an advertisement as described in subparagraph (A) may not be used to target the dissemination of additional advertisements or to knowingly enable an advertiser or third party to target the dissemination of additional advertisements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA955FD0387947DD878FA16402FE8528"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information provided by or on behalf of advertiser with attestation of compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) does not apply to the targeting of the dissemination of an advertisement based on information described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subparagraph (B) of such paragraph that is provided to an advertising facilitator by an advertiser or by a third party on behalf of an advertiser, if the advertising facilitator is provided a written attestation that the advertiser is not in violation of subsection (b) with respect to such information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA6461A67C6554F17BA34C7AB3DA919C1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on targeting by advertisers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An advertiser may not target, cause an advertising facilitator to target, or knowingly enable a third party to target or cause an advertising facilitator to target, the dissemination of an advertisement (including by providing any information described in clauses (i) through (iv) of subsection (a)(1)(B)) based on personal information—</text><paragraph id="H5E904A55DD934159AD053D4D3D251494"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that the advertiser has purchased or otherwise obtained from another person (other than an individual to whom the personal information pertains); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DDDE46F27EE44BC8292C8F736950443"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that—</text><subparagraph id="HF019E2365C3A45CDB0A0EBEC03F9B306"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies an individual as a member of a protected class; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4924A180D424D1C90A84E9944DF2A54"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is known or should reasonably be known by the advertiser to act as a reasonable proxy for identifying an individual as a member of a protected class.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF1F9647402B4A3A9A8CE222643314C2" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception for targeting based on recognized place</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the dissemination of an advertisement shall not be considered to be targeted to an individual, connected device, or group of individuals or connected devices based on a recognized place associated with the individual, connected device, or group of individuals or connected devices.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA40FA0D015B34DB3823846320C84E526"><enum>3.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="H0558FCCCA92B4E5BB9FCC03934473D84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission</header><paragraph id="H17A5675BFFDC47CC96A782569D6A5BE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA97FDADD8445449281BD096FCA50A27D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><subparagraph id="H35DFDC756D4B4D50A3E7052F323510AD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B) and paragraph (3)—</text><clause id="H326B6F716641474CB3A5E07BE9A632F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Commission shall enforce this Act and the regulations promulgated under this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H5FC79B930AD44251B932B07D9F6D740E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any person who violates this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF126279178F64CAD9867CE29846BFA40"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusive litigation authority</header><text>Notwithstanding section 16(a) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/56">15 U.S.C. 56(a)</external-xref>), the Commission shall have exclusive authority to commence or defend, and supervise the litigation of, any action for a violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act, and any appeal of such action, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, without first referring the matter to the Attorney General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C9D26E93C584FF8B107B9ED34F82748"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Common carriers and nonprofit organizations</header><text>Notwithstanding section 4, 5(a)(2), or 6 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/44">15 U.S.C. 44</external-xref>; 45(a)(2); 46) or any jurisdictional limitation of the Commission, the Commission shall also enforce this Act and the regulations promulgated under this Act, in the same manner provided in paragraphs (1) and (2), with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H700F8EF1344048A789BBFF092F1EBC64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>common carriers subject to the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) and all Acts amendatory thereof and supplementary thereto; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBA21C19AE2843FCB51BBE8FB1544B75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>organizations not organized to carry on business for their own profit or that of their members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30EE2E7E9DAB4926A365192F191AF701"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rulemaking authority</header><text>The Commission may promulgate, under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, any regulations necessary to implement this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6064C2EC6F504690BA78DCABEC07207C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under any other provision of law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H68722242DE9F4A65A1B971788AB3AA82"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header><paragraph id="HDE3624BFEF084EC7A631F09D34E6B13B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by an act or practice in violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act, the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States or an appropriate State court to obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC08ABE80C4804837B3B638D2A03F9995"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of the Commission</header><subparagraph id="H8A365C88FB184A67A9CD10C9A7C62636"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice to the Commission</header><clause id="HF078E501D3484552A231496AB52DA5F1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring a civil action under paragraph (1) before initiating the civil action.</text></clause><clause id="HBA946399EBE0418D8B024908088131B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required by clause (i) with respect to a civil action shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause><clause id="H64453E23AE274EB5B7F206DA3EED2132"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA19758146274F7CB29BD4D7C4A2B5AE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention by the Commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text><clause id="H72D792A446064B5AAB09AA0609F0C111"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="H7F1E220FD074485A811FAD4FBB73E2DB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text><subclause id="H79F3C2BC6D594D9A8FDD5F1EB32E8E76" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remove the civil action to the appropriate district court of the United States, if the action was not originally brought in such court; </text></subclause><subclause id="H2E93B8921BAA4DC2B1EDE52362834C00"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB0184F2038594F46AB00764BAA35D473"><enum>(III)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in the civil action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43981323CC9640D7B6C5B0B69ABAFF8C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBED2EE1F7963414EB61B76FD2E3D5E51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Action by the Commission</header><text>If the Commission institutes a civil action with respect to a violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act, the attorney general of a State may not, during the pendency of such action, bring a civil action under paragraph (1) against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for the violation with respect to which the Commission instituted such action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86F054E0C6C4E48A970A6D255F0EC4B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Actions by other State officials</header><subparagraph id="H6FF92C91E3144ECBB2593DD69A16FBBA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to civil actions brought by attorneys general under paragraph (1), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under such paragraph, subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA69D0C5BE3484163853F714DEB6846C8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an attorney general or authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8317214347E4624988C72E9936E73BE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><paragraph id="HE3213DDA3A1E480DB9BBB0DEC7FB438A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enforcement by individuals</header><subparagraph id="HB79FAA9CACD94A2CB56C7F7B9855160E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual alleging a violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act may bring a civil action in any Federal or State court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6748D2C979FB4F1187BB752A0E27A826"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A) in which the plaintiff prevails, the court may award—</text><clause id="H27FFF80D15974C2F8C21F5277921BFD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount equal to—</text><subclause id="HFF40059623F94E349122317C9AF5564B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a negligent violation, not less than $100 and not greater than $1,000 per violation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H39ACF3790D3245BCBC6A39CA804A6C87"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a reckless, knowing, willful, or intentional violation, not less than $500 and not greater than $5,000 per violation;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2395CCEA4DDF4B4EADDBDBD23122599A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reasonable attorney’s fees and litigation costs; and</text></clause><clause id="H3E27A083314B431C9B22E2C148C9EA1E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other relief, including equitable or declaratory relief, that the court determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H379D0F7D753748D7889224001AE63114" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Injury in fact</header><text>A violation of this Act or a regulation promulgated under this Act with respect to the personal information of an individual constitutes a concrete and particularized injury in fact to that individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B7AFF737B9E4787B59602D1055CAE05"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Invalidity of pre-dispute arbitration agreements and pre-dispute joint-action waivers</header><subparagraph id="H4AFDCF7434F44BE68085011664C7EB4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no pre-dispute arbitration agreement or pre-dispute joint-action waiver shall be valid or enforceable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA545CBA47AE4037919E37BD4055F5F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Any determination as to whether or how this paragraph applies to any dispute shall be made by a court, rather than an arbitrator, without regard to whether such agreement purports to delegate such determination to an arbitrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB1BF4CC9811D4392B2BC75AE34496DFF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4880A4DBDF0F4AF895F17C9F14FE43E4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advertisement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>advertisement</quote> means information provided by an advertiser to an advertising facilitator that the advertising facilitator, in exchange for monetary consideration or another thing of value, disseminates to an individual, connected device, or group of individuals or connected devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BECADD341A645C3B1ED0DF402A88D6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advertiser</header><subparagraph id="H92385455425C41118824C91C6FCE5C3B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>advertiser</quote> means a person to the extent such person, directly or indirectly, provides an advertising facilitator with monetary consideration or another thing of value for the dissemination of an advertisement to an individual, connected device, or group of individuals or connected devices.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C8374C297CD4D358959D57B03477F6D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>advertiser</quote> does not include a natural person, except to the extent such person is engaged in a commercial activity that is more than de minimis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE954BD8A5EED4681B5AFF9321784E446"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Advertising facilitator</header><subparagraph id="HB2A0DF27254C49B5ADCA074E781CE51F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>advertising facilitator</quote> means a person to the extent such person—</text><clause id="HF58CD6E1D78B4372A008C404F71469E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">receives monetary consideration or another thing of value to disseminate an advertisement to an individual, connected device, or group of individuals or connected devices; and</text></clause><clause id="H0FCBF13893A24F80AEF0970E96CD50D8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>collects or processes personal information with respect to the dissemination of the advertisement.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H856B1F7EB0F647C4B39EEA161F08FCD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <quote>advertising facilitator</quote> does not include a natural person, except to the extent such person is engaged in a commercial activity that is more than de minimis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA862CDA2701D4722A908255A1B645B4E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Collect</header><text>The term <quote>collect</quote> means, with respect to personal information, to obtain such information in any manner, except when solely transmitting, routing, providing intermediate storage for, or providing connections for such information through a system or network.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ABA8E3FAB4040F58BAA20F1EC9C00CA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF70078184E204D9CBFC72C7BCCEE5BFB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Connected device</header><text>The term <quote>connected device</quote> means any electronic equipment that is—</text><subparagraph id="H41C732A0178F481290034D37F4212E4A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>primarily designed for or marketed to consumers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48FF8EEB296A4513B26C76DA106B97B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>capable of connecting to the internet or another communication network; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DFCC6338D4846FC91467C6216AFBF37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>capable of sending, receiving, or processing personal information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2323E7D5D0B64265B27E118C61B30195"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The term <quote>contents</quote>, when used with respect to any communication, has the meaning given such term in section 2510 of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5382B53C5B5414CA2D48EB9021CF64E" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Dispute</header><text>The term <quote>dispute</quote> means any claim by an individual that a person has violated this Act or the regulations promulgated under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F9BEC99D66F42DCB664787844A336A1"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Disseminate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>disseminate</quote> means, with respect to an advertisement, to transmit, display, or otherwise disseminate the advertisement electronically or through communication by wire or radio.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H350A1BDCA375421BA29E07A7E297D364"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Dissemination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>dissemination</quote> means, with respect to an advertisement, the transmission, display, or other dissemination of the advertisement electronically or through communication by wire or radio.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H075FBBDAADB246F1A8E86AE351A4166F" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Indian lands</header><text>The term <quote>Indian lands</quote> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H03EF8A3D598248D68C44FE9490F03C45" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any Indian country of an Indian Tribe (as such term is defined in section 1151 of title 18, United States Code);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22B7A9DB818942E4875894EDFFE2B63F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any land in Alaska owned, pursuant to the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), by an Indian Tribe that is a Native village (as such term is defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)) or by a Village Corporation (as such term is defined in section 3 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)) that is associated with an Indian Tribe; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1D7532A14854EE99EDCA118D02BB231" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any land that is part or all of a Tribal designated statistical area associated with an Indian Tribe, or is part or all of an Alaska Native village statistical area associated with an Indian Tribe, as defined by the Bureau of the Census for the purposes of the most recent decennial census.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0128CA49130646A6B3E427576C05215E"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB150975D255844979B76CF269EDB1111"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Personal information</header><text>The term <quote>personal information</quote> means data linked or reasonably linkable to an individual or connected device, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5A6DBB17B364463699EF4FA53E154C99"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data inferred or derived about the individual or connected device from other collected data, if such data is still linked or reasonably linkable to the individual or connected device;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD72B8CAC28234DFC998C6819253AAA03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contents of communications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9205C8F49114E0CA455863A966D35D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>internet browsing history and online activity; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H273F7A8D24CD4A5C8C58F66457DD25D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a unique identifier used for the purposes of targeting the dissemination of an advertisement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7E0D281BE0247E5BB7025F064A5814E" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Pre-dispute arbitration agreement</header><text>The term <quote>pre-dispute arbitration agreement</quote> means any agreement to arbitrate a dispute that has not arisen at the time of making the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09F3C67434474747A0D7B20FD9AFAC22" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Pre-dispute joint-action waiver</header><text>The term <quote>pre-dispute joint-action waiver</quote> means an agreement, whether or not part of a pre-dispute arbitration agreement, that would prohibit, or waive the right of, one of the parties to the agreement to participate in a joint, class, or collective action in a judicial, arbitral, administrative, or other forum, concerning a dispute that has not yet arisen at the time of making the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92F01D03E0FC46DA93B04E17AFBAB12D" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Protected class</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>protected class</quote> means the actual or perceived race, color, ethnicity, national origin, religion, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity or gender expression), familial status, or disability of an individual or group of individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H632AAE3BB5944B57835D8AB437CD1288"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Recognized place</header><subparagraph id="H9CBAB53574454D26847CE5CFA6EF022F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>recognized place</quote> means any of the following:</text><clause id="HE26D310CA82A49CBAC0E40608A803675" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A State.</text></clause><clause id="H783721F1134F461C8B81265922C2F8E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Indian lands.</text></clause><clause id="HD29FB4C1B6134E3F952C47D1714AC731"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A county, municipality, city, town, township, village, borough, or similar unit of general government that is—</text><subclause id="H12A051FE68364DDAB64C713AAA7A4595"><enum>(I)</enum><text>incorporated pursuant to a State law; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA044B4CD54CD4A11B1025C922643E845"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an incorporated place (as defined in the most recent glossary of the Bureau of the Census).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7A9A0E4B2A36415F9A49569DD886C1AA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A census designated place (as defined in the most recent glossary of the Bureau of the Census).</text></clause><clause id="HA3EBA03319884F04AB506DDB5CE4A677"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A designated market area (as defined in section 122(j) of title 17, United States Code).</text></clause><clause id="HE716BBCE0EF942C5A9AF09756E00F7C5" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A congressional district.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H393FFC9FD64F4E5DAFDECE2A984AD0AE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>recognized place</quote> does not include—</text><clause id="HC970F4183BCC448F8058D6977E3C8FAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a subdivision of any item listed in subparagraph (A) that is not itself listed in such subparagraph; or</text></clause><clause id="HE5A668D8C5394BE1B2E2E7475C44B667"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a ZIP Code. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F8C76A84C8142BB808C00ADDFBBB2B4" commented="no"><enum>(18)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and any possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H354093A177D24395BFDA679D44821B25"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Target</header><subparagraph id="H8B3358ED4E4F459AAF46F0D922EDEA85"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>target</quote> means, with respect to the dissemination of an advertisement, to perform or cause to be performed any computational process designed to select an individual, connected device, or group of individuals or connected devices to which to disseminate the advertisement based on personal information pertaining to the individual or connected device or to the individuals or connected devices that make up the group.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC50EFB2CF9854633B08D03E1CC2E9902" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <quote>target</quote> does not include, with respect to the dissemination of an advertisement, the performance or causing the performance of any computational process undertaken solely for transmitting, routing, providing intermediate storage for, or providing connections for the advertisement through a system or network.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD48F382BB1B247B9AE80E224793AF4E0"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Third party</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>third party</quote> includes, with respect to an advertiser or an advertising facilitator, a subsidiary, a corporate affiliate, or other related party of the advertiser or advertising facilitator.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

