<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H52D68C85E04745639351BC3C95CB2F87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6842 IH: To provide for the imposition of sanctions on members of parliament of the Russian Federation who voted on February 15, 2022, in favor of the appeal to President Vladimir Putin to recognize the regions of Donetsk and Luhansk in southeastern Ukraine as one or more independent states.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6842</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide for the imposition of sanctions on members of parliament of the Russian Federation who voted on February 15, 2022, in favor of the appeal to President Vladimir Putin to recognize the regions of Donetsk and Luhansk in southeastern Ukraine as one or more independent states.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H73DEBC3E6CDE4F598ABAE28A8A55346B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCFCD40639E764FADADC8101DAFE9884F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Sanctions on members of parliament of the Russian Federation who voted on February 15, 2022, in favor of the appeal to President Vladimir Putin to recognize the regions of Donetsk and Luhansk in southeastern Ukraine as one or more independent states</header> 
<subsection id="HB688397A2D494DBDB248375EB8EF1422"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a result of the decision of the Government of the Russian Federation to recognize the regions of Donetsk and Luhansk in southeastern Ukraine as one or more independent states on February 21, 2022, the President is authorized to impose sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any member of the parliament of the Russian Federation who voted on February 15, 2022, in favor of the appeal to President Vladimir Putin to recognize the regions of Donetsk and Luhansk in southeastern Ukraine as one or more independent states.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAAEE40FC5FA34C64BF5E8F8AFD864ACD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header> <paragraph id="HB84665C6386348CEA735D3AD63883FC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sanctions described in this subsection are the following: </text> 
<subparagraph id="H4DC3BBC93E5D4B25A786C28C4A8DC016"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text>The exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE132FF2ED5A147D6872B9CE98D48B1A7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header> <clause id="HF1FFCE1EA31E44CB9AFE52F46B6326AF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas, admission, or parole</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person determined by the President to be subject to subsection (a) is—</text> 
<subclause id="HE2E74772548C4CC1A461AB7800B0C193"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H7D88C9274CEA4322B74A084EF32CED14"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7CBD614D47D24F21B83FFFD684ECD390"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD80982A02E2149A985B85E06E28C3D1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><text>A foreign person described in clause (i) is also subject to the following:</text> 
<subclause id="H8922791340F6496FB7C12F33F7885908"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB0148D027F7F48019AF06ABB620DAB6F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the foreign person’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H25C0A6F2614E42EE9B3695BD5163019C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>In subparagraph (A), the term <term>United States person</term> means—</text> <clause id="HC1FC637BF78C4179AA6DDAF6F9B45B1E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H96C4C7E6F6B54BB6A43540B8CB27BFC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or of any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H195B5A5FF0254A9481F10EC0DFCC8458"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of paragraph (1)(A) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out paragraph (1)(A) shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7851DC61090748A8A2D9C90477496494"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEBFF268CB11546B799B6C2A197480700"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A1FB29D2445464D97D6A42632B98046"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception to comply with international obligations and for law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply to an alien if admitting the alien into the United States is necessary—</text> 
<clause id="H278F30CFD8834E718C5088A89F8F964B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations; or</text></clause> <clause id="H43D8EAAF340544E4A4D6E283F62B0F05"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to carry out or assist law enforcement activities in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H309910BA98CF45A39306BB2FFF50CC6C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception relating to the importation of goods</header> 
<clause id="HAD82AC9C7A2B4BC8A4731CEC0456E416"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirement to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property under paragraph (1)(A) shall not include the authority to impose sanctions on the importation of goods. </text></clause> <clause id="HFB369BF6136543B5AD3BD8C7CA237D40"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H56E5818913AA444790AE20E63DA8AE56"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to a person if the President—</text> <paragraph id="H9937447969A946C1B352C86F9E72FC9D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4D0F21A3E2324640B1094DE2E4239935"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on or before the date on which the waiver takes effect, submits to the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives a notice of and a justification for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H88AB89CDFB934111A094D77212D5F9FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this section.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 

