<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF6897F585BF4C05845613252F0795ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7780 IH: Mental Health Matters Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7780</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220516">May 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support the behavioral needs of students and youth, invest in the school-based behavioral health workforce, and ensure access to mental health and substance use disorder benefits.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF226685E86044CFA90C7B42D4F88F05C" style="OLC"><section id="H848AC339B33B46278CA569A6426A5FEA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Mental Health Matters Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H037A695A0CB24CBDB6C769013C41F4C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents of this Act is as follows: </text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H848AC339B33B46278CA569A6426A5FEA" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H037A695A0CB24CBDB6C769013C41F4C3" level="section">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7A7CCDBDE2C44657A4BA33343089F273" level="title">Title I—Early Childhood Mental Health Act</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2C27D0C6F7724827BCCA937CB488D2FD" level="section">Sec. 101. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA42AAEC04B9D4B75AC634849DBFC5D77" level="section">Sec. 102. Identification of effective interventions in Head Start programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB932635B0AA04C51B825B25A27C630D3" level="section">Sec. 103. Implementing the interventions in Head Start programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8F11BC3DACC34D339C9836EE6D0CF368" level="section">Sec. 104. Evaluating implementation of interventions in Head Start programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCE0BBC4F343D498CA365C494725C86DF" level="section">Sec. 105. Implementing the evaluation framework for Head Start programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC8A0D83E021045D7B214B8D37F7EBF2A" level="section">Sec. 106. Best Practice Centers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC772851BBADC4EFC89EB16FA60A4DA20" level="section">Sec. 107. Funding.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBFE7750186CA42E9B683CA81A0D710C1" level="title">Title II—Building Pipeline of School-Based Mental Health Service Providers Act </toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF45B4396DD1B4FF4867E81104284CCA4" level="section">Sec. 201. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9B1D59F499A04167996AB37876A07DE8" level="section">Sec. 202. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H09BD9F459D8B483BB01CF3F113CA8CC0" level="section">Sec. 203. Grant program to increase the number of school-based mental health services providers serving in high-need local educational agencies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H326863C416874EFB99751E97A77EB1C5" level="title">Title III—Elementary and Secondary School Counseling Act</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0EE86403C6374A0DB82C30C945846C11" level="section">Sec. 301. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9DF25F3DD42342478D3AC570F1AE3F55" level="section">Sec. 302. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF643B4E442534F1C8CBE94AB7BD817EC" level="section">Sec. 303. Allotments to States and subgrants to local educational agencies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF11AC34DC7E44AC9812129523D228DEF" level="section">Sec. 304. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H927775C983AE4D0AA572BFB5C65EB0E0" level="title">Title IV—Supporting Trauma-Informed Education Practices Act</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H43A075599E414AD29A7ABB8B9CCAC1A3" level="section">Sec. 401. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA058E0C5D34C4B27BFD23910E8C9C4B0" level="section">Sec. 402. Amendment to the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H87132182AFC94E819C93F24CFDA6B704" level="title">Title V—Respond, Innovate, Succeed, and Empower</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE34A2B1B77404D939C0FF8FEFF758A41" level="section">Sec. 501. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2AA27A7284A94E98B1C0C3AC6FEAC7E5" level="section">Sec. 502. Perfecting amendment to the definition of disability.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H255DF0C2B9A74D6E97A49AAEB6A1D469" level="section">Sec. 503. Supporting students with disabilities to succeed once enrolled in college.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7C565B9891CD474E9357E8AA1B14B8B6" level="section">Sec. 504. Authorization of funds for the National Center for Information and Technical Support for Postsecondary Students With Disabilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE40AFF187A04434D96172C3CB2F3C27C" level="section">Sec. 505. Inclusion of information on students with disabilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0DEB43F3F3C341D4A0EC115A18E39385" level="section">Sec. 506. Rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0A71239814C141D9AE7B2F10EAF3C495" level="title">Title VI—Strengthening Behavioral Health Benefits</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB02A731DA3D24CE390FF151134BCD132" level="section">Sec. 601. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3C7557BCAB87463A961D0E00C0335990" level="section">Sec. 602. Enforcement of Mental Health and Substance Use Disorder Requirements.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H47A2C6C4CFC8445BBD624CBEEF243E9F" level="title">Title VII—Employee and Retiree Access to Justice</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD04FADACDB9A44CDB2AEC61D8FB25469" level="section">Sec. 701. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H864A66FAB7D242FB810F3921A2FBC277" level="section">Sec. 702. Unenforceable arbitration clauses, class action waivers, representation waivers, and discretionary clauses.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCA31D7D215CE4D5981327CF900FD6327" level="section">Sec. 703. Prohibition on mandatory arbitration clauses, class action waivers, representation waivers, and discretionary clauses.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6FC8107EE2654B1B9F92E5B9DD09253A" level="section">Sec. 704. Effective date.</toc-entry></toc></section><title id="H7A7CCDBDE2C44657A4BA33343089F273"><enum>I</enum><header>Early Childhood Mental Health Act</header><section id="H2C27D0C6F7724827BCCA937CB488D2FD" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>101.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Early Childhood Mental Health Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA42AAEC04B9D4B75AC634849DBFC5D77"><enum>102.</enum><header>Identification of effective interventions in Head Start programs</header><subsection id="H1D844191EE86472D920CAECE755FC9EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Interventions that improve social-Emotional and behavioral health of children</header><paragraph id="HCA5898ED3AD340078B9840AABDFAEC9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services acting through the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall identify and review interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings—</text><subparagraph id="H1AB6BE5914EC4F6C89BC2DA1221F0D4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that improve the behavioral health of children; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBED60D545A74F698094C420D3DDFE4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are evidence based.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H298C64161A88445AB8CF6ED919F023A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Focus</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall focus on interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings that—</text><subparagraph id="HF246073FEBCF4FEA86493589D3479852"><enum>(A)</enum><text>can be delivered by a provider or other staff member in or associated with a Head Start program or Early Head Start center;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H516472B7247F4BDBA2DAF02E3AC829B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are demonstrated to improve or support healthy social, emotional, or cognitive development for children in Head Start or Early Head Start programs, with an empirical or theoretical relationship to later mental health or substance abuse outcomes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H256CB592742B49498B1040FD97F67B83"><enum>(C)</enum><text>involve changes to center-wide policies or practices, or other services and supports offered in conjunction with Head Start programs or Early Head Start centers, including services provided to adults or families (with or without a child present) for the benefit of the children;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4BCBA2990DD4CF48652AC13BFA88CA7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrate effectiveness across racial, ethnic, and geographic populations or demonstrate the capacity to be adapted to be effective across populations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H471A72A0973745ACAE808005C9F38E45"><enum>(E)</enum><text>offer a tiered approach to addressing need, including—</text><clause id="HDBDFFFB2F5634E328E6A615AD5D80FB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>universal interventions for all children;</text></clause><clause id="H62D6F94C47334EB58475B390C4E181BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selected prevention for children demonstrating increased need; and</text></clause><clause id="HC88EF312EDEF42DE8A0E10244DC09A1A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>indicated prevention for children demonstrating substantial need;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC69F6F3CBEDA4629A1A66F4EEBB38AC6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>incorporate trauma-informed care approaches; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4083B79A37CF42D993169CA1AEE03D74"><enum>(G)</enum><text>have a proven record of improving early childhood and social emotional development.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H204250CDE90D4EF78425016D82C25498"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interventions that support staff wellness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary shall identify and review interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings that support staff wellness and self-care.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC5C74FA9DE224BF5809D691852004D96"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credentials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsections (a) and (b), the Secretary, in consultation with relevant experts, shall determine the appropriate credentials for individuals who deliver the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7417DA3856744D1FBCC7ABBC3CD2BB29"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation; public input</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H518717D1186B4FEDAC7ACDCEDF45AB92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with relevant agencies, experts, academics, think tanks, and nonprofit organizations with expertise in early childhood, mental health, and trauma-informed care, including the National Institute of Mental Health, the Administration for Children and Families, the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration, the Institute of Education Sciences, and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3988C0A99FC4E8A9289453C4CE5456E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit public input on—</text><subparagraph id="H51FA37234BBA415F97873BB101AF60AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the design of the reviews under subsections (a) and (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BD447BFB8834281840C2EDCCDE514E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the findings and conclusions resulting from such reviews.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5332AB6AC4EE4A7D8654352D4AB77748"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HA82A6E29CDB3475BAEFB9B65EDCCAD00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete the initial reviews required by subsections (a) and (b) not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CFA516A3A204723B38316833C2E7025"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such reviews and the findings and conclusions therefrom at least every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF49ED77005F9474EBB9AAA95DC0AA665"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress on the results of implementing this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB932635B0AA04C51B825B25A27C630D3"><enum>103.</enum><header>Implementing the interventions in Head Start programs</header><subsection id="H24C028FEDB8547F085A55A2A2001A0BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families shall award grants to participating Head Start agencies to implement the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings that are identified pursuant to section 102.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4F95D9B3861F4B71B89F018260F90DD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall ensure that grants awarded under this section are awarded to grantees representing a diversity of geographic areas across the United States, including urban, suburban, and rural areas.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8F11BC3DACC34D339C9836EE6D0CF368"><enum>104.</enum><header>Evaluating implementation of interventions in Head Start programs</header><subsection id="H2F5BF392B3AB4FF58146E6E65376B5CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Planning and Evaluation and in coordination with the Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families, shall—</text><paragraph id="H5D481568010B434F8B171BEDBFDC2038"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings implemented pursuant to section 103—</text><subparagraph id="HE214E25E54634EF495C94ADE733E962C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are effectively implemented pursuant to section 103 and other relevant provisions of law such that the anticipated effect sizes of the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings are achieved; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BB5FA83248F44FF9AE36870F9752FB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">yield long-term savings;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H667AA28E049B4804BE7BCA935C69ACF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop a method for making the determination required by paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H550272D91D4845689C44F23DAA589120"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that such method includes competency and testing approaches, performance or outcome measures, or any other methods deemed appropriate by the Assistant Secretary, taking into consideration existing monitoring components of the Head Start and Early Head Start programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H616E4FFB7CF74BE19D01D9CA376DE1EE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Assistant Secretaries shall solicit public input on the design, findings, and conclusions of this process and shall consider whether updates are necessary at least every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H64E75E3AE53A4D41AB9CC3CED26AFB1C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Process</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text><paragraph id="H8746A7314DFD4A40931AB4EB1EC859E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct any research and evaluation studies needed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EE67F08A83043E889FD3FAFC8C84716"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit public input on—</text><subparagraph id="HC27B0D4DDB47461B956D4C8F4ED91914"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the design of the method developed pursuant to subsection (a)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EA15967C8014357828B0DF9DA25157C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the resulting findings and conclusions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD776C564B43048409456D5EB2FE308DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall—</text><paragraph id="H563900B7226249B69B036E29F6C0719E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop the method required by subsection (a)(2) and make the initial determination required by subsection (a)(1) not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H415F7FD51DF64006B29868F9052C0940"><enum>(2)</enum><text>update such method and determination at least every 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCE0BBC4F343D498CA365C494725C86DF"><enum>105.</enum><header>Implementing the evaluation framework for Head Start programs</header><subsection id="HE86FE585430B4A68AC92646937E7D866"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Evaluation method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families shall implement the evaluation method developed pursuant to section 104(a) in the Head Start program as a voluntary mechanism for interested Head Start programs or Early Head Start centers to evaluate the extent to which such programs or centers have effectively implemented the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified pursuant to section 102, with minimal burden or disruption to programs and centers interested in participating.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB23BF3690CA648F79E3C51DADC004336"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families shall provide guidance, tools, resources, and technical assistance to grantees for implementing and evaluating interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified pursuant to section 102 and optimizing the performance of such grantees on the annual evaluations.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC8A0D83E021045D7B214B8D37F7EBF2A"><enum>106.</enum><header>Best Practice Centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary for the Administration for Children and Families may fund up to 5 Best Practice Centers in Early Childhood Training in universities and colleges to prepare future Head Start agencies and staff able to deliver the interventions, best practices, curricula, and staff trainings identified pursuant to section 102.</text></section><section id="HC772851BBADC4EFC89EB16FA60A4DA20"><enum>107.</enum><header>Funding</header><subsection id="H95BFA7D4772D4E16990AF6485EEE342B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2032 for carrying out sections 103(b), 104, and 106.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5B1F64AD43A9453E8A6688A959EAA0A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts authorized to be appropriated by subsection (a) are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HBFE7750186CA42E9B683CA81A0D710C1"><enum>II</enum><header>Building Pipeline of School-Based Mental Health Service Providers Act </header><section id="HF45B4396DD1B4FF4867E81104284CCA4" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>201.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Pipeline of School-Based Mental Health Service Providers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9B1D59F499A04167996AB37876A07DE8"><enum>202.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="H98AA6DACBBC149C3BE44BDDC06D8C004"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The term <term>best practices</term> means a technique or methodology that, through experience and research related to professional practice in a school-based mental health field, has proven to reliably lead to a desired result.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE130E6D9B4C64E729826DB505EE31BE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible institution</term> means an institution of higher education that offers a program of study that leads to a master's or other graduate degree—</text><subparagraph id="HDE43C90052244208B9A557BB07BF68B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in school psychology that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in school psychology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CD55088757D4ED3BB9DA9EFC88E42A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in school counseling that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in school counseling;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8E52621985D447D80BB118FFA73505F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in school social work that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in school social work;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50E1FADF0528455E903A9D63966B054F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in another school-based mental health field that prepares students in such program for the State licensing or certification examination in such field, if applicable; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3DB112886324D31837BEF9EAF0FB447"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in any combination of study described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA966417C7C654297B00B6BD2FB0336E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H049CAC866BDC404FB3620FEE50FD587C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a partnership between 1 or more high-need local educational agencies and 1 or more eligible institutions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38E71698A23C49EB86F686706535D9FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in any region in which local educational agencies may not have a sufficient elementary school and secondary school student population to support the placement of all participating graduate students, a partnership between a State educational agency, on behalf of 1 or more high-need local educational agencies, and 1 or more eligible graduate institutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2E77FE2169A4972A9F8449ACBDA4789"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-need local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>high-need local educational agency</term> means a local educational agency that—</text><subparagraph id="HB7978E068DAF46A0BA11DF02853B6F1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is described in section 200(10) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1021">20 U.S.C. 1021(10)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1748A32135D43719239352CABB7E62E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of the date of application for a grant under this title, has ratios of school counselors, school social workers, and school psychologists to students served by the agency that are not more than 1 school counselor per 250 students, not more than 1 school psychologist per 500 students, and not more than 1 school social worker per 250 students.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAF31FAB849B4A6DB0B2F82303B8D8B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Historically Black college or university</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>historically Black college or university</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36E3CF49D33D464AAA8232814DF26729"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Homeless children and youths</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>homeless children and youths</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 725 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11434a">42 U.S.C. 11434a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4A435A0D4A44B3AA3DD31DEA50BD93E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indian tribe; Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the terms <quote>Indian tribe</quote> and <quote>tribal organization</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD308BAED2B5049588F742874F796A6FF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB052DEAA02154D57BA417364D0697F4D"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB6E068B8CAD42E1B73B80C3F57514DA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>minority-serving institution</quote> means, as defined in section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>), a Hispanic-serving institution, an Alaska Native-serving institution or a Native Hawaiian-serving institution, a Predominantly Black Institution, an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, or a Native American-serving nontribal institution. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BD6DEF8067F498BBA6C93E865DCBEDD"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Outlying area</header><text>The term <quote>outlying area</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 8101(36)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(36)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBBF5C294E54094A1AF3AC0C364DF5F"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Participating eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>participating eligible institution</term> means an eligible institution that is part of an eligible partnership awarded a grant under section 203.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22F641815C8040A38F3818833A123287"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Participating graduate</header><text>The term <term>participating graduate</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H30856E9E76FD48A79707393A54E139B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has received a master’s or other graduate degree in a school-based mental health field from a participating eligible institution and has obtained a State license or credential in the school-based mental health field; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7A96D40C9914CBB8592A259A15741EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as a graduate student pursuing a career in a school-based mental health field, was placed in a school served by a participating high-need local educational agency to complete required field work, credit hours, internships, or related training as applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC401FD4FFC34E34A576F96A05456FDE"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Participating high-need local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>participating high-need local educational agency</term> means a high-need local educational agency that is part of an eligible partnership awarded a grant under section 203.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H793D3E10B9734484B183E4538D0098D2"><enum>(15)</enum><header>School-based mental health field</header><text>The term <term>school-based mental health field</term> means each of the following fields:</text><subparagraph id="H487DC3FA0489445EA8145E50B4A18C91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>School counseling.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BECFEC73AFF44FA9D10437086C70128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>School social work.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H190B5510B1364AB3ADCE7DD185FF323A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>School psychology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1BB6F108FFB4820827920297E3FABA1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any other field of study that leads to employment as a school-based mental health services provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BEA92EB1F7A46A8801BF2F4D1CBBBAA"><enum>(16)</enum><header>School-based mental health services provider</header><text>The term <term>school-based mental health services provider</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7112">20 U.S.C. 7112</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF5ED28FF3224F969DFCB9254C8D718B"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF0718DC956346A4AFD99DF6959A483B"><enum>(18)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87BCADE809CA41CA8DDCDEEE9E7D985C"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Student support personnel target ratios</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>student support personnel target ratios</term> means the ratios of school-based mental health services providers to students recommended to enable such personnel to effectively address the needs of students, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1AF396DDC2E44498A43D811C39F48A24"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 school counselor for every 250 students (as recommended by the American School Counselor Association and American Counseling Association);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6E5CEE9103E42469359B225DE05AD79"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 school psychologist for every 500 students (as recommended by the National Association of School Psychologists); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H729BB0B6D89C4C7DAFE7CCA9425A5F4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 school social worker for every 250 students (as recommended by the School Social Work Association of America).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2471A7B96AA44AB4A90A1653BD99B1BD"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Tribally controlled college or university</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>tribally controlled college or university</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1801">25 U.S.C. 1801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3E0A19CECDF4CEA8A9D3B37F4A341CC"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Unaccompanied youth</header><text>The term <term>unaccompanied youth</term> has the meaning given such term in section 725 of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11434a">42 U.S.C. 11434a</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H09BD9F459D8B483BB01CF3F113CA8CC0"><enum>203.</enum><header>Grant program to increase the number of school-based mental health services providers serving in high-need local educational agencies</header><subsection id="HF5B5940528F9450A8BDCE7455189E416"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grants</header><paragraph id="H584E27627C1D4DF297298A2876DB9049"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts made available to carry out this section, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships, to enable the eligible partnerships to carry out pipeline programs to increase the number of school-based mental health services providers employed by high-need local educational agencies by carrying out any of the activities described in subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1EAB34B50314EF2B856D77A14868A02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the total amount appropriated under subsection (j) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text><subparagraph id="HCCF95324537442ECAB770D9A53704634"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for the Secretary of the Interior to carry out programs under this title in schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education, Indian tribes and tribal organizations, or a consortium of Indian tribes and tribal organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01D142C37C8C4EB2904E956FFB2D8D5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for allotments to outlying areas based on the relative need of each such area with respect to mental health services in schools, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with the purpose of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44455E628D964EE0B2CAADBCD9A27B26"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not more than 3 percent to conduct the evaluations under subsection (h); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2010994850FD47A3B07423F730CB8335"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent for the administration of the program under this title and to provide technical assistance relating to such program. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA57B3F4E59EF47E3ACF195B88D5CA935"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section shall be for a 5-year period and may be renewed for additional 5-year periods upon a showing of adequate progress, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4405BCDA2D64159914542FD67110636"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an eligible partnership shall submit to the Secretary a grant application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. At a minimum, such application shall include—</text><paragraph id="H2C8ABDE4D40447C4A1DFF2BB5519A65F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the existing (as of the date of application) ratios of school-based mental health services providers (in the aggregate and disaggregated by profession) to students enrolled in schools in each high-need local educational agency that is part of the eligible partnership; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E69FB562F574C2193D309706A57872B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a detailed description of—</text><subparagraph id="HEEC995B16F9B41A49ED6151F5CF7F37C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a plan to carry out a pipeline program to train, place, and retain school-based mental health services providers in high-need local educational agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB03A83298694FEA831F654560A2705A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the proposed allocation and use of grant funds to carry out activities described in subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEC367940D0941C890E86802A3A16084"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H7FE1F72984BB4CB4A358FDD0E45710E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that to the extent practicable, grants are distributed among eligible entities that will serve geographically diverse areas; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D648F603DD142ED95B1CB2A43998750"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give priority to eligible partnerships that—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64589B0AD4BE46D1A174B551B13D2661"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">propose to use the grant funds to carry out the activities described under paragraphs (1) through (3) of subsection (e) in schools that have higher numbers or percentages of low-income students (determined using any of the measures of poverty described in section 1113(a)(5) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6313">20 U.S.C. 6313(a)(5)</external-xref>)), in comparison to other schools that are served by the high-need local educational agency that is part of the eligible partnership;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65F47F74DF0C4DD5831878AD2E4B8BC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include 1 or more high-need local educational agencies that have fewer school-based mental health services providers, in the aggregate or for a particular school-based mental health field, per student than other eligible partnerships;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H227A8B04B9A649A5AAA9C9E01E41DCC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include 1 or more eligible institutions of higher education which are a historically Black college or university, a minority-serving institution, or a tribally controlled college or university;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD7FE335209284FE3AFA2B718614BD548"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">propose to collaborate with other institutions of higher education with similar programs, including sharing facilities, faculty members, and administrative costs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8A70450C8E148A9B83E8A5AE943A30E"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">propose to use grant funds to increase the diversity of school-based mental health services providers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD266B3BDE2A1495192971F401BC074E5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grant funds awarded under this section may be used—</text><paragraph id="HF86C8CD164A842479F8B6ECCCF041608"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to pay the administrative costs (including supplies, office and classroom space, supervision, mentoring, and transportation stipends as necessary and appropriate) related to—</text><subparagraph id="H769F6016DA594A5B9A7CD4E2EF1EBC8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>having graduate students of programs in school-based mental health fields placed in schools served by participating high-need local educational agencies to complete required field work, credit hours, internships, or related training as applicable for the degree, license, or credential program of each such student; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3249D8B14C147EA9FB2176D1F650F2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering required graduate coursework for students of a graduate program in a school-based mental health services field on the site of a participating high-need local educational agency;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C2FE2F48CB542C0A11ED33DBF591B2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for not more than the first 3 years after a participating graduate receives a master's or other graduate degree from a program in a school-based mental health field, or obtains a State license or credential in a school-based mental health field, to hire and pay all or part of the salary of the participating graduates working as a school-based mental health services provider in a school served by a participating high-need local educational agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DC387C9FFA04892BAC123BAD68D97A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase the number of school-based mental health services providers per student in schools served by participating high-need local educational agencies, in order to meet the student support personnel target ratios;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HEAEF9DA6E8314C10B26DA03F49D04DDF"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to recruit, hire, and retain culturally or linguistically under-represented graduate students of programs in school-based mental health fields for placement in schools served by participating low-income educational agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4728254CEDE4E07B0345067761905D2"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop coursework that will—</text><subparagraph id="H47A35413126D4886AA698A30E1EE59E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourage a commitment by graduate students in school-based mental health fields to work for high-need local educational agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA43EE428FD004B05AA13C035F1A46551"><enum>(B)</enum><text>give participating graduates the knowledge and skill sets necessary to meet the needs of—</text><clause id="HD055F89DE34A494ABAB2859A175FE109"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">students and families served by high-need local educational agencies;</text></clause><clause id="H698C4C53DEB24186A179BB500B6A7387"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>students at risk of not meeting State academic standards;</text></clause><clause id="H5C9A554FAE89470C9C7165B2A687AA62"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>students who—</text><subclause id="H6A2B1D384E8B469FA9409FA08A36F52A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are English learners (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="H813F46C68EEE4AA8B33004085D3CB33A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are migratory children (as defined in section 1309 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6399">20 U.S.C. 6399</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="H30294F20BE7945D092238738588072FF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>have a parent or caregiver who is a member of the armed forces, including the National Guard, who has been deployed or returned from deployment;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC0CCB090C11644B9ACB14E1EF4ECAE15"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>are LGBTQ+, including students who are lesbian, gay, bisexual, transgender, queer or questioning, nonbinary, or Two-Spirit;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCC70AEDDB7204B9D8598603928A46A03"><enum>(V)</enum><text>are homeless children and youth, including unaccompanied youth;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDBEFE7D0CA094ECBB23DD07622C5E45C"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>have come into contact with the juvenile justice system or adult criminal justice system, including students currently or previously held in juvenile detention facilities or adult jails and students currently or previously held in juvenile correctional facilities or adult prisons;</text></subclause><subclause id="H980DF70121ED42D781C78D9707F8497D"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>are a child with a disability (as defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>));</text></subclause><subclause id="H5A0AF10668F84287B5C0D902DC2D4672"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>have been a victim to, or witnessed, domestic violence or violence in their community;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA1F5B473C3B74BCEA9AEFB774B567E05"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>have been exposed to substance misuse at home or in the community;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4915D1C6CBF5453C9EB680BD7D8A283A"><enum>(X)</enum><text>are in foster care, are aging out of foster care, or were formerly in foster care; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H4B22DC7FF8AF405EAA74CA140B4141BC"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>have been a victim to or witnessed trafficking in persons; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H334E46B4038A4DAA81EA46D1F80EE838"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>teachers, administrators, and other staff who work for high-need local educational agencies; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H51DDDFD1F27B4A1FAFCAAD7768022F8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilize best practices determined by the American School Counselor Association, National Association of Social Workers, School Social Work Association of America, and National Association of School Psychologists and other relevant organizations;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F76ED19144D46D5A521145A31684CC3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide tuition credits to graduate students participating in the pipeline program supported under the grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H732B0AECD5224E8892F805EFDA0925B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fund high-quality <quote>Grow Your Own</quote> teacher preparation programs that provide pathways to State licensure or certification as a school psychologist, school counselor, school social worker, or other school-based mental services provider to recruit and prepare local community members, career changers, paraprofessionals, after-school program staff, and others currently working in schools to become school-based mental health services providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCEA916BEF354AEE974CCB2520DE05DB"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to cover the costs of licensure and preparation for required licensure exams; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1578EDC5F8D40779857C43401E51EDF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>for similar activities to fulfill the purpose of this title, as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3596998D64704788BD1BB6383E40C7CF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds made available under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant, other Federal, State, or local funds available for the activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6A1B25D8DCA74892A21557BED5BC5E08"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="H3CED3E83EE394D258C42448531DE3B32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section shall prepare and submit to the Secretary an annual report on the progress of the eligible partnership in carrying out the grant. Such report shall contain such information as the Secretary may require, including, at a minimum, a description of—</text><subparagraph id="H5EA24DEFACF94525B7FE3403DAD8A860"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actual service delivery provided through the grant funds, including—</text><clause id="HDBA24A41C8EE4875AB3328AF6C4978D1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>characteristics of the participating eligible graduate institution, including descriptive information on the educational model used and the actual academic program performance;</text></clause><clause id="HE33359A5671640A1861B8C7A812C1D5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>characteristics of graduate students participating in the pipeline program supported under the grant, including—</text><subclause id="HD1E47D87D64A4FC384A5740529745AAF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>performance on any examinations required by the State for credentialing or licensing;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC551E0D1333548BA98E050887C485095"><enum>(II)</enum><text>demographic characteristics; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H06E5C530859B4E36ABAC740F2BFCF8A1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>graduate student retention rates;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCF4BD1E26ACF44BEA54B694B835DADD8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>characteristics of students of the participating high-need local educational agency, including performance on any tests required by the State educational agency, demographic characteristics, and graduation rates, as appropriate;</text></clause><clause id="H59E3A881776C49E5952A2D478E8AB082"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an estimate of the annual implementation costs of the pipeline program supported under the grant; and</text></clause><clause id="H1CA08900E8254126A753DA739FBCA75D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number of public elementary and secondary school students, public elementary and secondary schools, graduate students, and institutions of higher education participating in the pipeline program supported under the grant;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H825A2BDF82824D789DF179588FBC4EFD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>outcomes that are consistent with the purpose of the grant program under this title, including—</text><clause id="H4947D86216AB4C7EBEE3DDEF87A5FC58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>internship and post-graduation placement of the participating graduate students;</text></clause><clause id="HFF2A8D979CE449E8A3489DCD6EABD180"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>graduation and professional career readiness indicators; and</text></clause><clause id="H34936C412C1F45AABFA74FF3786C5C9E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">characteristics of the participating high-need local educational agency, including with respect to fully certified and effective teachers and school-based mental health services providers employed by such agency—</text><subclause id="H5EDBFA2255C54657AF4347CADAE5725E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>changes in the rate of hiring and retention of such teachers and providers (in the aggregate and disaggregated by each such profession); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H181A961368F94A329C4090B3E87390AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the demographics, including the race, ethnicity, and gender, of such teachers and providers.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74A6E3363D6A4CBEB9B8656F3CFC765A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the instruction, materials, and activities being funded under the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82B23B3087D24D389EF7A4AD937441D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the effectiveness of any training and ongoing professional development provided—</text><clause id="HB0D925C0A2F648F882EA0CF9D5078C24"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to students and faculty in the appropriate departments or schools of the participating eligible graduate institution;</text></clause><clause id="H20A25BE9E9574118A075209F260EF81D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to the faculty, administration, and staff of the participating high-need local educational agency; and</text></clause><clause id="H2D6B157F1440490484B54D13AED8521D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the broader community of providers of social, emotional, behavioral, and related support to students and to those individuals who train such providers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28DA486B504F4CC7930F17E99AD63962"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary shall publish the annual reports submitted under paragraph (1) on the website of the Department of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35C29DB0F49F4BB68FD208F5801DB932"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Evaluations</header><paragraph id="H41EBCB2B63E54B87992DF2AB12AB0974"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim evaluations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may conduct interim evaluations to determine whether each eligible partnership receiving a grant under this section is making adequate progress as the Secretary considers appropriate. The contents of the annual report submitted to the Secretary under subsection (g) may be used by the Secretary to determine whether an eligible partnership receiving a grant is demonstrating adequate progress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58BB1B52ECB547699B2BE99B321EBD7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a final evaluation to—</text><subparagraph id="HA242CAB0503542BD927FC77B2BA3FD00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine the effectiveness of the grant program in carrying out the purpose of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFE87853DA66442DBB1A8D507F6BD57D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>compare the relative effectiveness of each of the various activities described in subsection (e) for which grant funds may be used.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99F425A8FCCB4B9291B96D84C39ABFA4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not earlier than 5 years, nor later than 6 years, after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report containing—</text><paragraph id="H7B32DE5EA7904F36898B3526686EF171"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the findings of the final evaluation conducted under subsection (h)(2); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H033BB15FAF654B9586EB534BA65F8AD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such recommendations as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9715BA0C3D924166A8934515E403296B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $200,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H326863C416874EFB99751E97A77EB1C5"><enum>III</enum><header>Elementary and Secondary School Counseling Act</header><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H0EE86403C6374A0DB82C30C945846C11"><enum>301.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Elementary and Secondary School Counseling Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9DF25F3DD42342478D3AC570F1AE3F55"><enum>302.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HEAE7941BDDDD4BF1AC501C3FA12378D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA Definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, and <term>secondary school</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H900973781BC64FDFBD50D0BAA488653E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High-need school</header><text>The term <term>high-need school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2211(b) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6631">20 U.S.C. 6631(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D55420ED4942568348AD4E9D7134F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Outlying area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>outlying area</quote> means an outlying area specified in section 8101(36)(A) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(36)(A)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2EEF7FF03174600ADA634E135E1BC95"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School-based mental health services provider</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>school-based mental health services provider</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7112">20 U.S.C. 7112</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF671228EA7D453FAE5EDDFD53475239"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E6CC484B784FA785C2541DF6E04D0F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF643B4E442534F1C8CBE94AB7BD817EC"><enum>303.</enum><header>Allotments to States and subgrants to local educational agencies</header><subsection commented="no" id="H3BB51302C5604BDD8019BEE899C0C153"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allotments to States, in accordance with subsection (c), to enable the States to award subgrants to local educational agencies in order to increase access to school-based mental health services providers at high-need schools served by the local educational agencies.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF8E0588FE0704596B5376120A7774C9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>From the total amount made available under section 304 for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text><paragraph id="HD14CCACD360549A389566C33BAFD3550"><enum>(1)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for the Secretary of the Interior for programs under this title in schools operated or funded by the Bureau of Indian Education, Indian tribes and tribal organizations, or consortia of Indian tribes and tribal organizations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B343A5B1FF04EABB7124E95D374545C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>one-half of 1 percent for allotments for the outlying areas to be distributed among those outlying areas on the basis of their relative need, as determined by the Secretary, in accordance with the purpose of this title; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H017807AD9F5647BB979985E054147A19"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent for the administration of the program under this title and to provide technical assistance relating to such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H10E62663685F4CC2B8527DB209AAA77B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allotments to States</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H32858BA4E29444D29A64F8877EC066DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC03A68A33DE9425DBFBE3F89CB49268E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>From the total amount made available under section 304 for a fiscal year and not reserved under subsection (b), the Secretary shall allot to each State that submits a true and complete application under paragraph (3) (as determined by the Secretary) an amount that bears the same relationship to such total amount as the amount received under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) by such State for such fiscal year bears to the amount received under such part for such fiscal year by all States that submit such applications.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE50268A67E244991ADD12401E2891A5E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Small state minimum</header><text>No State receiving an allotment under this paragraph shall receive less than one-half of 1 percent of the total amount allotted under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H733189C6BBCD4F73BE552179E4067FD2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matching requirements</header><text>In order to receive an allotment under paragraph (1), a State shall agree to provide matching funds, in an amount equal to 20 percent of the amount of the allotment, toward the costs of the activities carried out with the allotment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27F413C8231F4F0E8CFAB5352EA4CCAF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A State desiring an allotment under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. Each application shall include, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="HA321CD6C14CA4A3486C011FD417A4FCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that the State will use the allotment only for the purposes specified in subsection (d)(1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H236C1E34B5F249C284E887E4C0CB219E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the State will award subgrants to local educational agencies under such subsection;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H357C407A233C444988B31CB5515D9F30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the State will disseminate, in a timely manner, information regarding the subgrants and the application process for such subgrants to local educational agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0FAE506061941C5AF9A822224B9A49C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the ratios, as of the date of application, of students to school-based mental health services providers in each public elementary school and secondary school in the State, in the aggregate and disaggregated to include—</text><clause id="H95BE2BFAE2C94834A1EE92FAA4F76FC6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the ratios of students to school counselors, school psychologists, and school social workers; and</text></clause><clause id="HE03DA5EEDD5145D989705C53450E6878"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as applicable, the ratios of students to other school-based mental health services providers not described in clause (i), in the aggregate and disaggregated by type of provider.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4D06AC0FD5048FFA70CA796CB4A3DF7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>An allotment to a State under paragraph (1) shall be for a 5-year period and may be renewed for additional 5-year periods upon a showing of adequate progress on meeting the goals of the program under this title, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABD73F2006B74BAF99B5638C658280EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subgrants to local educational agencies</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H387D7F294040421EBA85844AF1A5A7FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State receiving an allotment under subsection (c) shall use the allotment to award subgrants, on a competitive basis, to local educational agencies in the State, to enable the local educational agencies to—</text><subparagraph id="HB4EF82B1A210479AB7A36EE63B1123AA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recruit and retain school-based mental health services providers to work at high-need schools served by the local educational agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49524921738942239F986DA74D44C2E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work toward effectively staffing the high-need schools of the local educational agency with school-based mental health services providers, including by meeting the recommended maximum ratios of—</text><clause id="HEFEDFDFC283E4973A439541F5980381A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>250 students per school counselor;</text></clause><clause id="HA744C7684D4948BB8071BED6EF4E40B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>500 students per school psychologist; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B2EE7A5763C4B65AB8814DC19DC4C50" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>250 students per school social worker.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HECD69EEEE03546E998B7F9479E78F26F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding subgrants under this subsection, the State shall give priority to local educational agencies that serve a significant number of high-need schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1FEB4AE12F5643B49D639BE867D17243"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency desiring a subgrant under this subsection shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require, including information on how the local educational agency will prioritize assisting high-need schools with the largest numbers or percentages of students from low-income families (as counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C6E182B14D54308B3F1B5374C6EA6CA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Allotment and subgrant requirements</header><paragraph id="H14500BD912424793B3FA54E6B62159F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Amounts received from an allotment under subsection (c) or a subgrant under subsection (d) shall supplement, and not supplant, any other funds available to a State or local educational agency for school-based mental health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3056F2FC4687495E879A2178D196827D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Combining funds allowed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency receiving a subgrant under subsection (d) may combine such subgrant with State or local funds to carry out the activities described in subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D77E3EE634A4F3DB6AA947A48BA8E81"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="HEDEAD6486558439E96E7A7739A57896A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agencies</header><text>A local educational agency that receives a subgrant under subsection (d) shall submit an annual report to the State on the activities carried out with the subgrant funds. Each such report shall—</text><subparagraph id="H626EFFAD0ECF41A5ACB9CCF92E365866"><enum>(A)</enum><text>describe the activities carried out using subgrant funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE400A2CA986E434B9F9272A075583271"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enumerate the number of school-based mental health services providers (in the aggregate and disaggregated by profession) who—</text><clause id="H5B69BF2E13D3495CB02FF1A44B1201B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>were employed by or otherwise served in high-need public elementary and secondary schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency over the year covered by the report; and</text></clause><clause id="HCC1046F03B5647EC9121489B07657998"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>were supported with funds from the subgrant or matching funds during such year; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E9E6B2FE16E48EB9BEE001857E6DD6D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include the most recent student to provider ratios, in the aggregate and disaggregated as provided in subsection (c)(3)(D), for high-need schools under the jurisdiction of the local educational agency that were supported with the subgrant or matching funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01142D64A79649ECBA689ACD432DB581"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>A State receiving an allotment under subsection (c) shall annually prepare and submit a report to the Secretary that—</text><subparagraph id="HDD6B33AEF98A46669FE3E91D351945F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluates the progress made in achieving the purposes of the program under this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE4CD25B46F486F82D6E3645F9A708C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the most recent student to provider ratios, in the aggregate and disaggregated as provided in subsection (c)(3)(D), for high-need schools in the State that were assisted with subgrants under subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA39EA0E4C5A941A7A9819B9873DEB558"><enum>(C)</enum><text>describes any other resources needed to meet the required recommended maximum student to school-based mental health services provider ratios.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8942D17B8AB64D5487C331B9D4EBE8C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make all reports submitted under this subsection available to the public, including through the website of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF11AC34DC7E44AC9812129523D228DEF"><enum>304.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this title—</text><paragraph id="H4269F93193ED43B99508FF696AEE2E07"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2023; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE76A2EBDA83495D94B04D426AACA415"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H927775C983AE4D0AA572BFB5C65EB0E0"><enum>IV</enum><header>Supporting Trauma-Informed Education Practices Act</header><section id="H43A075599E414AD29A7ABB8B9CCAC1A3" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Trauma-Informed Education Practices Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA058E0C5D34C4B27BFD23910E8C9C4B0"><enum>402.</enum><header>Amendment to the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7134 of the SUPPORT for Patients and Communities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280h-7">42 U.S.C. 280h-7</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H882E095C9F73490F91492455AA3AAFB1"><section id="H708D12029206470B85F31DFCBC86D0B2"><enum>7134.</enum><header>Grants to improve trauma support services and mental health care for children and youth in educational settings</header><subsection id="H46F6B4F83B8C41E2B2BABC738B04831A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization of grants</header><paragraph id="HB563385C95954D77B4243377421C73C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, is authorized to award grants to, or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements with, an eligible entity for the purpose of increasing student, teacher, school leader, and other school personnel access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health services by developing innovative initiatives, activities, or programs to connect schools and local educational agencies, or tribal educational agencies, as applicable, with community trauma-informed support and mental health systems, including such systems under the Indian Health Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC71FAD7F2F347BB8CFC6C6E40B6E4AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reservations</header><text>From the total amount appropriated under subsection (l) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text><subparagraph id="HDE91ABB70924422BBEA55851FBE6D4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not more than 3 percent to conduct the evaluation under subsection (f); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABDB9D095A4A40E2B2374F56F99F1182"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent for technical assistance and administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE898C9057D504E1892BC439A8D0CDF83"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>With respect to a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement awarded or entered into under this section, the period during which payments under such grant, contract or agreement are made to the recipient may not exceed 5 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCCA38F95C38F49179D940B5C98E0229E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity that receives or enters into a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section shall use amounts made available through such grant, contract, or cooperative agreement for evidence-based initiatives, activities, or programs, which shall include at least 1 of the following:</text><paragraph id="H3EADA08708074119BF40078F54A35BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Enhancing, improving, or developing collaborative efforts between schools, local educational agencies or tribal educational agencies, as applicable, and community mental health and trauma-informed service delivery systems to provide, develop, or improve prevention, referral, treatment, and support services to students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90F4FB2046A6497881DD7EC430E0BC3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing trauma-informed models of support, including positive behavioral interventions and supports in schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA32DFDB125A1499ABFC940DA5AF77783"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing professional development to teachers, paraprofessionals, school leaders, school-based mental health services providers, and other specialized instructional support personnel employed by local educational agencies or tribal educational agencies, as applicable or schools served by the eligible entity that—</text><subparagraph id="H0D30179EA7954381A2EDB7E98A5064A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fosters safe and stable learning environments that prevent and mitigate the effects of trauma, including through social and emotional learning;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0C22E89ED6C46C2B1DA09066AC6C251"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improves school capacity to identify, refer, and provide services to students in need of trauma-informed support or mental health services, including by helping educators to identify the unique personal and contextual variables that influence the manifestation of trauma; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC8E6EE5B2E14960B28102B20912AF80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reflects the best practices for trauma-informed identification, referral, and support developed by the Interagency Task Force on Trauma-Informed Care (as established by section 7132).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCB76B86AD99448A8080442E2166D6A9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing trauma-informed support services and mental health services to students at full-service community schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF5C99592BA04CDFA6C0808AE4F2E734"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Engaging families and communities to increase awareness of child and youth trauma, which may include sharing best practices with law enforcement regarding trauma-informed services and working with mental health professionals to provide interventions and longer term coordinated care within the community for children and youth who have experienced trauma and the families of such children and youth.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H085DFD244F36418D8E43878F05F61F69"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Evaluating the effectiveness of the initiatives, activities, or programs carried out under this section in increasing student access to evidence-based trauma support services and mental health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD80BCAC498604653BC3B02AD7DF4CA51" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Establishing partnerships with or providing subgrants to early childhood education programs or other eligible entities, to include such entities in the evidence-based trauma-informed or mental health initiatives, activities, and support services established under this section in order to provide, develop, or improve prevention, referral, treatment, and support services to children and their families.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC958BBA9D700428DBA51FAF597D109C8"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Establishing new, or enhancing existing, evidence-based educational, awareness, and prevention programs to improve mental health and resiliency among teachers, paraprofessionals, school leaders, school-based mental health services providers, and other specialized instructional support personnel employed by local educational agencies or tribal educational agencies, as applicable, or schools served by the eligible entity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEE69AEEF25C449181586436C5C3944D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HC6ED494A09914BA2B31C7FB6A97D9EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the innovative initiatives, activities, or programs to be funded under the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement, including how such initiatives, activities, or programs will increase access to evidence-based trauma-informed support services and mental health services for students, and, as applicable, the families of such students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7997879AB9E54B6F90B2A71C283514A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the initiatives, activities, or programs will provide linguistically appropriate and culturally competent services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19BAA53EBDA84254921B528D110C5209"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the initiatives, activities, or programs will support schools served by the eligible entity in improving school climate in order to support an environment conducive to learning.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H917D67E4833148C2ADCC7773FBE21539"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assurance that—</text><subparagraph id="H9E112FFC9AAE4B0E8163E32CB5A7B9C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>persons providing services under the initiative, activity, or program funded by the grant, contract, or cooperative agreement are fully licensed or certified to provide such services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38118D00512C49CBA5CAE1AE2261E5B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>teachers, school leaders, administrators, school-based mental health services providers and other specialized instructional support personnel, representatives of local Indian Tribes or tribal organizations as appropriate, other school personnel, individuals who have experience receiving mental health services as children, and parents of students participating in services under this section will be engaged and involved in the design and implementation of the services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01F314177F744C01913E1123F0BEA737"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the eligible entity will comply with the evaluation required under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H102155D25C0543E293AFE1BAE136363D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will support and integrate existing school-based services at schools served by the eligible entity with the initiatives, activities, or programs funded under this section in order to provide trauma-informed support services or mental health services for students, as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD19A58D773E4C2CA921E368FC175379"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will incorporate peer support services into the initiatives, activities, or programs to be funded under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E57D3310BEE4BE3B6913936973AC8FC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of how the eligible entity will ensure that initiatives, activities, or programs funded under this section are accessible to and include students with disabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA503C841290C435DBBE875F1D78CA22A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>An assurance that the eligible entity will establish a local interagency agreement under subsection (e) and comply with such agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC783F980A3244D7DA8C35724EBA254E1" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Interagency agreements</header><paragraph id="H8BE49D5224DE4928A5F0C3A0838ECD60" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local interagency agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out an evidence-based initiative, activity, or program described in subsection (c), an eligible entity that receives a grant, contract, or cooperative agreement under this section, or a designee of such entity, shall establish an interagency agreement between local educational agencies, agencies responsible for early childhood education programs, Head Start agencies (including Early Head Start agencies), juvenile justice authorities, mental health agencies, child welfare agencies, and other relevant agencies, authorities, or entities in the community that will be involved in the provision of services under such initiative, activity, or program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A7B4B1C3F44D578A9C7D9443C4A868" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The local interagency agreement required under paragraph (1) shall specify, with respect to each agency, authority, or entity that is a party to such agreement—</text><subparagraph id="H81A443402DAA4F199E5B989E3F800BA3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the financial responsibility for any services provided by such entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H447D131522A4461DB75D63DEFF901F18" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the conditions and terms of responsibility for such any services, including quality, accountability, and coordination of the services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18180E54A7E44FC39B9E78522B380E60" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the conditions and terms of reimbursement of such agencies, authorities, or entities, including procedures for dispute resolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H54DBDA5FD0EE4B9EA5408BAB14BE6556"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct a rigorous and independent evaluation of the initiatives, activities, and programs carried out by an eligible entity under this section and disseminate evidence-based practices regarding trauma-informed support services and mental health services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4DC978AEE9464D77B4328BF5FDB7B014"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Distribution of awards</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements awarded or entered into under this section are equitably distributed among the geographical regions of the United States and among tribal, urban, suburban, and rural populations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H19F2761BBB7946B1AE53AA6982F28AC3"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed—</text><paragraph id="HA01F9DA8DE6645FAB63740B7508FF85C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prohibit an entity involved with an initiative, activity, or program carried out under this section from reporting a crime that is committed by a student to appropriate authorities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8358199DC92146DE9F7A8109735AC83C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent Federal, State, local, and tribal law enforcement and judicial authorities from exercising their responsibilities with regard to the application of Federal, State, local, and tribal law to crimes committed by a student.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9815E203F8374F50B8E6E1DF82DDC474"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, and not supplant, other Federal, State, or local funds available to carry out the initiatives, activities, and programs described in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C6B65F998E249E3A2B1D56F0F273234"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Consultation required</header><text>In awarding or entering into grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements under this section, the Secretary shall, in a timely manner, meaningfully consult with Indian Tribes, Regional Corporations, Native Hawaiian Educational Organizations, and their representatives to ensure notice of eligibility.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36AF6DD83BB5447F85E30AE8B2175110"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H691A5A6E3F8540C89279A96A82EDD955"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Early childhood education program</header><text>The term <term>early childhood education program</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CB1AF1145E44168BFB2A42E29FF07DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H86A043C6B2ED497E814152EEB5BA49D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State educational agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BD4651BBE8D4E348604860FDE1F3C21"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a local educational agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C89009FB8D84F7D894D264A2554B425"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act) or their tribal educational agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DB57402198C4D51A6BFA6AB17898278"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Bureau of Indian Education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73B24E7341FD4160A5B0FE60684B47B9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a Regional Corporation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6740F5BB36834193B35EAF42EBE185E1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a Native Hawaiian educational organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F4C5E5AFF1D4C80AF5E67FFE15DBF69" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">State, Territory, and Tribal Lead Agencies administering the Child Care and Development Fund as described in section 658D(a) of the Child Care and Development Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9858b">42 U.S.C. 9858b(a)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEE9BA15E53E4DE189B2860F446BBECC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><subparagraph id="H255CA082020A4EF0AD9072D6F995A059"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>evidence-based</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>paraprofessional</term>, <term>parent</term>, <term>professional development</term>, <term>school leader</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, <term>specialized instructional support personnel</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82DA3154E1694F3991D177BF8AE21F37"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>full-service community school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4622 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7272">20 U.S.C. 7272</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1954D638F8F484B87604CD2BC39D77C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>Native Hawaiian educational organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 6207 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7517">20 U.S.C. 7517</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F1A151334C6403D942AA91A3A8944BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The term <term>school-based mental health services provider</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4102 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7112">20 U.S.C. 7112</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D53A24AACFC4102BC4A3FFE7CDBAB4D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional corporation</header><text>The term <term>Regional Corporation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1602">43 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H396558BAD9694C459AC1D0FAC0CD47E0"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School</header><text>The term <term>school</term> means a public elementary school or public secondary school.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E60981E975B498BBD4F709B49B74D7E"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="H87132182AFC94E819C93F24CFDA6B704"><enum>V</enum><header>Respond, Innovate, Succeed, and Empower</header><section id="HE34A2B1B77404D939C0FF8FEFF758A41"><enum>501.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Respond, Innovate, Succeed, and Empower Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RISE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2AA27A7284A94E98B1C0C3AC6FEAC7E5"><enum>502.</enum><header>Perfecting amendment to the definition of disability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103(6) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003(6)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 3(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3</quote>.</text></section><section id="H255DF0C2B9A74D6E97A49AAEB6A1D469"><enum>503.</enum><header>Supporting students with disabilities to succeed once enrolled in college</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE19DAA9E9A4F40B0912A38647F619C30"><paragraph id="H56CCCB5319A544FC91DF846E8F97853E"><enum>(30)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAED1AAFEF266435AB25FD365CCCADCD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The institution will carry out the following:</text><clause indent="up1" id="H85E36DAD90274FEC92FD9F4BA3240F0A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Adopt policies that make any of the following documentation submitted by an individual sufficient to establish that such individual is an individual with a disability:</text><subclause id="H3A411830360045579B30EADA53315B90"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Documentation that the individual has had an individualized education program (IEP) in accordance with section 614(d) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1414">20 U.S.C. 1414(d)</external-xref>), including an IEP that may not be current on the date of the determination that the individual has a disability. The institution may ask for additional documentation from an individual who had an IEP but who was subsequently evaluated and determined to be ineligible for services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act, including an individual determined to be ineligible during elementary school.</text></subclause><subclause id="HBD33FFFFB4D644A99EDD360385FBE56F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Documentation describing services or accommodations provided to the individual pursuant to section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as a <quote>Section 504 plan</quote>).</text></subclause><subclause id="H15BB31383A7B46B18A066C6DAD371154"><enum>(III)</enum><text>A plan or record of service for the individual from a private school, a local educational agency, a State educational agency, or an institution of higher education provided in accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="H3748277C97EA429D88E8DB813173ED14"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>A record or evaluation from a relevant licensed professional finding that the individual has a disability.</text></subclause><subclause id="HDEB44747DE9049CD8F394F5EAA234EFC"><enum>(V)</enum><text>A plan or record of disability from another institution of higher education.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6494AF71B4BE490C863CC44F8D91F0AE"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Documentation of a disability due to service in the uniformed services, as defined in section 484C(a).</text></subclause></clause><clause indent="up1" id="H21AEBD86113E46A093930298C8C5358D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Adopt policies that are transparent and explicit regarding information about the process by which the institution determines eligibility for accommodations.</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="H6426FEF2E19C4AE8BFC9E8702CDC32F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Disseminate such information to students, parents, and faculty in an accessible format, including during any student orientation and making such information readily available on a public website of the institution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="HF6B903D4FA01468C964AA943D60E817F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to preclude an institution from establishing less burdensome criteria than that described in subparagraph (A) to establish an individual as an individual with a disability and therefore eligible for accommodations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H7C565B9891CD474E9357E8AA1B14B8B6"><enum>504.</enum><header>Authorization of funds for the National Center for Information and Technical Support for Postsecondary Students With Disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 777(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140q">20 U.S.C. 1140q(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H16B5910FA1CE490CB82545944A6BF6C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>From amounts appropriated under section 778,</quote> and inserting <quote>From amounts appropriated under paragraph (5),</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ABF303503DA4F4DB990AA747DC60A36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H39182FD5A6E74D2DA0BB58B5A457BFDE"><paragraph id="H91E1CCB5F8EF4D28AA350160E425E3F4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE40AFF187A04434D96172C3CB2F3C27C"><enum>505.</enum><header>Inclusion of information on students with disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 503, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H87DAF22639B1410F8CA493B250D57969"><paragraph id="H648B2DE1A9E54B09850602C92042C774"><enum>(31)</enum><text>The institution will submit, for inclusion in the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System (IPEDS) or any other Federal postsecondary institution data collection effort, key data related to undergraduate students enrolled at the institution who are formally registered as students with disabilities with the institution’s office of disability services (or the equivalent office), including the total number of students with disabilities enrolled, the number of students accessing or receiving accommodations, the percentage of students with disabilities of all undergraduate students, and the total number of undergraduate certificates or degrees awarded to students with disabilities. An institution shall not be required to submit the information described in the preceding sentence if the number of such students would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H0DEB43F3F3C341D4A0EC115A18E39385"><enum>506.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the amendments made by this title shall be construed to affect the meaning of the terms <term>reasonable accommodation</term> or <term>record of impairment</term> under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) or the rights or remedies provided under such Act.</text></section></title><title id="H0A71239814C141D9AE7B2F10EAF3C495"><enum>VI</enum><header>Strengthening Behavioral Health Benefits</header><section id="HB02A731DA3D24CE390FF151134BCD132" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>601.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening Behavioral Health Benefits Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H3C7557BCAB87463A961D0E00C0335990"><enum>602.</enum><header>Enforcement of Mental Health and Substance Use Disorder Requirements</header><subsection id="H95E253BDD0CB4805911B4518CDC67084"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC3103907809B46D58AB59A34536265C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71EE15A28A914AF0867C7CA6313BD5ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (11), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DB138181427466F97E0B1292D1C7E92"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H561D5A4C99DB4128B354A4BB1FFF734A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H28EDAF39F98C44159E5C2529479D87A1"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any case relating to the provision of mental health benefits and substance use disorder benefits under a group health plan or under group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer in connection with a group health plan (as such terms are defined in section 733), by the Secretary, or by a participant, beneficiary, or fiduciary, to enforce any provision of this title or the terms of the plan or coverage relating to such benefits against a group health plan, a health insurance issuer, a fiduciary of a plan, or any other person that contracts with a group health plan to provide group health insurance coverage or assistance in the administration of a group health plan (including a third party administrator, managed behavioral health organization, and a pharmacy benefit manager), if such person participates in or conceals a violation of any requirement of part 7 relating to such benefits or a wrongful denial of a claim for mental health benefits or substance use disorder benefits under the terms of the plan or coverage, to obtain appropriate relief, in addition to any other relief otherwise available under this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="H466BD35F1F434CF58AAD86D7FB6717A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to recover all losses to participants and beneficiaries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AE6908BD0C64D7EA72CDC0D957DDBE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reform impermissible plan or coverage terms and policies (as written or in operation) in accordance with the requirements of this title and its implementing regulations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F97F853C8F94CBBB02E725A335949F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure the readjudication of claims and payment of benefits in accordance with the plan or coverage terms without any impermissible limitation, plan or coverage term, or policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE258016C7BE44730A914F53946EC2C61"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clarification of general enforcement authorities</header><paragraph id="H3A974CEB83504C4787D4860624CBAFB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Actions brought by a participant, beneficiary, or fiduciary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502(a)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H06F61F18420B416F9101872419196428"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>(B)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B1DDC43F3FB422D960A5418F652EB6A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, or (C) to require re-adjudication and payment of benefits to remedy violations of this title notwithstanding the availability of relief under other provisions of this title</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D13831F400E4CF896B9078E533862EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions brought by the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 502(a)(5) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(a)(5)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H06B0E8361C9D4E2BAE29788E2A82C24A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>or (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>(B)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6884D58614D34FDA96C83E6E002069D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, or (C) to require re-adjudication and payment of benefits to remedy violations of this title notwithstanding the availability of relief under other provisions of this title</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2EAE9257040E49E7AB03984867FFF395"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exception to the general prohibition on enforcement</header><text>Section 502(b)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H857036267CCB4C338DC0110A34166CA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and except with respect to enforcement by the Secretary of section 712 or any other provision of part 7 in any case relating to mental health benefits and substance use disorder benefits</quote> after <quote>under subsection (c)(9))</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3E03986BBA424699E98F36E5749CF3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>706(a)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>733(a)(1)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96EACF518E6640D1A7A80C88F5E154F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part 7 of title I of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1181">29 U.S.C. 1181 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0378A3F4F52144AC8352B4D72D665BC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 712(e), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and section 502(a)(12)</quote> after <quote>this section</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06F3AE34D2DD4FC8BABF68311E45A581"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 733—</text><subparagraph id="HE9081D739D9C4CF1821017139B868416"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and section 502(a)(12)</quote> after <quote>this part</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC49A5F39E8AD4343B46A7A3AF816A61A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by inserting <quote>and section 502(a)(12)</quote> after <quote>this part</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2594D736DAB458EA9B8FA34AE536955"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H914C6B8788B84DF0BD2F37F0ED2B6021"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated (out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated) to the Department of Labor for fiscal year 2023, to remain available until September 30, 2032, $275,000,000, of which—</text><subparagraph id="H3258E420E30742BC8D306E78AC212743"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$240,000,000 shall be for the Employee Benefits Security Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7A4622012BA4D9B87CB3F48EDB2EAAB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$35,000,000 shall be for the Solicitor of Labor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABEED24A1944438999F2CF5073513DA4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of appropriated funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available under paragraph (1) may be used for audits and investigations, enforcement actions, litigation expenses, issuance of regulations or guidance, and any other Departmental activities relating to section 712 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and any other provision of title I of such Act relating to mental health and substance use disorder benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H47A2C6C4CFC8445BBD624CBEEF243E9F"><enum>VII</enum><header>Employee and Retiree Access to Justice</header><section id="HD04FADACDB9A44CDB2AEC61D8FB25469" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>701.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This title may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Employee and Retiree Access to Justice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H864A66FAB7D242FB810F3921A2FBC277"><enum>702.</enum><header>Unenforceable arbitration clauses, class action waivers, representation waivers, and discretionary clauses</header><subsection id="H626D289EE09F4CFEAAD6E92E0CD3EB82"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 502 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H03C5584F9C8B4F2EB5D8A03B2D32BE50" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE090CFDC077F434ABC9F284ADF4CB75A"><enum>(n)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H624650D0968749DBB418FB8D610F4985"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In any civil action brought by, or on behalf of, a participant or beneficiary pursuant to this section or with respect to a common law claim involving a plan or plan benefit, notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text><subparagraph id="HC3705A3301994F3EAAD5657C4CBA4888" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no predispute arbitration provision shall be valid or enforceable if it requires arbitration of a matter related to a claim brought under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB58BD7C0FAA9442A98E2BB31BBA41184" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no postdispute arbitration provision shall be valid or enforceable unless—</text><clause id="H75CCD19015E24C39858DC050A28A6628"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the provision was not required by any person, obtained by coercion or threat of adverse action, or made a condition of participating in a plan, receiving benefits under a plan, or receiving any other employment, work, or any employment-related or work-related privilege or benefit;</text></clause><clause id="H1FFA2105953D47D4AFD017B9A2FF66A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each participant or beneficiary agreeing to the provision was informed, through a paper notice, in a manner reasonably calculated to be understood by the average plan participant, of the right of the participant or beneficiary under subparagraph (C) to refuse to agree to the provision without retaliation or threat of retaliation;</text></clause><clause id="H55C8AF79CB2E4E28BDEA84C127EF5507"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each participant or beneficiary agreeing to the provision so agreed after a waiting period of not fewer than 45 days, beginning on the date on which the participant or beneficiary was provided both the final text of the provision and the disclosures required under clause (ii); and</text></clause><clause id="H78F0E5AF65CB4AFD8B4469EE5206A1FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each participant or beneficiary agreeing to the provision affirmatively consented to the provision in writing;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H853636E973094833B43127CDEBB0DF9A" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>no covered provision shall be valid or enforceable, if prior to a dispute to which the covered provision applies, a participant or beneficiary undertakes or promises not to pursue, bring, join, litigate, or support any kind of individual, joint, class, representative, or collective claim available under this section in any forum that, but for such covered provision, is of competent jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B9CE213D79A474CBC7FD114E932F2C1" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no covered provision shall be valid or enforceable, if after a dispute to which the covered provision applies arises, a participant or beneficiary undertakes or promises not to pursue, bring, join, litigate, or support any kind of individual, joint, class, representative, or collective claim under this section in any forum that, but for such covered provision, is of competent jurisdiction, unless the covered provision meets the requirements of subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB448835725FF43C7863DB18EA518C6F1" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no covered provision related to a plan other than a multiemployer plan shall be valid or enforceable that purports to confer discretionary authority to any person with respect to benefit determinations or interpretation of plan language, or to provide a standard of review of such determinations or interpretation by a reviewing court in an action brought under this section that would require anything other than de novo review of such determinations or interpretation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H41ED149268E14D81BE58476C141DD72D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H5C36733B98AC4B49B19FC387084190BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered provision</quote> means any document, instrument, or agreement related to a plan or plan benefit, regardless of whether such provision appears in a plan document or in a separate agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H515B859A96C14D01B879F46FB39FB2CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>predispute arbitration provision</quote> means a covered provision that requires a participant or beneficiary to arbitrate a dispute related to the plan or an amendment to the plan that had not yet arisen at the time such provision took effect;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBBA83BB45784ED491A960542CB44A7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>postdispute arbitration provision</quote> means a covered provision that requires a participant or beneficiary to arbitrate a dispute related to the plan or an amendment to the plan that arose before the time such provision took effect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94706C43827D40F9B65EB4F69139ADFE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <quote>retaliation</quote> means any action in violation of section 510.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69AD77B9A40C48F8A4C3C159B8F536CE" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2C74BE0DF26A493290559823A3535CF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any dispute as to whether a covered provision that requires a participant or beneficiary to arbitrate a dispute related to a plan is valid and enforceable shall be determined by a court, rather than an arbitrator, regardless of whether any contractual provision purports to delegate such determinations to the arbitrator and irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52E83F9365B64E66A128541F45578909" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, a dispute shall be considered to arise only when a plaintiff has actual knowledge (within the meaning of such term in section 413) of a breach or violation giving rise to a claim under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9DDF8A5B32204DAFA53ABF7162798535"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the amendment made by subsection (a), including providing for the form and content of notices required pursuant to such amendment.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCA31D7D215CE4D5981327CF900FD6327"><enum>703.</enum><header>Prohibition on mandatory arbitration clauses, class action waivers, representation waivers, and discretionary clauses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1102">29 U.S.C. 1102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H8AB2537885B442A1A0808A6AFBC95A9F" style="OLC"><subsection id="HCF8642AAEBEC4B1388AE27EDD28BEF71"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC1D0558EF4944EF282302984D751E26A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No covered person may—</text><subparagraph id="H8A5440584D1F422DBA16FF8D9DD51F83" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require participants or beneficiaries to agree to a predispute arbitration provision as a condition for participation in, or receipt of benefits under, a plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22D9E354B0084A558C61C75CB3B9079B" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to a postdispute arbitration provision with a participant or beneficiary with respect to a plan or plan benefit unless the conditions of clauses (i) through (iv) of section 502(n)(1)(B) are satisfied with respect to such provision; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC218BE5F0E63441D893E8F512A6FD5DE" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>agree to any other covered provision with respect to a plan or plan benefit under any circumstances under which such provision would not be valid and enforceable under subparagraphs (C) through (E) section 502(n)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65A1EA2F9BF84D7E9D5CA003A4A7B260" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HA9A7A639C7794FC6B69DBD67AAF8B932"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered person</quote> means—</text><clause id="HE04A2D3FA15D460CB2B7EBE99FE6D8F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a plan;</text></clause><clause id="HFB476364104F452EBDD47B80A267E6DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a plan sponsor;</text></clause><clause id="HEE9405F70A944424BE0F932A93CF4B8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an employer; or</text></clause><clause id="H17770AC49620477F9647568631842547"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a person engaged by a plan for purposes of administering or operating the plan; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF1F5873FCFE474899785694F6C82C89"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <quote>covered provision</quote>, <quote>predispute arbitration provision</quote> and <quote>postdispute arbitration provision</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 502(n)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6FC8107EE2654B1B9F92E5B9DD09253A"><enum>704.</enum><header>Effective date</header><subsection id="H3A6CE9D6784348799FCD1F9CE9B23186"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by sections 702 and 703 shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to any dispute or claim that arises or accrues on or after such date, including any dispute or claim to which a provision predating such date applies, regardless of whether plan documents have been updated in accordance with such amendments.</text></subsection><subsection id="H514FF7FB7EBC4993A88EC3C34E79FF0B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement with respect to plan document updates</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no person shall be deemed to be in violation of such amendments on account of plan documents that have not been updated in accordance with such amendments until after the beginning of the first plan year that begins on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, provided that such person acts in accordance with such amendments during the period in which the plan documents have not been updated.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

