<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H54A6C5C2668C438593D1FA1B251E6968" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 HR 6715 IH: Bridging the Gap for New Americans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6715</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220211">February 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Labor to conduct a study of the factors affecting employment opportunities for immigrants and refugees with professional credentials obtained in foreign countries.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD767B903301C4C9A960797D9A1AF1B20" style="OLC"><section id="HB28BE350F540473DA07268543698B67B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bridging the Gap for New Americans Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB3F3E9AA21354620804BB69BBE1881CE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7AC17C5997904065B48E0139CE47C38B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable immigrants and refugees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable immigrants and refugees</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H18B0F23FE6F549BE8E5F04E52FFD269D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means individuals who—</text><clause id="HE4C7D57DFC394730A95204325729AD0D"><enum>(i)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA26121F55BB64B0AB8924D5F257A4996"><enum>(I)</enum><text>are not citizens or nationals of the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H9F6B12AC194A4F7EADC82D1970ACC97D" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>are lawfully present in the United States and authorized to be employed in the United States; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H83D76661F389416DBAC58B49BCB1DC66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>are naturalized citizens of the United States who were born outside of the United States and its outlying possessions; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC281891E2517477886545094AD61434D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes individuals described in section 602(b)(2) of the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (title VI of division F of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/8">Public Law 111–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB69F458FA60C44C7BC3E23E45292E60B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>Except as otherwise defined in this section, terms used in this Act have the definitions given such terms under section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5C7785E2906B4A998C53BA7B2B281308"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on factors affecting employment opportunities for immigrants and refugees with professional credentials obtained in foreign countries</header><subsection id="HD3EDCDEF16E74B68A0F314349110EA79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><paragraph id="H2459FF6DD8334D97BC463A4A85576636"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor, in coordination with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator of the Internal Revenue Service, and the Commissioner of the Social Security Administration, shall conduct a study of the factors affecting employment opportunities in the United States for applicable immigrants and refugees who have professional credentials that were obtained in a country other than the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F461D4B0F3C4C9895471747AEFFA01F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Work with other entities</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall seek to work with relevant nonprofit organizations and State agencies to use the existing data and resources of such entities to conduct the study required under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1BD445A6F34D9BB88A3D5492970CCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitations on disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any information provided to the Secretary of Labor in connection with the study required under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H3C9AA343070F40B2B7E273DE5373595B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only be used for the purposes of, and to the extent necessary to ensure the efficient operation of, such study; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CCB0E6DF162456793BF812273A05C32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not be disclosed to any other person or entity except as provided under this subsection. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC5FE742059346D89DA5E7C1BFF5CE10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The study required under subsection (a)(1) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HEDCB521692CA430499F11921A2414B65"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of the employment history of applicable immigrants and refugees admitted to the United States during the 5-year period immediately preceding the date of the enactment of this Act, which shall include, to the extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="HDEFE35A1826848609953637BA241A506"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a comparison of the employment applicable immigrants and refugees held before immigrating to the United States with the employment they obtained in the United States, if any, since their arrival; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76E52B34C2C141BA9F2DD4369E04303A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the occupational and professional credentials and academic degrees held by applicable immigrants and refugees before immigrating to the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H72D60E59085D4120871FD954C009ED96"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of any barriers that prevent applicable immigrants and refugees from using occupational experience obtained outside the United States to obtain employment in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3872DB7F36F846248304645E28BF4F5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an analysis of available public and private resources assisting applicable immigrants and refugees who have professional experience and qualifications obtained outside of the United States to obtain skill-appropriate employment in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H978444A0904A406681EDE24B5722BBF2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy recommendations for better enabling applicable immigrants and refugees who have professional experience and qualifications obtained outside of the United States to obtain skill-appropriate employment in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81E112BE09D7402D9A935EF5EB6C1E35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall—</text><paragraph id="H3D741010C7364C36B9EA38BA30FF4875"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit a report to Congress that describes the results of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H740B7E09BE0F41F4B32D1C0A8D045F33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such report publically available on the website of the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

