<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE03F6804506C475F980B1B3D0C485211" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8452 IH: Reproductive Health Travel Fund Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8452</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220720">July 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants to eligible entities to pay for travel-related expenses and logistical support for individuals with respect to accessing abortion services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3C63C15DDE8C494C977F030839372FC2" style="OLC"><section id="HC03B9D210D6143BBBD307B503489DF2E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reproductive Health Travel Fund Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H383700227DAD4B72B17F35F99144E038"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H293789B8EFB546B480C987B854617FE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On June 24, 2022, in its decision in Dobbs v. Jackson Women’s Health Organization, the Supreme Court overruled Roe v. Wade, reversing decades of precedent recognizing the constitutional right to terminate a pregnancy. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7127602C98C426D8788A804560D52BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The abortion access landscape was already strained. This decision will decimate access for millions of people in the United States. Roughly half of States are predicted to ban or severely restrict abortion in the coming months. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0EFFF5C3FC2447BB6E63103A72FAD9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The implications of this decision will fall hardest on people who already face barriers to health care access, particularly Black people, Indigenous people, and other people of color, people with disabilities, people in rural areas, young people, people with documentation barriers, and those having difficulty making ends meet.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F259434B8194B29B8D7C40FBC3B7926"><enum>(4)</enum><text>People have always had abortions and always will, even in the face of legal, financial, and logistical barriers, or criminalization. While some will self-manage their abortions, and have the option of using pills that are medically safe and effective, many others are traveling hundreds of miles out of State, or forced to carry pregnancies to term.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1E2D0DB59614B7094DC4DBE897FC328"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Abortion funds and practical support funds are community-based organizations that support people in overcoming financial and logistical barriers to abortion care. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A033E2A7E254582A28DF4ADCA2B90E2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Funds work together to remove financial and logistical barriers to abortion access and have been doing this work for years. Some of these barriers are, but are not limited to, transportation, food, lodging, childcare, translation, and doula services. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD810216B627A44F58F289BC396E7146E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Many funds are led by people who have had abortions themselves, including a growing base of Black and Brown leaders who have themselves faced abortion obstacles and understand the complex circumstances callers may face. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB650916F79FA42CDAF50137D965C6F7A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Abortion funds have a history of being underresourced and rely mostly on volunteer time and energy to support communities. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1CFFB56F26241F495B19E13FCCC9EF6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Abortion and practical support funds hold some of the closest ties to people who are having abortions and have the first-hand experience, up-to-date and on-the-ground knowledge, and the regional and national connections needed to support abortion seekers financially, emotionally, or logistically. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB39568FCD30949F4899D709B919D6806"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Clinics in States where abortion is legal and more accessible are receiving an influx of people seeking abortions. Provider shortages plus this rapid increase in patients will cause longer waits for appointments. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA09C1956C1C342E0AF74689E46DA09A2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>When people are not able to access an abortion when they need it, they are often pushed much further into pregnancy. This increases costs exponentially. For many, the increased financial burden will push abortion care completely out of reach. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE6E315C39546038BAF39B97121DA4B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>A rapidly changing access landscape, as bans are implemented and challenged, means that the window to access care in certain States may be limited. People who are put in a position where they must postpone their care due to financial or other constraints may face appointment cancellations due to overnight changes in legality. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H671D560B66D44D76B02DC7EA2A03F062"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Funds often work with each other if they cannot fully assist a caller, or if a caller is traveling across regions. A national network of almost 100 abortion and practical support funds has demonstrated these funds are uniquely positioned to lead in this moment and need support.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB0C93535971443DB891A8F74F0C53EA3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Grants to pay for travel expenses and logistical support for individuals accessing abortion services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254b">42 U.S.C. 254b et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H11171090B0704F40B6E5554F57903D2E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subpart id="H957D8623984B474A92C7B9CF34F4F23B"><enum>XIII</enum><header>Accessing abortion services</header><section id="H0D05E16345614CE19612E6083FAA91EF"><enum>340J.</enum><header>Grants to pay for travel expenses and logistical support for individuals accessing abortion services</header><subsection id="H6F26EFE9E03D460EABBC1A54AABE8BB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants to eligible entities to pay for travel-related expenses and logistical support for individuals with respect to accessing abortion services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H589769E043EE4382A95587720FB2D87E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall solicit applications for grants under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H16C31931130D4C2AB2E00BFE63F337B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H969D985DF2D84F41A4FA827A385AF76A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permissible uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant for travel-related expenses and logistical support for individuals with respect to accessing abortion services, which may include any of the following expenses and support:</text><subparagraph id="HABC398FA83424CB0A90333F1B6B892F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Round trip travel to the location where the abortion services are provided.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF4A19DB05244CB2BF3006907CE59684"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Lodging.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D8A16BC7114E40B0E11402D290E5CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Meals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C081C19FAFB4D80B75BDDCE928FC837"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Childcare.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A421107A0074AB6B9FB5CE81DBF281A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Translation services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB93F4E32B6A74460911E679A1C129AD2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Doula care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H077FF37B90A747F2831317AD957B5C42"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Patient education and information services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31D2A1414C84D90AFF0346EEAFA52AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Organizational costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section may use up to, but not more than, 15 percent of the grant funds to cover organizational costs such as—</text><subparagraph id="H54EFBCA9A19743E1A861FC0EC7C2E614"><enum>(A)</enum><text>community outreach efforts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0904F6F981DD456196A2C42626404C19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>physical infrastructure construction and maintenance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F4EA44BF0F04025AD95E6181D12F48B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>website development and maintenance; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H597B0AD82979426E8D0D8226CADFA098"><enum>(D)</enum><text>increasing staff capacity and training.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78E044D3956847B4876C3F0E78D62448"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Impermissible uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall not use the grant for costs of an abortion procedure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF312E41BE1E94A2DB198DC001147449D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To seek a grant under this section, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35877EAC52244F52A2867170ECF43510"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting the recipients of grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text><paragraph id="H4C7EE1C295DA452FB21B408E56446A4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve people who live in a jurisdiction that has banned or severely restricted access to abortion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D3FA62CA378473EB7CB1C5571BD2AF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve people who travel to a jurisdiction other than the one where they live to be provided abortion services; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFDD7585F630482CAB79A0FD2C184A89"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have a program in operation, or submit as part of the application required under subsection (d) a plan to establish and operate a program, to help patients access abortion services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAB250CC947E45C698E873B35D05B552"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><paragraph id="H4F7AF1489D31424989E090E3ABD2EF3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Congress a report on the program under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC074032741304FB78EE16864CF0BF87B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The reports under paragraph (1) shall not include any individually identifiable information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9F17C9D54CA1473C9D485B8BAC3AC1FF"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HBE5182590F7C4B27B9AE1A54B0675FEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HA6A3EEC1043844338356297FC15BD614"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a nonprofit organization, or a community-based organization, that assists individuals seeking an abortion through programs, services, or activities that are unbiased and medically and factually accurate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F514ECA16BF4D2D9FCFD52ACAE21EE8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes any entity that discourages individuals from seeking an abortion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC3D8E90CC684A889A5B0DEDFCE98080"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that—</text><subparagraph id="H8AFF822F9530494989E9B65721E44E58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is described in subsection (c)(3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CBDA9679B104A42AF8D249CD8E25479"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is, under subsection (a) of such section, exempt from taxation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F5055A638054643B5221CB38390EDAD"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $300,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section></subpart><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

