<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8AD67B1C43424994BC515467A9C983CE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9406 IH: Customs and Border Protection Crisis Hardship and Incentive Pay Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9406</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221202">December 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create a special pay incentive for Customs and Border Protection law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H28B3D6EC3AB849C4851FD729650BAFB5" style="OLC"><section id="H0503DCA58D5F493086B7D9409A277F1B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Customs and Border Protection Crisis Hardship and Incentive Pay Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7A974C0DB0304C51B275617E73C6598E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment and eligibility of hardship incentive pay program</header><subsection id="HAB1EBCD789B94B8DB7AAD59BFC23BEA7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Homeland Security, a covered employee shall be paid special pay under subsection (b) of this section for any day or portion of a day in which the covered employee—</text><paragraph id="H0CFEFEF8F0644BB4B7BA8A0FE3EB3BFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was on duty along a border in which an average of more than 1,000 aliens were encountered per day over a month long period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63CAEEF9C53D4321B289DF1EE30465A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was on duty in a sector in which more than 250 aliens were encountered per day;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H502C4BE680DD430289F07B67F93C0F83"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was on duty in a sector in which the covered employee was subject to the threat of physical harm or imminent danger on the basis of armed cartel presence; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C7C59C115844C08E7BE96C61D69D7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>was on duty in a sector in which fentanyl was encountered.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FE4E4E00FBE496D9991852286B3EE46"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special pay amount</header><paragraph id="H7ED8620194834E2EB26E3C8965A029B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (2), the amount of special pay authorized by subsection (a) for qualifying service during a day or portion of a day shall be the amount equal to <fraction>1/30</fraction> of the maximum amount of special pay payable to a covered employee as specified in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4265F7E6E3704FD889D9A7D0C0349419"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a covered employee who is subject to the threat of physical harm or imminent danger on the basis of armed cartel presence in or for a day or portion of a day, at the election of the Secretary, pay the covered employee special pay under subsection (a) for such service in an amount not to exceed the maximum amount specified in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE49989B17D934A4F827A5D5FF7F51C5B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The maximum amount of special pay payable to a covered employee under this subsection for any pay period is $250.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H934DE6E0FB4B4E4095484CC6B493E805"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continuation during hospitalization</header><paragraph id="HBA6A0FCFD6E845FD9625D678DBDCD696"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered employee described in paragraph (2) may be paid special pay under this section for any day (or portion of a day) of not more than three additional months during which the employee is hospitalized as described in such paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H967D9E90855D45A7BF9C04DC9E8DDCD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) applies with respect to a covered employee who—</text><subparagraph id="HC0A5E1C8A526494D9AD49813229782F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is injured or wounded under the circumstances described in subsection (a)(3) and is hospitalized for the treatment of the injury or wound; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FD5CB54ECC34EB58C86469916D0838D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>while in the line of duty, incurs a wound, injury, or illness in a sector designated by the Secretary of Homeland Security and is hospitalized outside of the sector for the treatment of the wound, injury, or illness.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD9E27E9E1F74DC48DD7C0A14BAD05A7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations and administration</header><paragraph id="H2A0B738D127742A08038E3666D49F4D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an area described in subsection (a)(1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall be responsible for designating the period during which duty in the area will qualify covered employees for special pay under this section. The effective date designated for the commencement of such a period may be a date occurring before, on, or after the actual date on which the Secretary makes the designation. If the commencement date for such a period is a date occurring before the date on which the Secretary makes the designation, the payment of special pay under this section for the period between the commencement date and the date on which the Secretary makes the designation shall be subject to the availability of appropriated funds for that purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H737EE74E932C4A19B1668C4CF0EAB8EC" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>In making the determination to designate a period of eligibility provided in paragraph (1), the Secretary shall review eligibility factors beginning from March 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49F2D6CD90A54B708986555D78548F51"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other matters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered employee—</text><subparagraph id="HDF4A2D7E72B445DB8D5B58A13D14B38D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may not be paid more than one instance of special pay under this section for any day; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF26C3783854C4572AE44E667964E8BB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be paid special pay under this section in addition to any other pay and allowances to which he may be entitled, and such special pay shall be considered basic pay under chapter 83 or 84 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF53FD78D10E14AD28713BF4EFAB0F862"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H34C45CA542B541F69EE9396960F9128B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>alien</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H305EF1EA97594F79B5D356FD0B1FB082"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered employee</quote> means an employee of U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigrations and Customs Enforcement whose primary duty is as a law enforcement officer; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC0EF43F780745A18AAB0E4C1D932E24"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>law enforcement officer</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 8401(17) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

