<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC33E33D5C6B4281BEE992A2E970D88F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8058 IH: Fighting Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8058</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Attorney General to propose a program for making treatment for post-traumatic stress disorder and acute stress disorder available to public safety officers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAF4AA72586BB442183B142FE22BE8F4F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5B0242E6EE1848D295492B17A51D5AB3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fighting Post-Traumatic Stress Disorder Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6FCCD3AFCD2A46EB98988C088D51DF61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE6FFB24236344E359037A470BEF2E2B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Public safety officers serve their communities with bravery and distinction in order to keep their communities safe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H112934630EF945968E593B057C42EB2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Public safety officers, including police officers, firefighters, emergency medical technicians, and 911 dispatchers, are on the front lines of dealing with situations that are stressful, graphic, harrowing, and life-threatening.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAE073316807405D95FEA53CFC9E58FC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The work of public safety officers puts them at risk for developing post-traumatic stress disorder and acute stress disorder.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBCC28916284D440BA31279826339182A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>It is estimated that 30 percent of public safety officers develop behavioral health conditions at some point in their lifetimes, including depression and post-traumatic stress disorder, in comparison to 20 percent of the general population that develops such conditions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA56B0EEC9DFF42F48512786561F396CD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Victims of post-traumatic stress disorder and acute stress disorder are at a higher risk of dying by suicide.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5586EF77EA054342BEF239B1C8548A49"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Firefighters have been reported to have higher suicide-attempt and ideation rates than the general population.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H308ED38C60914B85A7FB7D4AA1AE4417"><enum>(7)</enum><text>It is estimated that between 125 and 300 police officers die by suicide every year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H508C143612164AA4B328756FB1534419"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In 2019, pursuant to section 2(b) of the Law Enforcement Mental Health and Wellness Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/113">Public Law 115–113</external-xref>; 131 Stat. 2276), the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice developed a report (referred to in this section as the <quote>LEMHWA report</quote>) that expressed that many law enforcement agencies do not have the capacity or local access to the mental health professionals necessary for treating their law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H65759D4D20BF444DA182B215A7D9F923"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The LEMHWA report recommended methods for establishing remote access or regional mental health check programs at the State or Federal level.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E2AFF7769B142BC8DEDC5216DA50A00"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Individual police and fire departments generally do not have the resources to employ full-time mental health experts who are able to treat public safety officers with state-of-the-art techniques for the purpose of treating job-related post-traumatic stress disorder and acute stress disorder.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H9240E322BEC64AFB9D6B55B658F7EB21"><enum>3.</enum><header>Programming for post-traumatic stress disorder</header> 
<subsection id="H4E1916CC0F6B4F7F822F7F60DA7CF29C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H0F93002D4DDD4FA9883943112ECEF484"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public safety officer</header><text>The term <term>public safety officer</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3CE2E98E6ECF454CB92D6586B6D5C4D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the meaning given the term in section 1204 of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10284">34 U.S.C. 10284</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9824EF3DCDF4AF0AFACA31946B3650C"><enum>(B)<italic></italic></enum><text>includes Tribal public safety officers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA9AFCE9FE8FD4226814E46A831D6BA15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public safety telecommunicator</header><text>The term <term>public safety telecommunicator</term> means an individual who—</text> <subparagraph id="H8D6028EDBCE04B208B014424528F2983"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operates telephone, radio, or other communication systems to receive and communicate requests for emergency assistance at 911 public safety answering points and emergency operations centers;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF85A263999E54C9CB5231391AD03FFE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>takes information from the public and other sources relating to crimes, threats, disturbances, acts of terrorism, fires, medical emergencies, and other public safety matters; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0B16B71278040E4AE459C4E87DE2217"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinates and provides information to law enforcement and emergency response personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDDF7E309B3D64B6ABFE566F833EA3C5B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on—</text> <paragraph id="HA644663EE6944678A46EA03A80724324"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not fewer than 1 proposed program if the Attorney General determines it appropriate and feasible to do so to be administered by the Department of Justice for making state-of-the-art treatments or preventative care available to public safety officers and public safety telecommunicators with regard to job-related post-traumatic stress disorder or acute stress disorder by providing public safety officers and public safety telecommunicators access to evidence-based trauma-informed care, peer support, counselor services, and family supports for the purpose of treating or preventing post-traumatic stress disorder or acute stress disorder;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7F16408C5E454F5DB1F7FD921843A2CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a draft of any necessary legislation required to ensure that confidentiality is afforded to public safety officers on account of seeking the care or services described in paragraph (1) under the proposed program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7CB7C4091864003B8A36397B6FD1787"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how each proposed program described in paragraph (1) could be most efficiently administered throughout the United States at the State, Tribal, territorial and local levels, taking into account in-person and telehealth capabilities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H049F8F1FAFCD4472B3934A68B60406C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a draft of legislative language necessary to authorize each proposed program described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H782EA4B086444AF7A2264DAD92646804"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an estimate of the amount of annual appropriation necessary for administering each proposed program described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H90F8F06FA1A6445787DCF51F07528DBC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Development</header><text>In developing the report required under subsection (b), the Attorney General shall consult relevant stakeholders, including—</text> <paragraph id="H80BCAA5AF7124C1A81DAD799F1B9C50A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, and local agencies employing public safety officers and public safety telecommunicators; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H124DF4E96D844E8388259F2D030EE73D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>non-governmental organizations, international organizations, academies, or other entities, including organizations that support the interests of public safety officers and public safety telecommunicators and the interests of family members of public safety officers and public safety telecommunicators. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

