<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9E8EAA04C1834485A7E924ABA3DC80C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8355 IH: Closing Loopholes and Ending Asylum Abuse Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8355</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to reform the asylum claim process, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC5C440A5000B40BBAD9B235E56B2E555" style="OLC"><section id="H9693A59C21204236959CFAAD99039F83" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Closing Loopholes and Ending Asylum Abuse Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF2F5AB36BC2E4323A09EA564E9330CA5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reform asylum claim process</header><subsection id="H964002E88A514EA296108FA266C78B9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9E335DF6E4A24DBD954E8389E50C5DD2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 101(a)—</text><subparagraph id="H94AA0D38C7984BDFBBD80308F2281428"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (42)—</text><clause id="H34341E266AC546429CAAA529EAD65A81"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the government or a governmental-affiliated entity</quote> after <quote>fear of persecution</quote> each place it appears;</text></clause><clause id="HDF790ADF9FC44F1C938317847F1B983E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the government or a governmental-affiliated entity</quote> after <quote>persecution of any person</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HDEAB64A9F15A4FFC8F447749EDE024B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the government or a governmental-affiliated entity</quote> after <quote>has been persecuted</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="HBC0D654093F04E3A8EA161F6F6F31794"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the government or a governmental-affiliated entity</quote> after <quote>have been persecuted</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HCD8357534FE840D48534660F9B97FA54"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>by the government or a governmental-affiliated entity</quote> after <quote>subject to persecution</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80F64D3ADF9041B6833ACB14B3F68FD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC0AD7DFD46624CCC895A6AF76F0C9AF8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H855C1E8241DE440DB398BBD2174830AC" commented="no"><enum>(53)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>governmental-affiliated entity</quote> means a person, ministry, bureau, department, agency, government corporation, or any other entity chartered, established, sponsored, or supported by the government or a dominant political organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FB6AE54FA454443B87F74212EC85DE3" commented="no"><enum>(54)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>particular social group</quote> means a group of individuals that is composed of immutable characteristics, socially distinct within the society in question, and defined with particularity. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52030F9F43CF4BD7AFE7B46271D7487C"><enum>(55)</enum><text>The term <quote>immutable characteristic</quote> means a characteristic not capable of or susceptible to change.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF3E9CDC0EDE4F47A0106296378CDE1B"><enum>(56)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>socially distinct within the society in question</quote> means there is societal differentiation between people in a society who possess a shared belief or trait and people in such society who do not possess such shared belief or trait.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FF47BB1EECB454EB15F3CA5F0195A3E"><enum>(57)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>defined with particularity</quote> means there are clear, well-defined boundaries between people who fall within a particular social group and people who do not fall within such particular social group. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32338828047344B08C1F5820313856F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 208—</text><subparagraph id="H727E0E91FEEC47B0B13BC57998C279B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66331CF4181D4D21B39622ACD725DCEC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H56D678923694499BBA2248E000074862"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asylum process</header><subparagraph id="HA0C3E70CCFEB44ADA0AC87D85A6D78D8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Physical presence in United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any alien who is physically present in the United States or who arrives at the United States (at a designated port of entry and including an alien who is brought to the United States after having been interdicted in international or United States waters), irrespective of such alien’s status, may apply for asylum in accordance with this section or, where applicable, section 235(b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H234E2A32E13D40ED83400BABAE1DD61C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Outside of United States</header><text>Any alien who is physically present outside of the United States, irrespective of such alien’s status, may apply for asylum at a United States diplomatic mission established under section 2(c) of the Closing Loopholes and Ending Asylum Abuse Act of 2022.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6DFEF70FA3E40A1AA029F1A31CCFCD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H1F56E4D64C3F44C1B0D65E1AF905652B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subclause id="HF668F8ABD6084A009A800CA3A9EDE7AE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iii)—</text><item id="H904D574EAF7E4C94B52BF32C8FADFE11"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>whenever made and whether or not under oath</quote> and inserting <quote>which shall be made under oath</quote>; and</text></item><item id="HC82C64EB38544B5FA18B2BA66D9D6857"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and any reports on country conditions written by a law enforcement agency in the United States or a law enforcement agency in the country the report describes</quote> after <quote>country conditions</quote>; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H1BF52E9270334DAE91587499D09E4B84"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0C87A00B82B54BDDB29A4021EA6C0567" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD9042151D9E946FAB5BDD74A2ADB5FCE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Location of claim</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an alien passes through a country (other than the United States or the country of citizenship, nationality, or origin of such alien) that has a United States diplomatic mission established under section 2(c) of the Closing Loopholes and Ending Asylum Abuse Act of 2022, such alien shall make any application for asylum in accordance with this section in such country and may not enter the United States unless such claim is granted or other immigration benefit or relief is awarded.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="H318A2FECB64F4EDBAFECA7E62828D9DA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)—</text><subclause id="H25BDB05EF5444BAD8D82A707DC12FA0A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subclause><subclause id="H746BC800F7B54CA6BB5E3910B086ECD4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (vi), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8023D7A56E554EA6918054626CD344DB"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA5B896A4DF4E4E758AAFDAF08BD09994" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="HB45586AE7FEE460EA2A5F4EE514D349B"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the alien has violated section 275 (relating to entering the United States improperly); or</text></clause><clause id="H6C15563DFD7D45E0BDF496E9739C82A1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the alien has received a final order of removal issued in absentia under section 240(b)(5)(A). </text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE1B95D43DDD4F85B7CEE44109D2DFD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 235(b)(1)(B)(v)—</text><subparagraph id="HC4C7C949F8024C719E0EC0F8299789EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>possibility</quote> and inserting <quote>likelihood</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEC4D8EAAC544DFBA53C8F4F38057494"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and the evidence presented</quote> after <quote>by the alien</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC42C128B88DE4A0C9FA6910ADE4DE030"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Claims for asylum abroad</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 4 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1221">8 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 235A the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF3AECD57C12B40A793C245BD2E7F14EB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H058A47CE72084BA59BBD3C0B49CAE47F"><enum>235B.</enum><header>Claims for asylum outside of United States</header><subsection id="H4DB21764EE53405BAEE650FED4B76B46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Screening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien outside of the United States who indicates an intention to apply for asylum at a diplomatic mission established under section 2(c) of the Closing Loopholes and Ending Asylum Abuse Act of 2022, shall be examined, assessed, and referred to an asylum officer for an interview to determine if such alien has a credible fear of persecution in accordance with section 235(b)(1)(B). </text></subsection><subsection id="H16B5F7A40A0A4C4B9300C631D57BC049"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Admission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an alien described in subsection (a) is found to have a credible fear of persecution, the alien shall be admitted to the United States for the purpose of further consideration of their application for asylum as directed by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE6A04B5960D04BDAA857175C69D599A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>No credible fear found</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an alien described in subsection (a) is found to not have a credible fear of persecution—</text><paragraph id="H902B405B71BE426FB7604319B1E8432E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the alien shall not be eligible to apply for asylum in the United States unless such alien can demonstrate a chance in circumstance with respect to their credible fear of persecution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F3263562DD243899EB9E7A407E39EC3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the asylum officer shall prepare a written record of a determination, including a summary of the material facts as stated by the alien, any additional facts relied upon by the officer, and the officer’s analysis of why, in the light of such facts, the alien has not established a credible fear of persecution, and a copy of the officer’s interview notes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CFAE9065ADB4749994AEF386B2FE86E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish all necessary processes, rules, and procedures to store, maintain, access, and share information related to an alien applying for asylum outside of the United States. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDA10D7F8852F4D0A97273EE8CA6C17A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization To establish asylum offices abroad</header><paragraph id="H2217D217E7734DCEBDC4D37BD97DAC16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, shall establish United States diplomatic missions at a United States embassy or consulate in accordance with this subsection to review an application for asylum under section 208 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B2FB8541D7843AF9FC23056283501D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Location</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A United States diplomatic mission established pursuant to paragraph (1) may be located at any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC4CC53F62C9046E2A8074FD741B956EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Embassy in Mexico City.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B07FFDCC90F4DD789F54709B2D1A3A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The United States Consulate General in Ciudad Juarez.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD354D58FC1BD42CCB6FCC09228F3B370"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Consulate General in Matamoros.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F8CDC9EB7BF47F9B8C667E2150D3A48"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Consulate General in Monterrey.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF53B722B7BC04F32ADD7A28DE0845702"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Consulate General in Nogales.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C7CE256D164996980FB4AE9CE0146A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Consulate General in Tijuana.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D161835EABF494F90A1E72E5AD4CAF7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Any other United States embassy or consulate the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and Attorney General, recommends pursuant to subsection (c)(5).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB85F4B41FB7F4693A3E71035328E7D66"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Staff</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, shall provide necessary facilities and staff to serve the United States diplomatic missions established pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E7A4EA8089E4B0EBEDDE78F3B1C3205"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every year thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the United States diplomatic missions established pursuant to subsection (b)(1), including the following:</text><paragraph id="HD90513E8553F4947B31FD8EA1B79221D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of applications for asylum reviewed at each United States diplomatic mission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1903D5D1794B491A8A4990A4BA8C5EAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The number of asylum seekers found to have a credible fear of persecution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE08C8CC046CB4CEC9172D64FE92A6518"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of staff employed at each United States diplomatic mission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04A773246975402C9034001927A6E04C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the effectiveness of reviewing applications for asylum at the United States diplomatic missions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE0F9B6BEAD548F288558CB63AD3CB8E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Recommendations on where to establish additional United States diplomatic missions as necessary based on migrant flows.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27C5E49D786E4854B2FA174303824439"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other matter the Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the Attorney General, determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C0E42358B9141AE8A2F23C8BEF7639B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>relevant congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HD96BC231F282469F82B5E5661649DF3C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Homeland Security, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A84CCC0F10B48D1ADF337112553174B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

