<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAE92F2A14B954649954A3B0E7A054579" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7927 IH: To prohibit the use of funds to propose amendments to the International Health Regulations, the Global Pandemic Treaty, or any other agreement among World Health Organization member states, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7927</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220531">May 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of funds to propose amendments to the International Health Regulations, the Global Pandemic Treaty, or any other agreement among World Health Organization member states, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H592116C7D8C3482589D8CFFDD59254B4" style="OLC"><section id="H419A301327AA4408B70CD45D870D540D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that absent a United States withdrawal from the World Health Organization (WHO), the United States should hold the WHO accountable and overhaul its operations, including by—</text><paragraph id="H7FA806A615024182968F78D87CA6174D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensuring the People’s Republic of China is held accountable for the COVID-19 pandemic and for failing to comply with the International Health Regulations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41693706464B4D9C88E143E0682B099B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring the WHO conducts a thorough investigation into the role that the People’s Republic of China played in the origin and spread of COVID-19; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBFC1AA438D74FBC8DBD7866D72E5C95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring the United States does not relinquish any authorities to the WHO that would supersede any new or existing United States authorities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H03DE4D8181614C65A35946B86399A49B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds to propose amendments to the International Health Regulations, the Global Pandemic Treaty, or any other agreement among World Health Organization member states</header><subsection id="HAE8CB9A565E84CAEBE58AC5A596ACA94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b) and notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds available to any Federal department or agency may be used to propose any amendment to the International Health Regulations, the Global Pandemic Treaty, or any other agreement among World Health Organization member states that would supersede or otherwise modify authorities under United States law, including authorities relating to required compliance or relinquishing reporting or oversight standards.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB2B1C8EA734B4B98B62143DA4763B997"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to the use of funds that is approved in advance by an Act of Congress.</text></subsection></section><section id="H70FA44E93317491E835A9D495A4DF16F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds to provide contributions to the World Health Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no funds available to any Federal department or agency may be used to provide contributions to the World Health Organization (WHO) unless and until the Secretary of State certifies to Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H383859A48829424B97497675EB1F101B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the WHO—</text><subparagraph id="HC4E7BDE938E249398E871E3025617CC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>holds the People’s Republic of China accountable for failing to comply with the International Health Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A551C50B35A478584B6857953E1F08E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>makes available a report of its findings and actions under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9615152AD915470D89FBB48B7B45C742"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the steps the WHO is taking to ensure China’s accountability, including the role China played in the origin and spread of COVID-19; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE795AA33154FA2A89119FD4C2E4516"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the steps the WHO is taking to strengthen accountability and its ability to be impartial and objective while improving its transparency and its overall effectiveness.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE7243A385B78436A8D0EAA5738BD222A"><enum>4.</enum><header>International Health Regulations defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>International Health Regulations</quote> means the International Health Regulations adopted by the 58th World Health Assembly in 2005 under Resolution WHA58.3.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

