<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H04139E3E2F2A47A290576831465261CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7983 IH: Biometric Verification for Entry and Reconfirming Identity with Forensics Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7983</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220608">June 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to expand the requirements for the collection of biometric data, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H092F504C2DF240AA9972EB52E14FCDB8" style="OLC"><section id="H4307590FCA8F45B4B5EA24BAF5E984A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biometric Verification for Entry and Reconfirming Identity with Forensics Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>B–VERIFY Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HB746AB44BB9A4B1D94C102658F904DAA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collection of biometric information for immigration benefits</header><subsection id="H5580056ABC76403FBF232109391209DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title I of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 106 the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H75F2FA142E634727A6C181D9FC4B4797" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H14B1F63FC71E4CD789B372B641DF0977"><enum>107.</enum><header>Collection of biometric information</header><subsection id="H2CF9B12F792047DAB4F1EBA643655577"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for immigration benefits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each individual, whether an alien (including a VAWA self-petitioner and an alien admitted or seeking admission under section 101(a)(15)(T)) or a national of the United States, who files or is the proposed beneficiary of an application or petition for an immigration benefit, shall provide biometric information to the Secretary of Homeland Security or Secretary of State, at a time and in a manner prescribed by the applicable Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF00FAED37984F3FA52C4A1C5FCCA9BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collection from aliens apprehended by CBP, ICE, or USCIS</header><paragraph id="HDAE4EC80D16D471BAA1BD1A79A445567"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall collect biometric information from each alien, including children, encountered by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Immigration and Customs Enforcement, or U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7003FF95D91D422587858AACAE0BC001"><enum>(2)</enum><header>DNA test results</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the collection of biometric information under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall collect DNA test results, which include a partial DNA profile, for the purpose of determining the existence of a claimed genetic relationship. The Secretary shall use and store such DNA test results for an associated adjudication or to perform any other functions necessary for administering and enforcing the immigration laws. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6389A1BBED5B46A7BE5C53AC0DE9C558"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorized uses of biometric information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall use biometric information collected under this section—</text><paragraph id="H8A162953462146ADA5F54D439C63B1F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to perform criminal history and national security background checks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA17ACDA7DA48529F80E4E2BA731B82"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for identity enrollment, verification, and management in the immigration lifecycle; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7446DF2BDC1414A8FED38CE7C2EF85D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for secure document production associated with certain immigration and naturalization benefits or actions; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE5A80EB6F5341348B45805E65CAD7F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to administer and enforce the immigration laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F2B10913C864979A8F8FA649F932ED1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on issuance of benefits</header><text>The Secretary may not provide an immigration benefit, and the Secretary of State may not issue a visa, to an alien prior to the collection of biometric information under subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H07BCC73F96284972883F3DF149E6568C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Immigration and Nationality Act is amended by inserting after the item related to section 106 the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H377FEA96EE1B4474B2DF5BD311699170" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">107. Collection of biometric information. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H82E15DEA0C954D4A9A837C04403FA03F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Biometric defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4972A69B920A4E7EB70E9255564BDDB7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H45884A2FA3324A0A899008DEDE0EA01B"><enum>(53)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biometric</term> means a measurable biological (anatomical and physiological) or behavioral characteristic used for identification of an individual, and includes—</text><subparagraph id="HF659722055CC4996B91E203F6D1D002A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> a fingerprint;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2511F1C307E346F39ABD12834A41DCCF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a palm print;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0518DB05E6844F15848BEB5C989E9583"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a photograph (including a facial image specifically for facial recognition, as well as a photograph of a physical or anatomical feature such as a scar, skin mark, or tattoo); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DBBBBABD74C42128E9A18B64A27AAAF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a signature;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H737CD3F2B1D241C0A499FA80CEC48B9B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a voice print;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DCC9D9DF51A498887252E0E4DF00FA8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an iris image; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FC4CE83725D4BA6984C92DE6DCE4EF3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>DNA (including DNA test results, which include a partial DNA profile attesting to genetic relationship). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H309C1D6258854F6DAF2648F4AA19BB35"><enum>4.</enum><header>Unaccompanied alien children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 235 of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF18354817AFD4E829B6D9FA948B0369F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HAC98D2E2D5C84DB6BBA0A73D6A69B784"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by inserting at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD2DD694256BC4100B73AF8A4A05859A5" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HAE9D2B83B1E74C008D0AA42A3ECBEFA0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Background checks of individuals with whom children are placed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before placing a child with an individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall conduct a background check on such individual, which background check shall include each of the following:</text><clause id="H91114EE1B9794BE7998BD9C70E9C7DD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A public records check.</text></clause><clause id="H7AEFAD8F66074A85BB4FADD901AA32D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A check using the Dru Sjodin National Sex Offender Public Website.</text></clause><clause id="H95E1DFF48ED24B0EBE02D05E3A5743F3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A National Criminal History Background Check, which shall be conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, based on digital fingerprints or digitized paper prints.</text></clause><clause id="H971F5083CE90489ABD845427BB96B6E0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A Child Abuse and Neglect (CA/N) check. </text></clause><clause id="H4115080C306E4A4197B0A7FC08703D7A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A State criminal history repository or local law enforcement check. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H206E1B37C6CA47319651743977739546"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Information about individuals with whom children are placed</header><clause id="H5988559D9A8A44C2B3A28E1E3C59DAE4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Information to be provided to homeland security</header><text>Before placing a child with an individual, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide to the Secretary of Homeland Security, regarding the individual with whom the child will be placed, the following information:</text><subclause id="H77EEA7DB1DA94F35B660D5FEBB96AEA5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The name of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="H58CC9BC9C87A4D51A63AB6BE811A43EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The social security number of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="H64B0EB2FBE6546D8B63DB9C94EF1AF02"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The date of birth of the individual.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD28297C9A9554A07B8774C051B4F046B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>The location of the individual’s residence where the child will be placed.</text></subclause><subclause id="H895249294BAA454986122A607882F7DB"><enum>(V)</enum><text>The immigration status of the individual, if known.</text></subclause><subclause id="H20C9E96394794ECCAB666D0F41C408E1"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Contact information for the individual.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFEF580F383A94C779176F229920A7AD8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>In the case of a child who was apprehended on or after June 15, 2012, and before the date of the enactment of this subparagraph, who the Secretary of Health and Human Services placed with an individual, the Secretary shall provide the information listed in clause (i) to the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 90 days after such date of enactment.</text></clause><clause id="H48C867CB84014112B0F9C53DE1480D93"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Activities of the secretary of homeland security</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving the information listed in clause (i), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text><subclause id="H48178DC37C8B46A893D3A2D555368A3E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case that the immigration status of an individual with whom a child is placed is unknown, investigate the immigration status of that individual; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2F7814F27B7A4CC19E242366C858D3C6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>upon determining that an individual with whom a child is placed is unlawfully present in the United States, initiate removal proceedings pursuant to chapter 4 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1221">8 U.S.C. 1221 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H377D4876163B41C78A35275B14366984"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><clause id="H879838EEEE59494FA8A09F52FB2AF312"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>to the greatest extent practicable</quote> the following: <quote>(at no expense to the Government)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B1E548B52B54A018D2BB6DA5025FD07"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>have counsel to represent them</quote> and inserting <quote>have access to counsel to represent them</quote>; and </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54035EB0F57549728DD8D0DE9086AE37" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4B24EF356F0648A2BA95BAFE87E94D0E" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE762FBCE720D417CBAAB667DB9CFDAF5"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an unaccompanied alien child who arrives at any international border of, port of entry to, or place between any ports of entry to, the United States—</text><paragraph id="HD0DD8568041149D58AAFC57288B84C5C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an alien parent or guardian, other than an alien admitted for lawful permanent residence, of such a child shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HF96B011022EE452F977B31D8C84D9329"><enum>(A)</enum><text>permanently barred from adjusting status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence and becoming a naturalized citizen of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB385C59007FF41838059AC6F479F3293"><enum>(B)</enum><text>deemed to be inadmissible for purposes of section 212(a)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C88250C84B847DB80D0795A29C09227"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deemed to have committed an offense described in paragraph (1)(A) of section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324</external-xref>); or </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD65F0B420DFE4BFDAB4F4C811A527F22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an alien parent or guardian, who is an alien admitted for lawful permanent residence, shall be ineligible for any Federal public benefit (as such term is defined in section 401(c) of the Personal Responsibility and Work Opportunity Reconciliation Act of 1996).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H25241B77F90543AE880948B86029B913"><enum>5.</enum><header>Collaboration with foreign governments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall improve collaboration and coordination with foreign governments and the Biometric Identification Transnational Migration Alert Program (commonly referred to as <quote>BITMAP</quote>) or any successor database, in order to deter and detect immigration and asylum fraud. </text></section><section id="HE7B1B95A67A14B82835FAFCF357C42BD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Notification about fraudulent potential sponsors of unaccompanied alien children</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall notify Immigration and Customs Enforcement and any appropriate law enforcement agency, and deny the placement of an unaccompanied alien child (as such term is defined in section 462 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279</external-xref>)) with a potential sponsor if the potential sponsor—</text><paragraph id="HCCC32FA0087B47268FE694954CF272D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>claims to have familial relationship to the unaccompanied alien child, but fails a DNA test, and is otherwise unable to prove such relationship beyond a reasonable doubt; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4012A72045E34B9FA8791304444AD26C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides a false document to confirm the potential sponsor’s identity.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA4758D42995B47AC9F9CF0D1A3610288"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal agencies to notify ICE of unlawfully present aliens</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If an alien presents a document to an officer or employee of the Federal Government for purposes of identification, which document indicates that the alien is unlawfully present in the United States, the officer or employee shall promptly notify Immigration and Customs Enforcement. Upon receiving a notification under this section, Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall promptly place the alien in removal proceedings. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

