<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1193 EAS: Cardiovascular Advances in Research and Opportunities Legacy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 1193</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221201">December 1, 2022.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="idf6058ba375a043d7a227665d05c5a668" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 1193) entitled <quote>An Act to amend title IV of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, to establish a program under which the Director of the National Institutes of Health shall support or conduct research on valvular heart disease, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following: </text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block style="OLC" changed="added" blank-lines-after="1" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="id161f8918-9164-4500-a12a-eb656f7b08f8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cardiovascular Advances in Research and Opportunities Legacy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id273ba060-2a8b-4c84-836d-c3816a31bff1"><enum>2.</enum><header>HHS valvular heart disease activities</header><subsection id="idFDA4C742425D4C78A02C07784A9D59B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall, as appropriate, continue activities related to research, education, and awareness of valvular heart diseases.</text></subsection><subsection id="id715360BD94BA43E5A867F29D43A0A328"><enum>(b)</enum><header>NIH research related to valvular heart diseases</header><paragraph id="id7b4a4c18-efb9-4907-8454-baf12629b15c"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the National Institutes of Health, in consultation with the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute, may support or conduct research regarding valvular heart diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9b22e4af-126e-478e-ba8e-a56926acbfd0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Support further research</header><text>In order to improve information on, and understanding of, causation and risk factors for valvular heart diseases, research conducted or supported under this subsection for such diseases may include the following: </text><subparagraph id="id6c57ed16-5ee4-41e6-96b4-c512df6ce2d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Use of advanced technological imaging and other relevant methods to generate data related to valvular heart diseases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7e380ce4-f02c-48ae-bbda-431e525cc74a"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Assessing potential risk factors for sudden cardiac arrest or sudden cardiac death from valvular heart diseases.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id77bdbd28-30ce-47fe-8e5c-3ccde4b13c76"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Other activities, as appropriate, in order to improve the availability of information on, and advance research related to, valvular heart diseases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id03fc47b2-d6d4-4eef-a60d-aeebfe557bb2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mitral valve prolapse workshop</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute shall, as appropriate, convene a workshop composed of subject matter experts and stakeholders to identify research needs and opportunities to develop recommendations for the identification and treatment of individuals with mitral valve prolapse, including such individuals who may be at risk for sudden cardiac arrest or sudden cardiac death.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idb2807efe-880c-4fce-8bca-8f71a007683e"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prevention activities to improve awareness of sudden cardiac death as a result of valvular heart diseases</header><paragraph id="id5203c752-abca-42e8-b9cb-479b51d3d01b"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may carry out activities to increase education and awareness of valvular heart diseases in order to reduce the incidence of sudden cardiac death caused by such diseases. The Secretary may—</text><subparagraph id="id9636014302A64A51B0971DB73DC7ECCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>award grants or contracts to public or nonprofit private entities to carry out activities under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id286C58D45A674C559A036F75433D61F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>directly, or through grants or contracts, provide technical assistance with respect to such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id41bad69a-cca2-4524-90d4-f37a1a8a6fc6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain activities</header><text>Upon availability of applicable data, projects carried out under paragraph (1) may include—</text><subparagraph id="idee337295-7c61-4cf0-9813-e1aacde55d38"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">continuing activities at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention related to valvular heart diseases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="ide87a5dd8-d545-413c-b29f-52e5d03a23f3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving the awareness of the public concerning any risk factors for, the symptoms of, and the public health impact of, valvular heart diseases; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id81f177c1-7e9e-44b0-96a3-8cc71c64e81f"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhancing public health data collection and improving the quality of such data, as appropriate, regarding cardiac arrests, including cardiac arrests that occur outside of the hospital.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="ida95460f5-2a1b-449c-a408-2c55b28ba50c"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant prioritization</header><text>The Secretary may, in awarding grants or entering into contracts pursuant to paragraph (1), give priority to entities seeking to carry out projects for populations most impacted by valvular heart diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id5c66eeee-52cb-4852-bb4b-1fd3b9ddd5a5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination of activities</header><text>The Secretary shall, as appropriate, ensure that activities under this section are coordinated with other agencies and offices of the Department of Health and Human Services that carry out activities regarding valvular heart diseases.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id22baef03-0d10-453b-af56-5ccfd0a06fae"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Secretary shall, as applicable and appropriate, identify and disseminate best practices for relevant health care providers related to valvular heart diseases.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id32EE383E17F44C8F8F2FDE163EA76F32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For purposes of carrying out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $28,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 

