<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H4040FF7E08AC499B868895EDA5DFD7FC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1506 RH: Transparency in Energy Production Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 454</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1506</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–631, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210302">March 2, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 2, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the accurate reporting of fossil fuel extraction and emissions by entities with leases on public land, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HCB0015650CDB40BB9BCC8FE3DC1BFF02"><section id="H9DF37B234A4649B4A64E739BA97C6723" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short Title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transparency in Energy Production Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD594E130B1AE4C8E820ED9C7B8D988F0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure Requirements</header><subsection id="HC49758E62315477DB1334CA34C4A7E9D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required for an entity seeking a lease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall require any entity seeking a lease to develop covered operations on public land or Indian land to submit to the Secretary concerned a report, at the time of submission of a bid to develop covered operations. Such report shall—</text><paragraph id="HA979D3AA22B64CD8AAA275672AEBE8F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> make the disclosures described in the Sustainable Accounting Standard for the Extractives and Minerals Processing Sector and the Renewable Resources and Alternative Energy Sector in effect on the date the report is filed (that is produced by the Sustainability Accounting Standards Board) for the covered operations developed by the entity and in effect at the date of such bid; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9307E8B0482345A2BE79C6896CD7F8B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregate the information in paragraph (1) by State and by type of covered operation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA0D854F824D741339EE451FDC07290D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required for an entity holding a lease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall require any entity holding a lease to develop covered operations on public land or Indian land to submit to the Secretary concerned a report annually. Such report shall—</text><paragraph id="H7BD8B81977C34F9EAED24B2417DF2980"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> make the disclosures described in the Sustainable Accounting Standard for the Extractives and Minerals Processing Sector and the Renewable Resources and Alternative Energy Sector in effect on the date the report is filed (that is produced by the Sustainability Accounting Standards Board); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EE4D3FF922E452491C2510EEC5D71B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disaggregate the information in paragraph (1) by State and by type of covered operation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B4CB414812E431E8F3A87C03E7C9DEE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Failure To comply</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary concerned determines that an entity did not meet the requirements of subsection (a), the Secretary concerned—</text><paragraph id="H755E4A82CDA04D2C8C38A52CA019F53E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not issue to such entity a lease for a covered operation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF57429C8B48D49DC9A1C94298681E9F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may suspend a lease for a covered operation held by such entity. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H22AE866FFD3A4B1D9251DC2F10E9C895"><enum>3.</enum><header>Online Publication of Disclosure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall make the information reported under section 2 available to the public on an internet website in a machine readable format.</text></section><section id="H5D9BB67EC3E24170914722D895328DBC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary concerned shall submit a report to Congress that includes—</text><paragraph id="H8FB0F3301F984A2FBA9D0E0AD2AEC2BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to covered operations, the annual and 2-year totals of greenhouse gas emissions, air quality, water management, biodiversity impacts, production, and number of sites according to the metrics described in the Sustainable Accounting Standard for Oil and Gas Exploration and Production in effect on the date the report is filed (that is produced by the Sustainability Accounting Standards Board) for covered operations on public land or Indian land; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81700C40C001476193DF61A4A97EFB07" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the changes in the information in paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB818F5C9F2704DE99E1A9FCD298762B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the projected future changes for 5, 10, and 25 years; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03152E8773E745869A9500506A90E063"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for renewable energy operations, an estimate of the greenhouse gas emissions that would result from production of the same amount of energy using fossil fuels and water management, including water use, biodiversity impacts, production, number of sites, and acres including associated transmission lines; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0BF5CEB0A8C4C3FA70C805639047B62"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the emission produced during the construction of solar panels and wind turbines that would be used for renewable energy operations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF625879CF694B1FA49244F05A9250B9"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a determination as to whether the materials or labor for the construction of solar panels and wind turbines used for renewable energy operations would be sourced from the Xinjiang Autonomous Region in China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF821FA505A4015AB78A827365EADBD"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the environmental impacts of the decommissioning and disposal of renewable energy products and electronic waste, including batteries, solar panels, and products that have exceeded their life cycle;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14587572A87046D7AD62941B1C6B38E4"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to lands on which covered operations occur, the annual and 2-year totals of greenhouse gas emissions, air quality, water management, and biodiversity impacts of catastrophic wildfires, the number of acres identified as being at high or very high risk of wildfire, and the number of acres in need of treatment or fuels reduction activities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H566FC24325EA4049921C8FEA1C4A8CD8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>an assessment of the environmental and human rights impacts in the production of renewable energy products for the lifecycle of such products, including such impacts from source materials for and the disposal of such products.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3B818684A2E741DC8B1C64E69F7C6CB7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H3E3B4C1EEC6F4B9BBF22D95CF50BA82D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered operation</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE9C4BDB82D674029B9F3EA50C507F9A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any renewable energy operations; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFDBD88DDC87446FAAC84F163C02CD84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any fossil fuel operation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD0E5C2650C2458AA23B60512C9E3ED5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any operation using any right-of-way or special use permit that would cross public lands, Indian lands, or national forests that would facilitate fossil fuel development;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A692B925D424D13B5191A8912C6C20E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>fossil fuel</quote> means oil, natural gas, natural gas liquids, coal, and any derivative of these that is used for fuel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CE11973DF354403A3D30B3043F46528" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <quote>Indian land</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2601(2) of the Energy Policy Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3501">25 U.S.C. 3501(2)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A2E346104BF483BA9C61E1BDF1B9DAC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>public land</quote> means any land, interest in land, or submerged land owned by the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H540AF4A9EDE64DC5863D2A5C953240C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>renewable energy</quote> means a project carried out on public land or Indian land that uses wind, solar, geothermal, wave, current, tidal, or ocean thermal energy to generate electricity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H981F18FA44AA4593BA5448100F07A751"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>Secretary concerned</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF8925A54B00A4558AE53E1BC7B2E13E7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to public lands and Indian lands; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD201F41E0C4C4B4BB27365A984EECFCC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to National Forest System land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H75B092BF99F340A88D80468BC7E39CB7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

