<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDD0CE7D7E3814C39AF705E20C5F0EE5A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9064 IH: Jamal Khashoggi Protection for Dissidents and Journalists Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9064</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enshrine the legacy of Jamal Khashoggi by protecting dissidents and journalists, codifying the Khashoggi Ban, and introducing the Khashoggi Amendment to the Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H124150A45F304F3EBB8DE5B29AABFAD6" style="OLC"><section id="H4AE566DFB5384BB4BF91E24C45765E6F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Jamal Khashoggi Protection for Dissidents and Journalists Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC9A2D27278FD4199940256058EDAB51F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4C33B86D791D4C3EAC41AFA7F863F2F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jamal Khashoggi was a resident of the United States living in the Commonwealth of Virginia, a Saudi journalist, a Washington Post columnist, and critical of the Saudi regime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3708C4EFE4A4A388047AFC2837DFB22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On October 2, 2018, Khashoggi was lured to the Consulate of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia in Istanbul, Turkey under the false cover of needing to address a consular matter.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D8715934EFC4BE5BBAB79FC2F956FF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>While inside the Saudi consulate, Khashoggi was murdered, and his body was dismembered by intelligence officers of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8C21BD9B2B54A79AD5A34D8F7225E39"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office of the Director of National Intelligence determined in 2018 that Saudi Crown Prince Mohammed Bin Salman approved the capture or killing of Khashoggi in Istanbul.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4D47F7A8ADB4177933A172F36A8A1D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A highly credible inquiry by the United Nations concluded that Khashoggi’s killing was premeditated and that the mission was endorsed, planned, and overseen by senior Saudi officials. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H2D9B57F729074AA7A6F0AA28C288E26E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Khashoggi Amendment to the Foreign Sovereign Immunities Act</header><subsection id="H762CEEAD9EDF455AA6377C0CDCF28FCE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General exceptions to the jurisdictional immunity of a foreign state</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1605(a) of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H78A8062F4AFC4BB6A9E18CD7E0AF6C95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(B), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14F1093EBA6D4DCEBCB4705800345670"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period and insertin <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53EF47EE2AED4FFFB4CC6392180023B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H4127D259F96F4128AC365FA9E2497226" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H3E921F10E34643C5BDDEAD4502EA6484"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which money damages are sought against a foreign state for the personal injury or death of a United States person or resident taking place on or after October 2, 2017, anywhere other than on the territory of that foreign state, where the injury or death is a direct result of extraterritorial counter-dissident activities conducted by the defendant foreign state or its agents. </text></paragraph><quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subsection">For purposes of this subsection, <quote>counter-dissident activities</quote> includes activities that suppress, harass, surveil, threaten, or harm journalists, activists, or other persons perceived to be dissidents.</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76B73C1C6D844F92A016BF1EC4A4457D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions to the immunity from attachment or execution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1610 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 1605(a)(2), (3), or (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (2), (3), (5), or (7) of section 1605(a)</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBDDF6A72E9984EE0B553127986331BEE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Khashoggi ban ground of inadmissibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 212(a)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD3EFFA0BFBCC4046A3DF4FF806D7404F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H7CFC01B9BD564999BD0C82742069D509"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Khashoggi ban</header><clause id="HFFA857A0BB924EB287CB920D47D665FE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien who is determined by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security to be acting on behalf of a foreign government and is believed to be directly engaged in serious, extraterritorial counter-dissident activities, including those that suppress, harass, surveil, threaten, or harm—</text><subclause id="H8ACA73413F0041B3A37F3E1E94B9C6FF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>journalists;</text></subclause><subclause id="H95CC5B3D80774996A5443BA47AE65F90"><enum>(II)</enum><text>activists; </text></subclause><subclause id="H18E68A3A08C142FCAAF55DE08111F9E4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>other persons perceived to be dissidents for their work; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H8982D091EE2C419CB58C279E076222D1"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>families or other close associates of the persons described in clauses (i) through (iii),</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">is inadmissible.</continuation-text></clause><clause id="HCC50DBA007AB4B0DA96F04F7D905FFEE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Discretionary ban</header><text>Any alien who is a family member of an alien who is inadmissible under clause (i) may be inadmissible, as determined by the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></clause><clause id="H1559BB73A7FF4ACD96AF3029E1219FE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Notification of determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an alien is determined to be inadmissible under clause (i) or (ii), the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security shall make a public statement identifying the alien and the reasons for the determination.</text></clause><clause id="HF2140CD02A2747B1978DC1F1E26E8D5B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive the requirements of this subparagraph, or any part thereof, if such Secretary determines that such requirements do not serve the national security interest of the United States. Such waiver shall be made in writing to Congress and shall include a brief description of the national security reason for such waiver.</text></clause><clause id="H4E3A40640BC94F4395DB72E3670EC620"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $1,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each fiscal year thereafter to carry out this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

