<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H3B9A4799C4A94FBAAA674F05331AFD7D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 570 RH: Offshore Accountability Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 403</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 570</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–562]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210128">January 28, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require operators of offshore oil and gas facilities to report failures of critical systems to the Secretary of the Interior, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HF98F36C146044133A7119EF8B015F5FF" style="OLC"><section id="HF98F4E2CCD9348A6A1860633B1386792" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be referred to as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Accountability Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEC865D37856E4965ABA602F1498DDAC0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><subsection id="HBA06FD8E59594DFC9E39EB53FA0D7AA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 30 days after the discovery of an equipment failure of a critical system operated at an offshore oil or gas facility, the operator of such facility shall provide a written notice of such failure to the Secretary and the manufacturer of such equipment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H41FA9BD1A3DE4B2891F7104E4BC892D7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investigation</header><paragraph id="H395B0E8B497A4B548A0535104AC15E22"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Analysis report</header><text>Subject to subsection (d), an operator required to provide notice to the Secretary under subsection (a) shall ensure that an investigation and an equipment failure analysis are completed within 120 days of the failure to determine the cause of such failure. The operator shall provide an analysis report to the Secretary and to the manufacturer of such equipment documenting such investigation and any corrective action taken.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34861C50B97D460095EBD248D53AD32F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Not more than 30 days after receiving an analysis report submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall make such analysis report available to the public on the Department of the Interior website.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF217D6C8A894BE88C770AFF754FD103"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Extension</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An operator required to provide an analysis report under subsection (b) may request an extension of up to 60 days from the Secretary for such requirement by submitting a written request detailing how such operator will complete the investigation and report required by subsection (b). The Secretary shall review and respond to such request not later than 30 days after the date on which such request is submitted, and may not grant more than one such extension with respect to a single investigation and report.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1EA50745629A46FFAB105896CF5298A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of change in equipment or procedures</header><text>An operator required to provide a notice under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H12ABA53D2BD54440A3B87D933EC7CEE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 30 days after receiving notice from a manufacturer of any critical system that made changes in the design of a critical system as the result of the reported failure, report in writing such notice to the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D3201D2F2D54542B5A8426B30AC2B30"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 30 days after a change in such operator’s operating or repair procedures as a result of the reported failure, report in writing such change to the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC14654CACB24CEF8E02256A38534576"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HF0D04BE195194957A68E40AD181AE2C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blowout preventer system</header><text>The term <quote>blowout preventer system</quote> means a wellhead device or combination of devices that is specifically designed to prevent the uncontrolled release of gas, oil, or other fluids or hydrocarbons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A56E809EAE6450CBC4C63F853366C50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical system</header><text>The term <quote>critical system</quote> means safety and pollution prevention equipment or a blowout preventer system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD561CDC3F5DA49C0858244464409527E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Equipment failure</header><text>The term <quote>equipment failure</quote> means any conditions that prevents equipment from meeting its functional specifications or purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1422D881FB04B05B85CFDEC232249EC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Operator</header><text>The term <quote>operator</quote> means the operator of an offshore oil or gas facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28F0D0D47939403EADD907F36074AF0B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Safety and pollution prevention equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>safety and pollution prevention system</quote> means any equipment that is specifically designed to prevent a malfunction or failure of an offshore well, resulting in injury or loss of life, damage to the environment, or serious damage to the equipment, including—</text><subparagraph id="H74877C740DCA43A6BFD842B9033A1FED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>surface safety valves and actuators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF814F28019BF4E8CBA2425BBF3DC289E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>boarding shutdown valves and the actuators of such valves;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B506B3F0EE04AC79BADBB511CD23BD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>underwater safety valves and actuators;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H785E5C0C02E1471B8E99EF8985D669A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>subsurface safety valves and associated safety valve locks and landing nipples; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC781B4E3B754FF2BED115137FE09CFD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>gas lift shutdown valves and actuators associated with such valves.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H681CF1441B504894AFC2A4901EC574B5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221116">November 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

