<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB3B1F407452F4AE79283FB46232FBF51" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8562 IH: Defense Production Oversight Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8562</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for disapproval by Congress of the invocation of authorities under the Defense Production Act of 1950.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BAD1547E5A04BFF9D70FC08F0243431" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2163E88637954DD997DE20F6BFF79390" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defense Production Oversight Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA610219350CE4BB885D1406541799E6A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional disapproval of invocation of Defense Production Act of 1950 authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4551">50 U.S.C. 4551 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4B6A946B3DB8487DA9DA7A38ED6C5FF4"> 
<section id="HE040D303C8C24971993AC02690BB3DB5"><enum>724.</enum><header>Congressional disapproval of invocation of title I and III authorities</header> 
<subsection id="H90DF15B7A2644D85AD06F5E2E19242A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An invocation by the President of authorities under title I or III shall have no force or effect on or after the date of the enactment of a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5ADB4B1FF2AF4978A9D0254273A99939"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means a joint resolution the sole matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves of the invocation by the President of authorities under the Defense Production Act of 1950 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4501">50 U.S.C. 4501 et seq.</external-xref>) relating to ___.</quote>, with the blank space being filled with a brief description of the matter with respect to which the President invoked such authorities.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H74192E3853C34ADC9E3C985CAABC3B68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>A joint resolution of disapproval shall be referred to the committees in each House of Congress with jurisdiction.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3D8B72B584F54305BFDEE5A1D045B678"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consideration in Senate</header> <paragraph id="H2519F8F3BA794A639121F316A7D16F41"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Committee discharge</header><text>In the Senate, if the committee to which is referred a joint resolution of disapproval has not reported such joint resolution (or an identical joint resolution) at the end of 20 calendar days after the date on which the President invokes the authorities that are the subject of the joint resolution of disapproval, such committee may be discharged from further consideration of such joint resolution upon a petition supported in writing by 30 Members of the Senate, and such joint resolution shall be placed on the calendar.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9843F9F6D87E4E36B31643677CD60B4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Floor consideration</header> 
<subparagraph id="H45028EDD5775426B8E9DFD1FA8C0A1A4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>In the Senate, when the committee to which a joint resolution of disapproval is referred has reported, or when a committee is discharged (under paragraph (1)) from further consideration of, a joint resolution of disapproval, it is at any time thereafter in order (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) for a motion to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion is not subject to amendment, or to a motion to postpone, or to a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution is agreed to, the joint resolution shall remain the unfinished business of the Senate until disposed of.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7D436F2375440869657D1B74065B5D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>In the Senate, debate on a joint resolution of disapproval, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between those favoring and those opposing the joint resolution. A motion further to limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution is not in order.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A3228249242497294BEDEB06D26D2B6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vote on final passage</header><text>In the Senate, immediately following the conclusion of the debate on a joint resolution of disapproval, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate, the vote on final passage of the joint resolution shall occur.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAEB6561C2FD54ED880055CF9FB3E0E70"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Appeals from decisions of the Chair</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate to the procedure relating to a joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H758C5BDA6E8845E3BE175F58660E2D23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Time for consideration</header><text>In the Senate, the procedures specified in this subsection shall not apply to the consideration of a joint resolution of disapproval after the expiration of the period of 60 session days beginning on the date on which the President invokes the authorities that are the subject of the joint resolution.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H118B43B7077247EF9E2FF7A462DD945B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consideration of resolution of other House</header><text>If, before the passage by one House of a joint resolution of disapproval of that House, that House receives from the other House a joint resolution of disapproval, then the following procedures shall apply:</text> 
<paragraph id="H056EF69AE20E489AA37917F5AEE2EABC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The joint resolution of the other House shall not be referred to a committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8073D676F9704CF4961070AF2FE86291"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to a joint resolution of the House receiving the joint resolution—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDF33064274A04FE7BA6D7DFAF87D6B8A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the procedure in that House shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the other House; but</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF15E3428B09E4690A59E9FA6A48C711C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the vote on final passage shall be on the joint resolution of the other House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0BC3E947054F461898489E6155F985AC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rules of Senate and House of Representatives</header><text>This section is enacted by Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H0ACD05FC58C0468381F727D30BE200BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, and as such it is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution of disapproval, and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA627CAF11AB54BE9AAF8AB8E61852AC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

