<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9238F17837F64A168D042EB14BB38497" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8356 IH: Flores Settlement Update and Establishment Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8356</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000755">Mr. Brady</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 with respect to minor children, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H00F490C5CF3246FC9FAC827DD27E2DAC" style="OLC"><section id="HA5A21295A44A4DF9A74D4BAF3DDEF915" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flores Settlement Update and Establishment Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD89214FEDA6D4BC7976495A81534E8EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Holding and processing of minor children</header><subsection id="H9B196D6FEFA54A9BA30E9CDFB93D4204"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Treatment of minor children</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act the Secretary of Homeland Security shall: </text><paragraph id="H08E313C44C244D0C8C09E30C9EB69437"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Permit a minor child to be held by the Secretary of Homeland Security for not more than 120 days prior to being transferred to the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD363C845783425EB92D795CCC197862"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Require each member of a family unit seeking asylum at the United States-Mexico border to take a DNA test, within 72 hours of such family unit encountering the U.S. Customs and Border Protection, to ensure that the minor children and an adult of the family unit are first-degree or second-degree relatives (as described in section 1635.3 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H531D77A6D17F4F8FA289DE17F8DC39B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Require the detention and segregation, at the same site, of minor children and each adult in a family unit until evidence of a familial relationship is established pursuant to paragraph (2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98F775C3E7DA48D690579886A28D32B3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Segregate unaccompanied alien children from non-related adults. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FF76D95FCF940789EC7874F0FA53825"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Segregate unaccompanied alien children who are prepubescent from post-pubescent unaccompanied alien children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB36E8D44D4BD4AC0B868D579C6D2DB07"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Segregate a family unit from other populations at the same facility.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E29F5C607AF43858F18BB719BB2B5CD"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Require that the Commissioner of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection provide each minor child:</text><subparagraph id="HAB85C5FD33F64FCFB34BFB204581A9EB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilities that are safe and sanitary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D633BA4C0D1490AB386EADFC2BFF514"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Access to toilets, sinks, and hygiene facilities where non-related adults are not present at the time of use.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H471FB8937A0B4B8794EC52C0100CF175"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Access to drinking water and food.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5334358B8C864C28BB363E07C0D76241"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Access to appropriate medical assistance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4D4C64686394B119295C2CCDEB64138"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Facilities that have adequate temperature control and ventilation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H935FDAACC3B443D4BBE230201F0B1E7A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Adequate supervision to protect the minor child.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F7384F0797C4B1CA2FC8A352D6DDF5A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prosecution of certain adults</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that minor child and adult, presenting as a family unit, are not first-degree or second-degree relatives (as described in section 1635.3 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto)) pursuant to the DNA test required under subsection (a)(2), the adult shall be referred to the Attorney General for appropriate action under—</text><paragraph id="H352D741C2B274D7B85F0A1C903971E90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 1201 of title 18, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ED7A2CA99414C0988E010395B698971"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 274 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324">8 U.S.C. 1324</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1516B259EA5D461BB80979B9FED87511"><enum>(3)</enum><text>section 2422 of title 18, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F640449B90841BAAEB9B4683147D3AC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>section 1591 of title 18, United States Code; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA9BD38CF2ED4E3891EC820C11C995EE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other Federal law determined by the Attorney General to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3463ED4665C420D819EA082EB013854"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of unaccompanied alien child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 235(b)(3) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>72 hours</quote> and inserting <quote>120 days</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H5DFF846AAB36478B85167884256B75C1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Release of unaccompanied alien child</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 235(c)(3) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(c)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE9E3F0722C3E4A499444587182D9DC21" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H941C65AE48FA45ABABFB1482B2608F61"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Additional requirements for proposed custodians</header><clause id="H89057ABA198F48DB97D0265FB79CFD4A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Lawful presence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An unaccompanied alien child may not be placed with a proposed custodian unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, determines that such custodian is lawfully present in the United States.</text></clause><clause id="H7EE359F017574EB29299C1FD44777FC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Familial relation</header><text>An unaccompanied alien child may not be placed with a proposed custodian unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, determines that such custodian is a first-degree or second-degree relative of the unaccompanied alien child as defined in section 1635.3 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor thereto).</text></clause><clause id="HBA25C9C6F29449148A9BD241B23F113F"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Criminal conviction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An unaccompanied alien child may not be placed with a proposed custodian unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, determines that such custodian has not been convicted, or have a charge pending at the time of consideration of being a proposed custodian, for a crime of violence (as defined by section 16 of title 18, United States Code), a sexual offense, an offense with respect to human trafficking, or kidnapping (as described in section 1201 of title 18, United States Code) at the Federal, State, or local level.</text></clause><clause id="H65975D91725B4B8B80596B433E2D37ED"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this subparagraph:</text><subclause id="H32F86A44BD9645EF95054ADC227D2F2C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Crime of violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>crime of violence</quote> shall have the meaning given such term in section 16 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6295D5B447944136B99BA55A1DD0A3FE"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Sexual offense</header><text>The term <quote>sexual offense</quote> means an act described in subsections (a) through (d) of section 920, title 10, United States Code.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF8FC76DD4D6B4F2C9452B3B74BF781C3"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Offense with respect to human trafficking</header><text>The term <quote>offense with respect to human trafficking</quote> means—</text><item id="H97A6FDA4BAFC41819C28B13026E85319" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>sex trafficking in which a commercial sex act is induced by force, fraud, or coercion, or in which the person induced to perform such act has not attained 18 years of age; or</text></item><item id="H241EEEFAEBA448B3BEE2D378657FBF3A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the recruitment, harboring, transportation, provision, or obtaining of a person for labor or services, through the use of force, fraud, or coercion for the purpose of subjection to involuntary servitude, peonage, debt bondage, or slavery.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB83DA9025C2C45C79E172311533EF808"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Age determinations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 235(b)(4) of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE78BF5D9CA324A359D80CB61335BA939"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation</quote> and inserting: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEE6F2C85383348BE93DBD70D1C2FF5D8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H14C397F34C5740659BF357D4950756FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC64FC3771D814D70AE9F4A519F17C2E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4069B37E9C634E22A956FFC05B7E2B67" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H121A5D48F7A64E05B195837982EFAD55"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><clause id="H0691372BD5AE40CFA07A89BB2BB6AC50"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reasonable person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph may be construed—</text><subclause id="HA8DD0F3A95F54CA7ADE5C737242ABE74"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to prevent the Secretary of Homeland Security from treating an alien who claims to be a minor, but for whom the Commissioner of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection reasonably concludes is an adult, as an adult; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H16B0E490D4044DF696204FEC974451E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prevent the Commissioner of the U.S. Customs and Border Protection from segregating a minor child from other minor children if they reasonably conclude such minor child is a threat to other minor children.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBBEE6217593D41C98C2AE9A3A9E49657"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Display of certain affiliation</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to prevent the Secretary of Homeland Security from treating a minor child who has a tattoo or other means of affiliation, including jewelry, medallion, or other item, to a known gang, cartel, or other transnational criminal organizations as an adult. </text></clause><clause id="H4621CF0DE9554E0DB4D816D20711771A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Transnational criminal organization defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>transnational criminal organization</quote> means a self-perpetuating association of individuals who operate, wholly or in part, by illegal means and irrespective of geography. </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30D55240E94C4483BC1BDAB09936F308"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriation</header><paragraph id="HC449FCE3922B4CF2A8ACEC6EA346CFDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>DNA testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out the DNA testing required under subsection (a)(2) $35,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available through September 30, 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBCCC65C2D1A47D4A8C451F950910E71"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for the construction of permanent structures, leased spaces, and contracted staffing for the purposes described in subsection (a)(1) $115,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available through September 30, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

