<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9FBD45146D1548F8BBE49C425EDBF74F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9550 IH: Taking Action to Prevent Suicide Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9550</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000473">Mrs. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a task force on the prevention of suicide by U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8CB8C1DEAA03490E99FC4234A7EA983C" style="OLC"><section id="HE6BDABE68B7E48D2A0EAFE9E4C3C4C0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taking Action to Prevent Suicide Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TAPS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HADC4312F92B04AD4A5499D7918330471"><enum>2.</enum><header>Task force on the prevention of suicide by U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel</header><subsection id="HDEE3E82D640A4202B6CAA14398542954" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) shall jointly establish a task force to examine matters relating to prevention of suicide by U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5FC40910E2A3411887FEDB9F92826626"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header><paragraph id="HA9C49E85CA9345129027933FDBC53D18" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>The task force established in accordance with subsection (a) shall consist of not more than 14 members appointed by the Commissioner of CBP from among individuals described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FB60EDA5BB24AAEA036F849B3A70604"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>The individuals described in this paragraph are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEDA1E8A943CE490A9DC1ACFC3F9FD1BC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>At least one CBP agent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FC0574ACED14D568EC41ADC7279DEA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Deputy Commissioner of CBP.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H230117643DF148E6AB009014456A1F62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Chief of the U.S. Border Patrol.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FBF1C40CCBE4D31B89EB1BE027CC124"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner of Air and Marine Operations of CBP.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61183117309C4DB6BAA24D35877BFBA0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Executive Assistant Commissioner of Field Operations of CBP.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H516C094365CC4BBBA9EEB480478CFFCE" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one member of the National Border Patrol Council.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CE900BEC8E14CA690A111976387B3D9"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one member of the National Treasury Employees Union.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48EE5D5DBB34465B3771DE6AB4A4061" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Abuse of the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD6CE66C66A4E5E8EF53F927F38DD2A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Persons who have experience in the following:</text><clause id="H056FDA982C1E43AFAB8C38699ACB99A5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>National suicide prevention policy.</text></clause><clause id="H30EB7B8D03644621859933CBCF0B3CDF" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>CBP personnel policy.</text></clause><clause id="H133C9489E207498789D26DE93C2CEEFE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Research in the field of suicide prevention.</text></clause><clause id="H0DB817EA4F1749DAB5DE3783AE6389F0" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Clinical care in mental health.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFB12A8E73E34DBD9A8824C6FC7EA679" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>At least one family member of a CBP Customs Officer who has experience working with families of CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB2E579F3FE247D9905A69B7C99C1C88"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one family member of a U.S. Border Patrol agent who has experience working with families of CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DBB64E921914B34819677AD24C3869F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>To the greatest extent practicable, the Commissioner of CBP and the Secretary of HHS shall make every effort to ensure there is an equal representation of Federal and non-Federal members of the task force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE57FF3ECEDF84A58BBDCC80C611BD0C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deadline for appointment</header><text>All appointments of individuals to the task force shall be made not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BE5C44ED41543FF85349E7A369AA49E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Co-chairs of task force</header><text>There shall be two co-chairs of the task force, as follows:</text><subparagraph id="H27B8DA609E1B4EBDACD1FF5778BF4FB6" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One of the co-chairs shall be designated from among CBP personnel members. Such designation shall be made by the Commissioner of CBP at the time of appointment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD3B19F3F289498AA69C27F332C2D0FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>One of the co-chairs shall be designated from among non-CBP personnel members. Such designation shall be made by such non-CBP personnel members.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H061DD70B39B44EAEB36689F46D3C91E4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessment and recommendations on suicide prevention policy</header><paragraph id="H12736B0081E24FBABDD58242CA54BAE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date on which all personnel of the task force have been appointed, the task force shall submit to the Commissioner of CBP a report containing recommendations (including recommendations for legislative or administrative action) regarding a comprehensive policy designed to prevent suicide by CBP personnel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F76AB7CC8E947B18A0A44CD8A193A72"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Utilization of other efforts</header><text>In preparing the report required under paragraph (1), the task force shall take into consideration completed and ongoing efforts by CBP to improve the efficacy of suicide prevention programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B6B2A6083F04DB689FFD12F5F1C3C65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The recommendations referred to in paragraph (1) shall include measures to address the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEA7287C0F1C44BDC8CECE9B900642158"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Methods to identify trends and common causal factors in suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF19A318AB9594214A51F142057DFC2C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Methods to establish or update suicide education and prevention programs conducted by CBP based on identified trends and causal factors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE59245BEAAB84C14862D9CF71B4536EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of current suicide education and prevention programs of CBP.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33A904D594F9426BB30D0945D8064624" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of current mental health education programs and services available to CBP personnel, and the significance of any stigma with respect to such programs and services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0ED01CC7A1B4BD88E7D6F227B227F1F" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of suicide incidence by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96B90917E198450E8F3C1C6EBB3BA6E1" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The appropriate type and method of investigation to determine the causes and factors surrounding each suicide by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7B02123936A478CB151FA892B43F7E1" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The qualifications of individuals appointed to conduct an investigations of suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA24E7E6EA9014D1DB8282B50129B55CB" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The information required by an investigation to determine the causes and factors regarding suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9F67C3439904AB7987C76B563377056" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The appropriate reporting requirements after the conclusions of investigations conducted on suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F8A1D2FD686409E924265EBFA9B9E77" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The appropriate official or executive agent within the Department of Homeland Security to receive and analyze reports on investigations of suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD6F3D187FE4405FB1DE041E2B70C3C8" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The appropriate use of the information gathered during investigations of suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H856FFCCF3F1E4899A8D32DDBC8568514" commented="no"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Methods for protecting confidentiality of information contained in reports of investigations of suicides by CBP personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H452629069E0748C4B8FD41FC532B8A25"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative matters</header><paragraph id="HBE07E1778CB64A3A866D00D1E8EBC250" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Each member of the task force who is a Federal employee shall serve without compensation. Non-Federal members of the task force shall be treated for purposes of section 3161 of title 5, United States Code, as having been appointed under subsection (b) of such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7476A4E27CE846D391A985D555FAC453" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Commissioner of CBP and the Secretary of HHS shall oversee the activities of the task force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E2E843B6B94394AD92166FACF8FD13" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner of CBP and the Secretary of HHS shall provide the task force with such personnel, facilities, and other administrative support as may be necessary for the performance of the duties of the task force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8366EB6D61A42A6B4208185B36D15E9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H3289D99417034E15B425754596205AAF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the appointment of all individuals to the task force, the task force shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security a report on its activities under this section. The report shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFC0480363B844F169AAF99400475507B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the activities of the task force.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD107F761888C41B0BA8C64855AB1F07F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The assessment and recommendations required under subsection (c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8BB436A3D044855B0A7803D35551FEB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Such other matters relating to the activities of the task force that the task force considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H07ADC06AAFDD43D18CE950BA6D0CCE70"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transmittal to Congress</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receipt of the report under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall transmit the report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate. The Secretary may include in the transmittal such comments regarding the report as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD85D91C3826341549B375C3901D077D9" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after receipt of the report under subsection (e)(1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall develop a plan based on the assessments and recommendations of the task force and submit such plan to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H034C8B83B4164612AE30A7321901ABB2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the report of the task force is submitted to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate pursuant to subsection (e)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H87E870F157E44408B583AD3F9FEAD5B4"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

