<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA1C5EF77677B4CFD97E18553A064CF39" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8680 IH: Greater Mental Health Access Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8680</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a special enrollment period for family members of an individual who has died by suicide, to establish a competitive grant program to provide services and support to friends and family members impacted by an individual’s suicide, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE95365850FEE4990929A722E7E46BA9E" style="OLC"><section id="H8403684C73E04C3B88392F182B8BB5E9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Greater Mental Health Access Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5A813B67C5294CE987C1E6684FBDEE84"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6D8B6F56B017417294B59F026C427A90"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">One in five adults in America experience some form of mental illness, and nearly one in twenty-five adults live with serious mental illness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C8205BD5B29479791CD075429EC0551"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Access to mental health services is a particularly pervasive problem; 28 million residents of the United States are uninsured and have no access to mental health services. Studies show that nearly 60 percent of adults and 50 percent of children with a mental illness did not receive mental health services in the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C163800589C43C3BFFEC2507A180A02"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The lack of access to mental health services has, in part, contributed to an increase in the suicide rate in the United States, which is now the tenth leading cause of death in this country.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04E52A5911B844FC9B118DDC9B4841BB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2017, 47,173 Americans died by suicide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1134079F9B2045FCBA8AB73A87F6E0C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In 2017, there were an estimated 1,400,000 suicide attempts in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H215B4F37A128415EB64448C1C91E935C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Suicide by a loved one often results in <quote>suicide contagion</quote>; for surviving family and friends the risk of attempting suicide increases by 65 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5473053C06E94220BB8CD93B2668199E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Family and friends who lost a loved one to suicide are 80 percent more likely to drop out of school or stop working.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H156F508E20D847D5ABBB3C2118F740AE"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Access to mental health services is important to mitigate suicide, suicide contagion, and bereavement. Access to care also reduces the financial burden for individuals in need of mental health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE9D9B6F5192415EAF81455CDDF2F558"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act has increased access to mental health services, but there is still a large population that is uninsured or has insufficient coverage to seek mental health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3933F316393D42ECA2AEED7C0FF7A3FE"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Family and friends who have lost a loved one to suicide should not face hurdles when attempting to access mental health services. As such, a suicide or suicide attempt should constitute a <quote>qualifying life event</quote> for any individual who is eligible to enroll, but is not enrolled, in a health benefit plan under the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H93F3E04E920D4E8FA69FD3FB459EC28C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Providing for a special enrollment period for family members of individuals who have committed suicide</header><subsection id="HE1FACA9E31E448A0A21F3CF20A8A8317"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public Health Service Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2702(b)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-1">42 U.S.C. 300gg–1(b)(2)</external-xref> is amended by inserting <quote>including a special enrollment period for family members of individuals who have died by suicide, allowing them to enroll in, or change, their health care plan, beginning on the date on which the suicide is reported to the health insurance issuer</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD84FA7D619064220807CEFDB240592CD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act</header><text>Section 1311(c)(6) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18031">42 U.S.C. 18031(c)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H449C790F97264B3CAD21A3D152E4B420"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DD667A725264E72A6A4DFEF22D6083A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (E); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE28EF1E0453A4C4D9BA5AE2B135E7610"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1B8A074F8BD94B19A76DC3E0584A1908" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H1B368666E3B24E6CBF20070AAC37864D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a special enrollment period for family members of individuals who have died by suicide, beginning on the date on which the suicide is reported to the Exchange; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3987B6479FEC4D8FAB8F8BF909AB6492"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special Enrollment Periods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9801">Section 9801(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9801">26 U.S.C. 9801(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5F9F63210E5C44D1B3F3A144C39290CA" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H6306E0F1D32046AC850CA5134170BB53"><enum>(4)</enum><header>For family members of individuals who have died by suicide</header><subparagraph id="H68D5A4987CFA4F0C96C32CE3502FA59B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A group health plan shall permit an employee who is eligible, but not enrolled, for coverage under the terms of the plan (or a dependent of such an employee if the dependent is eligible, but not enrolled, for coverage under such terms) to enroll for coverage under the terms of the plan upon the suicide of a family member, with the special enrollment period beginning on the date on which the suicide is reported to the group health plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6627C2C10BD4AF0AF0A4AC9AA83829B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall promulgate regulations with respect to the special enrollment period under subparagraph (A), including establishing a time period for family members of an individual who has died by suicide to enroll in coverage or change coverage, and effective date of such coverage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEA53A4AD65364D749DBCEC401415C5C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal Employees’ Health Benefits Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements imposed by the amendments made by subsections (a), (b), and (c) of this section shall apply to any plan provided under the Federal Employees’ Health Benefits Program (<external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code).</text></subsection><subsection id="HFD72169F4481482A8A98B284D042DC92"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective Date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to plan years beginning after the date of enactment.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5DDA6999FAC14F2E838A78D2532B3420"><enum>4.</enum><header>Outpatient mental health services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part B of title V of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 520E–4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-36d">42 U.S.C. 290bb–36d</external-xref>) the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF20C3F37DAC442BBEFBEB6BE905C403" style="OLC"><section id="H255233A53A474B729AB3C4CB93E49AB2"><enum>520E–5</enum><header>Outpatient mental health services</header><subsection id="H58532DB715C7428CBBE1991BDB4911EA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, shall award grants to medical providers, hospitals, clinics, not-for-profit organizations, and religious organizations, to provide outpatient mental health services for individuals impacted by the attempted or completed suicide of a friend or family member.</text></subsection><subsection id="H91E3078272B74CC5BCDC275AF97937B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transfer of funds</header><text>Of the unobligated balance of the amount appropriated under section 4002 of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act, the Secretary shall transfer $6,000,000 to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2B7517053BCB46E0B5F799C2B577E26B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the implementation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H629BA1B0EE234D9B86CC17060B51B287"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Outpatient mental health services</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>outpatient mental health services</quote> includes each of the following services:</text><paragraph id="H96CA02F9E0EC47EEB610E3B8D9BC27EE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Short-term counseling.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B5C6B49B3A14AD3A069F1AF813DF6F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Referral services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DB7B96D727D4F25AA60B1882FDA510B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Follow-up services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

