<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3180A998DF1A428DA84950D314C23812" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7073 IH: Into the Light for Maternal Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7073</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220315">March 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to reauthorize a grant program for screening, assessment, and treatment services for maternal mental health and substance use disorders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5FC66DC919F7408793954BB2AA7F1258" style="OLC"><section id="H85AF5B5EE499439D86345B383B6F80A9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Into the Light for Maternal Mental Health and Substance Use Disorders Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Into the Light for MMH and SUD Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H935F7CDB1CC243D795195FA6CB7D7408"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HE6B6C5E0517F42BDB0D7E2A766BA9F9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Maternal mental health conditions are the most common complications of pregnancy and childbirth, affecting 1 in 5 women or 800,000 women annually, during pregnancy or the year following pregnancy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21AC18FD5FE14E018A2DC70134C29DED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Maternal mental health and substance use disorders contribute to the high rate of maternal mortality in the United States, with suicide and drug overdose combined being the leading cause of death for women in the first year following pregnancy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H646962F26AD04859B0C50436822818F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Women who experience racial and economic inequities are 3 to 4 times more likely to be impacted by maternal mental health and other behavioral health disorders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H838872548F1145A293AF14BF19DF53C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Untreated maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders can have long-term negative impacts on the mother, baby, family, and society.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BCB5A8F46EA40E39C6AE025A9D5A06E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Mothers with untreated mental health conditions during pregnancy are more likely to have poor nutrition and struggle with substance use disorders, which can lead to poor birth outcomes for the baby.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H059D8FB0E4264C1AAD74B14DC8B61EE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Untreated maternal mental health conditions and substance use disorders can contribute to—</text><subparagraph id="H0C051EAC39BB46CC911BE6978F13FAE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>impaired parent-child interactions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD41DE726F7E4DE6AF3EF1892ED80476"><enum>(B)</enum><text>behavioral, cognitive, or emotional delays in the child; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1373603A9E2437FB14BDE177CE101BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>adverse childhood experiences that can negatively impact the child’s life.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD141D4E830C44B29937475568A1C1BBC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Untreated maternal mental health conditions are estimated to cost the United States economy $14,000,000,000 or $32,000 per mother-infant pair every year in addressing poor health outcomes and accounting for lost wages and productivity of the mother.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA34B64054CED41E399D314E109B898A8"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Although the United States Preventive Services Task Force and several national medical organizations encourage health care providers to screen and treat maternal mental health conditions, 75 percent of women impacted remain untreated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC45DDD87A5AA4D408172D39685CDA797"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Frontline providers who care for women during pregnancy and the first year following pregnancy are often reluctant to screen for maternal mental health conditions, citing lack of education, insurance reimbursement, and resources for affected women.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4755961D493D4F7D96CA042EB714345D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Screening and treatment for a maternal mental health and substance use disorders</header><subsection id="H7CDE7EFF43E4456F9BE3C216C93F8371"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 317L–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H91DDC88E161B484C82F71AF42FEBF1C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">maternal depression</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">maternal mental health and substance use disorders</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CB26929BFE844D2B0C70BA6DB426C33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H1BCF8F67E0A749289C028776AE8FD74C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, Indian Tribes and Tribal Organizations (as such terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act), and Urban Indian organizations (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act)</quote> after <quote>States</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F5BB3CE2FA048AE97EE5D96E1F54082"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>for women who are pregnant, or who have given birth within the preceding 12 months, for maternal depression</quote> and inserting <quote>for women who are postpartum, pregnant, or have given birth within the preceding 12 months, for maternal mental health and substance use disorders</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F78FCEED43045B78978FDCB4837AEFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 317L–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB0EC9169DB624DEE985D7295063B5EAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a State shall submit</quote> and inserting <quote>an entity listed in subsection (a) shall submit</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09CB20E8CF464A2D933333504ECCF71C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraphs (1) and (2), by striking <quote>maternal depression</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>maternal mental health and substance use disorders</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H632AC2D77605440D8133FBDAF1E1F85F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 317L–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4E1452F684004444BE6CD567A5ED172C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>may give priority to States proposing to improve or enhance access to screening</quote> and inserting the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC16390BA75824F0FAEC611D77677AE2E" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>shall give priority to entities listed in subsection (a) that—</text><paragraph id="H612AE927BA884A6E885DAD72AC1B764D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are proposing to create, improve, or enhance screening, prevention, and treatment</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H221FCDA3DF424C65BF7DD8B86751CDB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>maternal depression</quote> and inserting <quote>maternal mental health and substance use disorders</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FBF1EE1E4B44EE385C1B3AA2B8B91A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of paragraph (1), as so designated, and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCCC2CFDD58A42F1B883122667425276"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after such paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC17DA7F5E39F4E07B7E6BF7796683EF3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H445F08CD151E45219945485DBB9BDE3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are currently partnered with, or will partner with, a community-based organization to address maternal mental health and substance use disorders;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H526CCAA775E14FE980099FBEDC64EA9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are located in an area with high rates of adverse maternal health outcomes or significant health, economic, racial, or ethnic disparities in maternal health and substance use disorder outcomes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB871176998C14102B552EB2147276742"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operate in a health professional shortage area designated under section 332.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02D3E17B420C4001BCF9044C976EB9A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 317L–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4D05EDBA0A0F429684DABBEAC43BB817"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H7ED338E63D3145E88CFB3FAE3C848963"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>to health care providers; and</quote> and inserting <quote>on maternal mental health and substance use disorder screening, brief intervention, treatment (as applicable for health care providers), and referrals for treatment to health care providers in the primary care setting and nonclinical perinatal support workers;</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98DDF33323F44500AA0067833D20FB1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>to health care providers, including information on maternal depression screening, treatment, and followup support services, and linkages to community-based resources; and</quote> and inserting <quote>on maternal mental health and substance use disorder screening, brief intervention, treatment (as applicable for health care providers) and referrals for treatment, followup support services, and linkages to community-based resources to health care providers in the primary care setting and clinical perinatal support workers; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF76B079C2D474E50A5D6EBB5787AC02F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H671B5F26899541B8820E7349B916FD77" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H1ADEEDBE28FB4E57AFBFBA803FBCC69B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enabling health care providers (such as obstetrician-gynecologists, nurse practitioners, nurse midwives, pediatricians, psychiatrists, mental and other behavioral health care providers, and adult primary care clinicians) to provide or receive real-time psychiatric consultation (in-person or remotely), including through the use of technology-enabled collaborative learning and capacity building models (as defined in section 330N), to aid in the treatment of pregnant and postpartum women; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4CC0F413EFD4F4F931FCD6FE4FE4475"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H1E74540D20F94B09B478A180DE18806B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (A) and redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8821A04AB6E5493C827EBC23A24BBADA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as redesignated, by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54CAC680B1FB46D5B789CE97C374B42A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), as redesignated—</text><clause id="H247857DA30DA44CFAF090F2EE1856527"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, including</quote> before <quote>for rural areas</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H053C35DBC61E4DD9BC76AB55316D5806"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB84F66A5C9C4E4E9636DA08EF485AD0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B), as redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5F83CDE038664BDEBACB86E0A6BC37D2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H28A10D446B1540EBAEEC83BE7F3033E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing assistance to pregnant and postpartum women to receive maternal mental health and substance use disorder treatment, including patient consultation, care coordination, and navigation for such treatment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4977FA79D422438B97E39B71381CC2FF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating with maternal and child health programs of the Federal Government and State, local, and Tribal governments, including child psychiatric access programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1836F73F2035476FA58D61593771CF81"><enum>(E)</enum><text>conducting public outreach and awareness regarding grants under subsection (a);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB80DC4461EC54A8F824E38DAF5E65CC6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>creating multi-State consortia to carry out the activities required or authorized under this subsection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H528C7FDEDA934BA4A48CB413845FF8C9"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training health care providers in the primary care setting and nonclinical perinatal support workers on trauma-informed care, culturally and linguistically appropriate services, and best practices related to training to improve the provision of maternal mental health and substance use disorder care for racial and ethnic minority populations, including with respect to perceptions and biases that may affect the approach to, and provision of, care.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF82A07E569684535AB3278307BD9AE85"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 317L–1 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDA0429BF86FF436EA5EC232500901346"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (h); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12E90641140041598AA8045651DF305F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA9BACA9FC6C545789B7818170862D83D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H2B3DEC9F7A804C1DB0712DC270FA8A20"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to grantees and entities listed in subsection (a) for carrying out activities pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDAFAEEAB4CE84A10977CA69F345A529A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Dissemination of best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, based on evaluation of the activities funded pursuant to this section, shall identify and disseminate evidence-based or evidence-informed best practices for screening, assessment, and treatment services for maternal mental health and substance use disorders, including culturally and linguistically appropriate services, for women during pregnancy and 12 months following pregnancy.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1DBCFD29CC104A2A92D9346849EE23DA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of the activities for which a grant is made to an entity under subsection (a) shall not exceed 90 percent of the total cost of such activities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84A8137C63114F2CBDCFB0FEA5510C21"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Subsection (h) of section 317L–1 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-13a">42 U.S.C. 247b–13a</external-xref>) of the Public Health Service Act, as redesignated, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HB3F6BA5F0FF841818ADD5F0A7A2405BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>$5,000,000</quote> and inserting <quote>$24,000,000</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D6A7372721402E8DEF20BA4759E6A3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>2018 through 2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2023 through 2028</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HECA1C3C1FC6B44789D82757104F6005B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Maternal mental health hotline</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9BFAF5694C4643C4BB0944ABF2FE422D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HE3165C6B5DF541E8A24C139DDF4524E8"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Maternal mental health hotline</header><subsection id="HE8A88A8271124A68A473C53956C97FAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall maintain, directly or by grant or contract, a national hotline to provide emotional support, information, brief intervention, and mental health and substance use disorder resources to pregnant and postpartum women at risk of, or affected by, maternal mental health and substance use disorders, and to their families or household members. </text></subsection><subsection id="H4B2778A258F84A05A46E831DB000CE47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for hotline</header><text>The hotline under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H0585E74418454FE59D6D5FEB654834AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be a 24/7 real-time hotline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67DE1CC6E6654DA68047CB02C2862BE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide voice and text support;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30F34BC477BE44E5A3CEFB67AFFB4C40"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be staffed by certified peer specialists, licensed health care professionals, or licensed mental health professionals who are trained on—</text><subparagraph id="HD6EB056009614DB297B29B30B78AD9D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maternal mental health and substance use disorder prevention, identification, and intervention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15F3CE24998B495B9C1F1C37B795E648"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing culturally and linguistically appropriate support; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80FB8DC30A8D4541BE981DF0399EF5BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide maternal mental health and substance use disorder assistance and referral services to meet the needs of underserved populations, individuals with disabilities, and family and household members of pregnant or postpartum women at risk of experiencing maternal mental health and substance use disorders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13B1B465C5CB4B62A9F757C9F8EC25BF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>In maintaining the hotline under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HA8ABBCDBDC444CEDBB57C2BE0C9D2E52"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with the Domestic Violence Hotline, National Suicide Prevention Lifeline, and Veterans Crisis Line to ensure that pregnant and postpartum women are connected in real-time to the appropriate specialized hotline service, when applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7846D7763B654F27A6E14272693DEAF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct a public awareness campaign for the hotline; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46D63776B9D04A91AF813B4B87196626"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with Federal departments and agencies, including the Centers of Excellence of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration and the Department of Veterans Affairs, to increase awareness regarding the hotline. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B462383AE9749589E6A16F6ADD33CD4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall submit an annual report to the Congress on the hotline under subsection (a) and implementation of this section, including—</text><paragraph id="H64385889013048C688E5FC8EA29564A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an evaluation of the effectiveness of activities conducted or supported under subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53DC57E832FE41E2BF4E156F5999FC23"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a directory of entities or organizations to which staff maintaining the hotline funded under this section may make referrals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA08A40BA14D5455985B566D8E2924F1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such additional information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B8934A89EC14C748365E61961FEF726"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

