<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7CFC28B0C8D649FFAAB4B204EABC4866" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8711 IH: United States-Ecuador Partnership Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8711</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220812">August 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen the bilateral partnership between the United States and Ecuador in support of democratic institutions and rule of law, sustainable and inclusive economic growth, and conservation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA4B8C61E6FF841119CCB4ACB2AAC94D9"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HCCF020C32E9B4F2992B32CB1A1876EA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Ecuador Partnership Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F5D632E57894CCBB90AF2E1821E0428"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows: </text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 4. Facilitating economic and commercial ties.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 5. Promoting inclusive economic development.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 6. Combating illicit economies, corruption, and negative foreign influence.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 7. Strengthening democratic governance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 8. Fostering conservation and stewardship.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H77A525F97FB34D029D076A0B08DEBE7F">Sec. 9. Authorization to transfer excess Coast Guard vessels.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 10. Reporting requirements.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA387FEAC850143C5A7278C660C13DCF2">Sec. 11. Sunset.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HD458541957514D45A1097EA4A194E5B6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><subsection id="HB57EE376BBD24B40B93F78DAB2C5F478"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H13A7110789564EDCA6B6916287ACAC77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The United States and Ecuador have a history of bilateral cooperation grounded in mutual respect, shared democratic values, and mutual security interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83C9E02B529543C7B493172346DAADA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On February 7, 2021, and April 11, 2021, Ecuador held democratic elections that included parties from across the political spectrum, paving the way for continued progress towards strengthening democratic institutions. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F4E1542C7E042ADBF9E3B7CD741D900"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United States and Ecuador share strategic interests in strengthening Ecuador’s democratic institutions, generating inclusive economic growth, and building capacity in law enforcement, anti-corruption, and conservation efforts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5606F36DB754472E8491560E72966B73"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States and Ecuador historically have enjoyed strong commercial, investment, and economic ties, yet Ecuador continues to face significant challenges to inclusive economic development, including—</text><subparagraph id="H14B0794C83094EA8BECAE712036CEA4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the heavy economic toll of the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B1DBA13AA0A4C8FBD603C34A69C44BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>vulnerabilities with respect to the growing role of the People’s Republic of China in the financing and refinancing of Ecuador’s debts, and in strategic infrastructure projects and sectors of the Ecuadorian economy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2F0D15B63734D0F82AB57D0BB63F0D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the need to develop and strengthen open and transparent economic policies that strengthen Ecuador’s integration with global markets, inclusive economic growth, and opportunities for upward social mobility for the Ecuadorian people.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78B1FEFCCE004D42921CFA59C23B8DE4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Since its establishment in December 2019, the United States Development Finance Corporation has provided more than $440,000,000 in financing to Ecuador. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD2681080754CB5A9F7F1BA22B8D319"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Ecuador’s justice system has taken important steps to fight corruption and criminality and to increase accountability. However, enduring challenges to the rule of law in Ecuador, including the activities of transnational criminal organizations, illicit mining, illegal, unreported, and unregulated (IUU) fishing, and undemocratic actors, present ongoing risks for political and social stability in Ecuador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4AD12105EA4934A870040575E2B99A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The activities undertaken by the Government of the People’s Republic of China in Ecuador, including its development of the ECU–911 video surveillance and facial recognition system, financing of the corruptly managed and environmentally deleterious Coca Codo Sinclair Dam, and support for illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing practices around the Galapagos Islands, pose risks to democratic governance and biodiversity in the country. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C08577B7417401FAB451ADDDDBCC285"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Ecuador, which is home to several of the Earth’s most biodiverse ecosystems, including the Galapagos Islands, the headwaters of the Amazon river, the Condor mountain range, and the Yasuni Biosphere Reserve, has seen a reduction in its rainforests between 1990 and 2016, due in part to the incursion of criminal networks into protected areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C61923E08684B6F90DC6EB1A21F0611"><enum>(9)</enum><text>On March 24, 2021, the Senate unanimously approved Senate Resolution 22 (117th Congress), reaffirming the partnership between the United States and the Republic of Ecuador, and recognizing the restoration and advancement of economic relations, security, and development opportunities in both nations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07F287BDC1854F7CA1163F10DACEC41F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>On August 13, 2021, the United States and Ecuador celebrated the entry into force of the Protocol to the Trade and Investment Council Agreement between the Government of the United States of America and the Government of the Republic of Ecuador Relating to Trade Rules and Transparency, recognizing the steps Ecuador has taken to decrease unnecessary regulatory burden and create a more transparent and predictable legal framework for foreign direct investment in recent years. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H285295ADAC0943A5AAD8AE4C1C75A216"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H27B3C4DC222C41DE91148D288F839692"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should take additional steps to strengthen its bilateral partnership with Ecuador, including by developing robust trade and investment frameworks, increasing law enforcement cooperation, renewing the activities of the United States Agency for International Development in Ecuador, and supporting Ecuador's response to and recovery from the COVID–19 pandemic, as necessary and appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9951DA8107AC498ABD5354B8CAD7D267"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthening the United States-Ecuador partnership presents an opportunity to advance core United States national security interests and work with other democratic partners to maintain a prosperous, politically stable, and democratic Western Hemisphere that is resilient to malign foreign influence.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2E6DBD11670D4B119B779492D359AFDC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Facilitating economic and commercial ties</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, the United States Trade Representative, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall develop and implement a strategy to strengthen commercial and economic ties between the United States and Ecuador by—</text><paragraph id="HD80068A287AC4FB38E3F1C64504E6E4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promoting cooperation and information sharing to encourage awareness of and increase trade and investment opportunities between the United States and Ecuador;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6213A70CA95D4F72A39228EFBB92F5A7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>supporting efforts by the Government of Ecuador to promote a more open, transparent, and competitive business environment, including by lowering trade barriers, implementing policies to reduce trading times, and improving efficiencies to expedite customs operations for importers and exporters of all sizes, in all sectors, and at all entry ports in Ecuador;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51CB21D334B8406EBD454944F6A6CFEE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing frameworks or mechanisms to review the long term financial sustainability and security implications of foreign investments in Ecuador in strategic sectors or services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C248E8F654F48FC8351B7D4C783FE03"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing competitive and transparent infrastructure project selection and procurement processes in Ecuador that promote transparency, open competition, financial sustainability, and robust adherence to global standards and norms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3AF73E6ADB249A08F00BBE59B0A590E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>developing programs to help the Government of Ecuador improve efficiency and transparency in customs administration, including through support for the Government of Ecuador’s ongoing efforts to digitize its customs process and accept electronic documents required for the import, export, and transit of goods under specific international standards, as well as related training to expedite customs, security, efficiency, and competitiveness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H811E406A495A428794779AC0C2853FB5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>spurring digital transformation that would advance—</text><subparagraph id="HE44062F359B241E6A25B588E8D3269E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of digitized government services with the greatest potential to improve transparency, lower business costs, and expand citizens’ access to public services and public information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2807AE0740C14735B1797B223FFFF6B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of transparent and affordable access to the internet and digital infrastructure; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC959E7792A734F58B4D34FFAFEC11A1D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>best practices to mitigate the risks to digital infrastructure by doing business with communication networks and communications supply chains with equipment and services from companies with close ties to or susceptible to pressure from governments or security services without reliable legal checks on governmental powers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2449D3A1CCFD4C5DAA84FF6A21FCF2FC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>identifying, as appropriate, a role for the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the United States Agency for International Development, and the United States private sector in supporting efforts to increase private sector investment and strengthen economic prosperity.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2F70963764C44274BF5BE09A70C32072"><enum>5.</enum><header>Promoting inclusive economic development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, shall develop and implement a strategy and related programs to support inclusive economic development across Ecuador’s national territory by—</text><paragraph id="HD55B6A54A4F44D6F9B31A2CD7CBFBDF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitating increased access to public and private financing, equity investments, grants, and market analysis for small and medium-sized businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD1917B7B3644B082D7B69F9200D547"><enum>(2)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to local governments to formulate and enact local development plans that invest in Indigenous and Afro-Ecuadorian communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF7EB65D15743228C7FA5920B5CDF85"><enum>(3)</enum><text>connecting rural agricultural networks, including Indigenous and Afro-Ecuadorian agricultural networks, to consumers in urban centers and export markets, including through infrastructure construction and maintenance programs that are subject to audits and carefully designed to minimize potential environmental harm;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7B60D0AAA6540C080B4971D7B7E9EBB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>partnering with local governments, the private sector, and local civil society organizations, including organizations representing marginalized communities and faith-based organizations, to provide skills training and investment in support of initiatives that provide economically viable, legal alternatives to participating in illegal economies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68FA5AF5A21742B8A33029E95EB1031F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>connecting small scale fishing enterprises to consumers and export markets, in order to reduce vulnerability to organized criminal networks.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9847872C7F1B492BAF88887C8ED0E5D5"><enum>6.</enum><header>Combating illicit economies, corruption, and negative foreign influence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall develop and implement a strategy and related programs to increase the capacity of Ecuador’s justice system and law enforcement authorities to combat illicit economies, corruption, transnational criminal organizations, and the harmful influence of malign foreign and domestic actors by—</text><paragraph id="H3FEF63563DFB414BA09384E83296892A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing technical assistance and support to specialized units within the Attorney General’s office to combat corruption and to promote and protect internationally recognized human rights in Ecuador, including the Transparency and Anti-Corruption Unit, the Anti-Money Laundering Unit, the Task Force to Combat Corruption in Central America, and the Environmental Crimes Unit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H561004FE12764356BFA3E7DE8B29A99D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthening bilateral assistance and complementary support through multilateral anti-corruption mechanisms, as necessary and appropriate, to counter corruption and recover assets derived from corruption, including through strengthening independent inspectors general to track and reduce corruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4B77BB7EE214FDB89A8063A730967DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving the technical capacity of prosecutors and financial institutions in Ecuador to combat corruption by—</text><subparagraph id="H181D52FD4C12488FBB0CE185577BEE82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>detecting and investigating suspicious financial transactions, and conducting asset forfeitures and criminal analysis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ED2FA61988D43508FD3A5D855E0A221"><enum>(B)</enum><text>combating money laundering, financial crimes, and extortion;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H013859AB886C4E69B2F5D9B24A88E5A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>providing technical assistance and material support (including, as appropriate, radars, vessels, and communications equipment) to vetted specialized units of Ecuador’s national police and the armed services to disrupt, degrade, and dismantle organizations involved in illicit narcotics trafficking, transnational criminal activities, illicit mining, and illegal, unregulated, and unreported fishing, among other illicit activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A0C37E80F304C9B814E0327FE6D494F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to address challenges related to Ecuador’s penitentiary and corrections system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1837DECC27B84139917298CF78F48B9A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>strengthening the regulatory framework of mining through collaboration with key Ecuadorian institutions, such as the Interior Ministry’s Special Commission for the Control of Illegal Mining and the National Police’s Investigative Unit on Mining Crimes, and providing technical assistance in support of their law enforcement activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE99041E9194A828B6033AE3EC3EDD1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to judges, prosecutors, and ombudsmen to increase capacity to enforce laws against human smuggling and trafficking, illicit mining, illegal logging, illegal, unregulated, and unreported (IUU) fishing, and other illicit economic activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3AF45F3BA974467932DCA61CD985F9B"><enum>(8)</enum><text>providing support to the Government of Ecuador to prevent illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing, including through expanding detection and response capabilities, and the use of dark vessel tracing technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H022A5421F5B94F17A2CD661C4C23E829"><enum>(9)</enum><text>supporting multilateral efforts to stem illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing with neighboring countries in South America and within the South Pacific Regional Fisheries Management Organisation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H291D8352B32B42189DEBFCBE297ED8F1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>assisting the Government of Ecuador’s efforts to protect defenders of internationally recognized human rights, including through the work of the Office of the Ombudsman of Ecuador, and by encouraging the inclusion of Indigenous and Afro-Ecuadorian communities and civil society organizations in this process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD506385A32424AB3B207459748487EB3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>supporting efforts to improve transparency, uphold accountability, and build capacity within the Office of the Comptroller General;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7AB6196CB14E9A93FDFEF14D862F28"><enum>(12)</enum><text>enhancing the institutional capacity and technical capabilities of defense and security institutions of Ecuador to conduct national or regional security missions, including through regular bilateral and multilateral cooperation, foreign military financing, international military education, and training programs, consistent with applicable Ecuadorian laws and regulations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB833CD1412F4FEE9B50C8D0DFCDB5E4"><enum>(13)</enum><text>enhancing port management and maritime security partnerships to disrupt, degrade, and dismantle transnational criminal networks and facilitate the legitimate flow of people, goods, and services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H605A68FE2A7D4CD781E05A416B2E4043"><enum>(14)</enum><text>strengthening cybersecurity cooperation—</text><subparagraph id="H4D2BB3BA25684E6F8D4BB1B90369130A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to effectively respond to cybersecurity threats, including state-sponsored threats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FBD3E303BE84427AF3A436FD0100F20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to share best practices to combat such threats;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64247B87FEA04A5B90735BEA03379B37"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to help develop and implement information architectures that respect individual privacy rights and reduce the risk that data collected through such systems will be exploited by malign state and non-state actors; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CE48333D6B44A5BB34DAAB10EE6DCDA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to strengthen resilience against cyberattacks, misinformation, and propaganda; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C304DF4B97446D6B1A5C13654AEDFB7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to strengthen the resilience of critical infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H0CFEEDA594EC4E25BA4FFDEE2F03415F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Strengthening democratic governance</header><subsection id="H13D2F0A3D7AB4BF2A200AA70EDB1C405"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strengthening democratic governance</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, should develop and implement initiatives to strengthen democratic governance in Ecuador by supporting—</text><paragraph id="H045E3320354B4C678A34FDB3D084D630"><enum>(1)</enum><text>measures to improve the capacity of national and subnational government institutions to govern through transparent, inclusive, and democratic processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1F00545B4FB458183B1A6E10110D664"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts that measurably enhance the capacity of political actors and parties to strengthen democratic institutions and the rule of law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D440B5804B142E7929EA1A84E5F2D3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>initiatives to strengthen democratic governance, including combating political, administrative, and judicial corruption and improving transparency of the administration of public budgets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE6778F9757641BD9435A04A33092521"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the efforts of civil society organizations and independent media—</text><subparagraph id="H505349DA9BF24E15BB44C4095B5E9F8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to conduct oversight of the Government of Ecuador and the National Assembly of Ecuador;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CBB42EA05B041209200BFA301A2BEE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to promote initiatives that strengthen democratic governance, anti-corruption standards, and public and private sector transparency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59C9BD9CADDC455EADDAA39BADF255A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to foster political engagement between the Government of Ecuador, including the National Assembly of Ecuador, and all parts of Ecuadorian society, including women, indigenous communities, and Afro-Ecuadorian communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CF38A09CD154A81900F300C9F9DEF5F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legislative strengthening</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, working through the Consortium for Elections and Political Process Strengthening or any equivalent or successor mechanism, shall develop and implement programs to strengthen the National Assembly of Ecuador by providing training and technical assistance to—</text><paragraph id="H650603004CAA4CCF827801A880610AF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>members and committee offices of the National Assembly of Ecuador, including the Ethics Committee and Audit Committee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A99E426212F421981B03870ACEE8E39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assist in the creation of entities that can offer comprehensive and independent research and analysis on legislative and oversight matters pending before the National Assembly, including budgetary and economic issues; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0AD426DB1244F87B60C9D2E8E5249BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve democratic governance and government transparency, including through effective legislation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H133E25810ABD45648DCB67559B1A6F41"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Bilateral legislative cooperation</header><text>To the degree practicable, in implementing the programs required under subsection (b), the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development should facilitate meetings and collaboration between members of the United States Congress and the National Assembly of Ecuador.</text></subsection></section><section id="H56AC538B822147A89F8E29399ED573E7"><enum>8.</enum><header>Fostering conservation and stewardship</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in coordination with the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall develop and implement programs and enhance existing programs, as necessary and appropriate, to improve ecosystem conservation and enhance the effective stewardship of Ecuador’s natural resources by— </text><paragraph id="H7802ECE097F0459D8D1BB390D3F7A15C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to Ecuador’s Ministry of the Environment to safeguard national parks and protected forests and protected species, while promoting the participation of Indigenous communities in this process;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE82CD05382242EDA6859EB00666713D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>strengthening the capacity of communities to access the right to prior consultation, encoded in Article 57 of the Constitution of Ecuador and related laws, executive decrees, administrative acts, and ministerial regulations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H983DB8F801D24DEBBB3C38759C0BBF47"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting Indigenous and Afro-Ecuadorian communities as they raise awareness of threats to biodiverse ancestral lands, including through support for local media in such communities and technical assistance to monitor illicit activities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A3561FA23BD49A58896E0006256C8DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>partnering with the Government of Ecuador in support of reforestation and improving river, lake, and coastal water quality; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01596E4E85254F4BB544BDA86505531D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>providing assistance to communities affected by illegal mining and deforestation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D084DBEBD8E4F5C9B87ACB482D23EA2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>fostering mechanisms for cooperation on emergency preparedness and rapid recovery from natural disasters, including by—</text><subparagraph id="HE353034B242A4DB5B6024F6487E3FF1A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establishing regional preparedness, recovery, and emergency management centers to facilitate rapid response to survey and help maintain planning on regional disaster anticipated needs and possible resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B08153AD0724D11B57A93C7DDF921A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>training disaster recovery officials on latest techniques and lessons learned from United States experiences.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H77A525F97FB34D029D076A0B08DEBE7F"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization to transfer excess Coast Guard vessels</header><subsection id="HEB3C7F7E54BA4CC1A7027F88C0D937E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States should undertake efforts to expand cooperation with the Government of Ecuador to—</text><paragraph id="H47984101F1584382B4AA93702C748E91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure protections for the Galápagos Marine Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4BFA67C78E46C289B4325E1C585619"><enum>(2)</enum><text>deter illegal, unreported, and unregulated fishing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD58A7C3DBE1546F5A68A7FF3C5E20A74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increase interdiction of narcotics trafficking and other forms of illicit trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H545A61557CA9484095A6735C2FDFA894"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To transfer excess Coast Guard vessels to the Government of Ecuador</header><text>The President shall conduct a joint assessment with the Government of Ecuador to ensure sufficient capacity exists to maintain Island class cutters. Upon completion of a favorable assessment, the President is authorized to transfer up to two ISLAND class cutters to the Government of Ecuador as excess defense articles pursuant to the authority of section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD5467B59F44043F491901D7FADA36017"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants not counted in annual total of transferred excess defense articles</header><text>The value of a vessel transferred to another country on a grant basis pursuant to authority provided by subsection (b) shall not be counted against the aggregate value of excess defense articles transferred in any fiscal year under section 516 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF19B006692240D6ABB72AA44F96A36D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs of transfers</header><text>Any expense incurred by the United States in connection with a transfer authorized by this section shall be charged to the recipient notwithstanding section 516(e) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(e)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F77764231314233B9A666D48E10A457"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repair and refurbishment in United States shipyards</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the President shall require, as a condition of the transfer of a vessel under this section, that the recipient to which the vessel is transferred have such repair or refurbishment of the vessel as is needed, before the vessel joins the naval forces of that recipient, performed at a shipyard located in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H548C7E6B7E0243FDA9B43DE5437BB6FD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expiration of authority</header><text>The authority to transfer a vessel under this section shall expire at the end of the 3-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="H0B198B50FC2445D585CF1EC74B2B5200"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="HD4C023B9AAEE4DD29B3073EDC633ED64"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Secretary of State</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies as described in sections 4, 6, and 7(a), shall—</text><paragraph id="H4D633C3DAA9E4EDBB90526E7476A53D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive strategy to address the requirements described in sections 4, 6, and 7(a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H345A10061E9C4DF69ABCE962318867AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 2 years and 4 years after submitting the comprehensive strategy under paragraph (1), submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the implementation of the strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2FC0879656794701B8C32214821FD598"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development</header><text>The Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies as described in sections 5, 7(b), and 8, shall— </text><paragraph id="H3A66C24AD0374666A3D0AED033F8A86D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to appropriate congressional committees a comprehensive strategy to address the requirements described in sections 4, 7(b), and 8; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D37DFCD815A400E8FEF416EFF77B341"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 2 years and 4 years after submitting the comprehensive strategy under paragraph (1), submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report describing the implementation of the strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC676DF570D17467D984C83EE1E3CA6A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The strategies and reports required under subsections (a) and (b) may be submitted to the appropriate congressional committees as joint strategies and reports.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9BEC47BC5C1F4AD48CE321F1B0E570AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this act, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives. </text></subsection></section><section id="HD0D0EBB3CF4948EBBB163E8081B8E3E8"><enum>11.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

