<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0949D04DE0F24BEAA9D4A770066C9B03" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6901 IH: To prohibit the use of Federal funds for the private interim storage of spent nuclear fuel, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220302">March 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000377">Ms. Granger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds for the private interim storage of spent nuclear fuel, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H69AC096D426F429EA663A07C5ED9526C" style="OLC"><section id="HE39FD7FAD3FA4F5D8864CD674D9F5BB3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of Federal funds for private interim storage of spent nuclear fuel until such time that a permanent repository is available to accept the spent nuclear fuel</header><subsection id="HC719EFEE9C4B43868409518975C30A6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE1C439E187504061BDB5A2A7BC7F790E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Disposal; monitored retrievable storage facility; repository; spent nuclear fuel; storage</header><text>The terms <term>disposal</term>, <term>monitored retrievable storage facility</term>, <term>repository</term>, <term>spent nuclear fuel</term>, and <term>storage</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 2 of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADF28AD03E8242829607AC7E99304DE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monitored retrievable storage</header><text>The term <term>monitored retrievable storage</term> has the same meaning as in subtitle C of title I of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10161">42 U.S.C. 10161 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEEAA9C1999A428BA3AE914B8554CFB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H7252D5D403284169A6AAAB307EB83136"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and subject to subsection (c), during the period described in subsection (d), no Federal funds made available under any Act, including amounts made available under the permanent judgment appropriation established pursuant to section 1304 of title 31, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Judgment Fund</quote>), for any fiscal year may be used for any costs associated with the identification, development, licensing, granting of rights-of-way, construction, operation, decommissioning, or post-decommissioning maintenance and monitoring of any privately owned— </text><subparagraph id="HBBA208008E854D77BAFDCAC4790DD082"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitored retrievable storage facility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18AAFFB37FE346E7B0A4FA170D1159F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>consolidated interim storage facility that serves the purpose and function of monitored retrievable storage under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABF546B4C87945EF8EA45B03616F4484"><enum>(C)</enum><text>spent nuclear fuel storage facility that—</text><clause id="HA5D28CD56D7B4719BFBF7A7FD1F30832"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not—</text><subclause id="H5FA7A4944152401482C1A2C46B4664FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>colocated at the site of a nuclear fuel production, fabrication, or utilization facility; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HD14F45778D2A40FF98AD1660CA5C5164"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in operation as of the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFF95070C9C674A25ACE54BA7490E3C40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serves the purpose and function of monitored retrievable storage under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H920251DDF5AB44AD84E7D4C39FAA8052"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The prohibition described in paragraph (1) extends to contracting for the services of a private company for any storage of spent nuclear fuel at, or transportation of spent nuclear fuel to, a privately owned facility that serves the purpose and function of monitored retrievable storage under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/10101">42 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) for the purpose of consolidating the storage of domestic spent nuclear fuel at 1 or more facilities until such time that a repository is available to accept the spent nuclear fuel for permanent disposal.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD1FF309F43E4D73A9DAACA8E6D0C6E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Subsection (b) does not prohibit—</text><paragraph id="H2E5D3395DB7C4E55962C3017F6D6413A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a manufacturer of nuclear reactors or fabricator of nuclear fuel from accepting spent nuclear fuel at the site where the spent nuclear fuel is fabricated or generated;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE9F338F3E3740F191EB6E17A2A049D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an operating or decommissioned nuclear power plant from accepting spent nuclear fuel for interim storage at the site of the plant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA09BFDB677974AD196E2AD5A72141D3F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of Federal funds for the costs described in that subsection that are associated with the activities described in paragraphs (1) and (2); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6123C3BD099049B1BDF126EBF6D713A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the use of Federal funds for storage of spent nuclear fuel at, or the transportation of spent nuclear fuel to, federally owned facilities at Department of Energy sites in existence as of the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6FB12EB4F843C1A20754B52BC7B79E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the transfer of spent nuclear fuel owned by the Department of Energy between Department of Energy sites. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27605CC25DAE43179AE666594EBC18F9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Period of prohibition described</header><text>The period referred to in subsection (b) is the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date on which the Secretary of Energy certifies to Congress that a permanent repository is available to accept the spent nuclear fuel. </text></subsection><subsection id="H4EA09C42A69A469BA49590742B3E4BC0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Department of Energy funds</header><text>No funds of the Department of Energy shall be used to pay to any privately owned facility described in subsection (b) any damages awarded in any civil action in an appropriate district court of the United States relating to the prohibition under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H76C066FAD83641C7BF205DE5E545B52C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to imply that, prior to the date of enactment of this Act, any privately owned facility described in subsection (b) may receive any funds from the Federal Government for the activities prohibited under that subsection. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7B0B681CA64640BE97CE9A6F54101A70"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy shall submit to Congress a report detailing—</text><paragraph id="HEC51643E2E3C462CB809EF652FFF5F7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>possible locations, or a description of a possible siting process, for future consolidated interim storage facilities and repositories of spent nuclear fuel if Congress were to authorize the siting, construction, and operation of new storage facilities or repositories through the use of a consent-based system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H848DC59492094BD09BEF0B5A69C3FA91"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the estimated costs and risks of that future consolidated interim storage. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

