<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H123DE3F9B40F45AB97C36386A57A983D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7888 IH: Bahrain Security Cooperation Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7888</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for United States security cooperation with Bahrain.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8E97C87EBF1542F788118F91FE6C8EE9" style="OLC"><section id="H3E59A768CB604057835C77DC925EFA58" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bahrain Security Cooperation Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H7EF851582F2D4DECBC06E96B933EE59E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on United States security cooperation with Bahrain</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H6FBF5C28AD854E4293BEB5FF67B300C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is in the national security interest of the United States to maintain a strong relationship with Bahrain and support its military efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9964C01B6484C0383EF686779242EE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Bahrain has a critical role as host of the United States Navy’s Fifth Fleet and the United States Naval Forces Central Command;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H283A887E39ED495A935D8F29C668F524"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Bahrain is a major defense and security cooperation partner of the United States, as recognized when the United States designated Bahrain as a major non-NATO ally in 2002;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D1A3411F47E44DB9950EFED17C9C284"><enum>(4)</enum><text>there should be an increase in exchanges between defense officials and law enforcement of the United States and Bahrain at the strategic, policy, and tactical levels, especially for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="HF0BAA0EC123044D1B62686846C5AA7A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing cooperation on defense planning; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04040F31125E4693B27F2B3B749E4005"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving intelligence sharing to combat terrorism; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53B6517936C340FF9500E97ADCBB4B48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving interoperability between the Ministry of Interior and the United States Navy’s Fifth Fleet;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD07BDFE854D54FAF99B70B62AE1E45AC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States should ensure Bahrain has capabilities with regards to its air, missile, and unmanned aerial system defense assets to support peace efforts in the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E584A22DA1344AB91EF77B4B6E9C5F8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>it is important for the United States to be a source of consistent and reliable defense assets for Bahrain;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4EB30E42A0A47CD9D253E573311CAE3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the United States should deepen interoperability with Bahrain in defense capabilities, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC224D63A60AD4D8786922E0BDF4F6D39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maritime and air domain awareness; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CFA2C89A4774FC29C98E14BA8C5CED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrated air and missile defense systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4125EAB221F043D587D47050D56F0145"><enum>(C)</enum><text>counter unmanned aircraft system measures;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H885C2607C0E844E99B008106C5A26E74"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense should prioritize including Bahrain in military exercises to the greatest extent possible, increasing security cooperation and readiness between Bahrain and the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF51916388144535852F7548CBD24210"><enum>(9)</enum><text>it is in the best interest of the United States and Bahrain to work together to oppose any efforts of terrorism or radical extremism in the Middle East.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA3FCB671F08C48C0A73FFA0F1DEEF4D6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report on upgrading capabilities of United States Fifth Fleet</header><subsection id="H63D4D2CCF0F04FB2906C7856D4447830"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report on upgrading the capabilities of the United States Fifth Fleet to address emerging threats in the region of the area of responsibility of the Fifth Fleet and any cost associated with such capability upgrades. Such report shall include an assessment of the efforts of the Department of Defense to—</text><paragraph id="H92F45D55D66240AEBB2967CF6813D89D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increase exchanges between defense officials and law enforcement of the United States and Bahrain at the strategic, policy, and tactical levels, especially for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="H20FF9E3A630D468D977C626B920B6398"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enhancing cooperation on defense planning;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1A705C5C8094A528528E3BD2C73B329"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improving intelligence sharing to combat terrorism; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H065E6FE9B12342199D3E5C8F54D39348"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improving interoperability between the public security forces and the United States Fifth Fleet;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAD0ABEB5DBA427F98FC590C6D295386"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that Bahrain has capabilities with regards to its air, missile, and unmanned aerial system defense assets to support peace efforts in the region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD698A97B343044068BE8696920701657"><enum>(3)</enum><text>deepen interoperability with Bahrain in defense capabilities, including—</text><subparagraph id="H437FE6A919C04CA68C869A37DA7AFC90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maritime and air domain awareness;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFF449F180C841C39A252BF7F171DA33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>integrated air and missile defense systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE156D94B14F64F6D93D8DD3B9EA7F1D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>counter unmanned aircraft system measures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H42FDB43FE9F34A0DB68027DB3B4899C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Congressional defense committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>congressional defense committees</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of title 10, United States Code. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

