<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA5CC46C95332450A951567C36F813CA0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8198 IH: Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8198</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220623">June 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the process by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines whether an educational institution meets requirements relating to the percentage of students who receive educational assistance furnished by the Secretary.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD0FA66C3C5E44E46A20B6BD7B01BBE88" style="OLC"><section id="HD9367CAA21E544A2AD11B2019AD9ACF2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring the Best Schools for Veterans Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H39955B19E38744F8999F08ED0D92BFD2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Determinations relating to percentage of students of educational institution who receive educational assistance by Department of Veterans Affairs</header><subsection id="HA29DD260BBD843CABC36CBF6A3283320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 3680A is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFE1F551D24004B8AA714BBEC123916B8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H9268FB81E6084346ACBD4AB0BE91F254"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7D39397B248E4777B7787A9A83A7E15D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall not approve the enrollment of any eligible veteran, not already enrolled, in any course for any period during which the Secretary finds that more than 85 percent of the students enrolled in the course are having all or part of their tuition, fees, or other charges paid to or for them by the educational institution or by the Department of Veterans Affairs under this title or under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/1606">chapter 1606</external-xref> of title 10, except with respect to tuition, fees, or other charges that are paid under a payment plan at an educational institution that the Secretary determines has a history of offering payment plans that are completed not later than 180 days after the end of the applicable term, quarter, or semester.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50FCE7F45E4D4F8BB1DC2422DF7C4D2F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary may waive the requirements of paragraph (1), in whole or in part, if the Secretary determines, pursuant to regulations which the Secretary shall prescribe, it to be in the interest of the eligible veteran and the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H462E37A3B5D047129985BCA20C7A49A2" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HC3CCD2CA8F924920B1D48DDC0C84544F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall establish a process by which an educational institution may request a review of a determination that the educational institution does not meet the requirements of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC847844FC4D74DEE94D5C2DAB7AFDC53" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An educational institution that requests a review under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H9D80E3A88C2D433B8A1E51597CA3EE32" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall request the review not later than 30 days after the start of the term, quarter, or semester for which the determination described in subparagraph (A) applies; and</text></clause><clause id="H7A8CFDE2D63F46A6AA9DF14EE42A160B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include any information that the educational institution believes the Department should have taken into account when making the determination, including with respect to any mitigating circumstances.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0FD88595B0442C5AFCFA0ADB5C10171" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Benefits shall issue an initial decision for each review requested under subparagraph (A) by not later than 30 days after the date of the request, to the extent feasible.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E85EE07478F438290A8B289565381BB" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An educational institution may request the Secretary to review the decision by the Under Secretary under subparagraph (C). The Secretary shall review each decision so requested and, pursuant to such review, shall issue a final decision sustaining, modifying, or overturning the decision by the Under Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36EC7FDB9969444688CA2228BDF16A0B" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary shall carry out this paragraph without regard to any review process carried out by the Secretary under chapter 51 of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H04B3301F5B0F4990B46C8AC09615CC6F" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any course offered by an educational institution if—</text><subparagraph id="H304DA2C3D633415786B32E9AD040B74E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the majority of courses offered by the educational institution are approved under section 3672 or 3675 of this title; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C77E8C83F954A9DA112A887BCE3CBEF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total number of veterans and persons receiving assistance under this title or under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/1606">chapter 1606</external-xref> of title 10 who are enrolled in such institution equals 35 percent or less of the total student enrollment at such institution (computed separately for the main campus and any branch or extension of such institution).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB05A057FA5724C8D901AB20CFECE0853" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H11E0AEE1BD6545D290422DC4827BD0C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to any course offered by an educational institution if—</text><clause id="H79F9A897A3154723BD7DB2F1943F97F8" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the majority of courses offered by the educational institution are approved under section 3676 of this title; and</text></clause><clause id="H57E589D5BDA443CD88D92D017AF812B6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of veterans and persons receiving assistance under this title or under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/1606">chapter 1606</external-xref> of title 10 who are enrolled in such institution equals 35 percent or less of the total student enrollment at such institution (computed separately for the main campus and any branch or extension of such institution).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5DD4A6F839AD4D0DA473612C5D93A0CA" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), on a case by case basis, the Secretary may apply paragraph (1) with respect to any course otherwise covered by such subparagraph if the Secretary has reason to believe that the enrollment of veterans and persons described in clause (ii) of such subparagraph may be in excess of 85 percent of the total student enrollment in such course.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H640CF193C48042188748199354487C55" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that an educational institution that meets the requirements of paragraph (4) or (5) submits information to the Secretary on a biennial basis to verify meeting such requirements. During such biennial period in which an educational institution is covered by such verification, the Secretary may not require the educational institution to submit information with respect to meeting the requirements of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H183ED511EF0D43948FD3C0E6151232D0" indent="up1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the enrollment of a veteran—</text><subparagraph id="HAD21EC908392496C965760CF7353B16F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a program of education for which fewer than 10 students are having all or part of their tuition, fees, or other charges paid to or for them by the educational institution or by the Department of Veterans Affairs under this title or under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/1606">chapter 1606</external-xref> of title 10;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE065B098B434F2181CA309A4B91747F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a course offered pursuant to section 3019, 3034(a)(3), 3234, or 3241(a)(2) of this title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD969CA9BA36D49469440EA2E420B3C6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in a farm cooperative training course; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H359A83580937466FB4CFA4B1E30AC128"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in a course described in subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCEDB4715078349A39FE280D1D130FBCC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to a quarter, semester, or term, as applicable, commencing on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

