<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H86DAA6B4A26E423B98811F9C9D2D7B51" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7123 IH: Studying Barriers to Homelessness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7123</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Government Accountability Office to conduct a study to identify barriers to reducing homelessness by providing housing assistance under the Public Housing and Housing Choice Voucher programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE3EE08C34DD742569359ECF805BA6E71" style="OLC"><section id="H1CB1E6D26B31438A801C13C163D2CB19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Studying Barriers to Homelessness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBB4E72735C04477EB551F82842DFF052"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study and report on reducing homelessness through public housing and section 8 rental assistance</header><subsection id="HDCAE4530220C4D59AFF2CE583139473B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to identify any barriers that limit the ability of a public housing agency in attempting to provide housing assistance under the Public Housing and Housing Choice Voucher programs under title I of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>) for populations experiencing homelessness, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H8D40421624ED4AC2931E11D4FC363AE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identification of any laws, regulations, and any other notices or guidance pertaining to—</text><subparagraph id="H8DE382518B944ABDA074798A64BDCF4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>waiting lists, documentation requirements, or tenant screening that effect the ability of a public housing agency to accept persons and families experiencing homelessness into the public housing or voucher program; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17AC86B17D384F57B5F214795F1BFB5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funding formulas and performance measures that may penalize public housing agencies trying to serve persons and families experiencing homelessness;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EA054F3DFEE421A91D1AF37A5F2C3E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyzing and determining the effect of the limitation under section 8(o)(13)(B) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f(o)(13)(B)</external-xref>; relating to the maximum amount of housing voucher assistance that a public housing agency may use for project-based assistance) has on the ability of public housing agencies to serve persons and families experiencing homelessness; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A179091338547CEBE209B83D39F06C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identification of barriers to fair housing and the coordination of Federal housing assistance and homelessness funds, including outreach and marketing of such funds, to affirmatively further fair housing for protected classes under the Fair Housing Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3601">42 U.S.C. 3601 et seq.</external-xref>) that are disproportionately experiencing homelessness.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC6C7D86864C45A6A72EAE81F84CC0E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the Congress describing the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a) and setting forth the results and conclusions of the study.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

