<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="H0CDF04AA8DD2406FA2C0003CAFACDD81" public-private="public" key="S" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1" slc-id="S1-FLO21D16-M45-W8-4R4"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2497 RS: Amache National Historic Site Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 255</calendar><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2497</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 117–58]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20210730">July 30, 2021</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSEG00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Energy and Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20220119" legis-day="20220118">January 19 (legislative day, January 18), 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S338">Mr. Manchin</sponsor>, with amendments</action-desc><action-instruction>Omit the part struck through and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Amache National Historic Site in the State of Colorado as a Unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HDFE343312BDA4F5FA0FA14540E9BC1ED"><section id="H8E1BB9519C4E41E4B30A3F415B15CA5E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Amache National Historic Site Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H89BC3891E93546BB867431D9EDA7C1C0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HBF6E1F623E634A20BCE869DDC9A405C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <quote>Map</quote> means the map entitled <quote>Amache National Historical Site Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 100/175348 and dated July 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FEFEF6F27DB4662A5589A4C5D2C9D24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National historic site</header><text>The term <term>National Historic Site</term> means the Amache National Historic Site established by section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3165930EA3AE4BB0B93F9D60D06EDA23"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H6176180D40094083800FCB346B623122"><enum>3.</enum><header>Amache national historic site</header><subsection id="HF78A0A5F111847EE93CAA3B5A4B4F8C1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (c), there is established the Amache National Historic Site in the State of Colorado as a unit of the National Park System.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE937DC4732F142279796A10A0DE78CFE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the National Historic Site is to preserve, protect, and interpret for the benefit of present and future generations resources associated with—</text><paragraph id="H1DD797BEF53A4E9A974717BB1B16A8C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the incarceration of civilians of Japanese ancestry during World War II at Amache, also known as the Granada Relocation Center, and the military service of center incarcerees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6261F50C99884504BF0DC034611CEA1E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>public reaction in the State of Colorado to the incarceration of Japanese Americans, including the position of Governor Ralph Carr and the local community; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CA80AD15D344718A35E20507737337"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the transition of the incarcerees and their descendants following the closure of the center and resettlement in the State of Colorado and other States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H935C95ACDD9343DCA0E098228F7CDEB2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Determination by the Secretary</header><text>The National Historic Site shall not be established until the date on which the Secretary determines that a sufficient quantity of land or interests in land has been acquired to constitute a manageable park unit.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7E4DB44BBDF041BA8D01943BA2958385"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the Secretary makes a determination under subsection (c), the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register notice of the establishment of the National Historic Site.</text></subsection><subsection id="H143287F443164D27A0EF28DA6170AD35"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Boundary; map</header><paragraph id="H83CB22D9E4144BA7951A47FB690E3C68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Boundary</header><text>The boundary of the National Historic Site shall be as generally depicted on the Map.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADF88DA0740B4EB78E0C7A9F3CD5ACC2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The Map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2467DE2231F84C8CB71099A7354DFEFE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Land acquisition authority</header><text>The Secretary may acquire any land or interests in land located within the boundary of the Camp Amache National Historic Landmark, as generally depicted on the Map, by—</text><paragraph id="HFDEC3B27F87E4340AB01CB880C0863FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>donation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1DDC9D20D5441E187A2E8AB4A45DEB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated Funds; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A3AAEA6F2474F4694E6DA0CA63EBBA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>exchange.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC219A186ACC46C49C23E742147EA658"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Addition to boundary</header><text>Any lands or interests in land acquired under <deleted-phrase committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="strikethrough">paragraph (1)</deleted-phrase><added-phrase committee-id="SSEG00" reported-display-style="italic">subsection (f)</added-phrase> shall be included within the boundary of the National Historic Site.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC8B4D3DBBD1449BB8CF295C0FCC99E84"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="H655E4726352D49E095758A4179D0C711"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the National Historic Site in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="H67A53A4EB8FB4B8488CFE555ECDFB191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86B0DA8A74C346D9B183D66431B0AF95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6DBFF065C5D4EB2BCDB3792FEF6CE00"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Management plan</header><subparagraph id="H243C517B4D244AB884B96AE5227F7779"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Deadline for completion</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to the Secretary for this purpose, the Secretary shall prepare a general management plan for the National Historic Site in accordance with section 100502 of title 54, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83B137D3592D4AD2B4495AA4DD588391"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text>On completion of the general management plan under subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives the general management plan prepared under that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H396B910E5BD04FD581C00DA970ABB906"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Administrative facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of ensuring the preservation, protection, and proper management of the site and associated resources, the Secretary may establish facilities for administration, visitor services, and curation of personal property, outside the boundary of, and in the vicinity of, the National Historic Site.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31C6073408B14919A829A542AACE3B08"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>The Secretary may enter into agreements with—</text><paragraph id="HC50F35B4F61C4A43B497F96D38B69C05"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the public or private entities for the purpose of establishing and operating facilities outside of the boundary of the National Historic Site for administration, visitor services and curation of personal property; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2929EF9EDBEF4184A53FBCB7C50DA3B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other public or private entities for the purposes of carrying out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED8EAA2BA9BD4CEFBAA1281044C4C3C4"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Effect on water rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided for in subsection (l), nothing in this Act shall affect—</text><paragraph id="H10C65D8635C1435187F334DA18BF412E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the use, allocation, ownership, or control, in existence on the date of the enactment of any water, water right, or any other valid existing right;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H630DC4AF0FAC456C950934910F235550"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of the enactment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EF8DAB4A0FC44E7967B0FBCB8E7D82F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any interstate water compact in existence on the date of the enactment; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H876B67C62C224DEB8892562C9D8466BC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State jurisdiction over any water law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3A8A98CF6234A1FB5A1AA2BE42CF346"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance of water infrastructure and appurtenances</header><paragraph id="H151408E8458E4C4DA9D4F3E09D22AC68" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The town of Granada, Colorado, shall maintain responsibility for the operation and maintenance </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id1F3B11B8BB6542AE9C27451CBB2FC72E"><enum><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">(1)</added-phrase></enum><header><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Effect</added-phrase></header><text><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Nothing in this Act affects the authority of the town of Granada, Colorado, with respect to the operation and maintenance</added-phrase> of all water infrastructure, systems and appurtenances located within the boundary of the National Historic Site in existence on the date of enactment of this Act, including but not limited to wells, pumps, tanks, water lines, valves, and water treatment facilities. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D96739F37154570ACA9A92943692075" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide the town of</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3BCB387ED03046F9B86BC3DF2827793B"><enum><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">(2)</added-phrase></enum><header><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">Determination</added-phrase></header><text><added-phrase reported-display-style="italic">The Secretary shall provide the town of</added-phrase> Granada, Colorado, with access to those areas of the National Historic Site determined as necessary for the operation and maintenance of water infrastructure and appurtenances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E9ECFCA2429450EB36CA7AEE9130AE7" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary may permit the city of Granada, Colorado, to construct or install new water infrastructure, systems and appurtenances consistent with applicable laws, limited only to those areas determined in subsection (i)(2), and in a manner that ensures the preservation, protection, and proper management of the National Historic Site.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H655D8659D075470893DE17A5F171B97D" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough"><enum>(4)</enum><text>At such time that all water infrastructure, systems and appurtenances located within the boundary of the National Historic Site are no longer utilized by the city of Granada, Colorado, associated improvements and associated water rights may be acquired through donation to and made part of the National Historic Site in a condition satisfactory to the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4f440ea4af2e485cbfef7b625da5fd82" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(3)</enum><header>New water infrastructure</header><text>The Secretary may permit the town of Granada, Colorado, to construct or install new water infrastructure, systems, or appurtenances—</text><subparagraph id="id76AC88B98375459AA2B13CDE1F44C5DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consistent with applicable laws;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id73B4B9E080554F9A8F2A84C3AEFFA4D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>limited to the areas determined to be necessary under paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idC2D20FDA1A1C475199580592752E80FE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in a manner that ensures the preservation, protection, and proper management of the National Historic Site.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idbf81af8f0c0547169610e1ce21f91d06" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Acceptance of donated water infrastructure</header><text>The Secretary may accept, for addition to and administration as part of the National Historic Site, the donation of water infrastructure, systems, or appurtenances within the boundary of the National Historic Site, including associated water rights, if the water infrastructure, systems, or appurtenances are no longer used by the town of Granada, Colorado. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20220119" legis-day="20220118">January 19 (legislative day, January 18), 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with amendments</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

