<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89137B0259D349ABAF867DAE88A44423" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7347 IH: Supporting Jobs through Evidence and Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7347</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reauthorize workforce development innovation grants for the implementation, expansion, and evaluation of evidence-based workforce programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE63AB7B87FE8450CB2369BFAB4659EF6" style="OLC"><section id="HD6BE3B24999C454D8B3DFD327F7AE34C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Jobs through Evidence and Innovation Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HDEFC0AFAFB1F4188A1A7D0F4D4A0F075" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Evaluations and research</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 169 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3224">29 U.S.C. 3224</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HED02CB377540461D900BAE48DA865DB7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD46DC8EB6363410584F71E479C6B477E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC9D11BFD49FC49C5A96DE2FF65F4E9C7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H790FA7A5C05F42EDAF1C396875425410" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Workforce development innovation fund</header><paragraph id="HF2C74A47713D43F0904A658BD8A44992" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program authorized</header><subparagraph id="H6FDE98FDA16B4629914A0191FB6B4459" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award workforce development innovation grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to enable such entities to—</text><clause id="H264436379BFC4F2DAC8F472972EA9B7D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create, implement, replicate, or take to scale entrepreneurial, evidence-based, field-initiated innovation programs and services for improving the design and delivery of employment and training services that generate long-term improvements in the performance of the workforce development system, in outcomes for job-seekers (including individuals with barriers to employment), and employers, and in the cost-effectiveness of programs and services; and</text></clause><clause id="H1BAAF6B0C5DF4E6FA10E371EEAD70332" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>rigorously evaluate such programs and services in accordance with this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8A02F86DAE4418888D1467CD08A9F10" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of grants</header><text>The grants described in subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="H2A01AB431C13423BB27C21864E304079" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>early-phase grants to fund the development, implementation, and feasibility testing of an innovation program or service, which prior research suggests has promise, for the purpose of determining whether such program or service can successfully improve the design and delivery of employment and training services that generate long-term improvements in the performance of the workforce development system, in outcomes for job-seekers, and in the cost-effectiveness of such programs and services;</text></clause><clause id="HC81D338C70D84792AB1C03D46FB13FEA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mid-phase grants to fund implementation and a well-designed and well-implemented evaluation of such a program or service that has been successfully implemented under an early-phase grant described in clause (i) or other effort meeting similar criteria, for the purpose of measuring the impact and cost effectiveness of such programs or services, using data collected pursuant to the implementation of such program or service, if possible; and</text></clause><clause id="H9F527316748C4C228B91D2DDD9E54DED" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">expansion grants to fund implementation and a well-designed and well-implemented replication evaluation of such a program or service that has been found to produce sizable, important impacts under a mid-phase grant described in clause (ii) or other effort meeting similar criteria, for the purposes of—</text><subclause id="H0EEE2501A7184C5894819DAAF781AC26" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determining whether such impacts may be successfully reproduced and sustained over time; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H62A224A2169147AF967E29A1DA2A95E3" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identifying the conditions in which such a program or service is most effective. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99BCA15B2E134EC9AE87ADEA1D375944" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>Of the funds made available to carry out this subsection for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve not more than 5 percent of the funds to—</text><subparagraph id="H790DF744D4CC4BC5AF55F72051DE20C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to eligible entities, which may include preapplication workshops, web-based seminars, and evaluation support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C0C6A9A1B0F41B6A0F2CAE19517895C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disseminate evidence-based best practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CFADF02970642A49FAD1971B7DDAE05" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H5EF916AD41C542CB9B2D5CE3C27D3F60" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means any of the following:</text><clause id="HD4F39DC4956B413DB1A7AD2DC195147C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A State board.</text></clause><clause id="H1BCAF7EE8A414F0D98F48E6BFC28E763" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A local board.</text></clause><clause id="HCBD3A26754264236A240DC0893903C7E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An Indian tribe, tribal organization, Alaska Native entity, Indian-controlled organization serving Indians, or Native Hawaiian organization that is eligible to receive an award under section 166.</text></clause><clause id="HD05837D4D2CE4F7290A357A8E9ADB97F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A community-based, nonprofit, or nongovernmental organization serving an underserved population.</text></clause><clause id="HE89F2C5A6F344F31A3FC249F009A1DE0" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A consortium of such entities described under clause (i) through clause (iv).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA33776E231AB4504BB716E37BBB93F69" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>evidence-based</term>, when used with respect to an activity, strategy, or intervention, means an activity, strategy or intervention that—</text><clause id="HDA0BB2BAD328439BB02A2E23CFAC807D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>demonstrates a statistically significant effect on improving participant outcomes or other relevant outcomes based on—</text><subclause id="H649E68B13CC7473CB21F2A0055504463"><enum>(I)</enum><text>strong evidence from at least 1 well-designed and well-implemented experimental study;</text></subclause><subclause id="H53B3329FAFAB4123B9AFADCBCA86B3F8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>moderate evidence from at least 1 well-designed and well-implemented quasi-experimental study; or </text></subclause><subclause id="HC37F9194FA2E41DAB26D34BAE9871938"><enum>(III)</enum><text>promising evidence from at least 1 well-designed and well-implemented correlational study with statistical controls for selection bias; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8B568E7A82D6442187AE552625B54441"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H098691C7021049598D88729980895739"><enum>(I)</enum><text>demonstrates a rationale based on high-quality research findings or positive evaluation that such activity, strategy, or intervention is likely to improve student outcomes or other relevant outcomes; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0CE6913358BB4CD89CFCA1048F624410" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>includes ongoing efforts to examine the effects of such activity, strategy, or intervention.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD35B08AEB9DE41ABB0EDA1481925AD9D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Well-designed and well-implemented</header><text>The term <term>well-designed and well-implemented</term>, as applied to an evaluation study, means a study that is replicable, uses programmatic and control groups that are representative of the type of population served by the program, uses controls for aggregate shifts that might affect baseline numbers, does not have problems with attrition from the program, and takes measures to avoid statistical creaming.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA78F4EBD502C4E6B99DAB99B619CCD2B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection, such sums as may be necessary for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

