<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB9565F697C49410A99C7BB11ED1212EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8646 IH: Increasing Nuclear Safety Protocols for Extended Canister Transfers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8646</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220802">August 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assign a resident inspector to certain commercial nuclear power plants to conduct inspections of decommissioning activities and spent nuclear fuel transfer activities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFCCD8904F95E4FB698D917D626E6222C" style="OLC"><section id="HF83F0FFC812B4ED2B4955BBF7C1F7AF3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Increasing Nuclear Safety Protocols for Extended Canister Transfers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>INSPECT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6E86CFC968EB42F980838B4C5FC0BC22"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inspection of decommissioning activity and spent nuclear fuel transfer activity</header><subsection id="H2706B27F577C49649A0F433238B2A296"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission shall assign, for the duration described in subsection (b), a resident inspector to each commercial nuclear power plant that has permanently ceased operation to conduct inspections of decommissioning activities and spent nuclear fuel transfer activities of the commercial nuclear power plant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BEE03B4EA6A4AD3B6B425D23BE02026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration described</header><text>The duration described in this subsection is the period of time it takes to transfer all spent nuclear fuel from the spent fuel pools of the commercial nuclear power plant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6206D4F13DA442EDA8793AF85DE9A390"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reassignment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If there are no decommissioning activities or spent nuclear fuel transfer activities at the commercial nuclear power plant to which a resident inspector is assigned under subsection (a), the Chairman of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission may assign such resident inspector to a different commercial nuclear power plant.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

