<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HE02BBBD9DE764F4F81C6BEDD72E886E2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 3075 RH: Illegal Fishing and Forced Labor Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 493</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3075</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–674, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210511">May 11, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc> Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 11, 2021</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address seafood slavery and combat illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H69588661CD1C442BAF71F4D873FED2A3"><section id="H3A48262588F641A3AD5356A57CA7C243" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Illegal Fishing and Forced Labor Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H92C76FDD14CB4267B1FE284EB53600E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H45717D11ABE745B9AE271A49C95E4795"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Oppressive Child labor</header><text>The term <term>oppressive child labor</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF0F5C5A91B4709A54395A7468487CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Forced labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>forced labor</term> means any labor or service provided for or obtained by any means described in section 1589(a) of title 18, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA598DA2FED034CFFB60FC0C73F074BE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Human trafficking</header><text>The term <term>human trafficking</term> has the meaning given the term <term>severe forms of trafficking in persons</term> in section 103 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE47EC9AB319B411BBEA09685F10D490E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</term> has the meaning given such term in section 609 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(e)</external-xref>), as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85021FAD09924BE8884576BA2544851E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Seafood</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>seafood</term> means fish meal, and all marine animal and plant life meant for consumption as food other than marine mammals and birds, including fish, shellfish, shellfish products, and processed fish.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78E75825E3684751B0E07EF67B4CE0EB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Seafood fraud</header><text>The term <term>seafood fraud</term> means the mislabeling or misrepresentation of the information required under this Act or other any other Federal law or international agreement (other than this Act) pertaining to the import, export, transport, sale, harvest, processing, or trade of seafood, including—</text><subparagraph id="H73F4110A5A0F47EE845DCF6951438E5D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1801">16 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1323726BF1E3451FB9EDD085B18EB563"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Lacey Act Amendments of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3371">16 U.S.C. 3371 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94548A5413CA481582297AF775B48B63"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8165F733B56F4174AE13C7D07FB3F4E1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the FDA Food Safety Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/353">Public Law 111–353</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A46A893EAA94BBF8BD8A14E2075FF80"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Fair Packaging and Labeling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1451">15 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D9750BF6FF046C99F931388584BFCAB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>subtitle D of the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1638">7 U.S.C. 1638 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C2D6591CD394A3094ABB364EFB6A33B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>parts 60 and 65 of title 7, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8598E3E1D10348389CF131093F326834"><enum>(H)</enum><text>part 123 of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8787897618284E5882AF9933FF5EC66F"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 216.24 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A6B1A36B2774D87BD6E54F2AE8EF5FC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Seafood Import Monitoring Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Seafood Import Monitoring Program</term> means the Seafood Traceability Program established under section 300.324 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3312334FA4C4DECB4D8CF4EBF4B2224"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph></section><title id="H39ED0FD1C9F746CDB1681ED227D532DE"><enum>I</enum><header>Combating Human Trafficking through Seafood Import Monitoring</header><section id="HBF05B70218E448F48324ACCEA75D5839"><enum>101.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title, the following additional definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="HDEF6503C8F28473296D05B9914B4CB7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Competent authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>competent authority</term> means government and any third party that meets certain governing criteria. Such criteria shall be established by regulation, after outreach to key environmental and labor stakeholders. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F5ECF34801E461CB4B425C4FF2B7324"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unique vessel identifier</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unique vessel identifier</term> means a unique number that stays with a vessel for the duration of the vessel’s life, regardless of changes in flag, ownership, name, or other changes to the vessel.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H70F26F62F8044AEF9D0912CB932F5172"><enum>102.</enum><header>Expansion of Seafood Import Monitoring Program to all species</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, expand the Seafood Import Monitoring Program to apply to all seafood and seafood products imported into the United States.</text></section><section id="HBD754CFD43B844F884989804E50BCBC5"><enum>103.</enum><header>Enhancement of Seafood Import Monitoring Program Automated Commercial Environment Message Set</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, shall, not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, develop a strategy to improve the quality and verifiability of already collected Seafood Import Monitoring Program Message Set data elements in the Automated Commercial Environment system that prioritizes the use of enumerated data types, such as checkboxes, dropdown menus, or radio buttons, and any additional elements the Agency finds necessary, among other options, rather than open text fields, for—</text><paragraph id="H961ED6C77FF44DB4B3B9612A110029A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorization to fish; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F1B54D053E4E0F8E002A1673C0AF67"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unique vessel identifier (if available);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA90A53A67A0444ABE3D52F0D065B061"><enum>(3)</enum><text>catch document identifier;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE17AC8EDA646EDABACC8205D997C58"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">location of wild-capture harvest and landing or aquaculture location; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07229D59B43640718F46FC77407A27B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>type of fishing gear used to harvest the fish;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6F7E5447884A48960604D6DCD106E3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">name of farm or aquaculture facility, if applicable; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13F8A26FA56E4415B3895A2DD8027D19"><enum>(7)</enum><text>location of aquaculture facility, if applicable.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC69E29CC38634FE98255A2E8CCC07459"><enum>104.</enum><header>Additional data requirements for Seafood Import Monitoring Program data collection</header><subsection id="HEF7E3BA373AC47AC878196ACA56C9E7B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall revise section 300.324 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, to—</text><paragraph id="H90DFD458B07D48AAB348240F79535C81"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require at the time of entry for imported seafood and seafood products—</text><subparagraph id="HA23200EEFB634730859CE4DC5A33F867"><enum>(A)</enum><text>location of catch or cultivation, including—</text><clause id="HF941BAE295FD4835B4E94E62DEF6FBF1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>geographic location at a resolution of not less than 1 degree latitude by 1 degree longitude;</text></clause><clause id="H2EA54025EF6B4EA58402254C92DBE65B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the country code of the International Organization for Standardization if the catch was within the exclusive economic zone or territorial waters of a country;</text></clause><clause id="H2D916B9AD529442CA1D5D612173C35D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if appropriate, the regional fisheries management organization or organizations having jurisdiction over the catch, if it occurs within the jurisdiction of any regional fisheries management organization; and</text></clause><clause id="H0C2DC240144046DABA4C36764D0A7A51"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Food and Agriculture Organization major fishing area codes;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED66B64BDEA44CAC971A4C090AED6F5B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">electronic reports of chain-of-custody records that identify, including with unique vessel identifiers when applicable, each custodian of the seafood, including transshippers, processors, storage facilities, and distributors and the physical address of such facilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB62D92497A2247F78B093696EB546F51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>maritime mobile service identity number of harvesting and transshipment vessels; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E880BE51DC247049092B8CABFFCEAF2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">beneficial owner of each harvesting and transshipment vessel or aquaculture facility, when applicable;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H194C744F046F486296AFFED70D5B1EA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require all importers submitting seafood import data to require prior notification and submission of seafood import data at least 72 hours and no more than 15 days prior to entry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5386A57706C4C13B39D0BA50F01EC65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>require verification and certification of harvest information by competent authorities at all major transfer points in the supply chain, including harvest, landing, processing, and transshipment at the time of entry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF017B2B8F79A4B179F5AB6796C0482ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Forced labor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, working in direct consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, Department of Labor, and Department of State, shall, not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, complete a regulatory process to establish additional key data elements for the Seafood Import Monitoring Program, that collect information about labor conditions in the harvest, transshipment, and processing of imported fish and fish products. </text></subsection><subsection id="HD9BAEA5AE02C4E2590AFA2A7583E2782"><enum>(c)</enum><header>International Fisheries Trade Permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H1C884B04127D4663B9A0CEF61EA7C2E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publish and maintain on the website of the National Marine Fisheries Service a list of all current International Fisheries Trade Permit holders, including the name of the permit holder and expiration date of the permit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2712123656DC43DDBA2EC33508DFB027"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begin to revoke, modify, or deny issuance of an International Fisheries Trade with respect to a permit holder or applicant that has violated any requirement of section 300.322, 300.323, 300.324, or 300.325 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A79189770A4FA6BF3C267254545700"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require an International Fisheries Trade Permit for importers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB981673BF51C497AB0694AD8AE9EEB3F"><enum>105.</enum><header>Efforts to improve detection of at-risk seafood imports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of State, shall, not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, finalize a detailed strategic plan to develop, mature, and adopt artificial intelligence and machine learning technologies to detect imports of fish and fish products at risk of being associated with illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing, human trafficking, forced labor, and seafood fraud, and provide a detailed report of such strategic plan to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, and Committee on Commerce of the Senate.</text></section><section id="H944B9368ED6D4BB78592B2CE6D2C2DAD"><enum>106.</enum><header>Import audits</header><subsection id="H1C46800055054C9985AC4A7F6B508D67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Audit procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, implement procedures to audit information and supporting records of sufficient numbers of imports of seafood and seafood products subject to the Seafood Import Monitoring Program to support statistically robust conclusions that the samples audited are representative of all seafood imports with respect to a given year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H907872FCA97B4A4A93F4A969FD85FF02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual revision</header><text>In developing the procedures required in subsection (a), the Secretary shall, not less frequently than once each year, revise such procedures to prioritize for audit those imports originating from countries—</text><paragraph id="H7A26B23753D54B0D9AC78008931DD82E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified pursuant to sections 609(b) or 610(a) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(b)</external-xref> or 1826k(a)) that have not yet received a subsequent positive certification pursuant to sections 609(d) or 610(c) of such Act, respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC19244B30C284EADA8414835700FEC4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified by an appropriate regional fishery management organization as being the flag state or landing location of vessels identified by other countries or regional fisheries management organizations as engaging in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CD1BAE404ED41FC95CBD82257271512"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified as having human trafficking, including forced labor, in any part of the seafood supply chain, including on vessels flagged in such country and including feed for cultured production, in the most recent Trafficking in Persons Report issued by the Department of State in accordance with the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C91EA3C47A84247837851FBB7BB4212"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified as producing goods that contain seafood using forced labor or oppressive child labor in the most recent List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor in accordance with the Trafficking Victims Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2051C012AF90422FAB1F22C7C069E8A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identified as at risk for human trafficking, including forced labor, in their seafood catching and processing industries by the report required in section 3563 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H915CC241B7004A82A7F543AFAE19BD2B"><enum>107.</enum><header>Interagency coordination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate with the relevant agencies to ensure that data elements described in this title can be submitted through the International Trade Data System Automated Commercial Environment to U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></section><section id="HCA1451E55FBE442D9C3CC04927F96DE1"><enum>108.</enum><header>Availability of fisheries information</header><subsection id="H704D34A479744C128CE6590BCCF514E8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 402(b)(1) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881a">16 U.S.C. 1881a(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end of subparagraph (G), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (H) and inserting <quote>; or</quote> , and by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0218F81620AF4A4BA69751C069A7A3C6" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subparagraph id="HED51FFB7E7714E4383BD447439D00B98"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to Federal agencies responsible for screening of imported seafood and for the purpose of carrying out the duties under or with respect to—</text><clause id="H1B5C33374E474E70BF6A8C1C1F52002F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Seafood Import Monitoring Program;</text></clause><clause id="H4AC7F9E1F7A3401B8FE57FF50CEAC957"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Antarctic Marine Living Resources Program;</text></clause><clause id="H20DA9D9A951A4E72A302A30C263F78D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Tuna Tracking and Verification Program;</text></clause><clause id="HB08D92961D0144C6A54308338B087E6A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Atlantic Highly Migratory Species International Trade Program;</text></clause><clause id="H32FB1E20799F433992E3B5ADFA4E5F0D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor in accordance with the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H8426D4907E414DF3B26113EAD9CCE032"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the Trafficking in Persons Report required by section 110 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>); </text></clause><clause id="HF79A1EE6AE174E90BDA7F4C0D012FF71"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>enforcement activities and regulations authorized under section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H5790E5C2C24E49D193B725EA7C1961EC"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the taking and related acts in commercial fishing operations under section 216.24 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCE7B6AD820946DD894B60D77C8BC740"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to Federal, State and local agencies for the purposes of verification and enforcement of title II of this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7E88889C71449B697E1A2C15F6B29B7"><enum>(K)</enum><text>information that pertains to catch documentation and legality of catch, if disclosure of that information would not materially damage the value of catch or business.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA93219DFA097495F89D53701634388BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation deadline</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue regulations implementing the amendments in this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1E42FBAA176B404C9EF0446E3503BAE4"><enum>109.</enum><header>Report on seafood import monitoring</header><subsection id="HACCFEFFEFFE744D48ED1D49081D131D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress and public availability of reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, not later than 120 days after the end of each fiscal year and annually thereafter, submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that summarizes the National Marine Fisheries Service’s efforts to prevent the importation of seafood harvested through illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing, particularly with respect to seafood harvested, produced, processed, or manufactured by forced labor. Each such report shall be made publicly available on the Internet website of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAD0AD60EAD2F4198AB801510E8F8D927"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H08464D4A783143B2A0873BB7FA9F7DCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the volume and value of seafood species subject to the Seafood Import Monitoring Program, described in section 300.324 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, reported by 10-digit Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States codes, imported during the previous fiscal year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19FDF00981AF4231A3D1C438CC76BC5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the enforcement activities and priorities of the National Marine Fisheries Service with respect to implementing the requirements under the Seafood Import Monitoring Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC059D20B40B84D96A8927D0CB0B4217A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the percentage of import shipments subject to this program selected for inspection or the information or records supporting entry selected for audit, as described in section 300.324(d) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H356AD7061082455C8E7B625A35D15F78"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the number and types of instances of noncompliance with the requirements of the Seafood Import Monitoring Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4859DB6A120B46EBAE8510836149DE74"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number and types of instances of violations of State or Federal law discovered through the Seafood Import Monitoring Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F3B86257E9F4A9FB1BC0E08C922F6B4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the seafood species with respect to which violations described in paragraphs (4) and (5) were most prevalent;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H516F2B79E68A48FCA0AC31DC421DCF50"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the location of catch or harvest with respect to which violations described in paragraphs (4) and (5) were most prevalent; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12D0630780F6460E829F8BB7AB4016CD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary considers appropriate with respect to monitoring and enforcing compliance with the Seafood Import Monitoring Program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE77EC31FEB954248A2F5ABD9D9B0CB46"><enum>110.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection to carry out enforcement actions pursuant to section 307 of the Tariff Act $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2021 through 2025 for enforcement of section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>).</text></section></title><title id="H3A88A0BF0BB34B10AD3A28397AFF9B4E"><enum>II</enum><header>Seafood Traceability and Labeling</header><section id="H01E0071741B54946A9FF5E5BD15D7F96"><enum>201.</enum><header>Federal activities on seafood safety and fraud</header><subsection id="HFBB42AE46A1741B396DD9A9249A02F2C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Sea Grant College Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration shall ensure that seafood inspection activities are coordinated with the National Sea Grant College Program established by the National Sea Grant College and Program Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1121">33 U.S.C. 1121 et seq.</external-xref>) which may provide outreach to the States, local health agencies, consumers, and the seafood industry on seafood safety and seafood fraud, as needed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H53EF1E96317F4FBD88366ECC2BBBE79A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inspecting To prevent seafood fraud</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that inspections and tests for seafood safety also collect information for seafood fraud prevention.</text></subsection></section><section id="H29551A4BEA3744FFAD6BD9105205E531"><enum>202.</enum><header>Seafood labeling and identification</header><subsection id="H58E1AF5E74AC475091D7C4D356E5F0FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in coordination with other relevant agencies shall, not later than three years after the date of enactment of this Act, implement the following requirements with respect to fish and fish products imported into the United States or otherwise distributed or offered for sale in interstate commerce:</text><paragraph id="H9456476DF256462DAE9A310AC57D93CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Traceability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A requirement that the following information shall accompany seafood through processing and distribution:</text><subparagraph id="H8DF60D7CC28F4ECDB32811ECA9CCEB30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization Major Fishing Area, or a more specific location, in which the seafood was caught or cultivated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC96C34FBC5F9453AB23673ACFD277AD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The acceptable market name (as determined by the Food and Drug Administration), scientific name, and specific Aquatic Sciences and Fisheries Information System number of the Fisheries and Aquaculture Statistics Information Service of the United Nations Food and Agriculture Organization for the seafood species.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE799BA5A88174ADE9126D314238D4AD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the seafood was harvested wild or was farm-raised.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD89C759C42DF4A25A470E4CFF66D680A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The method of harvest of the seafood, including gear type as listed in section 600.725 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, or successor regulation, and defined in section 600.10 of such title, or successor regulation. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D47E74BD18A4001AC9CD9E50FB5A87C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The date of the catch or harvest.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7F1162EAB384CDFB93C6C5491A711E1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The weight or number, as appropriate, of product for an individual fish or lot.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H507AB8DF202D4517BFED562FAA0B92B2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Date and name of entity (processor, dealer, vessel) to which the seafood was landed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F7F31A5D5834C0D81887F18E9D9B01F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Name and flag state of vessel and evidence of authorization, and if applicable, a unique vessel identifier.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19378594E62E4F199AAA4FD83DD89018"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Name and location of the facility from which farm-raised seafood were harvested, the method of cultivation, source and type of feed, and evidence of authorization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H445DF93AB6104608AC5287255AAFD75A"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Fisheries International Fisheries Trade Permit number issued to the importer of record for the entry, if applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0F42548A40847C18B845C6113C81F8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Labeling</header><text>The following information shall be included in the labeling of seafood through processing, distribution, and final sale:</text><subparagraph id="HC2AA95993E964B338ECC6AD45F517CA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The information required in subparagraphs (A), (B), (C), and (D) of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46CEF6262C9046CB9097FE0C9F3B85CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Whether the seafood has been previously frozen or treated with any substance other than ice or water.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78087505C3734947841704A7817B995C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Whether the seafood was farm-raised along with information regarding the country of cultivation, the location of the aquaculture production area, and the method of cultivation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H23D645DCE8F44E4DBC7E3CCDE9E11221"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Production codes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall allow compliance with subsection (a) through the use of production codes, quick response codes, or other types of commonly used processing codes and electronic bar coding methods.</text></subsection><subsection id="H46E1EDC0DA3449719F1B669747EBE300"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text>No importer, processor, distributor, or retailer may be found to be in violation of the requirements of this section for unknowingly selling a product that was already mislabeled upon receipt, provided that the importer, processor, distributor, or retailer can provide the required product traceability documentation.</text></subsection></section><section id="H72444A2131694BE78CF590BCD32BA182"><enum>203.</enum><header>Federal enforcement</header><subsection id="HE1DACF2123DB4F1092B74DDA730A5424"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement by Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce shall prevent any person from violating this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though section 307 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1857">16 U.S.C. 1857</external-xref>) was incorporated into and made a part of and applicable to this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="HBCBBEB8C22594196851F1274670505F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of offenders</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop, maintain, and post on the public website of the Department of Commerce a list that—</text><paragraph id="HFC293C73D8AF4713B179C78FB763452B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>includes, by country, each exporter whose seafood is imported or offered for import into the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37A4F95E2FC742C88AD95C8D7AB12EA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each such exporter, tracks the timing, type, and frequency of violations of Federal law relating to seafood fraud and illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H261CE746B1394B0DAB779B4986826EA4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspections</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall—</text><paragraph id="HCEA8155E41594E868741230481509B24"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase, as resources allow, the number of foreign and domestic seafood shipments that are audited or inspected for seafood fraud and illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing by National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration auditors and authorized officers, including verification of compliance with the traceability requirements of section 104(a); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H708ACDBC1FBB4744ADBC2DDDD687341C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct audits and inspections, as resources allow, at a sufficient level to promote compliance and deterrence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B55C21D9F964FEDB6C39E4E17DAC34A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, ensure that inspections and tests for seafood fraud prevention also collect information to support the Secretary of Health and Human Services in implementing the seafood safety requirements of the FDA Food Safety Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/353">Public Law 111–353</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73D06B0F8E7941D7BC1B842629EBE4BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interagency agreement</header><paragraph id="H653F06593A8140AA83E370E18F281CB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Labor, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall jointly execute a memorandum of understanding to codify and improve interagency cooperation on seafood safety, preventing illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing and human trafficking, including forced labor, and seafood fraud prevention, enforcement, and inspections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D5A1B0A5164FBF806F644353557E15"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The memorandum of understanding required by paragraph (1) shall include provisions, performance metrics, and timelines as the Secretaries consider appropriate to improve such cooperation described in such paragraph (acting under provisions of law other than this subsection)—</text><subparagraph id="HC6AD89662C114950A2150522F3C0E8DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify and execute specific procedures for using authorities granted under the FDA Food Safety Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/353">Public Law 111–353</external-xref>) to ensure and improve the safety of commercially marketed seafood in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H148FA08467ED4C41AADF8AEEF21AC0D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify and execute specific procedures for interagency cooperation on—</text><clause id="H60CBC94811D24872AE85848D33C9119B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>interagency resource and information sharing;</text></clause><clause id="HDF9DCCB100974B858F1F913262D1F13F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use and development of forensic tools including means to fill existing gaps in capabilities and eliminate duplication; and</text></clause><clause id="H79153F08C64F4FF99377743EC14BB6B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>development of specific forensic analysis information required by each agency to promote effective enforcement actions;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD411910026B0450D80180EB4FCD97311"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to maximize the effectiveness of limited personnel and resources by ensuring that—</text><clause id="HE2A37C199746416CA4A52821B44E0290"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inspections of seafood shipments and seafood processing and production facilities by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and the Food and Drug Administration are not duplicative; and</text></clause><clause id="H685F39816001463AA6CA1AD13D7B12C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information resulting from examinations, testing, and inspections conducted by the Department of Commerce with respect to seafood is considered in making risk-based determinations, including the establishment of inspection priorities for domestic and foreign facilities and the examination and testing of domestic and imported seafood;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF75E9D2974EF4C67AFDA664B665BE9FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to create a process—</text><clause id="HDAA73B6F6EE04427BA8BB9418DFCF07C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by which data collected by all seafood inspectors and officers of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration and U.S. Customs and Border Protection authorized to conduct inspections of seafood shipments or facilities that process or sell seafood, or authorized officers that conduct analysis of seafood import information, will be used for risk-based screening of seafood shipments, including food safety, adulteration and misbranding, by the Food and Drug Administration beginning not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H3FD9A0C351FB4C52A863B3BD0E8E3864"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by which data collected by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Department of Labor, the Department of State, and the Food and Drug Administration is shared to maximize efficiency and enforcement of seafood safety, fraud prevention, and prohibitions on illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C19E0CCF9F1436087AC7EF7ED8FF5BD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to create a process by which—</text><clause id="HE8B9AE8BBCD04C3A88F19A5782925F63"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data collected by inspectors and officers of other Federal, State, or local agencies authorized to conduct inspections of seafood, or inspections of facilities that process or sell seafood, or data from import analysts, will be used by the Food and Drug Administration for risk-based screening of seafood shipments; and</text></clause><clause id="HAD4B3125366F4986889A71A3FDC81C1D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data collected by such inspectors and officials is shared with the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, Department of Labor, and the Food and Drug Administration to maximize efficiency and enforcement of seafood safety and fraud prevention; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB51B13C1F94A8F916B5E02D5BF2BFE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to ensure that officers and employees of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration are utilized by the Secretary of Health and Human Services as third-party auditors pursuant to section 808 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/384d">21 U.S.C. 384d</external-xref>) to carry out seafood examinations and investigations under chapter VIII of such Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9319F96386724967B7ECAD239DC972EF"><enum>204.</enum><header>State enforcement</header><subsection id="H7A98CDC9C9164DC28403E3656BF99F2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, has reason to believe that any person has engaged or is engaging in a pattern or practice of seafood fraud in violation of section 203, the State may bring a civil action on behalf of its residents to enjoin fraud, an action to recover for actual monetary loss or receive $10,000 in damages for each violation, or both such actions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H068E5A506898484DB2C6CB679D02DCAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Willful or knowing violations</header><text>If the court finds the defendant willfully or knowingly violated this Act, the court may increase the amount of the award to an amount equal to not more than 3 times the amount available under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H7DDEE30A18704D888983544F4E0D6B8B"><enum>205.</enum><header>Effect on State law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this title shall preempt the authority of a State to establish and enforce anti-trafficking laws or requirements for improving seafood safety and preventing seafood fraud that are consistent with the requirements of this Act.</text></section></title><title id="H5EA73B7EBDDE4067A9DE894AFAA9DCC3"><enum>III</enum><header>Strengthening International Fisheries Management to Combat Human Trafficking</header><section id="H4C64F443482F42128A405FF84B8079D7"><enum>301.</enum><header>Denial of port privileges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 101(a)(2) of the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826a">16 U.S.C. 1826a(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H85D6F7C719934CB6B46820EDD421CE33" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><paragraph id="HDC000DFCB0D54B958D90B72159BCA56B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Denial of port privileges</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall, in accordance with international law—</text><subparagraph id="H53B778601A964732A4CC55369C125D3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withhold or revoke the clearance required by section 60105 of title 46, United States Code, for any large-scale driftnet fishing vessels of a nation that receives a negative certification under sections 609(d) or 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref> or 1826k(c)), or fishing vessels of a nation that has been listed pursuant to sections 609(b) or 610(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(b)</external-xref> or 1826k(a)) in two or more consecutive reports as described under section 607 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826h">16 U.S.C. 1826h</external-xref>), until a positive certification has been received;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0418B528E80A4BF1B4338FA9D14FCD37"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">withhold or revoke the clearance required by section 60105 of title 46, United States Code, for fishing vessels of a nation that has been listed pursuant to sections 609(b) or 610(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(b)</external-xref> or 1826k(a)) in two or more consecutive reports as described under section 607 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826h">16 U.S.C. 1826h</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBEB374AC9884DC38954F82F13A60790"><enum>(C)</enum><text>deny entry of that vessel to any place in the United States and to the navigable waters of the United States, except for the purposes of inspecting such vessel, conducting an investigation, or taking other appropriate enforcement action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H52734F94252445D8ABCB42C6C7A0E03B"><enum>302.</enum><header>Identification and certification criteria</header><subsection id="HE5920AC2B77244B2BEE45E724F7608D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denial of port privileges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strike subsections (a) and (b) of section 609 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(a)</external-xref> and (b)), and insert the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB25B59FC8022488CA74F9313AB29E9B5" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H66C137FC94C94C5DB648CF27B0CE6E02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperation with governments</header><paragraph id="HB9CFE9D31C8640ECBE0F17AFB48BC135"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information collection</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall engage with each flag, coastal, port, and market nation that exports seafood to the United States to collect information sufficient to evaluate the effectiveness of such nation’s management of fisheries and control systems to prevent illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19130ACD7CC94E01A4632B1A816DA0A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall provide recommendations to such nations to resolve compliance gaps and improve fisheries management and control systems in order to assist such nations in preventing illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FF66115B6B54F809C470B995E6A8017"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Identification and warning</header><paragraph id="HC1C1336E2EB14B939F234F249AE800EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>For actions of a fishing vessel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall identify and list in the report required by section 607 a nation if a fishing vessel of such nation is engaged or has, in the preceding 3 years, engaged in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing. The Secretary shall include all nations that qualify for identification, regardless of whether the Secretary has engaged in the process described in this subsection or under subsection (a). Any of the following relevant information is sufficient to form the basis of an identification: </text><subparagraph id="H33B8370765B44EA58B43203553B2141F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>compliance reports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D134D2E4386404E99F80AC499AF0C09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>data or information from international fishery management organizations, a foreign government, or an organization or stakeholder group;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA19A9BF4058648288BC776BF8CF489B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information submitted by the public;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DF0C6DE2F024CFE9F58D3A80088295B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information submitted to the Secretary under section 402(a) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1881a">16 U.S.C. 1881a(a)</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74573649631F4E088E4B39DF66F8ECE5"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">import data collected by the Secretary pursuant to part 300.324 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF57D1C4984F148B78AEFEA31FBDE4869"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information compiled from a Federal agency, including, the Coast Guard and agencies within the Interagency Working Group on Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE21AEF968BA4FF6B57B1E4F2BC20ACB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>For actions of a nation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall identify, and list in such report, a nation engaging in or endorsing illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEA033D4091FA46CEA7481FAFB82D6247"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that is failing, or has failed in the preceding 3-year period, to cooperate with the United States government in providing information about their fisheries management and control systems described in subsection (a) of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9095EB61EE9B46A3B794D0CD458F9878"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that is violating, or has violated at any point during the preceding 3 years, conservation and management measures, including catch and other data reporting obligations and requirements, required under an international fishery management agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA59234E1D2344B798B9B882B7C8EF66C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that is failing, or has failed in the preceding 3-year period, to effectively address or regulate illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing within its fleets in any areas where its vessels are fishing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8B0CC7324CB4E858F7ED1BF2AFD8CE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that fails to discharge duties incumbent upon it under international law or practice as a flag, port, or coastal state to take action to prevent, deter, and eliminate illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B7F7D4C6CBE41CEA90D29C4ECA928C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that provides subsidies that—</text><clause id="H33A18793A634404F8469D7DA6B8978E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contribute to illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing or increased capacity and overfishing at proportionally higher rates than subsidies that promote fishery resource conservation and management; or</text></clause><clause id="HDC8CB1FBA97341279E97DF1F55D2944D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that otherwise undermine the effectiveness of any international fishery conservation program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E08035E997E466EBC6C75490C457468"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that has been identified as having human trafficking, including forced labor, in any part of the seafood supply chain in the most recent Trafficking in Persons Report issued by the Department of State in accordance with the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48B8CE212C1B4E5C95637BD0B46B582F"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that has been identified as producing seafood-related goods through forced labor or oppressive child labor in the most recent List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor in accordance with the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H239ECFA546CF4842861AC07F47054751"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any nation that has been identified as at risk for human trafficking, including forced labor, in their seafood catching and processing industries in the report required in section 3563 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H641B36049DCF40C693C0CE20A4411CE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Warning</header><text>The Secretary shall issue a warning to each nation identified under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F74F11CC8274B87922DFEF0324FD192"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make an identification under paragraphs (1) or (2) at any time that the Secretary has sufficient information to make such identification. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2C19D620BFC64468971B1479D86BAC3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Illegal, Unreported, or Unregulated certification determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 609(d) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(d)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1B8572C37F6046B0B004BDE6C514EC12" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H5E9EA99A49B74C539C7E2B1D40830D98"><enum>(d)</enum><header>IUU certification procedure</header><paragraph id="H9CFD5BA24C6A4D6BBE7A9BA6188DC751"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification determination</header><subparagraph id="H32667D3F309E4656BE1B0AD59279385F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a procedure for certifying whether a nation identified under subsection (b) has taken appropriate corrective action with respect to the offending activities identified under section (b) that has led to measurable improvements in the reduction of illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing and any underlying regulatory, policy, or practice failings or gaps that may have contributed to such identification.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H194953C8B94A466D8B817F7311CBE042"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Opportunity for comment</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the procedure established under subparagraph (A) provides for notice and an opportunity for comment by the identified nation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B493BA28499408C8ADAB3B0D503FF75"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Secretary shall, consistent with such procedure, determine and certify to the Congress not later than 90 days after the date on which the Secretary issues a final rule containing the procedure, and biennially thereafter—</text><clause id="H1429B18E55D948ED87685F804B312746"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the government of each nation identified under subsection (b) has provided documentary evidence that such nation has taken corrective action with respect to such identification; or</text></clause><clause id="H7D5B7A917C904E1E859B95A616118905"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the relevant international fishery management organization has taken corrective action that has ended the illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing activity by vessels of that nation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A3367413C842E081549ADB338E73E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative procedure</header><text>The Secretary may establish a procedure to authorize, on a shipment-by-shipment, shipper-by-shipper, or other basis the importation of fish or fish products from a fishery within a nation issued a negative certification under paragraph (1) if the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H098EB4F39A8341C18064B6C5C6FCBF27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines the fishery has not engaged in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing under an international fishery management agreement to which the United States is a party; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAE9A3CF015045D8B97D4F429B44481C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>determines the fishery is not identified by an international fishery management organization as participating in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B01DE0A0744BD3B4D51BE1BCF5FC09"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensures that any such seafood or seafood products authorized for entry under this section are imported consistent with the reporting and the recordkeeping requirements of Seafood Import Monitoring Program described in part 300.324(b) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BB03B6D9CBE4BB489818680ABD99A1F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of certification determination</header><subparagraph id="H9CD713C0753D4AF0A6B579629C6DE98D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Effect of negative certification</header><text>The provisions of subsections (a) and (b)(3) and (4) of section 101 of the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826a">16 U.S.C. 1826a(a)</external-xref> and (b)(3) and (4)) shall apply to any nation that, after being identified and warned under subsection (b) has failed to take the appropriate corrective actions for which the Secretary has issued a negative certification under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34BFD38345D74A958196067E9DF5452B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of positive certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of subsections (a) and (b)(3) and (4) of section 101 of the High Seas Driftnet Fisheries Enforcement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826a">16 U.S.C. 1826a(a)</external-xref> and (b)(3) and (4)) shall not apply to any nation identified under subsection (a) for which the Secretary has issued a positive certification under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HDCE72E4F742C4E579643145C07BA8C31"><enum>303.</enum><header>Illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing defined</header><subsection id="HA298C7B4A3F64F6680DAA559914FD80F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing in the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 609(e) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826j">16 U.S.C. 1826j(e)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3908522B661049A9B6DDA432378BE2D7" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H825EE653203A42DBA3118EDD00B658FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing defined</header><text>In this title, the term <term>illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</term> means any activity set out in paragraph 3 of the 2001 Food and Agriculture Organization International Plan of Action to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDA4D529281EF46A59577EE20AD7CEB58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing in the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB946D07B7F07452C895D05E32092B00D" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><paragraph id="H900B79A95F0E41389B861933A2F8A8E4"><enum>(51)</enum><text>The term <term>illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</term> means any activity set out in paragraph 3 of the 2001 Food and Agriculture Organization International Plan of Action to Prevent, Deter and Eliminate Illegal, Unreported, and Unregulated Fishing.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6FAE303027E64CE9855097DB5EFFFF8A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In construing the term <term>illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing</term> for purposes of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act and the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act, the Secretary shall follow internationally recognized labor rights stated in the International Labour Organization Declaration on Fundamental Principles and Rights at Work and its Follow-Up (1998), including—</text><paragraph id="H576C91E963B74036BB5F501E8091CF34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>freedom of association and the effective recognition of the right to collective bargaining;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EBDF80905E14A8C870ED9A0F7EAE301"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the elimination of all forms of forced or compulsory labor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C87A2C123F84D5EBC570A4EA88A6337"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the effective abolition of oppressive child labor, a prohibition on the worst forms of child labor, and other labor protections for children and minors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69F2615A18484534B787DD5A0A4F1680"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the elimination of discrimination in respect of employment and occupation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BF5301C5144437EA85D10F1D321A67B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>acceptable conditions of work with respect to minimum wages, hours of work, and occupational safety and health.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5951E3F1DF3B4BE2A152244F7C3824E0"><enum>304.</enum><header>Equivalent conservation measures</header><subsection id="H932F5EA2CAD04C42B4298F35B7660AE3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 610(a) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HA82A7D8522B84413829B6B7F35A0E22B" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H2671E5E7A9374ED5B9BCFB8CA37DC07F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><paragraph id="H70454F667759424DA6505282DB4744E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall identify and list in the report under section 607—</text><subparagraph id="H49346451F17E4BFC83E73753060B3741"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nation if—</text><clause id="H127274EE5EA24B97879E015E392DF4E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fishing vessel of that country is engaged, or has been engaged during the preceding 3 years in fishing activities or practices on the high sees or within the exclusive economic zone of another country, that have resulted in bycatch of a protected living marine resource; and</text></clause><clause id="HF68FCDE1D8DA46BA908E7158F598E472"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the vessel’s flag state has not adopted, implemented, and enforced a regulatory program governing such fishing designed to end or reduce such bycatch that is comparable to the regulatory program of the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A01E1A4055F4C76BE34953496DCA0A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nation if—</text><clause id="HEAE1DA862C784D7E889569BA074100F8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any fishing vessel of that country is engaged, or has engaged during the preceding 3 years, in fishing activities on the high sees or within the exclusive economic zone of another country that target or incidentally catch sharks; and</text></clause><clause id="HF6CA19C9338B49FCAEBC687150B4719F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the vessel’s flag state has not adopted, implemented, and enforced a regulatory program to provide for the conservation of sharks, including measures to prohibit removal of any of the fins of a shark, including the tail, before landing the shark in port that is comparable to that of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3138E7A9663C4473B56852BC411668D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The Secretary shall make an identification under paragraph (1) at any time that the Secretary has sufficient information to make such identification.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA0F3E10C63C249AFB6916D866E3E9391"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and negotiation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 610(b) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k(b)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H7CBAA7FCFB9A4908AB98C16840C9E38D" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H7EB260BF19F14C9C93B74D5CB78BC401"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and negotiation</header><text>The Secretary of State, acting in conjunction with the Secretary, shall—</text><paragraph id="H1E1A5D9B3ABB44858A97A23B7D4E9CE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>notify, as soon as possible, the President, nations that have been identified under subsection (a), and other nations whose vessels engage in fishing activities or practices described in subsection (a), about the provisions of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB9AB264CCD344A9A3D70F6366DDD493"><enum>(2)</enum><text>initiate discussions as soon as possible with all foreign countries which are engaged in, or a fishing vessel of which has engaged in, fishing activities described in subsection (a), for the purpose of entering into bilateral and multilateral treaties with such countries to protect such species and to address any underlying failings or gaps that may have contributed to identification under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F7F4189263349228F8C111382B63155"><enum>(3)</enum><text>seek agreements calling for international restrictions on fishing activities or practices described in subsection (a) through the United Nations, the Food and Agriculture Organization’s Committee on Fisheries, and appropriate international fishery management bodies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D20FF6CBBC04FBAA7740F73712D879F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>initiate the amendment of any existing international treaty for the protection and conservation of such species to which the United States is a party in order to make such treaty consistent with the purposes and policies of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5EE9E2D5CA304FA8AD44DD0FAD76F689"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conservation certification procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 610(c) of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826k">16 U.S.C. 1826k(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDD1C4F259107485485B79EF69FD8796A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>, taking into account different conditions,</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H382AF3AF0618431B8B0B0DAE2AAEABDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>the public and</quote> after <quote>comment by</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD4596AFA5A948E1A1D115680F7D96E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H67AF65A030B34A178E93D6B0055F8A52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>, taking into account different conditions</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85A86E3F6DD3495387F5465F798521DA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEB82E563B5246BA918F33E665C6A098"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC2DDAD2B1BDC429DBFB4D9FF99797257" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subparagraph id="H634B0C7B3773480FA9279532AF45D58B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensures that any such fish or fish products authorized for entry under this section are imported consistent with the reporting and the recordkeeping requirements of the Seafood Import Monitoring Program established by part 300.324(b) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B036A97C1E044A3BBFBA55F0861AA00"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>(except to the extent that such provisions apply to sport fishing equipment or fish or fish products not caught by the vessels engaged in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H44ABE035225A48F8AE6853BBD75E6775"><enum>305.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate regulations implementing this title.</text></section></title><title id="H3C8090801B764F84889C1C61BC2AFD36"><enum>IV</enum><header>Maritime SAFE Amendments</header><section id="H78648C35751A493FA4521096AFEE2282"><enum>401.</enum><header>Illegal, Unreported, or Unregulated Fishing Working Group responsibilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3551(c) of the Maritime SAFE Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H26296AF1914945548F1DBA68177658DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (12), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAE68FAADFA6413187AC06D7C26168FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (13), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10E969B062E44003AF051E9BFD7D9333"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBBE0A08772B846689EC4A108FAA1FA65" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><paragraph id="HE2807D05349044FE9CC2182F9BCE33A5"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing a strategy for leveraging enforcement capacity against illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing and increasing enforcement and other actions across relevant import control and assessment programs including—</text><subparagraph id="HFDDE9774D6A54C40AF863D0CE852DFE4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Seafood Import Monitoring Program described in part 300.324(b) of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9431FDE064FF4EF097376CDF5C85F9A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the List of Goods Produced by Child Labor or Forced Labor produced pursuant to section 105 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7112">22 U.S.C. 7112</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9DA7AFFD03403886F0FCE93AC7910C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the List of Nations with vessels engaged in illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing pursuant to section 607 of the High Seas Driftnet Fishing Moratorium Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1826h">16 U.S.C. 1826h</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA313F932CE2C40B195498589E1B5E1B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Trafficking in Persons Report required by section 110 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7107">22 U.S.C. 7107</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE077C0CC7055460CA9D2100013DEEFF9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s Forced Labor Division and enforcement activities and regulations authorized under Section 307 of the Tariff Act of 1930 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/1307">19 U.S.C. 1307</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H719FB2B089DF4929B7EE3B0863EA1F87"><enum>(F)</enum><text>other relevant programs of Working Group member agencies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6ADA13FB3D04D209A04EE59314389C7"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing areas for increased information sharing and collaboration among Federal Working Group member agencies and State-based enforcement, wildlife, and fisheries management agencies to identify, interdict, investigate, and prosecute illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing and fraudulent seafood imports into the United States that were a product of such fishing, including through implementation of the Seafood Import Monitoring Program. The Federal Working Group shall emphasize developing, updating, and employing risk screens to analyze harvest, traceability, and verification and certification information in real time as a key pathway to trigger product audits and enforcement actions.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H153D481934C04CFC96319F7B88BDA784"><enum>402.</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3552 of the Maritime SAFE Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3FE7CF9DD6D741D38F2EE5745B44A0AE" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H7BD8669A26DA40408082F98E53F1E656"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategies To optimize data collection, sharing, and analysis</header><paragraph id="H34D4F38941C04730AA5E36683662B477"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategic plan submitted under subsection (a) shall identify information and resources to prevent illegal, unreported, or unregulated fishing or fraudulently labeled or otherwise misrepresented seafood from entering United States commerce. The report shall include a timeline for implementation of recommendations with respect to each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H70683AB728F04E21987BDA432892D695"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Identification of relevant data streams collected by Working Group members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC32504E7FDE94C35A99B2F201523237D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identification of legal, jurisdictional, or other barriers to the sharing of such data.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ADD39F137E545B4AB881FE5FEEF4844"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Strategies for integrating data streams through the International Trade Data System Automated Commercial Environment or other relevant digital platforms.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28B36B9024C84F83A7FD113D8F1D2186"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Recommendations for enhancing the automated risk targeting and effectiveness of risk analysis and detection of illegal, unauthorized, or unreported fishing and fraudulent seafood through the Seafood Import Monitoring Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BE99E587792456E829C4B2780EEEB9F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for improving the utility and effectiveness of the Commercial Targeting and Analysis Center in detecting illegal, unauthorized, or unreported fishing and fraudulent products through adoption of these strategies or other enhancements.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A75CBDB042E4801992D8068D8A37ACB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Recommendations for joint enforcement protocols, collaboration, and information sharing between Federal agencies and States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8171FA5970D4DD9AAB8C881E2B7ED60"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Recommendations for sharing and developing forensic resources between Federal agencies and States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD40F908D36B48D698C6D640D45876C8"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Recommendations for enhancing capacity for U.S. Customs and Border Protection and National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration to conduct field investigations and to coordinate enforcement efforts with State enforcement officials.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA9657AB943C4576B3E23068136F7999"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An implementation strategy, with milestones and deadlines and specific budgetary requirements, for implementing recommendations described in the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB010E8F2264464C8809D9D7757E0EEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after submission of the 5-year integrated strategic plan, the Working Group shall submit a report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives on progress in implementing the recommendations described in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H9A9063E26D364B63AE268EECDB725844"><enum>403.</enum><header>Authority to hold fish products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 311(b)(1) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1861">16 U.S.C. 1861(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDC30699D87354E198B10A2E9BB128FB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB894CE3DDF974064A1882BDED30C09F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26004E2672714ECDA75CC697CFDE2DA2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following a new subparagraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4B5AA7E6E68E4D22930E006E39498C8F" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subparagraph id="H9FE341A9D2664CCAB55B67EDA45B6AF9" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">detain, for a period of up to 14 days, any shipment of fish or fish product imported into, landed on, introduced into, exported from, or transported within the jurisdiction of the United States, or, if such fish or fish product is deemed to be perishable, sell and retain the proceeds therefrom for a period of up to 21 days.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title><title id="HBB2D65C732684A458996CA084F47BE8A"><enum>V</enum><header>Maritime Awareness</header><section id="H67651AB26A4A49099DBA05C00449B504"><enum>501.</enum><header>Automatic identification system requirements</header><subsection id="H6028FCC78F9A4AC086969622D5856A0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement for fishing vessels To have automatic identification systems</header><text>Section 70114(a)(1) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB6F3D2CBC9A74810B379CF37CA33D173"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>, while operating on the navigable waters of the United States,</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03040893333E433DA245FE8D8AF276D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) through (D) as clauses (i) through (iv); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ABCDF20EB4C4ABF8A90378BF565DC23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting before clauses (i) through (iv), as redesignated by paragraph (2), the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HDE13908E99354A37946E05E20599B243" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subparagraph id="H93A7643C46174993B6C42CCB76D289A2" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While operating on the navigable waters of the United States:</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H932A198E59734CF196062C6A19AF8515"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H92275DEFB07E4A17A0EBDDFDA0CD3EC8" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subparagraph id="HE0876CAA6788422BA00C1B3FBBE5E239" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vessel of the United States that is more than 65 feet overall in length, while engaged in fishing, fish processing, or fish tendering operations on the navigable waters of the United States or in the United States exclusive economic zone.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF30D6ADBCCCF4DC6AF733BF64CF189CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Commerce for fiscal year 2022, $5,000,000, to remain available until expended, to purchase automatic identification systems for fishing vessels, fish processing vessels, fish tender vessels more than 50 feet in length, as described under this title and the amendments made by this title.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc> Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

