<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AAE79A1A69946FA85E3B9DE0EBBC5E4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7953 IH: Expanding Opportunity for Minority Depository Institutions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7953</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 to establish a Financial Agent Mentor-Protégé Program within the Department of the Treasury, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H199C40187A164351A6791CBEFEAFA081" style="OLC"><section id="HEDA1F1E42BF94331B41F734655C6B04E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Opportunity for Minority Depository Institutions Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Expanding Opportunity for MDIs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB3B3C402799E4019A50D690B92538ED0" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Financial Agent Mentor-Protégé Program</header><subsection id="H33A421649884499790E2BFE7858B4BE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBD988562E65F4FE5A298615D3A341CB4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H88D15B79BD78417C9087BD3A06B2540C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Financial Agent Mentor-Protégé Program</header><paragraph id="HBB448D78C2784168A84BED3ECDBF4393"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Financial Agent Mentor-Protégé Program</quote> (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) under which a financial agent designated by the Secretary or a large financial institution may serve as a mentor, under guidance or regulations prescribed by the Secretary, to a small financial institution to allow such small financial institution—</text><subparagraph id="H1BF09A8DD8C5434C930D5056DDAC5C73"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to be prepared to perform as a financial agent; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFE21591090F41F3912580A4C869128B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to improve capacity to provide services to the customers of the small financial institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE10D8EDF720845E7B99A050818313D83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall hold outreach events to promote the participation of financial agents, large financial institutions, and small financial institutions in the Program at least once a year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA78EBA21CB2E4094AFDC35B1E5455E59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue guidance or regulations to establish a process under which a financial agent, large financial institution, or small financial institution may be excluded from participation in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D1FC0633A341DE8CC8FB4CAEE4F8E8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Office of Minority and Women Inclusion of the Department of the Treasury shall include in the report submitted to Congress under section 342(e) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act information pertaining to the Program, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCE34C5FFE7CF41449A3EF8B7F6197D1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of financial agents, large financial institutions, and small financial institutions participating in such Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7BAA5101F4A4A56B3DA919F8CCF8B3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of outreach events described in paragraph (2) held during the year covered by such report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF984F385077749E7A1D8C35BF684FA49"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H00996F3328EB40E9881EF13D154CBB86"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Financial agent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>financial agent</term> means any national banking association designated by the Secretary of the Treasury to be employed as a financial agent of the Government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9E92A528484FAD8EAA2CD741DD6553"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Large financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>large financial institution</term> means any entity regulated by the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration that has total consolidated assets greater than or equal to $50,000,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D68D0C4F429461789333EF8909F01B4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small financial institution</header><text>The term <term>small financial institution</term> means—</text><clause id="H8EFAA53C8BC7415AA2C371641EAA1A29"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any entity regulated by the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration that has total consolidated assets lesser than or equal to $2,000,000,000; or</text></clause><clause id="H011F987902FE4EC2808E8AF76196B98F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a minority depository institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC3BB62F0472A40F593695F2189F43345"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

