<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H229B53B071AA42BAA129006C5B7A5F87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8909 IH: Simplified Joint Consolidation Separation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8909</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220920">September 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000929">Mrs. Spartz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001219">Mr. Sempolinski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000473">Mrs. Flores</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a process for separating joint consolidation loans to ensure timely relief for borrowers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0C1DDC588E7C4C79B3AA2E26CD041681" style="OLC"><section id="H1E5D3AA459CA4CE5BA258BDFD5EC7A61" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Simplified Joint Consolidation Separation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H204C6AF0B1FC449AA31FA4D800CD56BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of guidance to separate joint consolidation loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 428C of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-3">20 U.S.C. 1078–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3A4E5B4162D14CEA89C14B7879CDA1F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(3)(B)(i)—</text><subparagraph id="HC46BFF6C3EF64321B864ACC0B0888C47"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subclause (IV);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0FE8BC799DF47ED8846FC72CC1B26CD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of subclause (V) and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5E250B197A142939E2DAEB5D901BAB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB6E34D7557FE42CEA3EDC5007DDB1D80" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="HED3425AA7249425FB873E333760B130F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">separation of a joint consolidation loan into individual consolidation loans in accordance with subsection (g) shall not be considered receipt of a consolidation loan for purposes of this clause, and an individual’s status as an eligible borrower shall not change solely as a result of such a separation.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H268CD55CEFCD4401831770302CE6EE3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA18B13D3D73D4E9E9FF698DB65E9D453" style="OLC"><subsection id="H9DD3104F1B78472CBB21A603930876B8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Secretary guidance on joint consolidation loans</header><paragraph id="H43F0F099256A4D57B264D8FE683C288B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HF7FD5C7CFD48458EB217E12E5C6E8782"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>Notwithstanding section 421(d), a married couple, or two individuals who were previously married and received a joint consolidation loan under subsection (a)(3)(C) (as such subsection was in effect on June 30, 2006), may jointly request the Secretary or holder, in accordance with paragraph (2), to separate the existing joint consolidation loan into two individual consolidation loans.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5245B10CFE53448881CC7F3FD1ED9673"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility for borrowers in default</header><text>A married couple, or two individuals who were previously a married couple, who received a joint consolidation loan described in <internal-xref idref="HF7FD5C7CFD48458EB217E12E5C6E8782" legis-path="(g)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> and are in default on such joint consolidation loan may both be eligible for separation of such joint consolidation loan into two individual consolidation loans in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DFD39F5FBB14A4CAE95CAC2CC7F56FD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligibility for individual requests</header><clause id="HF2BDDD5A41114D3D9AE9D98924932861"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Circumstances allowing for separate application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is one of the parties who received a joint consolidation loan described in <internal-xref idref="HF7FD5C7CFD48458EB217E12E5C6E8782" legis-path="(g)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> may, separately and without regard to whether or when the other individual borrower who received such joint consolidation loan applies under <internal-xref idref="HF7FD5C7CFD48458EB217E12E5C6E8782" legis-path="(g)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref>, request separation of such joint consolidation loan into two individual consolidation loans in accordance with this subsection in a case in which the requesting individual borrower certifies to the Secretary that such borrower—</text><subclause id="H986CA109C007409AB07955BCA73EB897"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has experienced an act of domestic violence from the other individual borrower;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2BACA39605E045638F232D734CF53148"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has experienced an act of economic abuse from the other individual borrower; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D2A373FC2F44F22B19B63608ECF54EB"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is subject to a divorce decree, court order, or settlement agreement requiring the separation of joint loans and obligations.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9674CD4100DC41A4BD2DC205384612F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Obligation from separate application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a joint consolidation loan that is separated upon request of an individual borrower due to one or more circumstances described in <internal-xref idref="HF2BDDD5A41114D3D9AE9D98924932861" legis-path="(g)(1)(C)(i)">clause (i)</internal-xref>, the other non-applying individual borrower shall be liable for the outstanding balance of the individual consolidation loan of such borrower in the same manner as if both borrowers of the joint consolidation loan had applied for such separation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5B1F481FFFA42CF966D9A66F88241C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretarial and holder requirements</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a)(3)(A) or any other provision of law, the Secretary or holder may separate the joint consolidation loan for eligible borrowers who meet the eligibility requirements specified in <internal-xref idref="H43F0F099256A4D57B264D8FE683C288B" legis-path="(g)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref>. The two separate individual consolidation loans shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7D614EB800B149DD83F71D2166DB4EBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be for an amount equal to the product of—</text><clause id="H821E0BB97437497393017C9C9391C60A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the unpaid principal and accrued unpaid interest of the joint consolidation loan (as of the date that is the day before separation of the joint consolidation loan) and any outstanding charges and fees with respect to such loan; and</text></clause><clause id="HC4F2089CE512448E99B481ECCF449C1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of the joint consolidation loan attributable to the loans of the individual borrower for whom such separate consolidation loan is being separated, as determined—</text><subclause id="H965D5628B85E450AB778746608E161C5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>on the basis of the loan obligations of such borrower with respect to such joint consolidation loan (as of the date such joint consolidation loan was made); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H2C9E57034DB64B5CAC9D572F8A1E8846"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case in which both borrowers request, on the basis of proportions requested by the borrowers, outlined in a divorce decree, court order, or settlement agreement; </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5BE046880E04BA8A83E63AC7C67C76F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have the same rate of interest as the joint consolidation loan (as of the date that is the day before separation of the joint consolidation loan); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82A9479B578C4DF1BE14F3921B1ADA0B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not be considered new loans, shall be deemed to have been made on the date such joint consolidation loan was made, and shall have the same terms and conditions as other consolidation loans made under this part on such date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

