<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8404 EAS: Respect for Marriage Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 8404</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221129">November 29, 2022.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendment:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="ide59d907ebf374657ac413db72b33b2ff" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 8404) entitled <quote>An Act to repeal the Defense of Marriage Act and ensure respect for State regulation of marriage, and for other purposes.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following: </text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block style="OLC" blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="H1AC2D41901DB453CA2AA14352A89BF3A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Respect for Marriage Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id2858e6d2d5cc4198a2ab9be5a6fc782c"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="id3b6400a5fa204017a92a119f129f51f6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No union is more profound than marriage, for it embodies the highest ideals of love, fidelity, devotion, sacrifice, and family.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddd49a29bb7b641b3b0a5fa5aa578684d"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Diverse beliefs about the role of gender in marriage are held by reasonable and sincere people based on decent and honorable religious or philosophical premises. Therefore, Congress affirms that such people and their diverse beliefs are due proper respect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="iddcc219b356624930aefb2d405830c42d"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Millions of people, including interracial and same-sex couples, have entered into marriages and have enjoyed the rights and privileges associated with marriage. Couples joining in marriage deserve to have the dignity, stability, and ongoing protection that marriage affords to families and children. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H5DB9FD0A5A72475DA9A17F2B70FF52DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal of section added to title 28, United States Code, by section 2 of the Defense of Marriage Act<editorial></editorial></header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1738C of title 28, United States Code, is repealed.</text></section><section id="HC2BB759B6D604582A006AB82CE5331AF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Full faith and credit given to marriage equality</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/115">Chapter 115</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this Act, is further amended by inserting after section 1738B the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC4669643571F4629A84BB660DF30C668" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H0697F2509ACB455C96E2D5155F3B5C38"><enum>1738C.</enum><header>Certain acts, records, and proceedings and the effect thereof</header><subsection id="H200407FDFAE64BB3B29A10224007C61E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No person acting under color of State law may deny—</text><paragraph id="HA68514374A3D41A59FE010F98260CD5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> full faith and credit to any public act, record, or judicial proceeding of any other State pertaining to a marriage between 2 individuals, on the basis of the sex, race, ethnicity, or national origin of those individuals; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91D3D83D4A29433E8344E4C22A9F7869"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a right or claim arising from such a marriage on the basis that such marriage would not be recognized under the law of that State on the basis of the sex, race, ethnicity, or national origin of those individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D7BF42B3857406092B8DC80BA910964"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may bring a civil action in the appropriate United States district court against any person who violates subsection (a) for declaratory and injunctive relief.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFFEBC386861E48AD8B1E797DE79B5A2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is harmed by a violation of subsection (a) may bring a civil action in the appropriate United States district court against the person who violated such subsection for declaratory and injunctive relief.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD882236517BB441C9358C3232CE143E2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>State defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term under section 7 of title 1.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H6DF603A5E4D4432C9785BF878982ACC8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Marriage recognition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7 of title 1, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA58FF4C7D5C4B168467D268B58B08DD" style="USC"><section id="H29C3FA5693AF44FAB7E8FC254C97324D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Marriage</header><subsection id="H1733ECD123E04C1AA7EE53ABA4B7FA81"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of any Federal law, rule, or regulation in which marital status is a factor, an individual shall be considered married if that individual’s marriage is between 2 individuals and is valid in the State where the marriage was entered into or, in the case of a marriage entered into outside any State, if the marriage is between 2 individuals and is valid in the place where entered into and the marriage could have been entered into in a State.</text></subsection><subsection id="H79AFA4227B0A40A5BB6FEA0EA29DABD8"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>State</term> means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, or any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD26D1D9C3E724D2C830ABC288FE67752"><enum>(c)</enum><text>For purposes of subsection (a), in determining whether a marriage is valid in a State or the place where entered into, if outside of any State, only the law of the jurisdiction applicable at the time the marriage was entered into may be considered. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="id8735008cc2624a22ac6786973349bfec"><enum>6.</enum><header>No impact on religious liberty and conscience</header><subsection id="id9f81bbb81c974ead9d977374f0b1d320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to diminish or abrogate a religious liberty or conscience protection otherwise available to an individual or organization under the Constitution of the United States or Federal law.</text></subsection><subsection id="idbebc991f419a4b988ba6a76ecf8199d0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Goods or services</header><text>Consistent with the First Amendment to the Constitution, nonprofit religious organizations, including churches, mosques, synagogues, temples, nondenominational ministries, interdenominational and ecumenical organizations, mission organizations, faith-based social agencies, religious educational institutions, and nonprofit entities whose principal purpose is the study, practice, or advancement of religion, and any employee of such an organization, shall not be required to provide services, accommodations, advantages, facilities, goods, or privileges for the solemnization or celebration of a marriage. Any refusal under this subsection to provide such services, accommodations, advantages, facilities, goods, or privileges shall not create any civil claim or cause of action.</text></subsection></section><section id="id0c67347ad614478aa5fadf7fddbb360c"><enum>7.</enum><header>Statutory prohibition</header><subsection id="ida22c8fbf7a4748b18cf44373b346a36c"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No impact on status and benefits not arising from a marriage</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to deny or alter any benefit, status, or right of an otherwise eligible entity or person which does not arise from a marriage, including tax-exempt status, tax treatment, educational funding, or a grant, contract, agreement, guarantee, loan, scholarship, license, certification, accreditation, claim, or defense. </text></subsection><subsection id="id87a311405ca24ac9a5a2bff020d09203"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No Federal recognition of polygamous marriages</header><text>Nothing in this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, shall be construed to require or authorize Federal recognition of marriages between more than 2 individuals.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE4836D80B7A644129EC73871CEEA1074"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or any amendment made by this Act, or the application of such provision to any person, entity, government, or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, or any amendment made thereby, or the application of such provision to all other persons, entities, governments, or circumstances, shall not be affected thereby. </text></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 

