<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7ECA0398ECCE4B169C00BDB04ACAC3BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8893 IH: To establish a pilot program on research and development of plant-based protein for the Navy, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8893</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a pilot program on research and development of plant-based protein for the Navy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFB6D38E43B16432B8AB15E0C50DE2B53" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HE04C573BCCE74855BE884DEBFE3488BA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Pilot program on research and development of plant-based protein for the Navy</header>
<subsection id="HE1E724A20422430195CA098132F5A277" commented="yes"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2023, the Secretary of the Navy shall establish and carry out a pilot program to offer plant-based protein options at <inline-comment display="yes">forward operating bases</inline-comment><inline-comment display="yes"><italic>should this be <quote>naval facilities</quote> to match the rest of the bill text (assuming that naval facilities are a subset of forward operating bases under the control of the Navy)</italic></inline-comment> for consumption by members of the Navy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2F7610856F4C4E2A8EF173EED4FE7C02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Locations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1, 2023, the Secretary shall identify not fewer than two naval facilities to participate in the pilot program and shall prioritize facilities (such as Joint Region Marianas, Guam, Navy Support Facility Diego Garcia, and U.S. Fleet Activities Sasebo, Japan) where livestock-based protein options may be costly to obtain or store.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1260A9BCD658498290E3F3450DAC2230"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorities</header><text>In establishing and carrying out the pilot program under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Navy may use the following authorities:</text> <paragraph id="HA0586AD203B24F1F82BCC5166E182753"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The authority to carry out research and development projects under section 4001 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2BA3762578534DF9AD0DE16A1BE64E71"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to enter into transactions other than contracts and grants under section 4021 of such title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36FED750486C4ADCB479698F61202309"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to enter into cooperative research and development agreements under section 4026 of such title.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0D4EA865393B45C68A9BA4A6D65F6ED9" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to prevent offering livestock-based protein options alongside plant-based protein options at naval facilities identified under subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFA1A4DE926E241A3BF81DBCEF358DB69"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to carry out the pilot program established under this section shall terminate three years after the date on which the Secretary establishes the pilot program required under this section.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H29AD18CC3F4C4017B535FCA8FEE8BF9C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the termination of the pilot program, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the pilot program that includes the following:</text> <paragraph id="HC8E2BFD328C94F7BB112235678229264"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The consumption rate of plant-based protein options by members of the Navy <inline-comment display="yes">under the pilot program</inline-comment><inline-comment display="yes"><italic>suggest <quote>at forward operating bases/naval facilities participating in the pilot program</quote></italic></inline-comment>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94A07328124742738A6F91FE6F277A42" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective criteria to increase plant-based protein options at naval facilities not identified under subsection (b).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9724F5EB1E3471DB3FFA67B363FF1F2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the costs of obtaining and storing plant-based protein options compared to the costs of obtaining and storing livestock-based protein options at <inline-comment display="yes">selected naval facilities</inline-comment><inline-comment display="yes"><italic>selected how? by whom? Is the intent that these facilities are different from those identified under subsection (b)?</italic> </inline-comment>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB265F25195D54F47936C8DA42B6828B2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HF1BFC6D8587C45DE9FFFA25E38E42B03"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2F8FF4721F46449BAF16D276DB4DDA42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plant-based protein options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>plant-based protein options</quote> means edible vegan or vegetarian meat alternative products made using plant and other non-livestock-based proteins.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

