<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0860C7D40EF04CAB9C81FE9659945A3A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6390 IH: Electric Vehicle Charging Infrastructure for Farmers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6390</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make financial assistance under the Rural Energy for America program available with respect to certain electric vehicle supply equipment expenses.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F6BAE3A364B433C9A3476C11B3DCD0E" style="OLC"><section id="H9E3E43EC945845A5A42E7F45A67F6161" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Electric Vehicle Charging Infrastructure for Farmers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1CF243CD63F1409787A21D2528A30543"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HE67BA8EF7A1046F1B3B651775FE7E5FA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The transition to electric vehicles is a critical step towards reducing global emissions. According to the United States Department of Energy, <quote>electric vehicles produce fewer emissions that contribute to climate change and smog than internal combustion vehicles</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6830FB0A63174E9B8F36C1D4517589DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Nearly half of all people in the United States live in counties with unhealthy levels of ozone or particle pollution. Every year, more than 20,000 people in the United States die prematurely from pollution stemming from the transportation sector.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFF003812A14D6FB73A4B147488B64C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Demand for publicly accessible electric vehicle chargers continues to grow. The National Renewable Energy Laboratory estimates that by 2050, between 106,000 and 138,000 stations with 343,000 and 447,000 ports could be needed to meet consumer demand.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EF9E87240E44D0A892C520ED449DAF6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Travel by people who live in rural areas constitutes 68 percent of our Nation’s lane miles, but such people represent only 19 percent of our Nation’s population. The cost per mile traveled is lower for electric vehicles, saving rural drivers thousands of dollars over the lifetimes of their vehicles.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H08073ED1C5624D2C9A689893745E9833"><enum>3.</enum><header>Eligibility of electric vehicle supply equipment expenses for financial assistance under the Rural Energy for America program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 9007 of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/8107">7 U.S.C. 8107</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB95C076575F74FF4BE522D4AA52FEFAC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8098995805E14864BD455D975C58ACF0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authority To provide financial assistance with respect to certain electric vehicle supply equipment expenses</header><paragraph id="H3C46F7520FC144BD84B9680322A2A693"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may provide financial assistance in accordance with this section with respect to expenses for electric vehicle supply equipment for light-duty vehicles, for medium-duty vehicles, and for heavy-duty vehicles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAF412475ED548A68320DCF3D2BCC3A2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H72CAFBC80AB54AE2B3ED7EF4C27E85FF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Electric vehicle supply equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electric vehicle supply equipment</term> means any conductors, including ungrounded, grounded, and equipment grounding conductors, electric vehicle connectors, attachment plugs, and all other fittings, devices, power outlets, electrical equipment, or apparatuses installed specifically for the purpose of delivering energy to an electric vehicle or to a battery intended to be used in an electric vehicle.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H029EC9742A9446F697044A37304FBCFC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Light-duty electric vehicle</header><text>The term <term>light-duty electric vehicle</term> means a vehicle that—</text><clause id="H2A5CD939997C483AA6B9C547C9FA299B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">derives all of the power of the vehicle from electricity; and</text></clause><clause id="H9683EDC648A24AD7B15ECEF9E396ED2F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a gross vehicle weight rating of less than 10,000 pounds.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9FE00EC33544763B8F08B71B914FAAD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Medium-duty electric vehicle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>medium-duty electric vehicle</term> means a vehicle that—</text><clause id="HF5634324C29348C98B8E161E6431D075"><enum>(i)</enum><text>derives all of the power of the vehicle from electricity; and</text></clause><clause id="H4DAEA76888394CF08CB47BE250619A9A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a gross vehicle weight rating of—</text><subclause id="HFD72AF65AB0D4A01A98662398776E6B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than 10,000 pounds; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAF16B147C3D244649898EDB2E8165AB2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>less than 26,000 pounds.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H835942C76D014C499C10D209480B22FB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Heavy-duty electric vehicle</header><text>The term <term>heavy-duty electric vehicle</term> means a vehicle that—</text><clause id="HDC8368BFF66342E1809A6992AD22466C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>derives all of the power of the vehicle from electricity; and</text></clause><clause id="HF75C8C6A9DB24B3683171654C1137510"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has a gross vehicle weight rating of not less than 26,000 pounds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

