<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF91BFF572F5248E7846AB6250C275A0D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9281 IH: Food Deserts Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9281</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221110">November 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants to States to support the establishment and operation of grocery stores in underserved communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0304E37B08D94923A70C9AA083DF39FA" style="OLC"><section id="H2E66D195931B458AA8A7B3B5B6DDA674" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Food Deserts Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB3AD481E2710422D8ABF3664D238A1F5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program to establish grocery stores in underserved communities</header><subsection id="HABA3C60869714366A0CE849751309D45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a program to provide capitalization grants to States for the purpose of establishing revolving funds to support the establishment and operation of grocery stores in underserved communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDF49B3407FF7495CA3414F6C4BB1F07B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State receiving funds under this Act shall administer the revolving fund of the State through an instrumentality of the State with such powers and limitations as may be required to operate such fund in accordance with the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D69DC4262C940C8B6496DBAF1009DF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Projects and activities eligible for assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts in a revolving fund shall be used for the purpose of making loans—</text><paragraph id="HB05FE7F4C4854F85A07EE440033A1318"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to open a grocery store in an underserved community, except that such loan may not be used for the purpose of new construction;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H853A640F7158472E8E5477D2B8B59888"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support the operations of an existing grocery store in an underserved community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5140DF81B694A2AA7E4C7AE01EB6127"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide access to healthy food; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88779EFF0F7E4F32BE897F5D30C62DD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support the operations of a program participant that is located in a community that would be an underserved community if the program participant was not located in such community.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4947E77A046D434097D204A05F8AB542"><enum>(d)</enum><header> Grocery stores eligible for assistance</header><paragraph id="H14661460F57F491F9B34BBBF2B5B8592"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Required criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State receiving a capitalization grant under this Act may only make a loan from the revolving fund of the State to an entity that the State determines—</text><subparagraph id="H99F5863959804A3EA927B2CDA2A6A48F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is a grocery store or will be a grocery store after opening;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AEC5D86BD054BB9BE55EABAF8DA63DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>emphasizes or will emphasize unprocessed, healthful foods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00E8107D4D34BF991EDC06947F8D97B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides or will provide a variety of raw fruits and vegetables;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C0B21BA0B26478ABBCD9FAB8AE5E876"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides or will provide staple foods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD621DDC8B81495986D5A076A3229192"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a plan to keep such foods in stock to the extent possible;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H410B9758DEA64648854C496ACB2BB244"><enum>(F)</enum><text>charge affordable at or below market values;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA27C04C5E908412690C692CB6E610E40"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">either—</text><clause id="H376699BAEEBD40668CBC7613BDB7C96A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is demonstrably qualified to operate a grocery store; or</text></clause><clause id="H356E774E827B47F0A555B510E8212E45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of such application, has existing partnerships with organizations that provide technical assistance on business operations of food services; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74B30BC22B6E4E19B1C30280D9D7C51F"><enum>(H)</enum><text>will match no less than 20 percent, from non-Federal funds, of the amount of such loan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F76A176CE9D463F808E995F0158E169"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority criteria</header><text>A State shall prioritize an application for a loan from the revolving fund of the State from an entity that the State determines—</text><subparagraph id="HFA5948B636F9478E8F30E7B372CC20EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hires or plans to hire workers who reside within the underserved community that would be served by the entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B2B49C7B8CF49CC94A8C0F34B69A5F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides or plans to provide classes or other educational information about a healthful diet;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF900335042D040C0B2606D30965AB62D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sources or plans to source food from local urban farms and gardens; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E2FD58239174FAE8A9592F33B808D14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrates existing supply chain relationships in the grocery industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H16F45AD9A6CF4F06B8F922A7910493E4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity that desires a loan from a revolving fund of a State shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H98426EDFB5C04A00819FCC7F8E9CF8D8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Loan conditions</header><paragraph id="H77CEC83C6A3E4297BA78C1019C1A0074"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A loan distributed from a revolving fund by a State may be used by a program participant only for the purposes specified in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDF4BB0C283A4877A59A2FD1A22BCBF6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interest rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A loan distributed by a State from a revolving fund—</text><subparagraph id="H0F7F21527E0144FE81BBE0B44B4003BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be made at or below market interest rates; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FE2D59B58314C8EBBF7336323C14DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be an interest free loan, at terms not to exceed the lesser of 30 years or the projected useful life (as determined by the State) of the project to be financed with the proceeds of the loan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF34670EC43E6400CB40FD5E3A064E3C8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Structure of loan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A loan may be distributed from a revolving fund by a State to a program participant in—</text><subparagraph id="H7B560BF457C14EC4BDFD09CDE226F37F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a lump sum; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE351D4DF203F4A0282BB1D9276FF65A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in multiple distributions over a period of years, if the State determines multiple distributions are necessary to carry out the project.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A672AB685E74CD2BD4DCE29795D10DE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Loan amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State may not provide a loan to a program participant from the revolving fund of the State in a fiscal year that exceeds 10 percent of the amount available from the fund for making distributions in that fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD578410D084546E5849E54BE64EAFC67"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annual principal and interest payments on a loan received from a revolving fund of a State shall commence not later than 1 year after the loan is disbursed to the program participant and all loans will be fully amortized upon the expiration of the term of the loan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CF59AFF84414A0A945344DEC4F4501A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Revenue for repayment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A program participant shall establish a dedicated source of revenue for repayment of a loan received from a revolving fund of a State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C83E5CFCF44ECE8E463F79670D90AD"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Crediting revolving fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A revolving fund of a State shall be credited with all payments of principal and interest on all loans made from the revolving fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD21ED6DAD81E4534A033D1852CAF6A7C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administration costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall charge a program participant an administrative fee of not more than 4 percent of the loan amount. The State shall use the fees to administer the revolving fund and conduct administration activities under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA630BE553C6A479D87FD161D8C7BAB70"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to program participants to assist with sourcing of food, food storage, and other operational requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H08D7C313020146538B1563FBC1A9CA76"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Bankruptcy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of the bankruptcy of a program participant, amounts owed on a loan from a revolving fund shall be afforded precedence over other debt.</text></subsection><subsection id="H51F4C22DFFD341EDA9C13AD99D323382"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Change in underserved status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a community that qualified as underserved during a period in which loans were made by a State pursuant to this section and no longer qualifies as underserved, recipients of loans under this section in such community—</text><paragraph id="H3518385C7F154A34BD1AE0CC232EF474"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not be eligible for further loans under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA96865C1EE3472198904FFDC54D59BF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not have their loan agreements altered.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H490C9EA843344545857643CD8CFDE3EA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Grocery store earnings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Earnings of a nonprofit organization or municipally owned program participant that are attributable to a loan received from a revolving fund of a State shall be used for reinvestment into the program participant or to support the continuity of operations of the program participant.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5F8A2FE543D74D499CCF84C12BA66D82"><enum>3.</enum><header>Capitalization grants to fund State revolving funds</header><subsection id="H36CF04F1DF6240CA90A9BA03A8AE132D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligibility of State for capitalization grant</header><text>To be eligible for a capitalization grant, a State shall—</text><paragraph id="HB65591E4FD484017AEB2E476BC2C715B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a revolving fund that complies with the requirements of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA30D5E57C057477783C17B021C45FBEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a process for applications and criteria for making loans from the revolving fund, subject to the requirements in section 2(d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H880CEC03BE6541CE8D8DAC2C102392D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Upon receipt of capitalization grant</header><text>Upon the receipt of a capitalization grant, a State shall deposit such capitalization grant into the revolving fund of the State.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD37A2DC3DF2146F18DF0C4E67E0A6E81"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a fiscal year, the Secretary shall apportion amounts made available for capitalization grants under this section among the States eligible under subsection (a) in the ratio that—</text><paragraph id="H65C5A6FA5A0E4A80BD5E338A241567E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the population of underserved communities in each State eligible under subsection (a), bears to</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD28B82E14564444BC943F6668344D51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the population of underserved communities in all States eligible under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H84D298F2C4F04B47A3D0BB5AE80A9BB9"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $150,000,000 for fiscal year 2022.</text></section><section id="HB861DEDC46F7444A8334B1369A8D1CFF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7CA3556F72F7499DAF693E99FD0C23BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capitalization grant</header><text>The term <term>capitalization grant</term> means a grant made to a State under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB285C496A7C4304A2A6D776C7DDCB51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Healthful food</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>healthful food</term> means food that reflects the most recent Dietary Guidelines for Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD829F6A127C46E3BC439BC1056FD305"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grocery store</header><text>The term <term>grocery store</term> means a retail store that derives income primarily from the sale of food for home preparation and consumption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F5FE8D8A094E6798576404F87266CA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program</term> means the program described in section 2(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H985B6D8902B04D59AB9FD6F43A57DBD3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Program participant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>program participant</term> means an entity that has received a loan under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1273631088C343BCABE4604C85240A20"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Revolving fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>revolving fund</term> means a fund established by a State for use as a depository for a capitalization grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H260276652EC640E38A0C776AB408C57B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE85BDF0549E04F54960EEC58431907B6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Staple food</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>staple food</term> has the meaning given the term in section 243(b) of the Department of Agriculture Reorganization Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/6953">7 U.S.C. 6953(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB3AACE714134F959D83E9C9A018479F"><enum>(9)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means States of the Union, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFF51A2CD62B4E31A5702BA4F6442AAB"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Underserved community</header><text>The term <term>underserved community</term> has the meaning given the term in section 310B(g)(9)(A) of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1932">7 U.S.C. 1932(g)(9)(A)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

