<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H86EF192C6F8B4E95852AB677B73281FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4227 EH: Developing and Empowering our Aspiring Leaders Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4227</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission to revise the definition of a qualifying investment to include an equity security issued by a qualifying portfolio company, whether acquired directly from the company or in a secondary acquisition, for purposes of the exemption from registration for venture capital fund advisers under the Investment Advisers Act of 1940, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H103E96EDD2D64D01BFA8B31630483756" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA007295356D245B0AC676DBE9223CFF7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing and Empowering our Aspiring Leaders Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF8D1BFDF34014B7D9F3F12C66E26046F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 180-day period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, if the Securities and Exchange Commission determines the revisions would facilitate capital formation without compromising investor protection, the Commission shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5FF503DC7C7741369E10CA5450BE856E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>revise the definition of a qualifying investment under paragraph (c) of section 275.203(l)–1 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations, to include an equity security issued by a qualifying portfolio company, whether acquired directly from the company or in a secondary acquisition; and</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H718767130B8F4D33A8657F2F0951212D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise paragraph (a) of such section to require, as a condition of a private fund qualifying as a venture capital fund under such paragraph, that the qualifying investments of the private fund are predominantly qualifying investments that were acquired directly from a qualifying portfolio company.</text> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220726" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 26, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


