<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H0766947EF4CF4E249564E16B49896A98" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6824 RH: President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 243</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6824</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–324]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220513">May 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220513">May 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 25, 2022</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security to hold an annual cybersecurity competition relating to offensive and defensive cybersecurity disciplines, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HHM00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HCA2154B5278346CCB09D13E4EBF227C8"><section id="H5E8D47A76EF94FB7B38F6E46500AD6D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H257A3C89A02245AD98EAFE7F5464C16E"><enum>2.</enum><header>President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition</header><subsection id="H03C4CDA13C5B4DA1810C06475FD8E312"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency (referred to in this section as the <quote>Director</quote>) of the Department of Homeland Security is authorized to hold an annual cybersecurity competition to be known as the <quote>Department of Homeland Security Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency’s President’s Cup Cybersecurity Competition</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>competition</quote>) for the purpose of identifying, challenging, and competitively awarding prizes, including cash prizes, to the United States Government’s best cybersecurity practitioners and teams across offensive and defensive cybersecurity disciplines.</text></subsection><subsection id="H972EB21460AC4CBFACF83EB7878D72F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Competition design</header><paragraph id="HA1A1369086D44F85B337FE2483A49972" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Director, in carrying out the competition, may consult with, and consider advice from, any person who has experience or expertise in the development, design, or execution of cybersecurity competitions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF772BB42AB5145DDA25F761A91165942"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to consultations pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEA445810F464553A6219D6EBA1C7B8A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>A person with whom the Director consults under paragraph (1) may not—</text><subparagraph id="H20E7207FF8EB4A98BB44CB63F47D533E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive pay by reason of being so consulted; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC76663DE1BFC47FC8CC610BCC6076C31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be considered an employee of the Federal Government by reason of so consulting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1E99A960E0EC47B6B063035160C4F7A8" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to participate in the competition, an individual shall be a Federal civilian employee or member of the uniformed services (as such term is defined in section 2101(3) of title 5, United States Code) and shall comply with any rules promulgated by the Director regarding the competition.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D7235FB5A644132B9BFBC10ACB4696E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Competition administration</header><text>The Director may enter into a grant, contract, cooperative agreement, or other agreement with a private sector for-profit or nonprofit entity or State or local government agency to administer the competition.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD7F54DC0ACF64489A90721FCF0416791"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Competition parameters</header><text>Each competition shall incorporate the following elements:</text><paragraph id="HE610760728E8420889B49201A32AAE8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Cybersecurity skills outlined in the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education Framework, or any successor framework.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46A73FD93AD4492A976A9C91A0E9CB6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Individual and team events.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H146BD7837EF94987A0A26EB0EBD0C860"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Categories demonstrating offensive and defensive cyber operations, such as software reverse engineering and exploitation, network operations, forensics, big data analysis, cyber analysis, cyber defense, cyber exploitation, secure programming, obfuscated coding, or cyber-physical systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E9D64DB9ECE44DF8E05EB7B04A56A16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other elements related to paragraphs (1), (2), or (3) as determined necessary by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8995C7DE18BE452FB0DA31B20A8D6FFF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Support for the competition, including financial support for the design and administration of the competition or funds for a cash prize, may consist of—</text><paragraph id="H84594AD92C5C40F4B807116B065DD0E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>amounts appropriated pursuant to appropriations Acts or otherwise made available for such purpose; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0BCA7829669497B973A61AFF1AC3CBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funds provided by other Federal agencies, which—</text><subparagraph id="HCD5FB57978544201BB1D8C96CE5B1002"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be credited to, and in addition to, any amounts appropriated or otherwise made available pursuant to paragraph (1) to carry out this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E4F4D60A8324B9A86553BF3473195D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be obligated and expended for such purpose by the Secretary of the Homeland Security, acting through the Director.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H241015E24F4A462C97BD7ECFC653AA29"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Director may use funds available for carrying out the competition authorized under this section for the following:</text><paragraph id="HD66E947D2F614E3798121F9C61AB29BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advertising, marketing, and promoting the competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98D34599223540EBA3E398AC1666E561"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Meals for participants and organizers of the competition if attendance at the meal during the competition is necessary to maintain the integrity of the competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4423180CD30431688658F6FAE2490B3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Promotional items, including merchandise and apparel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B3CF261915B439C9D8F29D7647EA06E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Monetary and nonmonetary awards for competition participants, including members of the uniformed services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H648D63547A684A7CB6838AF21E7F5DD4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Necessary expenses for the honorary recognition of competition participants, including members of the uniformed services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H132ECF7834BA412BB6BEB89CD477D584"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other appropriate activity necessary to carry out the competition, as determined by the Director.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H02908FA8B2374AE8842A446AAE55FD12"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Prize limitation</header><text>The Director may make one or more awards per competition, except that the amount or value of each shall not exceed $10,000. The Secretary of Homeland Security may make one or more awards per competition, except the amount or the value of each shall not to exceed $25,000. A monetary award under this section shall be in addition to the regular pay of the recipient.</text></subsection><subsection id="H902C586F7B2142CCB04284EC51A4A4C0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text>The Director shall annually provide to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="H60593A8CE9C6492CB97985FAAA29A91B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of available funds under subsection (f) for each competition conducted in the preceding year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0407D199FC74689B41FF877D09F7B2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of expenditures authorized in subsection (g) for each competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42A14FB7F203430D9F8BEDED98F2AB3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information relating to the participation of each competition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5723C26BDB564F3EB633FB77814D8DC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Information relating to lessons learned from each competition and how such lessons may be applied to improve cybersecurity operations and recruitment of the Cybersecurity and Infrastructure Security Agency of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220513">May 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc display="yes">Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

