<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H170F1C2814DD437F9F5D1E4C7D20B8F7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9448 IH: Free Speech Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9448</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001108">Mr. Comer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Federal Government from taking certain action relating to social media companies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCC9AD0C3518D4FF68F65B6A8C585ED83" style="OLC"><section id="H4492E8B71F5E4637A8B8893ADE0D9A1B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Free Speech Defense Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1459E18A3DD44133BDF6164398D7DB98" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4D85957E11264E4B9E0BE2F158C33954" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The First Amendment guarantees freedoms concerning religion, expression, assembly, and petition of the government. The First Amendment guarantees the freedom of expression by prohibiting the government from restricting the press or the right of an individual to speak freely. The First Amendment also guarantees the right of an individual to assemble peaceably and to petition the government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC639FA40ABAB4AF88C96DFB970432E1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Fourth Amendment states that each individual is secure from unreasonable searches and seizures of property by the government. The Fourth Amendment protects against arbitrary arrests, wiretaps, and other forms of surveillance conducted without a search warrant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H587E1ED2E4B047D1AFF75CD6D5A41D23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In July 2021, the White House press secretary, Jen Psaki, admitted that the White House was working with social media companies to identify <quote>misinformation.</quote></text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC387931030480285FA1B9D66280A2A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Specifically, Psaki said, <quote>[W]e’re regularly making sure social media platforms are aware of the latest narratives, dangerous to public health that we and many other Americans are seeing across all of social and traditional media.</quote>. Psaki also said, <quote>[W]e work to engage with them to better understand the enforcement of social media platform policies.</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FD0C9C0EE3C4D3CAB1D31EED2D565C7"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">286 pages of documents produced in July 2022 by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, in response to a Freedom of Information Act request submitted by the America First Legal Foundation, revealed shocking information, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6BFD01697C8946E58FB06356F2F5FC81"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention sent to officials of Twitter a chart of tweets that the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention determined to be <quote>misinformation</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77E97035BDDB4F3EB7F3885B8E0B3439"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention held regular BOLO (Be On The Lookout) meetings in which the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention would share with social media companies, including Twitter and Facebook, what the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention determined to be <quote>misinformation</quote>. In the meetings, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention would provide slide decks requesting, among other things, <quote>[p]lease do not share outside your trust and safety teams</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA76F389EA94A4EA8B60799AD6A4FE73F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommended to Twitter that information about the Vaccine Adverse Event Reporting System be added to tweets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H867AAA299347467681E458A72F404C26"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Officials from the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention directly engaged with Facebook, requesting that Facebook flag certain posts as disinformation and ensure that <quote>verifiable information sources</quote> were not blocked because posts on Facebook by State Health Departments were being blocked as vaccine misinformation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56DBFF087C2447C0B38E808EA31E2E27"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention created a COVID–19 Misinformation Reporting Channel for the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Census Bureau to make reports to Facebook and held a <quote>training meeting</quote> about the Misinformation Reporting Channel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD513240B7A3480FA016A94BF8544268"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$15,000,000 of Facebook advertising credits were provided to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the Department of Health and Human Services as a <quote>non-monetary gift</quote> to promote vaccines, social distancing, travel, and priority communication messages, which may have violated the limitation on voluntary services described in section 1342 of the Antideficiency Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/1342">31 U.S.C. 1342</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63D714B33A85486894A48F6BA0D151F6"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, Alejandro Mayorkas, failed to provide clear answers to Congress about the so-called <quote>Disinformation Governance Board</quote> and the selection of Nina Jankowicz to lead the Disinformation Governance Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECAD48314115459A93EA047824C1EA7A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Damning whistleblower documents revealed by Senators Josh Hawley and Chuck Grassley show the shocking extent to which the Disinformation Governance Board was willing to spy on Americans, without a warrant, and flag posts for social media companies as so-called <quote>disinformation</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB92100CA837747669E92EC17F743494D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that:</text><paragraph id="HB744DB8129214B98BB0C72153F0108F9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The records produced by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention in response to the Freedom of Information Act request described in section 2(5) reveal the extent to which the Biden Administration is willing to engage in unconstitutional and otherwise unlawful activities in total disregard of the rights of the American people. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H056EF1E05CED483CA9076E254E6A7117"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The <quote>Disinformation Governance Board</quote> established by the Department of Homeland Security is unconstitutional and should be terminated immediately.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8DE61B6A2764E1880AA1B01AFEF725C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The failure of Secretary Mayorkas to provide clear answers about the Disinformation Governance Board is disqualifying, and Secretary Mayorkas should resign immediately. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE52439F4A4544C3EAA4333C5B79DD657"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The antidote to <quote>misinformation</quote> and <quote>disinformation</quote> is not censorship but more information, so the American people can make informed decisions independently.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC12B7757362A432C81854175FC7FD033"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Government should not be allowed to circumvent the Constitution of the United States through intermediaries and third parties to violate the rights of the American people to information and freedom from intrusion by the Federal Government, even if the information is not consistent with the views of officials in the Federal Government.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9848AC54866B45E6849EC58BABF908AF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition against Federal regulation of social media companies</header><subsection id="H486886AEF9B2402896D9C0AE01FD4284"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition against regulation</header><paragraph id="H085995F171E64E38AE320E62AE18CFF0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Federal Government may not direct or encourage a social media company to—</text><subparagraph id="H6CE8D48E94A84EF7BED7119D5AF7044C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remove or suspend a user from the social media platform of the social media company;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0676BFD1D468429C9C83676EA5121CF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>label content on the social media platform of the social media company as information, disinformation, true, false, or any other similar characterization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE8B0D98B33B43DF873C00B0982C8DE2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>share with the Federal Government data or information about a particular topic or group of users on the social media platform of the social media company, including—</text><clause id="H13B7CE91A0924ADB8A0D73EBFD6FF08C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name, age, or demographic of the users; and</text></clause><clause id="H02A4B54FB852467DB7EDA7EF3CC7C925"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the content such users share on the social media platform of the social media company.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75F942DB37414CE0944566E7C012A698"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibitions described in subparagraphs (A) and (C) of paragraph (1) do not apply to an action taken by the Federal Government pursuant to a warrant—</text><subparagraph id="HB328222F05484220AE588193646C991D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issued by a Federal court of competent jurisdiction in accordance with the procedures described in rule 41 of the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H988755EBB57942F1B0F81F5C5BFCABEE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issued by a State court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE077CB2E8CD466FBF65F6B20255B050" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition against public-Private partnerships</header><paragraph id="HA112A433A07348A9B9FBB161DDA2CD6C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Federal Government may not enter into a public-private partnership with a social media company to monitor any content disseminated on the social media platform of the social media company.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H056BE358D9CE4186AFEDA55E58BF4324" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of existing public-private partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any public-private partnership described in paragraph (1), if in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, is terminated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD06942C3EB014321B8642EDF3455A37F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination of Disinformation Governance Board</header><paragraph id="H7B21D57E5A7C42DD8614E9E2A3D429D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Disinformation Governance Board established by the Department of Homeland Security, if in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, is terminated.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C1FCD6549CC4EBBB013777332BE7DC5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition against Federal funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal funds may not be used to fund any other entity that is substantially similar to the Disinformation Governance Board terminated pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEDF6212BC964E7DABACDD0FADDC0801" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition against soliciting or accepting free social media advertising</header><paragraph id="HA052087E49224E16B29C6313C5991E85" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency employee may not solicit or accept, or enter into a contract or other agreement (including a no-cost agreement) for, free advertising or other promotion on the social media platform of a social media company.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC658AC96C7874FD19384FB24D1FECBB8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation on funds</header><text>No Federal funds may be obligated or expended to—</text><subparagraph id="HCB7DB1EAD4F64F41AF3C9885089FD18A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into a contract or other agreement (including a no-cost agreement) for free advertising or other promotion on the social media platform of a social media company; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57667D47A0CB48239D6A463D07FC8E32" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>pay the salary or expenses of any agency employee to solicit or accept free advertising or other promotion on the social media platform of a social media company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0097CC1FA0C544ECB44ACDEE206A7F46" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual whose account, content, or information on the social media platform of a social media company has been affected in violation of this Act may file a civil action against the United States in the United States District Court for the District of Columbia for reasonable attorneys’ fees, injunctive relief, and actual damages.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0E09EC970AC3421A83AFC4F78A41529A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Assistant Attorney General for Civil Rights, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report evaluating the compliance by the Federal Government with this Act, including a description of any action by the head of an agency to—</text><paragraph id="HBF38929B41D048609E98571BF638E53C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consult with a social media company about labeling content on the social media platform of the social media company as described in subsection (a)(1)(B); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD949F94BA8A14F468792B00861F386AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engage in any other prohibited activity under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5951142285F74EE78A7537B47291F1D9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of any such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of such provision to any other person or circumstance, shall not be affected by the holding.</text></subsection></section><section id="HFCC8DD611F8249D195D717E0ACFDC847"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H49FF46F76FF64BC6AC72E26308E8871C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H579C492E5E514430B8654014094490B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H8C7CFF183D604D1A9E313DEC9DFE99B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C9248714AF487D93D48CF4B381C78B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA198B61F9C4CAC9578C0C9F5B3C469"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Social media company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>social media company</term> means a company that provides, in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce, a social media platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01F4B872E46A4F27AB7AC1215350391E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Social media platform</header><text>The term <term>social media platform</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H8B4859F9729C40E5BC41284B0EB4D4C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a website or internet medium that—</text><clause id="H62DF17CCE1674FD7A0F93F087DE87FC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permits a person to become a registered user, establish an account, or create a profile for the purpose of allowing users to create, share, and view user-generated content through such an account or profile;</text></clause><clause id="H60BCB03AFC4D46C09A3C6B1CA2583316"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>primarily serves as a medium for users to interact with content generated by other users of the medium; and</text></clause><clause id="HC7C58AEBBBE0416F8837A76C1627841D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enables one or more users to generate content that can be viewed by other users of the medium; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A7E961B3F1F44EFBEBDD813E5324B34"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="H02E6F69554C1481D92AD799FCF8D18B5"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any such platform that serves fewer than 100,000 users;</text></clause><clause id="H8A371CBD8E2547B1A7A06E09F09435F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an email program, email distribution lists, multi-person text message groups, or a website that is primarily for the purpose of internet commerce;</text></clause><clause id="HCA88DD4817064790939B5C34615D8E04"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a private platform or messaging service used by an entity solely to communicate with others employed by or affiliated with such entity; or</text></clause><clause id="HB9D193F7EBC444818647657577F80D6F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an internet-based platform whose primary purpose is—</text><subclause id="H5736C05A2C604FE7AC2E3E0342DF4DED"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to allow users to post product reviews, business reviews, travel information and reviews; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H50CD43FD6F944C8EA4DED7BD64B67C56"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide news or entertainment content, but that may also include a comment section for users to discuss such news or entertainment content.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A2E3A82DFC4C63A4F75D2AFD75A020"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

