<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" dms-id="H2FB5C2586E9747E683C95DD8AD442791" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6531 : Targeting Resources to Communities in Need Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 6531</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220519" legis-day="20220517">May 19 (legislative day, May 17), 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide an increased allocation of funding under certain programs for assistance in areas of persistent poverty, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H003109D6515943D08F991D58FDA4F313" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H8507E37ED885447B9F4A61A2DA203CCE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Targeting Resources to Communities in Need Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7092584BD7E54116843E3524C227F7E2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increasing share of Federal resources to areas of persistent poverty and other high-poverty areas</header><subsection id="H2D44B39C03464492BD04A9B75D049307"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Increasing share of Federal resources</header><paragraph id="HA1E3C847EE0A477485B39446B3CCE637"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidance and measures to increase Federal investments</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director, in consultation with Federal agencies, shall implement guidance to increase the share of Federal investments targeted to—</text><subparagraph id="HC1D0E7B6182443B69F6272BCC07299A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">areas of persistent poverty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30E515FA60224EE29AD50A85567712D0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other areas of high and persistent poverty that the Director, in consultation with Federal agencies, determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED18E815EEDD4CC08533145C77E94F0C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Guidance for agencies</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall issue guidance to Federal agencies identifying—</text><subparagraph id="H16F5436718DE4CE0A6F84735AC1CF8B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the scope and type of programs subject to the guidance and measures required by paragraph (1); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC692A0444B0F46B0905461C34A5A6628"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the share of Federal investments to be targeted to the areas described under paragraph (1); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1BAEEC61B0A4AAD86B51D3EDCD69581" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the manner in which Federal investments are to be targeted to the areas described under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8596C7CFBB643F7860059370B79BA17" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>measures to track the Federal investments targeted to the areas described under paragraph (1) over time. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E6647AB61374BD1B2D38F1182712312"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investment amount</header><text>In developing the guidance and measures under paragraph (1), the Director shall include a minimum goal that Federal investments targeted to areas of persistent poverty or other areas with high and persistent poverty be in an amount that is greater than the amount that is proportional to the population of such areas in the United States relative to the population of the United States as a whole.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9349E2EBE42D4F2E9A134836DE280845"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>The Director, in consultation with Federal agencies, shall submit each fiscal year to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H54B1E3AE88714448BB2A0923ADDBD845"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the programs, by agency, under which the amount of Federal funds targeted to areas described under paragraph (1) were increased in the previous fiscal year, in accordance with such paragraph; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD523B9A956C6417092EEE2BF8DB2AFE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each program listed under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H2BA3B3E587FB40EF99C6C8B3BD05D64B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount of funds that were targeted under the program to an area of persistent poverty or other area with high and persistent poverty during the previous fiscal year; </text></clause><clause id="H20BCCAF17BFD40E0BAF3FB69F444ADE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percent change from the fiscal year before the previous fiscal year in the amount of funds that were targeted under the program toward an area of persistent poverty or other area with high and persistent poverty; and</text></clause><clause id="H7AE6E28DE7A5418FB58832BE5ABCBD1D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, an assessment of the economic impact of the program on the area, including data on the categories of individuals impacted by the targeting of funds to such areas under the program, disaggregated by household income, race, gender, age, national origin, disability status, and whether the individuals live in an urban area, suburban area, or rural area. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E970DE1316A40BC9976F247FCDA4279"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Publication of list of areas of persistent poverty</header><paragraph id="H7E7061C238F14DA9867E2E73052F886A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Bureau of the Census shall publish a list of all areas of persistent poverty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC37EE1F258C4483BA885269AD27B99F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Update</header><text>The Bureau of the Census shall update annually the list published under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05C7F2C7B573462092A3EC115FE1CAF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO reports</header><paragraph id="HA6EB49E734D34A16AD3C829D43EF6D6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the effectiveness of the measures implemented under subsection (a), including an assessment regarding the impact of increasing Federal investments spent in areas of persistent poverty and other areas with high and persistent poverty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96D25E7875564699A346A947C5FB1648"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall provide at least two subsequent reports (as described in paragraph (1)) to the appropriate committees of Congress. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE17EF397A3224B0E9CF7C2DD7DC4FB31" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2023, $5,000,000 for salaries and expenses (including for entering contracts with non-Federal persons) to carry out this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7B14508C99E444DDA00320DCE5028DD3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3E21D5D92C0C4D4782289C4DE96CBFBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9E3C01DF0B9047B29687CF1FD536B006"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Budget, the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F692483BDAF4F2A98B154E1CDE8FDAD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on the Budget, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure, and the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FF291AD99044C92BA178C1E0E692B81" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other committee of Congress that has jurisdiction over an agency with a role developing or implementing measures under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90A48D2DCA3A4B4CB6EBD4B594B2A7BA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Area of persistent poverty</header><text>The term <term>area of persistent poverty</term> means an area that is a high-poverty census tract or a persistent poverty county. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAA457A705104FB0B5175F356FFB3FB2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H158EAC916F1C47189529D8C839ACAD53"><enum>(4)</enum><header>High-poverty census tract</header><text>The term <term>high-poverty census tract</term> means a census tract that has a poverty rate of not less than 20 percent in the most recent American Community Survey 5-year data published by the Bureau of the Census, and in the case of areas where no such data is collected from the American Community Survey, such term includes a census tract with a poverty rate of not less than 20 percent in the most recent decennial census of population conducted by the Bureau.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DB58899C7AD47348F45297C1FF69977"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Persistent poverty county</header><text>The term <term>persistent poverty county</term> means— </text><subparagraph id="H82A63BE858E8400EAFFD7FAAE200A5DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a county, parish, or other equivalent county division (as determined by the Bureau of the Census) with a poverty rate of not less than 20 percent in the Small Area Income and Poverty Estimates by the Bureau of the Census in at least 25 of the last 30 years, including the most recent year for which the estimates are available; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H423AE42C02C04E74AE6F20FB9C5CE2D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for areas where Small Area Income and Poverty Estimates are not available, a county, parish, or equivalent level of geography, with a poverty rate of not less than 20 percent in at least 25 of the last 30 years, including the most recent year for which an estimate is available, as determined by the Bureau of the Census. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220518" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 18, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

