<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA848C6194BD4757AD37D810BFC2459F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6971 IH: Educating Against Misinformation and Disinformation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6971</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a commission to promote information and media literacy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF47766D35F424B60866ED1CD5BB86688" style="OLC"><section id="H2BA4DCE02F514E3384F774B710DF9D0D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H9EB60084937049CA965855ECBEA4730C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Educating Against Misinformation and Disinformation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H85E604527B6A46E2BBB2E2C108C38DCF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H2BA4DCE02F514E3384F774B710DF9D0D" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0C62FB915E5B41F3AB70350471AA9E42" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H036A3DCD9C5945CEAC07674F0795DA76" level="title">Title I—Commission to Support Information and Media Literacy and Address Misinformation and Disinformation</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H42CD6018BCF1449084339556EB92DF63" level="section">Sec. 101. Establishment and duties.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4A85CC8C5B19488DAEAB8776AC127943" level="section">Sec. 102. Membership.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD9900EAE6A5C48C0BBFB09B416DCE427" level="section">Sec. 103. Hearings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7DDD709C704541BA84100B84159BCD33" level="section">Sec. 104. Commission personnel matters.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1BC9BD77B87F420BA043FBCBA948F2C2" level="section">Sec. 105. National strategy for information and media literacy and preventing misinformation and disinformation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1652556FA8574878A325AA106077BA73" level="section">Sec. 106. Report to Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5EF59DE843CA44EFA7575CF58AC58AB4" level="section">Sec. 107. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H806D8461F1574ACA9A47A838BD00FD8A" level="title">Title II—Department of Education activities</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H50324D3382C4424E8D5ECBCF0799BAF0" level="section">Sec. 201. Grants to improve the American public’s information and media literacy and resilience to misinformation and disinformation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4F222E9521D14FFF9E99659FABCA1A14" level="section">Sec. 202. Study and report on information and media literacy among the American public.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0A16428FE4864C8D93B2ADECE7829198" level="section">Sec. 203. Department of Education assessment.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H0C62FB915E5B41F3AB70350471AA9E42"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFB907E812EEB4CBDB09B7232020DD4CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF3E8C52DC77548BAB38F9F2B4EF993C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6078E1CBEFF746A6B2C1C25225906484"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Education and Labor and the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5D5CAF70B0F43F1BED38C841C026DB1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA Terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State educational agency</term> have the meanings given those terms in the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCADE261A461B4969B5A8218D13FFECFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information literacy</header><text>The term <term>information literacy</term> means the integrated set of skills, knowledge, practices, and dispositions that prepares individuals to discover, interpret, and create information ethically while gaining a critical understanding of how information systems interact to produce and circulate news, information and knowledge (including digital information such as website and social media content).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6246A83E19FE4419B97355E2D8569608" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D3A55C8DDC34F0593E34B501BE282E3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Media literacy</header><text>The term <term>media literacy</term> means the ability to access, analyze, evaluate, and participate in the creation and circulation of media messages regardless of format, including learning the skills and dispositions to seek out, critically evaluate, and create media messages and understand the role of media and algorithmic information systems in society.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C76AA5D93843159148D072ACB53B69"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Social media</header><text>The term <term>social media</term> means forms of interactive, internet-based applications (such as websites for social networking and microblogging) through which users create online communities to share information, ideas, personal messages, and other content (such as videos).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3D292613B134F36B6D6E63082307878" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State higher education agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State higher education agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><title id="H036A3DCD9C5945CEAC07674F0795DA76"><enum>I</enum><header>Commission to Support Information and Media Literacy and Address Misinformation and Disinformation</header><section id="H42CD6018BCF1449084339556EB92DF63"><enum>101.</enum><header>Establishment and duties</header><subsection id="H12E31393FA8B49B8A41001B85A673F2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a commission to be known as the <quote>Commission to Support Information and Media Literacy and Prevent Misinformation and Disinformation</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D88266069FE4CF1B0711F5FC1FDE58B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The duties of the Commission are as follows:</text><paragraph id="H5A35A08159D44D7A8A3FD387BCCC95C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify and assess programs and interdisciplinary resources relating to information and media literacy in elementary, secondary, higher education, and adult education programs, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H3822A150A15048A4866180D82D394880"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying and assessing programs and other educational materials made available by the Federal Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E069FD119804A3D895DCBFEA717E107" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing metrics to report on the status of information and media literacy education in elementary, secondary, higher, and public informal education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE32CEF492DA74A708593004A44518934"><enum>(C)</enum><text>requesting that the Public Library Survey of the Institute of Museum and Library Services continue to collect such data on an ongoing basis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE59080F69C84C14959B599543623FCF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>annually reporting on the status of such efforts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59905422A1B644E5A257793A71AB67F1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Develop and regularly update, not less frequently than annually, a national strategy to promote information and media literacy in accordance with section 105 and coordinate the implementation of such strategy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7EC6790F8D848BB94CAD5A9A6DC87FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Report on how information on the internet and social media is created and consumed, with a particular focus on how disinformation and misinformation are spread.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3AB114289774541B31C82D5524CAC81"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Develop age-appropriate materials to promote information and media literacy and education with a particular focus on misinformation and disinformation and disseminate such materials to the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DB6E3499C9445A584358617499871FB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Assess and report on strategies and techniques to help students and the public at large judge the trustworthiness and reliability of information and images.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00754F66315047FEB707870EE0DBF0BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promote information and media literacy and related educational efforts and materials at the State and local levels, including by promoting partnerships among Federal, State, and local governments and nonprofit organizations with recognized expertise in media literacy. These efforts include misinformation and disinformation educational and media literacy campaigns for the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4DD9E20B6D54B70B83A77A96150E3C9"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Make recommendations to the appropriate congressional committees and the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3693E2FC5FBD4A13BBAD2ECC54B9CF69"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Areas of emphasis</header><text>In carrying out the duties specified in subsection (b), the Commission shall seek to—</text><paragraph id="HAEE76503162C484D8BDD41A1B151C486"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase public awareness of and education on—</text><subparagraph id="H230EE9DB0B5B411988D96E84CC113A59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how to find and identify if information is from a trustworthy source;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3D345A70422425187F61395B1E6035D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how to craft arguments, when claims are supported by evidence, and how to analyze the validity of claims and strength of arguments being made;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CFD867E61B540ADB21E6171069CE01D"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods to understand the difference between fact or opinion or a mixture thereof;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA1BCD60098F4874AEF975B78D77DA63"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">methods to identify misinformation and disinformation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9635CC79DBC480DA98ACDAE9A5F871D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how to find and evaluate context for information from different sources;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H889B3C544CEF4CAC8CAF2628255B5F4A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>how to detect manipulation of images or information on digital platforms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB581635428DF4FD182CD23B7F82E2209"><enum>(G)</enum><text>how influencers and various organizations target and manipulate audiences through digital platforms;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB66EC3FB657C4F8B9E6150B4F0CE3013"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve information and media literacy and education by encouraging individuals to develop related skills, including—</text><subparagraph id="H529DD6F116B44C0A87465EE663AD4F6C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">critical thinking skills, including how to identify the difference between credible and noncredible claims and information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC2614990A5F447BB9DD51D5C74BDAB07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>awareness of the impact of disinformation and misinformation on individuals and society;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F0BC29237074AE7889A5A4B1FF336D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>increased familiarity and facility with new and digital media with a particular emphasis on techniques individuals may use to—</text><clause id="H0D451490449B4F56A8FFFB65009FA3E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>find reliable and trustworthy information sources; and</text></clause><clause id="H2FB620DBAD84408AB9B1C75E2182312C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identify how information can be manipulated for the consumer; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FF0595234A84EDFB6844609EFC65886"><enum>(D)</enum><text>encourage habits that support the motivation to learn based on verifiably true facts when engaging with information sources; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47229EE56FE142169083DD92A2CA207E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve information and media literacy and resilience to misinformation and disinformation among students attending elementary schools, secondary schools, institutions of higher education, and adult education institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D15C1A89CB34E6E9D0AAB57E0A0FF5A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the duties under subsection (b), the Commission shall actively consult with experts in media and information literacy and experts in misinformation and disinformation, State and local educational agencies, and State higher education agencies as determined appropriate by the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3AFC8409163F46479E986200336F2D50"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Periodic studies</header><text>The Commission may conduct periodic studies regarding the status of information and media literacy and educational resources in the United States, as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2BDD798C0BCF4525897F00DC82ADC595"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Materials in other languages</header><text>The Commission may take such steps as are appropriate to support the development of information and media literacy and education materials in languages other than English.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4A85CC8C5B19488DAEAB8776AC127943"><enum>102.</enum><header>Membership</header><subsection id="HE84FD857E219444593C128CE187A2E1E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of the following members:</text><paragraph id="HD6EA981C45E24CF596A98E9026801D15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education, or the Secretary’s designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5130076AFA144E41975809F975B258A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the Institute of Museum and Library Sciences, or the Director’s designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF309286052544CB89CF88E6B718DA257"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission, or the Chair’s designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E8C412E52CC4F30B08F148EAEDF33DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Chair of the Federal Trade Commission, or the Chair’s designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AA3C6574D6D4B24A98C85F2AECD5467"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Department of Health and Human Services, or the Secretary’s designee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H786C4908E4824436B01418FB5CD206E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not fewer than seven experts, selected by the Secretary of Education, who represent diverse populations in the field of information and media literacy, including experts such as—</text><subparagraph id="HB2ED80629450454A89D0225FA1270033"><enum>(A)</enum><text>members of the International Communication Association and Association for Education in Journalism and Mass Communication; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0D6FB86228841B79CD87B25C3F2F76A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>experts cited in relevant professional journals such as <quote>First Monday, Journal of Information Literacy</quote>, and <quote>Communications in Information Literacy</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1D73F30FB844D16B2770F11EEE0E72E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alternates</header><text>Each member of the Commission may designate an alternate if the member is unable to attend a meeting of the Commission. Such alternate shall be an individual who exercises significant decision-making authority in the organization of the member, as determined by the member concerned.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE64DCD34BEC94FB8B33A89ED6EFA208D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary of Education or the Secretary’s designee shall serve as the Chairperson of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9E756874F7FD439581E04120009FB08D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="HC46645749BF248B8A98B4FF0697D1AD0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chairperson—</text><subparagraph id="HE257EE16652E462780F103028AA9E7AC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less frequently than once every 4 months during the period of one year following the date of the initial meeting of the Commission under subsection (f);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0D2C8DCB5AC46DF9FD50C53936E55B8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less frequently than biannually after the expiration of such period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24186A8398744CF9B96B05C6563A50A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at such other times as the Chairperson determines appropriate to carry out this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F73E59DD6064D62B090DA2DD81F9B17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Open to public</header><text>All meetings of the Commission shall be open to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5AC0EB684CE740138F8F6A50CE59CA12"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9638B298CD294035BDEA76EDA9F0BE4A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall hold its first meeting not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD9900EAE6A5C48C0BBFB09B416DCE427"><enum>103.</enum><header>Hearings</header><subsection id="HB18393F05C3248268D6104C1A8D7276D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Commission considers appropriate to carry out this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H391D259ECF0B44FCBDEA68FD7F4F8442"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation</header><text>In hearings held under this subsection, the Commission shall consider inviting witnesses from—</text><paragraph id="H0841F05E91E344AB8A9AD16849C7DDEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State and local educational agencies and State higher education agencies with expertise in information or media literacy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA1BDE4CB127473B9DE65FBD87449EEC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognized information or media literacy experts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB91A1B1737FE46F09779D2E200E72233"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognized experts in online hate, disinformation, and misinformation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7DDD709C704541BA84100B84159BCD33"><enum>104.</enum><header>Commission personnel matters</header><subsection id="HE3510E92AB37487E959EE1BD80E0B56C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation. Members of the Commission who are full-time officers or employees of the United States may not receive additional pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H775302195A92476A96817BA7C8FE767A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H26EE723266A941D2A5D8B8A7949252B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Detail of Federal Government employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any employee of the Federal Government may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1BC9BD77B87F420BA043FBCBA948F2C2"><enum>105.</enum><header>National strategy for information and media literacy and preventing misinformation and disinformation</header><subsection id="H907DE1D6807F4072A997701C67403638"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="HACF51BE98503463C8CAF29C127D35085"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, develop a national strategy to promote information and media literacy and resilience to misinformation and disinformation among the American public; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EBA205E692645F291418ACD350B8D0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate the efforts of the Federal Government to implement the strategy developed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9B910A4A195E44E3B6B7442ACD5E4286"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HC56607DEF599477AAFF8FD9ACF16075B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be developed with the participation of State and local governments (including State higher education agencies), nonprofit organizations, and institutions of higher education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCAB75CFB4184A38A8EA65825F485744"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include strategies for—</text><subparagraph id="HAF7F9A7E42B04DF5BB6DDF20BD037A32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing the general information and media literacy education level of the American public;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD705BD53C50405C87DF61D5B2D7AA9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhancing the public’s general understanding of how information platforms operate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5522A981D1843A1AF061A919A82B186"><enum>(C)</enum><text>encouraging members of the public to critically analyze information sources and recognize manipulation, misinformation, and disinformation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7FEA70F07BB4F52BE3A48A212358537"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include an assessment of existing efforts to promote information and media literacy and education with a particular focus on misinformation and disinformation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A67140E1C4B4C6EB4B9755D8C51343E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>National strategy review</header><text>On a periodic basis at times determined appropriate by the Commission, the Commission shall review the national strategy developed under subsection (b) and make such changes and recommendations as it determines necessary.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1652556FA8574878A325AA106077BA73"><enum>106.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><subsection id="HCEA8B28D3F5A41F2B04297CD384B8CD8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the first meeting of the Commission, and annually thereafter, the Commission shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the progress of the Commission in carrying out this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H23D2C14416C64F1DB47E1A4386ACC49C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HB837CCAEB7AE4F56B1946C94A7CD2D12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a copy of the national strategy developed under section 105;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03DB59D8C01D4997A2864F87A9DEE70D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information concerning the implementation of the duties of the Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD6621EC1D946D18C90D5F396815DD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the availability, utilization, and effectiveness of existing information and media literacy and educational materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F3D32C163A949A58B946D722C0A26A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a brief summary of the information and media literacy and education materials and data regarding the dissemination and impact of such materials;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E9A16E5E94845D885D134E1C8C97344"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a brief summary of any hearings conducted by the Commission, including a list of witnesses who testified at such hearings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88E7C34B6A58401E9E1E1BF897D91E3B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>information about any activities of the Commission planned for the year following the date of the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H824FB15A22C74647ACAC24D0D4C460B0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>such other information as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5EF59DE843CA44EFA7575CF58AC58AB4"><enum>107.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this title.</text></section></title><title id="H806D8461F1574ACA9A47A838BD00FD8A"><enum>II</enum><header>Department of Education activities</header><section id="H50324D3382C4424E8D5ECBCF0799BAF0"><enum>201.</enum><header>Grants to improve the American public’s information and media literacy and resilience to misinformation and disinformation</header><subsection id="H17C8114AC8BA4B84B2099EED70C05CCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning after the Commission completes the development of the national strategy under section 105, the Secretary of Education shall carry out a program under which the Secretary awards grants, on a competitive basis, to one or more qualified nonprofit organizations, including institutions of higher education, to develop educational materials, multimedia awareness campaigns, and programming to support information and media literacy and to combat misinformation and disinformation for the greater American public.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEBAFF60663954306BBFC335D5FAFDFDD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relationship to Commission activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall carry out the grant program under this section in a manner that reflects the findings of the Commission with respect to—</text><paragraph id="H5A8042500DF543CDAC491AF8971158D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting public awareness of information and media literacy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32F1F84BEFAE45EE8C4B6647632087CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improving individual information and media literacy skills;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE05071D5943A4C0EB054457130001D77"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improving how information and media literacy is addressed in educational settings; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57F974CABB5F4E5687CEE204408D3862"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving the public's resilience to misinformation and disinformation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE4489CE05F14753B8A080A3764E5E7C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Multilingual materials</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may award grants for the development of educational materials, multimedia awareness campaigns, and programming in languages other than English as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E5908785AC3435FB1F2FFC9FB721EE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance measures</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a process to evaluate the effectiveness of the activities carried out with grants under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H765E247FA0B54D9EAD110EE2F57170FF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>On an annual basis during each year of the grant program under this section, the Secretary shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the status of the program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H78C8F44CCF564AE1BD2D66039022BD69" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022, 2023, and 2024.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4F222E9521D14FFF9E99659FABCA1A14" commented="no"><enum>202.</enum><header>Study and report on information and media literacy among the American public</header><subsection id="H7BD43ACDA5104899974DA6B6E17C74E1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall conduct a study to evaluate the extent of information and media literacy among the American public.</text></subsection><subsection id="H318FD002C6AF4F8B9C7AB33CD19273E6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study under subsection (a) shall examine the extent of the American public’s knowledge and awareness of—</text><paragraph id="H20994D1D0C3742808B597D2DD0996C36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>how social media content is created;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39B6DFCE1484419DBB6468F79BCD3676"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how members of the public make choices about information as they consume, create, and share it;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46F09E31C942428A86186CF34D64D55F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how intermediary technologies for search and social sharing use algorithms and personal information to influence the circulation and amplification or suppression of news, information, opinion, and disinformation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B632665E5A244399F2BA03BF24E447A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>methods to search and evaluate the reliability of information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFD15E891F254305ACB239F44BE807CB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>how news is gathered and reported and how that process differs from opinion writing and information presented in talk-show formats; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAE6E3E198E14594AB7DE902CBA4D6C1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how disinformation and misinformation are shared and circulated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC990E43EF0544A3B975C65939C3ECFB8" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the findings and conclusions the study conducted under subsection (a), together with—</text><paragraph id="HE3698E77AFF8410EB562D410904DFB21" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative or administrative action based on such study; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9EEF76E07144B4C9D1EAF6B12D58E39" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for improving information and media literacy and resilience to misinformation and disinformation among the American public.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0A16428FE4864C8D93B2ADECE7829198" commented="no"><enum>203.</enum><header>Department of Education assessment</header><subsection id="HDAC36B1B04354FF58C999ADE56EB43DE" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Effectiveness study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education shall conduct an assessment of the effectiveness of the Commission in promoting information and media literacy and education in accordance with title I.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA7E0439B3EB74B13A87510CBE7D5C019" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Department of Education shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the results of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

