<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H528043521975454DA3C8CD1009102B0E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7944 IH: To name the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic to be constructed in Toms River, New Jersey, the Leonard G. 'Bud' Lomell, Jr. VA Clinic, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7944</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220603">June 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To name the Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic to be constructed in Toms River, New Jersey, the Leonard G. 'Bud' Lomell, Jr. VA Clinic, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H871575B1E4704DEFADE3EDE209CC27A7" style="OLC"><section id="H21FD62B4A0CD475184A4D34C208BA8FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HDF211F81A917433BB89E8DE50B850B1F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Township of Toms River, New Jersey, was recently designated as the site for the new Department of Veterans Affairs outpatient clinic, a state-of-the-art facility serving the region’s large veteran population, to be located at the corner of Hooper and Caudina Avenues, and expected to be completed and functioning in 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC1DF4884F8E4FE38502C63155BD3D2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Mayor and the Township Council believe that this facility deserves to be named in honor of Second Lieutenant Leonard G. <quote>Bud</quote> Lomell, Jr., a long time Toms River and Ocean County resident, who served courageously and heroically during World War II.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CC8661432AA455F9B1AA645136C32A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Second Lieutenant Lomell was born in 1920, the adopted son of Scandinavian immigrant parents living in Brooklyn, New York, and his family eventually moved to Point Pleasant Beach, New Jersey.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B2744CC3C88471BBA9F61447F8399AD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Second Lieutenant Lomell attended Tennessee Wesleyan College, and following college, he enlisted in the Army, volunteering for the elite Ranger Corps, and was a member of the Second Rangers Battalion during the June 6, 1944, D-Day invasion, commanding his own platoon as First Sergeant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62CF7CD4444F4ECEB3A1B1A1EB56521B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Then-First Sergeant Lomell’s Platoon landed at Pointe-du-Hoc, Normandy, France, a rugged 100-foot high coastal promenade along the English Channel coast located between the American-targeted Omaha and Utah beaches, successfully scaling the cliffs, despite a withering German defensive barrage.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEDCEE774A6947538D7B4F668A047335"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Pointe-du-Hoc was heavily defended by the Germans, and the mission of the 225 Rangers was to disable five 155 millimeter artillery guns, which could have rained artillery fire on the Americans landing on either beach, jeopardizing the invasion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H425D16EE954D4AB1A723EE311649E332"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Unknown to the Americans, the guns had been moved from the tip of the Pointe and hidden, pointed in the direction of Utah Beach, in an inland apple orchard nearly a mile from the coastal batteries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C264CBF5E5446ECB129AE2D0B6EA107"><enum>(8)</enum><text>First Sergeant Lomell and another Ranger, Sergeant Jack Kuhn, found the guns undefended, and with Kuhn providing cover, Lomell destroyed the weapons with thermite grenades and using his rifle butt to smash the sights, saving countless Allied lives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83A0C2325BE74110AFCD0C4B2BFD2946"><enum>(9)</enum><text>First Sergeant Lomell subsequently received a battlefield promotion to Second Lieutenant, and was awarded some of the military’s highest honors, including the Distinguished Service Cross, Purple Heart, and Silver Star.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC24FC59BF4F4C3C91458F1DA5C526F3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Renowned historian Steven Ambrose regarded First Sergeant Lomell’s valiant acts along with General Eisenhower’s decision to invade on June 6, 1944, as the most significant actions ensuring the Allied victory on D-Day.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2605FB24720D425EB9F5E491619A44B5"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Following World War II, Second Lieutenant Lomell attended law school on the G.I. Bill, eventually settling with his family in Toms River and, in 1957, establishing his own law firm, which grew to become one of Ocean County’s largest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD72151DA49B4CC2B8A7CB53BD6FFFE4"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Serving as selflessly in civilian life as he did in the military, Second Lieutenant Lomell was involved in numerous civic and charitable organizations, including by serving as president of the Ocean County Bar Association, a director of the First National Bank of Toms River, a member of the Dover Township Board of Education, and as a founding member of the World War II Army Rangers Battalion Association.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD44FD72909F74C7FAE5628D61BFDD890"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Second Lieutenant Lomell is profiled in the Greatest Generation, former NBC news Anchor Tom Brokaw’s testament to the heroes of World War II.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE649ACDEEE8448D9735D6AE004A545E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>As a decorated war hero, model citizen, and dedicated husband and father, Second Lieutenant Lomell is exceedingly deserving of the posthumous honor of having a new and long awaited Toms River-based Department of Veterans Affairs outpatient clinic named in his honor.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC67AB61FDB4244AC8D4BCCB16A8A1729" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Name of Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic, Toms River, New Jersey</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The Department of Veterans Affairs community-based outpatient clinic to be constructed in Toms River, New Jersey, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Leonard G. <quote>Bud</quote> Lomell, Jr. VA Clinic</quote>. Any reference to such clinic in any law, regulation, map, document, record, or other paper of the United States shall be considered to be a reference to the Leonard G. “Bud” Lomell, Jr. VA Clinic.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

