<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H21843AD6251443A3B6C34099D0FA1D8D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8462 IH: SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8462</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Securities and Exchange Commission, when developing rules and regulations about disclosures to retail investors, to conduct investor testing, including a survey and interviews of retail investors, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4DBC48063C9D4336802981EC54AE0197" style="OLC"><section id="HF523CE4E86E2468AB3490508D088019C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SEC Disclosure Effectiveness Testing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE02735E6885E43D6B5FCED75486887A7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure testing</header><subsection id="HAA2DF506E1034ACBAED8B25D9C4F38DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 23(a) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78w">15 U.S.C. 78w(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H61EC349DD8CB483EBDAEEDB62327CD36" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H0E4AD49255934932A3AC64E71B11DBFE" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Investor testing</header><subparagraph id="HC7713F3BF3764EBFBAC508AFDE4BE526"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall engage in investor testing prior to issuing any rule or regulation which designates documents or information to be disclosed under the securities laws, if such documents or information are required to be delivered to, and are intended or substantially likely to be materially relied upon by, a retail investor when—</text><clause id="HE87B2622207E4C4B8DEBB26CA2BE616C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">selecting a broker-dealer or investment adviser, evaluating their services and fees, or materially altering a brokerage or advisory relationship;</text></clause><clause id="HF7FA35C8D28E4067A2A687F7E04AAFF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing a securities recommendation or investment advice provided by a broker-dealer or investment adviser;</text></clause><clause id="HEBAC03BA883F41A2A9C97F96EC0E03EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">making a decision to purchase or sell a security; or</text></clause><clause id="HEBB1585003E649AFA83C97FAA191DAF9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other circumstances as the Commission may, with input from the Investor Advocate, determine appropriate for the protection of retail investors.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D237003B2D64CDB844A1327A79A8189"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption for certain disclosures</header><text>This section shall not apply to—</text><clause id="H11F41A4363AA4C959CED191B9D3B240A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disclosures made pursuant to Regulations S–K and S–X (including Industry Guides), Regulation 14A, Form N–PX, Form 10–K, Form 10–Q, Form 8–K, Form SD, Form N–PORT, Form PF, Regulation SBSR, disclosures mandated by or jointly with the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Financial Stability Oversight Council, or successors thereto; or</text></clause><clause id="H2777ED2EC61E46E2BC568B90226A7BDF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other documents or information that the Commission, with input from the Investor Advocate, determines are outside the intended scope and purposes of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20E05AD6D3A54F1B916934A6F4AF5332"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Commission authority to conduct additional testing</header><text>This section shall not be construed to limit the Commission’s ability to conduct any investor testing on any other documents or information not subject to this section 23(a), provided that any such investor testing shall not be subject to the requirements of this section 23(a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAE92563D0E24D57B8CBF770CB14FDEB"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Investor testing conducted pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall include the following: </text><clause id="HFEFA63C2116049AFB580E408F802863F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Qualitative testing in the form of one-on-one cognitive interviews of retail investors about documents or information, or samples of such documents or information, to be provided.</text></clause><clause id="HA0DF3A401C9945CE9230CEEDC1AE4C8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Such other forms of testing that the Commission, with input from the Investor Advocate, deems appropriate for evaluating the effectiveness of retail disclosures.</text></clause><clause id="H1A416BC935F2451C890069741455E321"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Analysis and publication in the Federal Register of the results of the testing.</text></clause><clause id="H1F619A440957453CBEC7DD7DE131A100"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>An opportunity for the public to comment on such results published in the Federal Register. </text></clause><clause id="H455E56A07E9F4514BF6D92B229C05742"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consideration of unique challenges faced by retail investors age 65 or older.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31196406A5564421AA57E09BF3330286"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Substantive changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission, in the period between engaging in investor testing and publishing a final rule, makes substantive changes to such rule that the Commission determines would have a significant impact on retail investors, and such changes were not already investor tested, the Commission shall again engage in investor testing related to such changes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54F9814FD0D7477BB2D50D074F23CE60"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Public availability of retail testing results</header><text>The Commission shall make the data and results of any investor testing performed pursuant to this paragraph available to the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2001510F0C6645C59DE8B01071EEE0AA"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><clause id="H19E1824C104F441C86678289632737FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The determination that some or all of a document or information is deemed to be subject to this paragraph shall not forestall the determination that such document or information may also be used or relied upon by the public, market participants other than retail investors, or government agencies.</text></clause><clause id="HFCBAFAA4B2B14188A39E264E4B2E1E35" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Commission may, in consultation with the Investor Advocate, determine which, if any, components of such document or information are substantially likely to be relied on by retail investors for the purposes outlined in paragraph (4)(A) above and focus testing under this paragraph on those components of the disclosure.</text></clause><clause id="HC5C2E3A7BB86475984623A6ADDCAC0D9" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Notwithstanding clause (ii) above, where any information subject to testing under this paragraph may be used or relied upon by the public, market participants other than retail investors, or government agencies, the results of testing made pursuant to this paragraph shall not provide grounds for reducing or eliminating (including any undermining of reliability of and accountability for) the information that existing or proposed regulation requires or would require be made available to the public, market participants other than retail investors, and government agencies, whether or not such information is delivered to retail investors. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE493FED0F564139837D84BCAED82097" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Retail investor defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>retail investor</quote> means any investor that is not an institutional investor. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H63DE55429EE846948F951BEFC7A23D19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participation of investor advocate</header><text>Section 4(g) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78d">15 U.S.C. 78d(g)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H224466DD36CB428F8B120E8638DE1AC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="HAD0B8E804AE14FD491CFD36B584F8B12"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(ii), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09E05157EAC2434C9A5C16755370C917"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (E) as subparagraph (F); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF021B55A3D64D8594E754AE74A370E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8AAF2FDEB10E46B092BD953A4EBED1AB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H583F82D72E384F7590FE097D6DA1DF96" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage in investor testing—</text><clause id="H75E3F79F2A424573B4024EA926ECF16F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to carry out the functions of the Office; and</text></clause><clause id="HBCCF400069654017B3CE9D250CB27C5E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pursuant to section 23(a)(4), as appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98206E2C6CF04A6792A1C434D9820CEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H449AE2FB7189426980C894EB4B3F4964" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H222B409A58A6432BA749B87B6A5DD5B2"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Publication of data and results of investor testing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any investor testing carried out by the Investor Advocate pursuant to paragraph (4)(E), the Investor Advocate may make the data and results of such investor testing available to the public, without further review or editing by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C8CA50789A54B929B6243C142827ECA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Investor Advocate decides, within its sole discretion, to conduct testing under this section, the Investor Advocate may do so and the Commission shall provide the Office of the Investor Advocate with sufficient personnel and funding necessary to carry out such testing. Such testing may qualify as the testing covered by this section, provided that all requirements of the section are met.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C0B68EAF4424B7B9153118468C3EF04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prior rules</header><paragraph id="HF725D8EAE74C4F008C80B13740A8D961"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any final rule or regulation issued by the Securities and Exchange Commission (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>) before the date of the enactment of this Act that would be subject to investor testing under section 23(a)(4) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934, had such rule been issued on or after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission shall perform investor testing with respect to such rule or regulation that includes the contents described in such section 23(a)(4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF268F13622784A998550F7285E9F973E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall, not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, with input from the Investor Advocate, establish a schedule for completing any investor testing required under paragraph (1) that prioritizes testing of any final rules and regulations that designate documents or information central to retail investor decision making, and in particular prioritize the testing of documents or information required to be delivered to retail investors in the form of summary documents or summary sections of documents including for the purpose of determining whether and how such summary documents can achieve the goals of informed investor decision-making in the circumstances set forth in section 23(a)(4) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 while maintaining full accessibility by retail investors, the public, other market participants, and government regulators to the full range of documents and information that they may utilize or rely on, whether or not such documents or information are required to be delivered to retail investors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9995D893F6B4015A9900E4A6C89C0C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Commission shall, with input from the Investor Advocate, issue a report to Congress each year containing the following:</text><subparagraph id="H92B8C906A9334BFFAEAA4B19BE8949AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The status of any investor testing required under paragraph (1) initiated within the last year or otherwise ongoing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF5D62CA4A5C4DC1B4E6875807C8467E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The results of any investor testing completed under paragraph (1) within the last year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B53659760048CCBC0A6E8A5978F4B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any priorities the Commission has, based on results of investor testing required by paragraph (1), for—</text><clause id="HDC131F8A044D41419FCADA1E949B9740"><enum>(i)</enum><text>revising any proposed or final rule or regulation based on the results of testing;</text></clause><clause id="H30092977CA21448AA6696108B004D86B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>initiating any rulemaking or actions arising from the results of the testing; and</text></clause><clause id="H97B19049A9354C99AC07066D356FEFDF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Investor Advocate’s views on the above priorities and any such other matters arising from the testing or results of testing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

