<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HCD11C60033064FB48E76AA474BCCF9CF" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 4693 : Global Malnutrition Prevention and Treatment Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4693</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To advance targeted and evidence-based interventions for the prevention and treatment of global malnutrition and to improve the coordination of such programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4B2B8C92E054481B8406F06BC9DB034C" style="OLC"><section id="H0085A99A81DC48869400467227720180" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Malnutrition Prevention and Treatment Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDDF8D461E0C84220B581400A12B5F0CC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of efforts to prevent and treat malnutrition globally</header><subsection id="H6819B4A8E4424CDBB5D86132D7EA7474"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, is authorized and encouraged to support efforts to prevent and treat malnutrition globally, including by—</text><paragraph id="HCE2459B7434641218FAB6F95FD4EDAED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>targeting resources and nutrition interventions to support the most vulnerable populations susceptible to severe malnutrition, including children under the age of 5 and pregnant and lactating women;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA407A3C20B434EAF4231168FD6B172"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increasing coverage, particularly in priority countries, of nutrition interventions that include coordinated deployment of prenatal nutrient supplements, breastfeeding support, vitamin A supplementation, specialized nutritious food products for the treatment of acute malnutrition, and other evidence-based interventions, as appropriate; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H164E4E4ED02E4E69A9F1C6F169F6B459"><enum>(3)</enum><text>increasing the use of context and country-appropriate fortification of staples and condiments with essential nutrients;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D3201E975F8448AA8B5E697FA5BEA9F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advancing evidence-based programs and interventions carried out using data-driven approaches, best practices, and targeted to country-specific contexts and needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61088B84250345168C0F7DB763AE0B0B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>supporting partner governments to develop policies to prevent and treat malnutrition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F6F26C71C6C4BAFB785E9BC5C5A21A7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>leveraging investments to strengthen health systems, including to support community health workers to advance improved nutrition outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF97A18211564BCCBAF527E4EABE8738"><enum>(7)</enum><text>improve diets through safe, affordable, nutritious foods in the food system; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFF3D4FDAEE74423B2D42E2E07393A1A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>ensuring rigorous monitoring and evaluation of such efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24EEEBBBF31D439EAAD947E0FF559CA7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>External coordination efforts related to nutrition programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, should coordinate, as appropriate, with bilateral and multilateral donors, governments of partner countries, United Nations agencies, civil society organizations, nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations, and the private sector to prevent and treat malnutrition globally, including by supporting efforts to—</text><paragraph id="HCD8E7121EB9D45C39608C559D59880E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>build the capacity of local and community-based organizations and governments of partner countries to ensure sustainability of nutrition interventions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59E6A2B45B3D4563BDCC461D86F2C4D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expand research and innovation to identify and increase effective and evidence-based nutrition interventions based on country-specific contexts; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H123477B5CF9F4FCBAD228452235A22C6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve coordination and structure of supply chains for nutrition interventions; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38A47D3D81A0443189D5A2AC97F9E7CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expand domestic resource mobilization and domestic financing for nutrition interventions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38673BCE1E7E4EF284E46C01214E90F6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>seek to leverage additional resources and encourage investment into innovative and multi-stakeholder finance partnerships to advance burden sharing in nutrition-related assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9684EE4733B6429EA965D04C536696EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interagency efforts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsections (a) and (b), the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, consistent with the Global Nutrition Coordination Plan, shall seek to leverage additional resources to prevent and treat malnutrition globally, including by—</text><paragraph id="HA2315E0C7C784728ADA458A341AB7FCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing cooperation among relevant Federal departments and agencies represented in the Global Nutrition Coordination Plan to better leverage grants, technical assistance, debt, equity, loan guaranties, and public-private partnerships; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6105A5A18E704C22B29987708EED3FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilizing the Administrator’s role as a member of the Board of Directors of the United States International Development Finance Corporation to consider opportunities within the Corporation’s development impact framework that support improved nutrition outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE25D1F3E69404E8F9797B78C5BEC7420"><enum>3.</enum><header>Selection of priority countries</header><subsection id="H2CA4CA9B3D8146A8A0FC412BE882A387"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Nutrition Leadership Council, shall select foreign countries as priority countries for purposes of targeting programs to prevent and treat malnutrition globally.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1D93716C97E74E0F9B6CB8EFFC7BB00E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>The selection of priority countries under subsection (a) shall be based on the following:</text><paragraph id="H510D66F613A040F09CCA0B1782903F53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The prevalence of severe malnutrition among children under the age of 5 and pregnant and lactating women.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8C15C1DF91144C9AFEB467EB3DE6685"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The presence of high-need, underserved, marginalized, vulnerable, or impoverished communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA254F1B6B2C1420D8759FD7C8993E95D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The enabling environment for improved nutrition, including presence of national nutrition plans and demonstration of strong political commitment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36001E0B2A20462FB91220BD582470FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other criteria that the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H648E2541C34649939EC00B9742882E6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall update the selection of priority countries under subsection (a) not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA45A51415C894872974283B05C5B1C65"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Administrator should continue to undertake nutrition interventions in countries not selected as priority countries, particularly in contexts in which opportunities are identified to advance multi-sectoral development programming and integrate efforts to prevent and treat global malnutrition with other priority areas and program objectives.</text></subsection></section><section id="H933076D522724C369AC9C07919D73A0F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Nutrition Leadership Council</header><subsection id="H6A5649DF2CA94C26B1BB86B4B61C258D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator is authorized to establish in the United States Agency for International Development the Nutrition Leadership Council (in this section referred to as the <quote>Council</quote>), which shall coordinate Agency efforts to prevent and treat malnutrition globally.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC5C4B579EEA84654A65FC9A878DADF41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Council shall include—</text><paragraph id="H4B7A7CC9D4C9454FA49E11469B98D975"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advancing United States Agency for International Development efforts to prevent and treat malnutrition globally;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H435271E76F154A6A9F0415109FB4A194"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensuring nutrition interventions, particularly in priority countries, are carried out in close coordination with other relevant United States Government strategies and policies and provisions of law, including—</text><subparagraph id="H40D647F9460947AE992B56D078C78C83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Global Food Security Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9301">22 U.S.C. 9301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H999B02D2ABF548C997BBC457C9C2AF7D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Senator Paul Simon Water for the World Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2151">22 U.S.C. 2151</external-xref> note);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1995E86A47848238A8627256D167EF2" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Global Child Thrive Act of 2020 (subtitle I of title XII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A3E619BBC98423492F60BE35F80F493"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Global Fragility Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9801">22 U.S.C. 9801 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBD90483953D42B8B04092144C5D10F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensuring nutrition interventions are coordinated with nutrition programs carried out by other relevant Federal departments and agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38E3FD0C4AB2496ABC727790AF618107"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Council shall include representatives of the following bureaus and independent offices of the United States Agency for International Development:</text><paragraph id="H66ECC9700F184F2B933E8CEEFCD9BF0F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Bureau for Global Health.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB777C41C57BD42DBA487AEEC5F96D36C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Bureau for Resilience and Food Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31DC0E7D601C42B79B5156735A51A0BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Bureau for Humanitarian Assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFCAA14F65F946F3864B2333EF0C2B3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other relevant bureau or independent office that the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H65D4EA35F24D438CBC709E85748701F3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><subsection id="H45BC316791FF4CAC942CE57D307BCD3D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 260 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall develop and submit to the appropriate congressional committees an implementation plan for programs to prevent and treat malnutrition globally described in section 2.</text></subsection><subsection id="H846A8119E105428C9146722693B0525C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The implementation plan required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HFE87F3C3A2B4485BA3FFD542649B001A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of specific and measurable goals, objectives, and performance metrics with respect to such programs, including clear benchmarks and intended timelines for achieving such goals and objectives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81C666ED24C74713BF01E6FA389CFF36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of monitoring and evaluation plans with respect to such programs, as appropriate. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DE64DD660E749C4B6A7D9EEBF000E51"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In priority countries, a description of efforts to ensure that nutrition is adequately addressed in the Country Development Cooperation Strategy to the extent practicable and identify opportunities to expand efforts to prevent and treat malnutrition, including through leveraging existing health and development programs and other ongoing activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA37B935DF014BD9AF2A939F4290477C" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The implementation plan required by subsection (a) shall be developed in consultation with, as appropriate and to the extent possible, representatives of nongovernmental organizations, including faith-based organizations, civil society organizations, multilateral organizations and donors, relevant private, academic, and philanthropic entities, and the appropriate congressional committees. </text></subsection></section><section id="HCDD489C644FF4EAEA08FDB35AA6034AF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="HCAA5C8B908AB419B917CE17D09B34D89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 5 years, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that describes progress made towards preventing and treating malnutrition globally.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7461A09DA6044B3384E2D02BEACBB206"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H09CFDA88F1434258B7BDD80D724F3F1D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A summary of progress made towards achieving the specific and measurable goals, objectives, and performance metrics towards ending global malnutrition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAE6F0B598C4E5DBF0771A35EB0AE5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In priority countries—</text><subparagraph id="H4503188CC8C1456198399DA257A8A929"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a detailed summary of nutrition programs and activities in the previous fiscal year, including a breakdown of the countries to which nutrition resources have been allocated and an estimated number of people reached through nutrition interventions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FB34D411F3B49F5884A26033F2AA33D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an description of the coordination of nutrition programs with other health and development programs and priorities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC94C49734E74FBA9DFE6E51A9514FAD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A summary of efforts to expand research and innovation to development and scale up new tools to prevent and treat malnutrition globally.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF3110C924554BB3A8524CE6ADED5984"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of the collaboration and coordination of nutrition efforts of the United States Agency for International Development with United Nations agencies, the World Bank, other donor governments, host country governments, civil society, and the private sector, as appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9966B287FCA44573884171DB59248E79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of other donor country and host country financial commitments and efforts to prevent and treat malnutrition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBBA1607EAD2457884F878B45F0C6DB8"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An identification of constraints on implementation of programs and activities and lessons learned from programs and activities from the previous fiscal years. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9516A651A66D44219526EAE3CC32EBD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion in other reports</header><text>The Administrator may include the report required by subsection (a) as a component of other congressionally mandated reports provided to appropriate congressional committees, as appropriate.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBD2D4ACADA9140A9BE9E9CCF40956773" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Compliance with the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(3) of the Foreign Aid Transparency and Accountability Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2394c">22 U.S.C. 2394c</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC97048A55FBF48BFBDC198719F0E5CCB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D1DDFF41CFF418B99390BEF6737030A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC034383FCE534DB5819AECC06BC08B45" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2077B5EE76E24DECB6402D896A371B1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC6465B79791946BC8A6D34D381952938" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Global Malnutrition Prevention and Treatment Act of 2021.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HC84871D8E5FA48028F2DE8A0DDF002B1"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H37760330A0E64B25A9AF7D649F181D7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the United States Agency for International Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CDEB57964D543D4A1E46F9F834B7DE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1015A117238C4EAF8191570847B667F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9F4AC019FC7425FAEDF288EB3361D74"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF3B5702864145B882246FF1EA52DDB5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nutrition Leadership Council</header><text>The term <quote>Nutrition Leadership Council</quote> means Nutrition Leadership Council established by section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD773CA2A18FE4511BAA7AE4EE6C0EDED"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority country</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>priority country</quote> means a foreign country selected under section 3 for purposes of targeting programs to prevent and treat malnutrition globally.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB948C559B92341DEBACD0EABB19D979E"><enum>9.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements of this Act and the amendments made by this Act shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220427" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 27, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

