<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H782D57030A374C608D1F16C5E1101708" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9147 IH: Haiti Criminal Collusion Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9147</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221007">October 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of State to submit an annual report to Congress regarding the ties between criminal gangs and political and economic elites in Haiti.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8AC8B3F2D0C4B08A6129A13BCAEB541" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HAE403EF412C647168EF10B0CBE14D2ED" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Haiti Criminal Collusion Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEFE6CC32E86E4D44A51D7DDD6B8EE5E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H244A62AD3AC042CE9FB9925AF5AAABDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>According to a United Nations estimate, approximately 167 criminal gangs operated in Haiti in October 2021, exerting territorial control over as much as two-thirds of the country.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3885F5EC81174848BB51828524092714"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Haitian armed criminal gangs, the most prominent of which are the G9 Family and Allies and 400 Mawozo gangs, conduct violent crimes, including murder, rape, arms and drug trafficking, racketeering, kidnapping, and blockades of fuel and aid deliveries. These crimes have perpetuated the ongoing security and humanitarian crises in Haiti, which have worsened since the assassination of President Jovenel Moise on July 7, 2021.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A4B691F6A584CC4A6DD7690701BB9B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The United Nations Office of the High Commissioner for Human Rights and the Human Rights Service jointly found a 333 percent increase in human rights violations and abuses against the rights to life and security in Haiti between July 2018 and December 2019.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7380B9B6CF024646835C4834610317D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>At least 19,000 Haitians were forcibly displaced during 2021 due to rising criminal violence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C0B58D62E4E4831A304143977DD0AEA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>At least 803 kidnappings were reported in Haiti during the first 10 months of 2021, including the kidnapping of more than 16 United States citizens, giving Haiti having the highest per capita kidnapping rate of any country in the world.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE4DD21411384C0AA93EAC1E63A77093"><enum>(6)</enum><text>There is significant evidence of collusion between criminal gangs and economic and political elites in Haiti, including members of the Haitian National Police, which has resulted in widespread impunity and directly contributed to Haiti’s current security crisis.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H22CE7A095F234DD280BD927F33ABFE9A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>On December 10, 2020, the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury designated former Haitian National Police officer Jimmy Cherizier, former Director General of the Ministry of the Interior Fednel Monchery, and former Departmental Delegate Joseph Pierre Richard Duplan under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act for their connections to armed criminal gangs, including organizing the November 2018 La Saline massacre.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H61AA26498D77422F8D43309F335593A5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header> <subsection id="HDD14ECEB28E54E70814B6C2E6865DF92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAECF4D2897FF470B9D4EF2F53D5411FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H27C0D9F3FCF64B7E9FEDEF4EF3F3CED7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73D906A63C354146AFF2AAE5A3143370"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF01D8ACE3B9544DD8FF8A0E68BCDA9F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D863849BCCA4FE98D42413F121113F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB709B93052D4140BF049008A9A88F55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3(4) of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0123453AAD9145CD83B4D76DBFF45F07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the intelligence community, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees regarding the ties between criminal gangs and political and economic elites in Haiti. The report shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD9287F67335146D9B10ACB87F76D5ABD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify prominent criminal gangs in Haiti, describe their criminal activities, and identify their primary geographic areas of operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H820B09073C1549299126B2256B5BD4AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>list Haitian political and economic elites who have links to criminal gangs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB23E2358706443F0BBF09EB4A8976959"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe in detail the relationship between the individuals listed pursuant to paragraph (2) and the criminal gangs identified pursuant to paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7E4F930E4DD843EB9D9B487F9E275AB1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describe in detail how Haitian political and economic elites use their relationships with criminal gangs to advance their political and economic interests and agenda;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C44A9CA82D24A378C8381A6C5E73154"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include an assessment of how the nature and extent of collusion between political and economic elites and criminal gangs threatens the Haitian people and United States national interests and activities in the country, including the provision of security assistance to the Haitian government; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF6BC10F62B20483FA5D9BCBFDAE11840"><enum>(6)</enum><text>include an assessment of potential actions that the Government of the United States and the Government of Haiti could take to address the findings made pursuant to paragraph (5).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC90A11BE06F14BF9B1973A4654FB9C99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designations of political and economic elites</header> <paragraph id="HA09CB0AD869B4750993057CD4350E144"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with other relevant Federal agencies and departments, shall identify persons identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2) who may be subjected to visa restrictions and sanctions under—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDD043AD179D145BBA6AB863EA17EE30F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 7031(c) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2022 (division K of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/103">Public Law 117–103</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182</external-xref> note); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6BF547C53B7343DCAC156D29BFA7B642"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1263 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of division A of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H43AD0891765A4BAA8E64955B9BE0AF41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The list of persons identified pursuant to subsection (b)(2) shall be posted on a publicly accessible website of the Department of State on the date on which the report required under subsection (b) is submitted to Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9F86E0BA0A1646188FAEEFCBCC6B1455"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

