<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD4B3F157C647415AA97A36ECC9495913" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5774 RH: Expediting Disaster Recovery Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 358</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5774</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–461]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20211028">October 28, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on October 28, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to ensure that unmet needs after a major disaster are met.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HDBA99F51B7104F48A055ED1908C26615"><section id="H309C00F3D95D42AE8331982D1AD96445" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expediting Disaster Recovery Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H86ADD7B7BAD5462FB6D4A00F5A26B27E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unmet need assistance</header><subsection id="H0C99A99E26064AAFA0B44CE7180D99C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title IV of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H318462AF3C4F4F2FB7A6746ECD8913B6" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><section id="H42C7B17316CC48EE998C1DC57D06EF64"><enum>431.</enum><header>Unmet needs assistance</header><subsection id="HFF885434647448E5A2B551751A0A8B99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After the declaration of a major disaster, the President may direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to provide, subject to amounts made available from appropriations, assistance necessary for meeting unmet needs as a result of such disaster.</text></subsection><subsection id="H62AE4229D7934420829911DE1CA680D5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HDAADA501D0734B299F605AFE72E33C90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amount of funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to appropriations and not later than 30 days after a declaration is made under section 401, the President acting through the Administrator may allocate an amount that equals up to 10 percent of the estimated aggregate amount of the grants to be made pursuant to sections 406 and 408 for the major disaster in order to provide technical and financial assistance under this section and such set aside shall be deemed to be related to activities carried out pursuant to major disasters under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF139BBB9464B4DB983E954E8425BEF35"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Estimated aggregate amount</header><text>Not later than 180 days after each major disaster declaration pursuant to this Act, the estimated aggregate amount of grants for purposes of paragraph (1) shall be determined by the President and such estimated amount need not be reduced, increased, or changed due to variations in estimates.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDF37415BADF4A03B587082F04EFB2F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>No reduction in amounts</header><text>The amount set aside pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not reduce the amounts otherwise made available for sections 403, 404, 406, 407, 408, 410, 416, and 428 under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67EB8F44A3724DC1A4E15D804CCAB94C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Unmet needs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Financial assistance provided under this section may be used to provide assistance, in addition to other amounts made available under this Act, for the following unmet needs:</text><paragraph id="H0295D9079402461A828F1F1A3D9AD926"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Disaster-related home repair and rebuilding assistance to families for permanent housing purposes, including in conjunction with eligible expenditures under section 408.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45B0200A600F42B28846B3E5857421E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Disaster-related unmet needs of families who are unable to obtain adequate assistance from other sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76126804166241FBA6B3F3A58A6EDD05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other services that alleviate human suffering and promote the well-being of disaster victims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6A7F75B16A946EA804A5779E93FFAF4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Economic and business activities (including food and agriculture) after a disaster to implement post-disaster economic recovery measures, including planning and technical assistance for long-term economic recovery plans, infrastructure improvements, business or infrastructure financing, market or industry research, and other activities authorized under a comprehensive economic development strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1EEC6B909B04D5197BDC267E14ED86C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accounting and fiscal controls</header><paragraph id="HC5442F91F15D42D68051C899FBB9DBC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after receipt of funds and every 6 months thereafter until all such funds are expended, a State shall submit a report to the Administrator that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H403E5CB1B23E4C698F542AD727F46BDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the criteria established for determining how the funds are spent;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H918CDEAA1A9C4F17AC387FFBDA9FEA78"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the allocation of those funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5737F00D7706443B867A88652C5CAB97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the process for public notice and comment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D9F65DE9A614FE9B080CC3DBD38033D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any individual who receives assistance pursuant to this section shall comply with section 312(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H656A2014AE7240F495D500A441CE2399"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State that receives funds under this section may expend not more than 5 percent of the amount of such funds for the administrative costs of providing financial assistance to individuals and households in the State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9185EF47A8E74B52AD8941AC1E47D34F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section and the amendments made by this section shall apply to funds appropriated on or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3C4022466FC24E27900F65BCB4E5D762"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repair and rebuilding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA20CB33C26294D56AFD812ADB6D90416"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H01084871611941A8811788CFEC926B9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i) by striking <quote>to a safe and sanitary living or functioning condition</quote> and inserting <quote>to ensure that their home is habitable during longer term recovery</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57010E00D9814FCF8841EE54710872B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by striking <quote>A recipient of</quote> and inserting <quote>(i) <header-in-text level="clause" style="OLC">Evidence of other means of assistance.—</header-in-text>A recipient of</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69763D38013E4C8F83B3624743E84AE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD6BE70CC6B6B495A8BA1E7E969735EAD" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><clause id="HC286D2EC3FD14A8799D0F9AA82A7E916" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Coordination with other assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance allowed under this paragraph may be used in coordination with other sources for the repair and rebuilding of an owner-occupied residence.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49E400A3658342C3AD4DB02517E2FBE9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4) by striking <quote>in cases in which</quote> and all that follows through the end of the paragraph and inserting <quote>if the President considers it a cost effective alternative to other housing solutions, including the costs associated with temporary housing provided under this section, and long-term rebuilding costs associated with section 431.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFD72F92860C747FB9A15D3004F804AE6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Review by Comptroller General</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review on the fiscal controls by States that receive funds under section 431 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act and shall make recommendations to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></section><section id="HE0F682D3B2D048C685CA5BB960C58E8C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duplication of benefits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 312(b)(4) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5155">42 U.S.C. 5155(b)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6E4180D0E95A4106A737E77555335F80" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><subparagraph id="H1F6758B1443C493B91CEB4C99312AE67"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Limitation on use of income criteria</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the President may not impose additional income criteria on a potential grant recipient who has accepted a qualified disaster loan in determining eligibility for duplications of benefit relief.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

