<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC8567690E60F48B39A6AB98D3CD16436" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6736 IH: Countering Human Trafficking Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6736</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Department of Homeland Security Center for Countering Human Trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4FA87D29AEDE485A8077197933B35A24" style="OLC"><section id="HD7A2714741004FD388AD7A786F1314E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Countering Human Trafficking Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H534857DB4453437D948CB88333238D40"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H9309F2F4E48445C8837AF1E7A6830FC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the victim-centered approach must become universally understood, adopted, and practiced;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F776CB085B945C09A8F184D7D4C8D2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>criminal justice efforts must increase the focus on, and adeptness at, investigating and prosecuting forced labor cases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06F9D7188EAF4E62B31191175BB72376"><enum>(3)</enum><text>corporations must eradicate forced labor from their supply chains;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8710BF601B4E8C866F2D52B7AC9A3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Department of Homeland Security must lead by example—</text><subparagraph id="HCE9899FCAC3F4F1F8C6D5D6BDCC9A339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by ensuring that its government supply chain of contracts and procurement are not tainted by forced labor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AAFF699AD7F4083A232D07C047B47C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by leveraging all of its authorities against the importation of goods produced with forced labor; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6581FF73D934468781B30AE44778DD94"><enum>(5)</enum><text>human trafficking training, awareness, identification, and screening efforts—</text><subparagraph id="H19455EF89ECC4C41896E16746F07A2BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are a necessary first step for prevention, protection, and enforcement; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2849FA9C17BB42EFAD816A23FCE9627E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should be evidence-based to be most effective.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HEAB116A8150440229400B475781F0A5C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Department of Homeland Security Center for Countering Human Trafficking</header><subsection id="H29E3F0868D53433D8BB095A0A97F195A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="HCE27328A605A44FDBD4EDA39FE0CB43C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall operate, within U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement’s Homeland Security Investigations, the Center for Countering Human Trafficking (referred to in this Act as <quote>CCHT</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDFED431268D4B36AA6435E9013967DF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of CCHT shall be to serve at the forefront of the Department of Homeland Security’s unified global efforts to counter human trafficking through law enforcement operations and victim protection, prevention, and awareness programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72897578C9BB4918A664852E80EC6623"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Homeland Security Investigations shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1C5E35CE0934427C85FBCC19C1E0D8CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maintain a concept of operations that identifies CCHT participants, funding, core functions, and personnel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF667D5207FC4DC39A2A47484B934128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>update such concept of operations, as needed, to accommodate its mission and the threats to such mission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4C991B5B3A74F61AA092F1D583CC058"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Personnel</header><subparagraph id="HDCBB7428679840BA87A81BDD45B28BAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall appoint a CCHT Director, who shall—</text><clause id="H72617423662D4879970B6959C0A456DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be a member of the Senior Executive Service; and</text></clause><clause id="HFC4701823C2040E09DF570FAA7219B96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serve as the Department of Homeland Security’s representative on human trafficking.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70A31A746F3B4F38B940BEA5C9FA8FDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum core personnel requirements</header><text>Subject to appropriations, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that CCHT is staffed with at least 45 employees in order to maintain continuity of effort, subject matter expertise, and necessary support to the Department of Homeland Security, including—</text><clause id="HE4DE9D8A87764C2DA9594CDD77E58EAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>employees who are responsible for the Continued Presence Program and other victim protection duties;</text></clause><clause id="H0D68468034894F4C8430FA81A3B63EF5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>employees who are responsible for training, including curriculum development, and public awareness and education;</text></clause><clause id="H8CB3C5111E6D4CEDA4D4938F7844FEF1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>employees who are responsible for stakeholder engagement, Federal interagency coordination, multilateral partnerships, and policy;</text></clause><clause id="HCFF8D095186C4D72851C53D2FC3C3C21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>employees who are responsible for public relations, human resources, evaluation, data analysis and reporting, and information technology;</text></clause><clause id="HAAB4F423A259471DBE75CC6F369F4477"><enum>(v)</enum><text>special agents and criminal analysts necessary to accomplish its mission of combating human trafficking and the importation of goods produced with forced labor; and</text></clause><clause id="H885C0B88CE024484B14D09E86F662AF9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>managers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H255ABB5AADF14ACEAA8B581EE5F7D77E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Operations unit</header><text>The CCHT Director shall operate, within CCHT, an Operations Unit, which shall, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="HF49DA146E27442D89DE83E8459B412DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support criminal investigations of human trafficking (including sex trafficking and forced labor)—</text><subparagraph id="H84B4D35B31B2403D880A4A70615808E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by developing, tracking, and coordinating leads; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8B7FFDE52E74D9C961D1B60A51EAD43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by providing subject matter expertise;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC1AB7C9569445FA9992C6941AE1FA6D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>augment the enforcement of the prohibition on the importation of goods produced with forced labor through civil and criminal authorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57D16C57B782494C89F92CF706C98EF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinate a Department-wide effort to conduct procurement audits and enforcement actions, including suspension and debarment, in order to mitigate the risk of human trafficking throughout Department acquisitions and contracts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD58F0E0538D4169B211B40BF1A1DA9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support all CCHT enforcement efforts with intelligence by conducting lead development, lead validation, case support, strategic analysis, and data analytics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6071F6B18B8B4CD89D0CA9BDD0CDA3C4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Protection and Awareness Programs Unit</header><text>The CCHT Director shall operate, within CCHT, a Protection and Awareness Programs Unit, which shall—</text><paragraph id="HF45CF62117AD4DF9B147FF23F4938262"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporate a victim-centered approach throughout Department of Homeland Security policies, training, and practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC387138FB1B431084662544A5927986"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operate a comprehensive Continued Presence program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H594AB4065AE5436E847B6C695B2E1930"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct, review, and assist with Department of Homeland Security human trafficking training, screening, and identification tools and efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C64B849100343739183CC17EB650986"><enum>(4)</enum><text>operate the Blue Campaign’s nationwide public awareness effort and any other awareness efforts needed to encourage victim identification and reporting to law enforcement and to prevent human trafficking; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DE4DDB92798403AB5A87BFC72E1CF71"><enum>(5)</enum><text>coordinate external engagement, including training and events, regarding human trafficking with critical partners, including survivors, nongovernmental organizations, corporations, multilateral entities, law enforcement agencies, and other interested parties.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H91095D4EBEF6475B9F695BABB37A5D9D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Specialized initiatives</header><subsection id="HCCEF3905210E49BD883A171BF5A62287"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Human trafficking information modernization initiative</header><text>The CCHT Director, in conjunction with the Science and Technology Directorate Office of Science and Engineering, shall develop a strategy and proposal to modify systems and processes throughout the Department of Homeland Security that are related to CCHT’s mission in order to—</text><paragraph id="HBA7918EF373C40C7ABFEDAA73CAB9EEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>decrease the response time to access victim protections;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H037122A9F46B4D98A59F68BFEE738304"><enum>(2)</enum><text>accelerate lead development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9EA9975C54B4220A1EE9C7CC3DC7263"><enum>(3)</enum><text>advance the identification of human trafficking characteristics and trends;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H556B36E511CB461EBD5328EDB7832E51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>fortify the security and protection of sensitive information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD0799882D8546189A6B88198E35A1EF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>apply analytics to automate manual processes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H622E37557D044D72B7BFCC58375C5510"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide artificial intelligence and machine learning to increase system capabilities and enhance data availability, reliability, comparability, and verifiability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3B0CFE107B14A5EBDF7E01EBAC7B66D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission of plan</header><text>Upon the completion of the strategy and proposal under subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a summary of the strategy and plan for executing the strategy to—</text><paragraph id="HE0E4B9910BBC4C57B6C87AF71F619A27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name> of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD8CD9428B5E4C819823FFBDA051A56D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3FFA5AF0B4B2480E9C6AD797F49AFB87"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reports</header><subsection id="H326AF9E7848A455BB377FA97B6937622"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Information sharing To facilitate reports and analysis</header><text>Each subagency of the Department of Homeland Security shall share with CCHT—</text><paragraph id="H30DE1A87989E4D0FBD5CAF86153F38F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any information needed by CCHT to develop the strategy and proposal required under section 4(a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF04BEEE55748D9B90AD0524404BBD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any additional data analysis to help CCHT better understand the issues surrounding human trafficking.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF91E1B98D9EE4882B1F254FDDD7CC0D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the CCHT Director shall submit a report to Congress that identifies any legislation that is needed to facilitate the Department of Homeland Security’s mission to end human trafficking.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA6F9AB469AA64684A49E658DD54F4D07"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transfer of other functions related to human trafficking</header><subsection id="HAB1BBEAB196A4445A591F8FB1F1C576C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Blue Campaign</header><text>The functions and resources of the Blue Campaign located within the Office of Partnership and Engagement on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act are hereby transferred to CCHT.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7623C19EBAC04BE1A652C74954B8AE88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other transfer</header><paragraph id="HB8C0AF41484D4D6C8C1924FDE7AE3B26"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security may transfer the functions and resources of any component, directorate, or other office of the Department of Homeland Security related to combating human trafficking to the CCHT. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05A973E7F9A04F5F96281AA1321E90AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 30 days before executing any transfer authorized under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name> of the Senate and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name> of the House of Representatives of such planned transfer. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB5EA5B9209FD47AB9240ECBA79986FA5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out this Act $14,000,000, which shall remain available until expended. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

