<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H94719A9609E348E2A5774073C5F95852" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7573 IH: Telehealth Extension and Evaluation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7573</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XI and XVIII of the Social Security Act to extend certain telehealth services covered by Medicare and to evaluate the impact of telehealth services on Medicare beneficiaries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94AA8637E2EC408D99D37734E5712F62" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HB92635BDFC8A4DD797B20F5D61790938"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H922C3FE009DF43A8868C4B5994697DE0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Telehealth Extension and Evaluation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6449B12BBBB04332BCA20BDAB339DEEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents of this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HB92635BDFC8A4DD797B20F5D61790938" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H563FA25480D14A4E97830A38F0091F11" level="section">Sec. 2. Extension of telehealth services.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H235A371132414F0AA58BD5EA92ABA209" level="section">Sec. 3. Temporary requirements for provision of high-cost durable medical equipment and laboratory tests.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H30AFC82E107A4F388DC22B07E3B56E4C" level="section">Sec. 4. Requirement to submit NPI number for telehealth billing.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H67BFC4EE23C5418683E39502FF8C2685" level="section">Sec. 5. Federally qualified health centers and rural health clinics.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3A0CD9C23AB74505A04730645BAC823B" level="section">Sec. 6. Telehealth flexibilities for critical access hospitals.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9FFF943872CC48BFA1BD4ABF22D4DF03" level="section">Sec. 7. Use of telehealth for the dispensing of controlled substances by means of the internet.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H78CD9E54B2DC462F85699A75DF727AD9" level="section">Sec. 8. Study on the effects of changes to telehealth under the Medicare and Medicaid programs during the COVID–19 emergency.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD001D55E210845BAB76EACF1368E55A8" level="section">Sec. 9. Extension of authority for audio-only telehealth services under the Medicare program.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H563FA25480D14A4E97830A38F0091F11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of telehealth services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1135(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H48206185405E46F38F95AEB7E0D187CD"><paragraph id="HC9BE7A14770C4403A92C52654E64E743"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Two-year extension of telehealth services following the COVID–19 emergency period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a waiver or modification of requirements pursuant to subsection (b)(8) shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after the last day of the emergency period described in subsection (g)(1)(B).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H235A371132414F0AA58BD5EA92ABA209"><enum>3.</enum><header>Temporary requirements for provision of high-cost durable medical equipment and laboratory tests</header><subsection id="H413AE680A5C84457889A7D47B6DF1F97"><enum>(a)</enum><header>High-Cost durable medical equipment</header><text>Section 1834(a)(1)(E) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clauses:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB58AE6C1F68F47EA8B140502AD2264FA"><clause id="HF1C4D4EEDFD04907AFBAB04BC8920A0A"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Standards for high-cost durable medical equipment</header><subclause id="H345D530478414661AFF6BE9109223034"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for high-cost durable medical equipment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 2-year period beginning on the day after the last day of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), payment may not be made under this subsection for high-cost durable medical equipment ordered by a physician or other practitioner described in clause (ii) via telehealth for an individual, unless such physician or practitioner furnished to such individual a service in person at least once during the 12-month period prior to ordering such high-cost durable medical equipment.</text></subclause><subclause id="H89B014DDDB2B46BA9E414A763CBCC96E"><enum>(II)</enum><header>High-cost durable medical equipment defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <term>high-cost durable medical equipment</term> means, with respect to a year, durable medical equipment for which payment may be made under paragraphs (2) through (8), the price under the clinical lab fee schedule which for such year is in the highest quartile of national purchase prices of durable medical equipment payable for such year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC3BBF34578D44FF9BE66EDF8CFBDCFE6"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Audit of providers and practitioners furnishing a high volume of durable medical equipment via telehealth</header><subclause id="H8D3CA8DDC61C48BEBCD0C107C18A15EC"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Identification of providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 2-year period beginning on the day after the last day of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), Medicare administrative contractors shall conduct reviews, on a schedule determined by the Secretary, of claims for durable medical equipment prescribed by a physician or other practitioner described in clause (ii) during the 12-month period preceding such review to identify physicians or other practitioners with respect to whom at least 90 percent of all durable medical equipment prescribed by such physician or practitioner during such period was prescribed pursuant to a telehealth visit.</text></subclause><subclause id="H93C84A412B41469F82756F457A739273"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>In the case of a physician or practitioner identified under subclause (I), with respect to a 12-month period described in such subclause, the Medicare administrative contractors shall conduct audits of all claims for durable medical equipment prescribed by such physicians or practitioners to determine whether such claims comply with the requirements for coverage under this title.</text></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H87F8EA4BFCCF4FE78CF8D99688EA09A0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>High-Cost laboratory tests</header><text>Section 1834A(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m-1">42 U.S.C. 1395m–1(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H392182F22E804C0FB2D1BB4419E8B091"><paragraph id="HB4AAA9869FF14E57B02BD553A1460ECA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Requirement for high-cost laboratory tests</header><subparagraph id="H20D4376004584FC0874B98E6E8118C60"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Limitation on payment for high-cost laboratory tests</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 2-year period beginning on the day after the last day of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), payment may not be made under this subsection for a high-cost laboratory test ordered by a physician or practitioner via telehealth for an individual, unless such physician or practitioner furnished to such individual a service in person at least once during the 12-month period prior to ordering such high-cost laboratory test.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CC3EEF72D50466380D9B7FC22044890"><enum>(B)</enum><header>High-cost laboratory test defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>high-cost laboratory test</term> means, with respect to a year, a laboratory test for which payment may be made under this section, and the purchase price of which for such year is in the highest quartile of purchase prices of laboratory tests for such year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H583B4E9522754FAF89F2DD1F62AC0C05"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Audit of laboratory testing ordered pursuant to telehealth visit</header><subparagraph id="HF930D7A208DA4384A34998B7AF7EC2CB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Identification of providers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 2-year period beginning on the day after the last day of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), Medicare administrative contractors shall conduct periodic reviews, on a schedule determined by the Secretary, of claims for laboratory tests prescribed by a physician or practitioner during the 12-month period preceding such review to identify physicians or other practitioners with respect to whom at least 90 percent of all laboratory tests prescribed by such physician or practitioner during such period were prescribed pursuant to a telehealth visit. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11FFBCDECB5F4495BE20E52823AD608D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>In the case of a physician or practitioner identified under subparagraph (A), with respect to a 12-month period described in such subparagraph, the Medicare administrative contractors shall conduct audits of all claims for laboratory tests prescribed by such physicians or practitioners during such period to determine whether such claims comply with the requirements for coverage under this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H30AFC82E107A4F388DC22B07E3B56E4C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirement to submit NPI number for telehealth billing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA7E090DCF73B42368BF9677A1A8401E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8), (9), and (10)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H608C4657DA4645A39C24F4C95EFD1D19"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4DF904F03ADA4DB68B8B5C7E64E1006C"><paragraph id="H52696E598F3C47FB952C8F701AF18D21" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Requirement to submit NPI number for telehealth billing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the 2-year period beginning on the day after the last day of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), payment may not be made under this subsection for telehealth services furnished by a health care professional eligible to bill Medicare for their professional services unless such health care professional submits a claim for payment—</text><subparagraph id="HBEDE536AB879469BA7BE6E1B28824D57" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">under the national provider identification number assigned to such health care professional;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H334496D24D8E4DF08B0B1EECC06BBA84" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of services provided under section 1833(a)(8), under the facility identification number; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5854AE55FF034ED6BBFEB93C57EA1324" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of occupational therapy assistants or physical therapy assistants in private practice, under the national provider identification of the supervising therapist.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H67BFC4EE23C5418683E39502FF8C2685"><enum>5.</enum><header>Federally qualified health centers and rural health clinics</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m)(8) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)(8)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H8C37789DEF654826B30D569355A54938"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>the 151-day period</quote> and inserting <quote>the 2-year period</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22B6267235524B6EA33CE79CF4F57280"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10C26951F11B4B92B4B0D3907FFA320A"><subparagraph id="H0B58BF833E494CC38AB727C9889F7A99"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><clause id="HB5795F397FF74A36BBE4BA529CE3358C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A telehealth service furnished by a Federally qualified health center or a rural health clinic to an individual pursuant to this paragraph on or after the date of the enactment of this subparagraph shall be deemed to be so furnished to such individual as an outpatient of such clinic or facility (as applicable) for purposes of paragraph (1) or (3), respectively, of section 1861(aa) and payable as a Federally qualified health center service or rural health clinic service (as applicable) under the prospective payment system established under section 1834(o) or under section 1833(a)(3), respectively.</text></clause><clause id="HF0D280E5E6AE4A5196FD5BED5A80555A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of costs for FQHC PPS calculations and RHC AIR calculations</header><text>Costs associated with the delivery of telehealth services by a Federally qualified health center or rural health clinic serving as a distant site pursuant to this paragraph shall be considered allowable costs for purposes of the prospective payment system established under section 1834(o) and any payment methodologies developed under section 1833(a)(3), as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H3A0CD9C23AB74505A04730645BAC823B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Telehealth flexibilities for critical access hospitals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>), as amended by section 4, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H62E2ABBA8F83406789CECC5C0D11485F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence of paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and (10)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (10), and (11)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H613A546E62444C8887F5DB1D0DAD8A25"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (11)</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA804F9624F64045A173DE4BFBE3F5AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H0E146725AD4549E9BCC684F0F97339B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (11)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8752C6C929A542CB83F0FA11E072D1C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (F)(i), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (11)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H42A5C68B51BD4BB29EA0F1BC2498CFF7"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block id="HB37F194C35A5438A8B11AE53F5A98D03" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF4ECE31B991947C49AEFC0F7410ADA45"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Telehealth flexibilities for critical access hospitals</header><subparagraph id="H7FD88B8645AF464EB06758FD2C9AA706"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this paragraph and ending on the date that is 2 years after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B), the following shall apply:</text><clause id="HB178B3905BC54A14A22212FBF382E02A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Secretary shall pay for telehealth services that are furnished via a telecommunications system by a critical access hospital, including any practitioner authorized to provide such services within the facility, that is a qualified provider (as defined in subparagraph (B)) to an eligible telehealth individual enrolled under this part notwithstanding that the critical access hospital providing the telehealth service is not at the same location as the beneficiary, if such services complement a plan of care that includes in-person care at some point, as may be appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="H4FFAE88B6F124D879CBF2C238E519738"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The amount of payment to a critical access hospital that serves as a distant site for such a telehealth service shall be determined under subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="HFF3FA3DE3190494DB470BB9D815D1F8F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subclause id="HCA44C3DFED164A92B338955918E4F4BB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the term <term>distant site</term> includes a critical access hospital that furnishes a telehealth service to an eligible telehealth individual; </text></subclause><subclause id="H87722024666645AB9CEEF1655204C66E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the term <term>qualified provider</term> means, with respect to a telehealth service described in clause (i) that is furnished to an eligible telehealth individual, a critical access hospital that has an established patient relationship with such individual as defined by the State in which the individual is located; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H64036AE2E9AA47C482AB3E2B6A3BE800"><enum>(III)</enum><text> the term <term>telehealth services</term> includes behavioral health services and any other outpatient critical access hospital service that is furnished using telehealth to the extent that payment codes corresponding to services identified by the Secretary under clause (i) or (ii) of paragraph (4)(F) are listed on the corresponding claim for such critical access hospital service.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04E438D041BD49FAB360C0652CE4CD1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Payment</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(ii), the amount of payment to a critical access hospital that serves as a distant site that furnishes a telehealth service to an eligible telehealth individual under this paragraph shall be equal to 101 percent of the reasonable costs of the hospital in providing such services, unless the hospital makes an election under paragraph (2) of section 1834(g) to be paid for such services based on the methodology described in such paragraph. Telehealth services furnished by a critical access hospital shall be counted for purposes of determining the provider productivity rate of the critical access hospital for purposes of payment under such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43509FA74B794E85BFE576C3AC587881" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may implement this paragraph through program instruction, interim final rule, or otherwise.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H9FFF943872CC48BFA1BD4ABF22D4DF03"><enum>7.</enum><header>Use of telehealth for the dispensing of controlled substances by means of the internet</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 309(e)(2) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/829">21 U.S.C. 829(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9538D10438804226B60023C06B06846F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text><subparagraph id="HAA0DAF0808A94EEC8532355168866723"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>at least 1 in-person medical evaluation</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF444B8C505AE4BA799E0D5966AC113A7"><text>at least—</text><subclause id="H2F9DAB874B46464E9EB7BC87E0793E62"><enum>(I)</enum><text>1 in-person medical evaluation</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC36FDF590D824BE9801360DCCED56461"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H07039C87440B4B91AEE67516A61043EB"><subclause id="H091633256E7C48C586342DA59E6D581F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>during the period beginning on the date of the enactment of this subclause and ending on the date that is 2 years after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>), for purposes of prescribing a controlled substance in schedules II through V, 1 telehealth evaluation; or</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC80E2F1C308C406E818BB4F9449BD9FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFC1358E9666A41EBBE8C7C4A713BB9AF" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H23E1825F55454F9298F574F66609D408"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H92BEAFD58775442882AB8118AF4CB065"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The term <term>telehealth evaluation</term> means a medical evaluation that is conducted in accordance with applicable Federal and State laws by a practitioner (other than a pharmacist) who is at a location remote from the patient and is communicating with the patient using a telecommunications system referred to in section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) that includes, at a minimum, audio and video equipment permitting two-way, real-time interactive communication between the patient and distant site practitioner.</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H30D9ABDAA9B24400B5ED932118CEEB28" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Nothing in clause (i) shall be construed to imply that 1 telehealth evaluation demonstrates that a prescription has been issued for a legitimate medical purpose within the usual course of professional practice.</text></clause><clause id="H95BB1E33DDCE401FB50252DED6063D09" indent="up1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A practitioner who prescribes the drugs or combination of drugs that are covered under section 303(g)(2)(C) using the authority under subparagraph (A)(i)(II) of this paragraph shall adhere to nationally recognized evidence-based guidelines for the treatment of patients with opioid use disorders and a diversion control plan, as those terms are defined in section 8.2 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H78CD9E54B2DC462F85699A75DF727AD9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>8.</enum><header>Study on the effects of changes to telehealth under the Medicare and Medicaid programs during the COVID–19 emergency</header><subsection id="H1B43D6A7C0604EB387A119B75BF974BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct a study and submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate an interim report on any changes made to the provision or availability of telehealth services under part A or B of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (including by reason of the amendments made to the Controlled Substances Act under section 7) since the start of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>). Such report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H4F753D8F3CAD4D4CA918C3B47375988F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A summary of utilization of all health care services furnished under such part A or B during such emergency period, including the number of telehealth visits (broken down by service type, the number of such visits furnished via audio-visual technology, the number of such visits furnished via audio-only technology, and the number of such visits furnished by a Federally qualified health center, rural health clinic, or community health center, respectively, if practicable), in-person outpatient visits, inpatient admissions, and emergency department visits. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4BFEACA46464949A1DE26C9B4B1C07C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any changes in utilization patterns for the care settings described in paragraph (1) over the course of such emergency period compared to such patterns prior to such emergency period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F44AC6E1C0249F08DF667076C10B1B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of utilization of telehealth services under such part A or B during such emergency period, broken down by race and ethnicity, geographic region, and income level (as measured directly or indirectly, such as by patient’s zip code tabulation area median income as publicly reported by the United States Census Bureau), and of any trends in such utilization during such emergency period, so broken down. Such analysis may not include any personally identifiable information or protected health information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D3843C951BF43979E400A0713224FF2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of expenditures and any savings under such part A or B attributable to use of such telehealth services during such emergency period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13A2EE43887346538F9BCDF15891C181"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any instances of fraud identified by the Secretary, acting through the Office of the Inspector General or other relevant agencies and departments, with respect to such telehealth services furnished under such part A or B during such emergency period and a comparison of the number of such instances with the number of instances of fraud so identified with respect to in-person services so furnished during such emergency period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87CA3C06A63B40C6BA2FB68B897A06EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any privacy concerns with respect to the furnishing of such telehealth services (such as cybersecurity or ransomware concerns), including a description of any actions taken by the Secretary, acting through the Health Sector Cybersecurity Coordination Center or other relevant agencies and departments, during such emergency period to assist health care providers secure telecommunications systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF44A04ED82874CDCB06851DACC72136F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Identification of common ICD–10 codes billed via telehealth, comparing measures of quality and outcomes between telehealth care and in-person care for the same category of service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89413312027640788C74374BC1B7E5C4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Recommendations regarding the permanency of the waivers and authorities under the provisions of, and amendments made by, this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFD3572982324F2DA4B8810DBEF0C856"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting the study and submitting the report under subsection (a), the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="H26AD5E1514734A238F30C4B120B8D908"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H622F36478D6C4A138528DFC6647727D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Medicaid and CHIP Payment and Access Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC703939C47D4CADBF24081DF19B1E69"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2662C51480364B4796D0048CDB1D2993"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Office of Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD66CD14FC8BF487A9D7F4BBDD256C09D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other stakeholders determined appropriate by the Secretary, such as patients, tribal communities, medical professionals, health facilities, State medical boards, State nursing boards, telehealth providers, health professional liability providers, public and private payers, and State leaders; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA529D6151CDD4D4B90DCA53A284C8690"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall endeavor to include as many racially, ethnically, geographically, and professionally diverse perspectives as possible.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF12C9B1844984930AFBE8115091AFAD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>), the Secretary shall— </text><paragraph id="H50CD57AA646341DB89B74607EB376014"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">update and finalize the interim report under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE4E645E1A2D4437B059EAB0534AE35A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit such updated and finalized report to the committees specified in such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC93AB6980DC4B02A3D21BA824AE9DB0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants for Medicaid reports</header><paragraph id="H30E2A629BB2D434E9D3D8330C5AE4680"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than January 1, 2023, the Secretary shall award grants to States with a State plan (or waiver of such plan) in effect under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r</external-xref>) that submit an application under this subsection for purposes of enabling such States to study and submit reports to the Secretary on any changes made to the provision or availability of telehealth services under such plans (or such waivers) during such period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78F78C796E884496A8DD5885BE376743"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under paragraph (1), a State shall—</text><subparagraph id="H80120EB63EE84973A7A67A94F6909182"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide benefits for telehealth services under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) in effect under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r">42 U.S.C. 1396r</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71FAA1A8E39F4E3DBE290A46EF7A8F1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be able to differentiate telehealth from in-person visits within claims data submitted under such plan (or such waiver) during such period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1B059F6A9A14D95847E7ED62FB0EEF7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information (including the amount of the grant requested) as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE46D23AB11154AD7A862C8919F1593A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State shall use amounts received under a grant under this subsection to conduct a study and report findings regarding the effects of changes to telehealth services offered under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) of such State under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) during such period in accordance with paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C4FC184FEA545139BFAF2095A4A9411"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="HBB3CBB17FD7C4E98A081B8304AB91F51"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later 1 year after the date a State receives a grant under this subsection, the State shall submit to the Secretary an interim report that—</text><clause id="HC41B69B4BEE34AC092FC16D6D8E2FFB0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">details any changes made to the provision or availability of telehealth benefits (such as eligibility, coverage, or payment changes) under the State plan (or waiver of such plan) of the State under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>) during the emergency period described in paragraph (1); and</text></clause><clause id="H13F26F1BA09D41CD928E1CFC8B3605F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contains—</text><subclause id="HD458FC30F6774229A1F9559A8C1BFBD9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a summary and description of the type described in paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively, of subsection (a); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H1A11004E3EC6404AA4DEBCC3E806ED35"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to the extent practicable, an analysis of the type described in paragraph (3) of subsection (a),</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">except that any reference in such subsection to <quote>such part A or B</quote> shall, for purposes of subclauses (I) and (II), be treated as a reference to such State plan (or waiver). </continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7493FF5C573416BB4BA2DB90D264F21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date a State receives a grant under this subsection, the State shall update and finalize the interim report and submit such final report to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H747899908F994910AC9069C2950FB990"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report by Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the earlier of the date that is 1 year after the submission of all final reports under subparagraph (B) and December 31, 2027, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the grant program, including a summary of the reports received from States under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF63787250F6540AFB496D3030A7A1F23"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Modification authority</header><text>The Secretary may modify any deadline described in paragraph (4) or any information required to be included in a report made under this subsection to provide flexibility for States to modify the scope of the study and timeline for such reports.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AE6389800C4BC886C74214B8C1E2E4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide such technical assistance as may be necessary to a State receiving a grant under this subsection in order to assist such State in conducting studies and submitting reports under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30C1EAB4A79D49DCAB2B4A339B85EB32"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, and each territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FEBD77762BC40F993DD8F9B3C1B008D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H33AC43D6F22748FC937B8FDFD67A62E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Medicare</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of carrying out subsections (a) through (c), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6C127415C541C28D805D83C8A13761" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of carrying out subsection (d), there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD001D55E210845BAB76EACF1368E55A8" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Extension of authority for audio-only telehealth services under the Medicare program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (9) of section 1834(m) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395m">42 U.S.C. 1395m(m)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>151-day period</quote> and inserting <quote>2-year period</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

