<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAED46D4F95BE4FFA9F1EC4DF80C6FFD1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7099 IH: Stop Gas Price Gouging Tax and Rebate Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7099</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220316">March 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish a windfall profits excise tax on crude oil and to rebate the tax collected back to individual taxpayers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCBD23205DE5440E9BEF963C9BAB647D4" style="OLC"><section id="H0FF909052A9948D8987702E5E4370987" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Gas Price Gouging Tax and Rebate Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HA382F5EDF4564F32B3CBE13E4E2F1755"><enum>2.</enum><header>Windfall profits tax</header><subsection id="HD736CB33DAE04495B26DF0BACF5B2922"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle E of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to alcohol, tobacco, and certain other excise taxes) is amended by adding at the end thereof the following new chapter:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDEE84EDECCF04AE697711EEB8511F0A9" style="OLC"><chapter id="H55FA06FD51E44746A46F16A03077EB7D"><enum>56</enum><header>Windfall profits on crude oil</header><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5896. Imposition of tax. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5897. Windfall profit. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5898. Special rules and definitions. </toc-entry></toc><section id="HAA3987AABA604901B6D958FD3006BAEB"><enum>5896.</enum><header>Imposition of tax</header><subsection id="H8B9695F8A0D543B2AAFD6F257B732AF6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to any other tax imposed under this title, there is hereby imposed on any applicable taxpayer an excise tax in an amount equal to 50 percent of the excess of the windfall profit (as defined in section 5897(a)) of such taxpayer. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2942F126F1FA4749BFEF4E89D45F5FB6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicable taxpayer</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, the term <term>applicable taxpayer</term> means, with respect to a taxable year, a producer of crude oil—</text><paragraph id="H2B50DA75817B4BA488A05E30B35CEB5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which has an average daily worldwide production of crude oil of at least 300,000 barrels for the taxable year, and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0803542B0F314120B45A5BD2AD3496A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which had gross receipts in excess of $1,000,000,000 for its last taxable year ending during calendar year 2005. </text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">For purposes of this subsection, all persons treated as a single employer under subsections (a) and (b) of section 52 shall be treated as 1 person and, in case of a short taxable year, the rule under section 448(c)(3)(B) shall apply. </continuation-text></subsection></section><section id="H5CBED0DA581140B8871677FE157D7F01"><enum>5897.</enum><header>Windfall profit</header><subsection id="H8F8F39C8AFA24113A04D8D32A68E2713"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General rule</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, the term <term>windfall profit</term> means the excess of the adjusted taxable income of the applicable taxpayer for taxable year 2022 over the reasonably inflated average profit for such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD7A5C7892CC548F68329BED08AF6B7AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjusted taxable income</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, with respect to any applicable taxpayer, the adjusted taxable income for taxable year 2022 is equal to the taxable income for such taxable year (within the meaning of section 63 and determined without regard to this subsection)—</text><paragraph id="H796CF56E6B2D40B497BBAC42880309C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increased by any interest expense deduction, charitable contribution deduction, and any net operating loss deduction carried forward from any prior taxable year, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23D416F606CA44C292A0059AA0436379"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reduced by any interest income, dividend income, and net operating losses to the extent such losses exceed taxable income for the taxable year.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">In the case of any applicable taxpayer which is a foreign corporation, the adjusted taxable income shall be determined with respect to such income which is effectively connected with the conduct of a trade or business in the United States. </continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="HA23AF43B8CEB4F87A82694A2F6E0038E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reasonably inflated average profit</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, with respect to any applicable taxpayer, the reasonably inflated average profit for any taxable year is an amount equal to the average of the adjusted taxable income of such taxpayer for taxable years beginning during the 2015–2019 taxable year period (determined without regard to the taxable year with the highest adjusted taxable income in such period) plus 10 percent of such average.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC82465941465410A858A6FEB79AC12A8"><enum>5898.</enum><header>Special rules and definitions</header><subsection id="HA01D068395614EFBA40A405A40C5A3A0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withholding and deposit of tax</header><text>The Secretary shall provide such rules as are necessary for the withholding and deposit of the tax imposed under section 5896.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD2D62133AAAD4B9A866C2552D13F5DFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Records and information</header><text>Each taxpayer liable for tax under section 5896 shall keep such records, make such returns, and furnish such information as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6EE9F3F1121B4EA78E02C99CA986DCEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Return of windfall profit tax</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for the filing and the time of such filing of the return of the tax imposed under section 5896.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36B55A2908E24AD48FEC1E1BC766FB0B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Crude oil</header><text>The term <term>crude oil</term> includes crude oil condensates and natural gasoline.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3B71FDC4C8994B629DACC60F0142436C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Businesses under common control</header><text>For purposes of this chapter, all members of the same controlled group of corporations (within the meaning of section 267(f)) and all persons under common control (within the meaning of section 52(b) but determined by treating an interest of more than 50 percent as a controlling interest) shall be treated as 1 person.</text></subsection><subsection id="H371920D53D464ED0B60ADFE7D38A0EBE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this chapter.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HDD02FE014B7648C9907BA777B0D6C43E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for subtitle E of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0279FFB80B914DB6BCFC4BCAE22665D1" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="chapter">Chapter 56. Windfall profit on crude oil. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9A37DE110F8B450DA9964A0879A9765D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deductibility of windfall profit tax</header><text>The first sentence of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/164">section 164(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to deduction for taxes) is amended by inserting after paragraph (5) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H466FB9C16DE84032B3AB6115718A488D" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HCC7BE182BD3B45749CABED7132A91A20"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The windfall profit tax imposed by section 5896.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5668601F2E08470F9B51566F379446F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after December 31, 2021.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83CCDA6AAEF34B55AA6DC2A8BDF3DF39" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Energy price rebates</header><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4841297D26894285874938B22A49BE3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/65">chapter 65</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA56B5331E7C64892B2544F23887E9FC1" style="OLC"><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD104FB4686A44BB7AA8FFF0EF1F939ED" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>6433.</enum><header>Energy price rebates</header><subsection id="H9D760B907CB04B7FA9233AEE403C6C2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an eligible individual, there shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by subtitle A for taxable year 2022 an amount equal to the sum of the energy price rebate amount for each month beginning in such taxable year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB3A27F7309844DC92B18ECC3B6FAAD8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Energy price rebate amount</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HECBCC35E4E594104BB1C7D85488DCB16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>energy price rebate amount</term> means, with respect to any taxpayer for any month beginning in taxable year 2022, an amount determined by the Secretary as soon as practicable after the end of such month taking into account the number of eligible individuals and the amount of revenues in the general fund resulting from the tax imposed by section 5896 for such month. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H341D3178E4464A69B9B8DF9BC233BB68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special rule for joint returns</header><text>In the case of an eligible individual filing a joint return, the energy price rebate amount shall be 150 percent of the amount determined under paragraph (1) with respect to other taxpayers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A204D13C0DD426DA8E68A8A6803BE12" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation based on adjusted gross income</header><text>The amount of the credit allowed by subsection (a) (determined without regard to this subsection and subsection (e)) shall be reduced (but not below zero) by 5 percent of so much of the eligible individual's adjusted gross income as exceeds—</text><subparagraph id="H73E251F1C625429EB84E77F63AF9B671"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$150,000 in the case of a joint return,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E725748BBF24565ACB20C27C8115963"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$112,500 in the case of a head of household, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6CDE7ED084F4D15B671772DA537BE6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$75,000 in any other case.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED184DAAEA5242E984C4EEAF0AD7E08E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible individual</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>eligible individual</term> means any individual other than—</text><paragraph id="H230E4BDB1E2D4BB8A08FD97667C69FE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any nonresident alien individual,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71480440872F4C1D8D065E2E1A60C728"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any individual who is a dependent of another taxpayer for a taxable year beginning in the calendar year in which the individual’s taxable year begins, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H471189A435D24E7A9ABB4A7906163E00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an estate or trust. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2581454F18DA4BB1BF7ACBCBACACD946"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><paragraph id="H610A8D3300554C06900F788745F8B54B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dependent defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>dependent</term> has the meaning given such term by section 152. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB49127901CEA4007A4322D3FAE69B207" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification number requirement</header><subparagraph id="HA9352E50C11C4A56B931D63C4FBBD6BE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a return other than a joint return, the energy price rebate amount in subsection (b)(1) shall be treated as being zero unless the taxpayer includes the valid identification number of the taxpayer on the return of tax for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3EF75E736844FF3A81B3256169D9DB0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text>In the case of a joint return, the energy price rebate amount in subsection (b)(1) shall be treated as being—</text><clause id="H47654A8E366C4AA48C11CA4D07850C97"><enum>(i)</enum><text>50 percent of the amount otherwise determined without regard to this paragraph if the valid identification number of only 1 spouse is included on the return of tax for the taxable year, and</text></clause><clause id="H58C8BE06B79D4439BD9AA10492217BB0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>zero if the valid identification number of neither spouse is so included.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA43DE5FA5F2349389E09B40715EEBE70"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Valid identification number</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>valid identification number</quote> means a social security number issued to an individual by the Social Security Administration on or before the due date for filing the return for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4142F5D0B34A4F03AD1F1EEF19C88F27" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rule for members of the Armed Forces</header><text>Subparagraph (B) shall not apply in the case where at least 1 spouse was a member of the Armed Forces of the United States at any time during the taxable year and the valid identification number of at least 1 spouse is included on the return of tax for the taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCC48106EAED4D9FAA0E62994816FA34" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Coordination with certain advance payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any payment determined pursuant to subsection (f)(6), a valid identification number shall be treated for purposes of this paragraph as included on the taxpayer’s return of tax if such valid identification number is available to the Secretary as described in such subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB8A738A96384BC5B57F1FA131FE27BC"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Mathematical or clerical error authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any omission of a correct valid identification number required under this paragraph shall be treated as a mathematical or clerical error for purposes of applying section 6213(g)(2) to such omission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29BDAFD287DB49D295F568CAD64BC3BD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Credit treated as refundable</header><text>The credit allowed by subsection (a) shall be treated as allowed by subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFF755D7372C45FC98BDF624454D7864"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination with advance refunds of credit</header><paragraph id="HFC474A41748B49539B7B6C3C5392168E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reduction of refundable credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of the credit which would (but for this paragraph) be allowable under subsection (a) for any taxable year shall be reduced (but not below zero) by the aggregate refunds and credits made or allowed to the taxpayer (or, except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, any dependent of the taxpayer) under subsection (f) for such taxable year. Any failure to so reduce the credit shall be treated as arising out of a mathematical or clerical error and assessed according to section 6213(b)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H840F46D20E27405D9AED28DF04F91CE4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Joint returns</header><text>Except as otherwise provided by the Secretary, in the case of a refund or credit made or allowed under subsection (f) with respect to a joint return, half of such refund or credit shall be treated as having been made or allowed to each individual filing such return.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DF5BD02B1694858A8F87FDAC4D49196"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Advance refunds and credits</header><paragraph id="HA2CCCC9201EB41AF8D59E5EF1CE5C7B8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraphs (5) and (6), for any rebate taxable year, each individual who was an eligible individual for such individual’s first taxable year beginning in 2020 shall be treated as having made a payment against the tax imposed by chapter 1 for such applicable taxable year in an amount equal to advance refund amount for such rebate taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B7CE78BD18547F2B7EBFB3796FCB45E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Advance refund amount</header><subparagraph id="HCB060FB60EE84DB9A38B8D7296E07380"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the advance refund amount is the amount that would have been allowed as a credit under this section for such taxable year if this section (other than subsection (e) and this subsection) had applied to such taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71687EA7E95742C0B8C38A6A874731D4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of deceased individuals</header><text>For purposes of determining the advanced refund amount with respect to such taxable year—</text><clause id="H133EA031563F42B5AD5357BDBF881004" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any individual who was deceased before January 1, 2022 shall be treated for purposes of applying subsection (d)(2) in the same manner as if the valid identification number of such person was not included on the return of tax for the applicable taxable year (except that subparagraph (D) thereof shall not apply), and</text></clause><clause id="HA81EDA8266E541338DB9037C52DD3DCA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>notwithstanding clause (i), in the case of a joint return with respect to which only 1 spouse is deceased before January 1, 2022, such deceased spouse was a member of the Armed Forces of the United States at any time during the applicable taxable year, and the valid identification number of such deceased spouse is included on the return of tax for the applicable taxable year, the valid identification number of 1 (and only 1) spouse shall be treated as included on the return of tax for the applicable taxable year for purposes of applying subsection (d)(2)(B) with respect to such joint return. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BE66BEC86E64FE59C51D3FC67B6DBE7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Timing and manner of payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, subject to the provisions of this title, refund or credit any overpayment attributable to this section and determined with respect to any month as rapidly as possible, consistent with a rapid effort to make payments attributable to such overpayments electronically if appropriate. No refund or credit shall be made or allowed under this subsection after December 31, 2022. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51FF7EEAC4BC4770A38E34B94F10E591"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No interest</header><text>No interest shall be allowed on any overpayment attributable to this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAFC1DACB6B6461CBE26C6D6AEEA18EA" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application to individuals who have filed a return of tax for 2021</header><subparagraph id="H6633D3A045D84F4F9888743F5096C87C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application to 2021 returns filed at time of initial determination</header><text>If, at the time of any determination made pursuant to paragraph (3), the individual referred to in paragraph (1) has filed a return of tax for the individual’s first taxable year beginning in 2021, paragraph (1) shall be applied with respect to such individual by substituting <quote>2021</quote> for <quote>2020</quote>. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H337D578D28CA4DE9BE526C88288D7E8E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional payment</header><clause id="H1340BD662D454CFCA58BD77AB536436A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any individual who files, before the additional payment determination date, a return of tax for such individual’s first taxable year beginning in 2021, the Secretary shall make a payment (in addition to any payment made under paragraph (1)) to such individual equal to the excess (if any) of—</text><subclause id="HB2A1E5CBBCEF40FCB9464AF6BA2FC9F1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount which would be determined under paragraph (1) (after the application of subparagraph (A)) by applying paragraph (1) as of the additional payment determination date, over</text></subclause><subclause id="HC9F5C476DEC549989C8E74E015D383D0" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the amount of any payment made with respect to such individual under paragraph (1).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H852AE0F6CBA94B1196250CC2EDB8A6D8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional payment determination date</header><text>The term <quote>additional payment determination date</quote> means the earlier of—</text><subclause id="HD16DF02D7FD64D8085AF2F3FBCEE9773" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date which is 90 days after the 2021 calendar year filing deadline, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H641E4C584AF54E15AD33B1CC38EBF3D6" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">September 1, 2022.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00A9FD03141B4B508F0B1FFB080DABE5" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Application to certain individuals who have not filed a return of tax for 2020 or 2021 at the time of determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any individual who, at the time of any determination made pursuant to paragraph (3), has filed a tax return for neither the year described in paragraph (1) nor for the year described in paragraph (5)(A), the Secretary shall, consistent with rules similar to the rules of section 6428A(f)(5)(H)(i), apply paragraph (1) on the basis of information available to the Secretary and shall, on the basis of such information, determine the advance refund amount with respect to such individual without regard to subsection (d) unless the Secretary has reason to know that such amount would otherwise be reduced by reason of such subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAF0CE6EA6E04A018A5F5143A8F0691F"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Special rule related to time of filing return</header><text>Solely for purposes of this subsection, a return of tax shall not be treated as filed until such return has been processed by the Internal Revenue Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB1901BA145E4508869157477EE3F97F" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section, including—</text><paragraph id="HB41A07F41170408B8EBAC353D8EE5976"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regulations or other guidance providing taxpayers the opportunity to provide the Secretary information sufficient to allow the Secretary to make payments to such taxpayers under subsection (f) (including the determination of the amount of such payment) if such information is not otherwise available to the Secretary, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABDE1AB277B2410992B2F83E8C2A1A74"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulations or other guidance to ensure to the maximum extent administratively practicable that, in determining the amount of any credit under subsection (a) and any credit or refund under subsection (f), an individual is not taken into account more than once, including by different taxpayers and including by reason of a change in joint return status or dependent status between the taxable year for which an advance refund amount is determined and the taxable year for which a credit under subsection (a) is determined. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FB53C6FEE0C4EFC9D5A99F373C100A0" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a robust and comprehensive outreach program to ensure that all taxpayers described in subsection (g)(1) learn of their eligibility for the advance refunds and credits under subsection (f); are advised of the opportunity to receive such advance refunds and credits as provided under subsection (g)(1); and are provided assistance in applying for such advance refunds and credits.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H39932EA46B1749FD99F27E52BD7A98E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of certain possessions</header><paragraph id="HC6092258EC7F42D19C8C5F99D2282C29"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to possessions with mirror code tax systems</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States which has a mirror code tax system amounts equal to the loss (if any) to that possession by reason of the amendments made by this section. Such amounts shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H164EECF638F7432C83E35C62D0BD1CC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Payments to other possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system amounts estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the aggregate benefits (if any) that would have been provided to residents of such possession by reason of the amendments made by this section if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply unless the respective possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, under which such possession will promptly distribute such payments to its residents.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB80F8081D524DD99E2F1C9A50FB4F03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of administrative expenses</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall pay to each possession of the United States to which the Secretary makes a payment under paragraph (1) or (2) an amount equal to the increase (if any) of the administrative expenses of such possession—</text><subparagraph id="H679B772A275B4C42999D47FFAA8CC7B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a possession described in paragraph (1), by reason of the amendments made by this section, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED8F32B5F1A94216855BCCA974603379"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a possession described in paragraph (2), by reason of carrying out the plan described in such paragraph, or</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The amount described in subparagraph (A) shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession. </continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69BF40473CB24AAC9691D9D532C43BA2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against united states income taxes</header><text>No credit shall be allowed against United States income taxes under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6433">section 6433</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section), nor shall any credit or refund be made or allowed under subsection (f) of such section, to any person—</text><subparagraph id="HED8C0B30BBE545668617E39DC7D62A91"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to whom a credit is allowed against taxes imposed by the possession by reason of the amendments made by this section, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B1A32BE20EF42769ABF11E89B5EED89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is eligible for a payment under a plan described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H242B06E08343441BBB6740FFBA6B1984"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>mirror code tax system</term> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA38963D886C4897A20C553ECC1044FE" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1324 of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this subsection shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from a credit provision referred to in subsection (b)(2) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB12AAC28779B4B95B95BC6CA0F6517E6" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><paragraph id="HC99D687B7A954685ABDA41B7BEAA7729" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of deficiency</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6211">Section 6211(b)(4)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>6428A, 6428B</quote> and inserting <quote>6428A, 6428B, 6433,</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA35D0B67CA484404A819F05328164990" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception from reduction or offset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any refund payable by reason of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6433">section 6433(f)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by this section), or any such refund payable by reason of subsection (b) of this section, shall not be—</text><subparagraph id="H0E60E96509C8436C979B135B631AF282" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to reduction or offset pursuant to subsection (c), (d), (e), or (f) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/6402">section 6402</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 or any similar authority permitting offset, or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86184A4AEC6F467D90B0FF4BC2748674" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduced or offset by other assessed Federal taxes that would otherwise be subject to levy or collection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE543D60BE9F44E5894C3D579D2738ADC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Assignment of benefits</header><subparagraph id="HD9B4BACBDDD54CA38FBBE26E42E45ACA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The right of any person to any applicable payment shall not be transferable or assignable, at law or in equity, and no applicable payment shall be subject to, execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process, or the operation of any bankruptcy or insolvency law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFF8AA8AA77B4666BBA237CF2DA69F2B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Encoding of payments</header><text>In the case of an applicable payment described in subparagraph (E)(iii)(I) that is paid electronically by direct deposit through the Automated Clearing House (ACH) network, the Secretary of the Treasury (or the Secretary's delegate) shall—</text><clause id="H54AE6727CA124CAD8064AB639C006513" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>issue the payment using a unique identifier that is reasonably sufficient to allow a financial institution to identify the payment as an applicable payment, and</text></clause><clause id="H96C66EDAFDE5408ABA10DB575E641848" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>further encode the payment pursuant to the same specifications as required for a benefit payment defined in section 212.3 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A29FF698A51466CB83B760E2DDF2497" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Garnishment</header><clause id="H0C135845D7A24C058EBC87BA8F3AF0DB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Encoded payments</header><text>In the case of a garnishment order that applies to an account that has received an applicable payment that is encoded as provided in subparagraph (B), a financial institution shall follow the requirements and procedures set forth in part 212 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations, except—</text><subclause id="H052596FBF29E4154A5B2FC10D5A3DE2E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding section 212.4 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (and except as provided in subclause (II)), a financial institution shall not fail to follow the procedures of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/212">sections 212.5</external-xref> and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/212">212.6</external-xref> of such title with respect to a garnishment order merely because such order has attached, or includes, a notice of right to garnish federal benefits issued by a State child support enforcement agency, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H960B6F07CE144F6CB2EFBA6D311B594A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a financial institution shall not, with regard to any applicable payment, be required to provide the notice referenced in sections 212.6 and 212.7 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6B8E969A257F44559EFBE54DF5A0EAB3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other payments</header><text>In the case of a garnishment order (other than an order that has been served by the United States) that has been received by a financial institution and that applies to an account into which an applicable payment that has not been encoded as provided in subparagraph (B) has been deposited electronically on any date during the lookback period or into which an applicable payment that has been deposited by check on any date in the lookback period, the financial institution, upon the request of the account holder, shall treat the amount of the funds in the account at the time of the request, up to the amount of the applicable payment (in addition to any amounts otherwise protected under part 212 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations), as exempt from a garnishment order without requiring the consent of the party serving the garnishment order or the judgment creditor. </text></clause><clause id="H0FF7A624C07443E88D0DFE038C51B806" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>A financial institution that acts in good faith in reliance on clauses (i) or (ii) shall not be subject to liability or regulatory action under any Federal or State law, regulation, court or other order, or regulatory interpretation for actions concerning any applicable payments.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85FCE57E0D1448649F5AB462E5E0CA41" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>No reclamation rights</header><text>This paragraph shall not alter the status of applicable payments as tax refunds or other nonbenefit payments for purpose of any reclamation rights of the Department of the Treasury or the Internal Revenue Service as per part 210 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17BBD1D37F9D4006BE1FC19D40BF1363" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph—</text><clause id="H951E0F6755354E84ADB8A1C3DF7AE8BF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Account holder</header><text>The term <term>account holder</term> means a natural person whose name appears in a financial institution’s records as the direct or beneficial owner of an account. </text></clause><clause id="H6C70ABB605BB4E1E92A57E523E47407A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Account review</header><text>The term <term>account review</term> means the process of examining deposits in an account to determine if an applicable payment has been deposited into the account during the lookback period. The financial institution shall perform the account review following the procedures outlined in section 212.5 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations and in accordance with the requirements of section 212.6 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H1038F902124144A3950B3D5E3DD3A912" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Applicable payment</header><text>The term <term>applicable payment</term> means—</text><subclause id="HC6AAC3C0E53F49A3B95B49FFAC69E0DD" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any payment made to an individual under this section (other than any payment made pursuant to paragraph (5)),</text></subclause><subclause id="H642C42EDC3E545069BA0F3BE30637C7B" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any advance payment made by a possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system (as defined in section 24(h)) pursuant to an election under paragraph (5)(B) which corresponds to a payment described in subclause (I), and</text></subclause><subclause id="H33BDA6754BE549B29478EEA20645855A" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any advance payment made by American Samoa pursuant to a program for making such payments which is described in paragraph (5)(C)(ii).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5393A094BBE7484A8EB5AB045FEBDBDC" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Garnishment</header><text>The term <term>garnishment</term> means execution, levy, attachment, garnishment, or other legal process.</text></clause><clause id="H3A6EBAA4C5D844E38FC0B30DFEF76022" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Garnishment order</header><text>The term <term>garnishment order</term> means a writ, order, notice, summons, judgment, levy, or similar written instruction issued by a court, a State or State agency, a municipality or municipal corporation, or a State child support enforcement agency, including a lien arising by operation of law for overdue child support or an order to freeze the assets in an account, to effect a garnishment against a debtor.</text></clause><clause id="H24639A891B3342E89382F8C1988785DC" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Lookback period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lookback period</term> means the two-month period that begins on the date preceding the date of account review and ends on the corresponding date of the month two months earlier, or on the last date of the month two months earlier if the corresponding date does not exist. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0692A0D6B06E4AC382158AEFA281F283" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><subparagraph id="H1BA99DC0CACD4951AA2C1719D6D4E91B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 1324(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>6433,</quote> after <quote>6431,</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75CC54CD335F449E8866D7E63F88C2DE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/65">chapter 65</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA103494CDD4642D88C293A0C7A8A7DB0"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD104FB4686A44BB7AA8FFF0EF1F939ED">Sec. 6433. Energy price rebates.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

