<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H955AB056B6A34790B63C4B87A3C86B69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9603 IH: SEC Regulatory Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9603</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the consideration by the Securities and Exchange Commission of the costs and benefits of its regulations and orders.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAD34B7A753A348418064E8F9AAE945E3" style="OLC"><section id="HD035180F911346DBAE7FD61DC640FA68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>SEC Regulatory Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H125D470A0C3A4AA6AE2BE88069FDE2BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Consideration by the Securities and Exchange Commission of the costs and benefits of its regulations and certain other agency actions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 23 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78w">15 U.S.C. 78w</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0D1478255A94D70AAA1D47F294C8EF9" style="OLC"><subsection id="H5942D9B3D70F4D25B8AD67651441D061"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consideration of costs and benefits</header><paragraph id="H68C9A609218E4F14B106567162E8F644"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before issuing a regulation under the securities laws, as defined in section 3(a), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="HDD3AD18533A9485E811DF077C6FCEFA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly identify the nature and source of the problem that the proposed regulation is designed to address, as well as assess the significance of that problem, to enable assessment of whether any new regulation is warranted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4053D46FD70F478E8211D93B7CB8F6F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that any new regulation is within the Commission’s jurisdiction and that the Commission has sufficient experience and expertise to regulate the subject matter covered by the new regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA711D2214A146A1814118D4D0550F13"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly identify the market participants who will be impacted by the new regulation; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF424DC36B53C4D7AB59D6FC07BF961AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">utilize the Chief Economist to assess the costs and benefits, both qualitative and quantitative, of the intended regulation and propose or adopt a regulation only on a reasoned determination that the benefits of the intended regulation justify the costs of the regulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81902ACAD1CF42F1A761454056BBAF62"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and assess available alternatives to the regulation that were considered, including modification of an existing regulation, together with an explanation of why the regulation meets the regulatory objectives more effectively than the alternatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1604A5CF5E84AEDB24C7E292D83A451"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that any regulation is accessible, consistent, written in plain language, and easy to understand and shall measure, and seek to improve, the actual results of regulatory requirements.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC50362D8344F49E4BE3CCE05225A5479"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations and actions</header><subparagraph id="H8D01CDE6C3CA48FE9A85049087F94F30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required actions</header><text>In deciding whether and how to regulate, the Commission shall assess the costs and benefits of available regulatory alternatives, including the alternative of not regulating, and choose the approach that maximizes net benefits. Specifically, the Commission shall—</text><clause id="H59E8B67FA2ED4D0687AAFB341E12A6FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consistent with the requirements of section 3(f) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78c">15 U.S.C. 78c(f)</external-xref>), section 2(b) of the Securities Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/77b">15 U.S.C. 77b(b)</external-xref>), section 202(c) of the Investment Advisers Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80b-2">15 U.S.C. 80b–2(c)</external-xref>), and section 2(c) of the Investment Company Act of 1940 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/80a-2">15 U.S.C. 80a–2(c)</external-xref>), consider whether the rulemaking, in addition to being in the interest of protecting investors, will promote efficiency, competition, and capital formation;</text></clause><clause id="H23EEAB5CD9744260ACB2A5F129BA03D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluate whether, consistent with obtaining regulatory objectives, the regulation is tailored to impose the least burden on society, including market participants, individuals, businesses of differing sizes, and other entities (including State and local governmental entities), taking into account, to the extent practicable, the cumulative costs of regulations; and</text></clause><clause id="H69CEA9F0D4B44B2380861CAB40AF8017"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>evaluate whether the regulation is inconsistent, incompatible, or duplicative of other Federal regulations.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75A9CE20C5B141E18ED58846CE435D3D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Additional considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition, in making a reasoned determination of the costs and benefits of a potential regulation, the Commission shall, to the extent that each is relevant to the particular proposed regulation, take into consideration the impact of the regulation on—</text><clause id="H3E614D5023D7407A93976ACE7C59E99C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>investor choice;</text></clause><clause id="HF00A70BE8AC649AFAB0433995758A698"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>market liquidity in the securities markets;</text></clause><clause id="H71E7D8F583FD48A581213E01B8F101CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>small businesses;</text></clause><clause id="H8BB76AE2419C4CFF954BF6ADCB0D12C3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">competition in the marketplace;</text></clause><clause id="H994ED4F3C3724464A743685527C46B23"><enum>(v)</enum><text>investor access; and</text></clause><clause id="H05FB8B58EB20488F826DA157788B025A"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the United States economic competitiveness.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48FBEE498F3E4154A34BA30ED7FE0E2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Post-adoption impact assessment</header><subparagraph id="H6FEF57D2930048DFB5F0B74F01CBD2CD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever the Commission adopts or amends a regulation designated as a <quote>major rule</quote> within the meaning of section 804(2) of title 5, United States Code, it shall state, in its adopting release, the following:</text><clause id="H69CFC4687DF442968FA7A50D1FB63E5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes and intended consequences of the regulation.</text></clause><clause id="H2B65BD375AE54EA89CE7AD1AE3EFD00E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriate post-implementation quantitative and qualitative metrics to measure the economic impact of the regulation and to measure the extent to which the regulation has accomplished the stated purposes.</text></clause><clause id="H68F766DBD5BD42FEBE51C87C57D9D2AA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment plan that will be used, consistent with the requirements of subparagraph (B) and under the supervision of the Chief Economist of the Commission, to assess whether the regulation has achieved the stated purposes.</text></clause><clause id="H4DA87649AC894D7BBC18F1996A3F4DF3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Any unintended or negative consequences that the Commission foresees may result from the regulation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB02EF377D33842A8AA121EA170D4671E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements of assessment plan and report</header><clause id="HA8F56FB5895248609B86B75AB19B127E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Requirements of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The assessment plan required under this paragraph shall consider the costs, benefits, and intended and unintended consequences of the regulation. The plan shall specify the data to be collected, the methods for collection and analysis of the data and a date for completion of the assessment. The assessment plan shall include an analysis of any jobs added or lost as a result of the regulation, differentiating between public and private sector jobs.</text></clause><clause id="H6A189DEC7D0B4399B9EE7D7959B87538"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Submission and publication of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief Economist shall submit the completed assessment report to the Commission no later than 2 years after the publication of the adopting release, unless the Commission, at the request of the Chief Economist, has published at least 90 days before such date a notice in the Federal Register extending the date and providing specific reasons why an extension is necessary. Within 7 days after submission to the Commission of the final assessment report, it shall be published in the Federal Register for notice and comment. Any material modification of the plan, as necessary to assess unforeseen aspects or consequences of the regulation, shall be promptly published in the Federal Register for notice and comment.</text></clause><clause id="H33CA138426B34296BAA9D9393A3747DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Data collection not subject to notice and comment requirements</header><text>If the Commission has published its assessment plan for notice and comment, specifying the data to be collected and method of collection, at least 30 days prior to adoption of a final regulation or amendment, such collection of data shall not be subject to the notice and comment requirements in section 3506(c) of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Paperwork Reduction Act). Any material modifications of the plan that require collection of data not previously published for notice and comment shall also be exempt from such requirements if the Commission has published notice for comment in the Federal Register of the additional data to be collected, at least 30 days prior to initiation of data collection.</text></clause><clause id="H60DC2FE2D838438AB6E9C83D236D5A4E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Final action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after publication of the assessment report in the Federal Register, the Commission shall issue for notice and comment a proposal to amend or rescind the regulation, or publish a notice that the Commission has determined that no action will be taken on the regulation. Such a notice will be deemed a final agency action.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF0D8CE64F8549ACB2E2A85930043D36"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered regulations and other agency actions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solely as used in this subsection, the term <term>regulation</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HFB07EFA6130C413FB95E45D1BD76A830"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an agency statement of general applicability and future effect that is designed to implement, interpret, or prescribe law or policy or to describe the procedure or practice requirements of an agency, including rules, orders of general applicability, interpretive releases, and other statements of general applicability that the agency intends to have the force and effect of law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE73A43ADC50944A99E486E0DE4011546"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text><clause id="HE31EB54AFD144CB9A4211710824CE16D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a regulation issued in accordance with the formal rulemaking provisions of section 556 or 557 of title 5, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="HC27298E184DB4B738D9CB35C36823A63"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a regulation that is limited to agency organization, management, or personnel matters;</text></clause><clause id="HC8F790333603419E84B89CC3A00606FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a regulation promulgated pursuant to statutory authority that expressly prohibits compliance with this provision; and</text></clause><clause id="HC4E865E55E3943CA99B477FB485F1D1A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a regulation that is certified by the agency to be an emergency action, if such certification is published in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3587EE1EFBFA41019030FFB087E5A499"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to other regulatory entities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of the Congress that the Public Company Accounting Oversight Board should also follow the requirements of section 23(e) of such Act, as added by this title.</text></section><section id="HBC264582F13B49D9AE19F639312EEB7D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Accountability provision relating to other regulatory entities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A rule adopted by the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board or any national securities association registered under section 15A of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o-3">15 U.S.C. 78o–3</external-xref>) shall not take effect unless the Securities and Exchange Commission determines that, in adopting such rule, the Board or association has complied with the requirements of section 23(e) of such Act, as added by section 2, in the same manner as is required by the Commission under such section 23(e).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

