<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB5600AD7B0F4609B7625376D27DCBAF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9031 IH: No Pay for Congressional Recklessness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9031</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To decrease the pay of Members of Congress during any period in which continuing appropriations are in effect, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEFBFEBEFC5CE42F6853E14BAEF95410D" style="OLC"><section id="HC0E8F7C620C7494687A6588B45D48232" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Pay for Congressional Recklessness Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HF42477EBB7D44491B8DB177698543DC8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting use of funds for certain government activities while continuing appropriations are in effect</header><subsection id="HE95F5A03C80448CA9B11902A0D363232"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the period described in <internal-xref idref="H12E45281DA9A4928AE1FC3D9D6CA52F4" legis-path="2.(c)">subsection (c)</internal-xref>, no appropriated funds, including official funds of the House of Representatives, official funds of the Senate, or funds available under any Federal law, rule, or regulation, may be used to pay for the costs of any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H8F0C129E3DCC4FC994F6EEAA0025AAD2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Travel by Members of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Travel by a Member of Congress (except as provided in paragraph (1) of subsection (b)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA79842B3675941A7B5FBB97D7719853B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel by executive branch employees</header><text>Travel by an employee of an executive agency (except as provided in paragraph (2) of subsection (b)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB1E3EFD79E75496C9CDCC693C4625C23"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HAB65D87659EE482D98859F43DC0E0F50"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Travel by Members to Washington Metropolitan Area</header><text><internal-xref idref="HE95F5A03C80448CA9B11902A0D363232" legis-path="2.(a)">Subsection (a)</internal-xref> does not apply with respect to travel by a Member of Congress to the Washington Metropolitan Area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC99F47D72D8C459D9AA94327EF19E48B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waivers in case of emergency or threats to security</header><text>The head of an executive agency may waive the application of <internal-xref idref="HE95F5A03C80448CA9B11902A0D363232" legis-path="2.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref> to travel by an employee of the agency if the head of the agency determines that travel by the employee is necessary to respond to a threat to national security, a significant law enforcement event, or a natural disaster or other similar emergency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12E45281DA9A4928AE1FC3D9D6CA52F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Period described</header><text>The period described in this subsection is the period that—</text><paragraph id="HFD7A7775430144889454BB9C20FFF2B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begins on the 1st day on which a continuing resolution is in effect; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15ACA25ECE9E425B9C8E682F57B15C16"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ends on—</text><subparagraph id="H5423931B7A424366BEB131FDA6A02E3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which appropriations and funds are no longer made available pursuant to a continuing resolution; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA75D14DF49149499F90552FF2055F9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if such appropriations and funds are no longer made available as a result of a Government shutdown, the later of the date such shutdown ends or the date on which appropriations and funds are no longer made available pursuant to a continuing resolution after the date such shutdown ends.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H894FD3768A8F4451B72E08766615E320"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="HD7F45EE1732D4C51B83E937F4C0E829D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given that term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, and includes the Executive Office of the President, the United States Postal Service, and Postal Regulatory Commission, but does not include the Government Accountability Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3986B00D6E741E68D4D3F7BC354A7D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>Washington Metropolitan Area</term> means the District of Columbia, the Counties of Montgomery and Prince George’s in Maryland, and the Counties of Arlington, Fairfax, Loudon, and Prince William and the Cities of Alexandria and Falls Church in Virginia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H842F7FEAE2CB47B680C8C9C87E62755E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Withholding the pay of Members of Congress while continuing appropriations are in effect</header><subsection id="HF0156F1CE24C439B9029B0623C8343BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rule for One Hundred Seventeenth Congress</header><paragraph id="H67A0C976A9254A52BB1286585295DCCF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Holding salaries in escrow</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a pay period occurs during the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress during the period described in paragraph (2), the payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4DFDB6A5B3C9477CA29247E4B8FC3F9A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">deposit in an escrow account and exclude from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to that pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to the product of—</text><clause id="H36A9CE5DC4DA4C51A5923B6C9CC495CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the daily rate of pay of the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H68E8F634E0424135A56CAFDF7EE4030D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of 24-hour periods during the pay period; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBA742B2D06F4062869D1BAE50508E5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>release amounts deposited in an escrow account under subparagraph (A) to such Member of Congress only upon the expiration of the period described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25288973916C4F55BC6340A8369C566D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period described</header><text>The period described in this paragraph is the period that—</text><subparagraph id="H7CCEE85F4AB94D8CA47884B7FE16D24C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begins on the 1st day on which a continuing resolution is in effect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23BB2AB1F9574D09BA45B080188441C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ends on the earlier of—</text><clause id="H5946F61C209A4D498C01D0822220F186"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which appropriations and funds are no longer made available pursuant to a continuing resolution;</text></clause><clause id="HA0428D9647B0490EA7A9B40AE5480218"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if such appropriations and funds are no longer made available as a result of a Government shutdown, the later of the date such shutdown ends or the date on which appropriations and funds are no longer made available pursuant to a continuing resolution after the date such shutdown ends; or</text></clause><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BFDF100E9784BB58CF0E86DE2E0A6FA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the last day of the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AE3198CEC194EBC964D28DA1F83399B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Withholding and remittance of amounts from payments held in escrow</header><text>The payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall provide for the same withholding and remittance with respect to a payment deposited in an escrow account under paragraph (1) that would apply to the payment if the payment were not subject to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7CEBB63261164124822CAD5B3159DDA7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Release of amounts at end of the Congress</header><text>In order to ensure that this subsection is carried out in a manner that shall not vary the compensation of Senators or Representatives in violation of the twenty-seventh amendment to the Constitution of the United States, the payroll administrator of a House of Congress shall release for payment to Members of that House of Congress any amounts remaining in any escrow account under this section on the last day of the One Hundred Seventeenth Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D73B0D8B9FC4CD9B6BDB6B92CF9F149"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subsequent Congresses</header><paragraph id="H4137A827FD6144529A461A687B1A2B77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Withholding salaries</header><text>If a pay period occurs during the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress or any succeeding Congress during the period described in paragraph (2), the payroll administrator of each House of Congress shall exclude from the payments otherwise required to be made with respect to that pay period for the compensation of each Member of Congress who serves in that House of Congress an amount equal to a decrease of 1 percent of the annual rate of basic pay for the Member under section 601(a) of the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/4501">2 U.S.C. 4501</external-xref>) for each day during the pay period on which a continuing resolution is in effect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9B51D812F494BDAB5B7FCA77C099404"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Period described</header><text>The period described in this paragraph is the period that—</text><subparagraph id="H499A7CC3EE3A4BFB87DB7F2443234CF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">begins on the 1st day on which a continuing resolution is in effect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBCD1114FAD249D7863E6DF997EFF46F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ends on—</text><clause id="HF93414E27F2048A898CDD1C7AC202B8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which appropriations and funds are no longer made available pursuant to a continuing resolution; or</text></clause><clause id="HB172BC4C8E9D417483A1DF7A5712BF96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such appropriations and funds are no longer made available as a result of a Government shutdown, the later of the date such shutdown ends or the date on which appropriations and funds are no longer made available pursuant to a continuing resolution after the date such shutdown ends.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A7A9B89AA994C919D1097F15E0AE02A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Role of Secretary of the Treasury</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall provide the payroll administrator of each House of Congress with such assistance as may be necessary to enable the payroll administrator to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE16E6D3C09D846E6897C940DC17185DB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <term>payroll administrator</term>, with respect to a House of Congress, means—</text><paragraph id="H28843BA55DB142E1A0CDCEF27A9D0E11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of the House of Representatives, the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives, or an employee of the Office of the Chief Administrative Officer who is designated by the Chief Administrative Officer to carry out this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D86376AFA3142DCA8CB4BCF312503FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of the Senate, the Secretary of the Senate, or an employee of the Office of the Secretary of the Senate who is designated by the Secretary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFCA190CAC9A442A0B48ACAA48506A3AC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of Government shutdown</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, a Government shutdown shall be considered to be in effect if there is a lapse in appropriations for any Federal agency or department as a result of a failure to enact a regular appropriations bill or continuing resolution.</text></section><section id="H4EC615AD28CD4DAE8E21ED223848084B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H609FB07913C04C0087999BD1B18FF166"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>continuing resolution</term> means, with respect to a fiscal year for which an appropriation measure for the fiscal year is not enacted before the beginning of such fiscal year, a bill or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for any program, project, or activity for which funds were provided in the preceding fiscal year in the amount provided in the corresponding appropriation Act for such preceding fiscal year or, if the corresponding appropriation bill for such preceding fiscal year did not become law, the amount provided in a bill or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such preceding fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AADF7B334D54CCFB7E30A1399F83603"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Member of Congress</term> means a Senator or a Representative in, or Delegate or Resident Commissioner to, the Congress. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

