<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F700FBC1EF14E0EA82F173A7DE67214" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7740 IH: Employee and Retiree Access to Justice Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7740</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220512">May 12, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide that any mandatory predispute or coerced postdispute arbitration clause, class action waiver, representation waiver, or discretionary clause with respect to a plan is unenforceable, to prohibit any such clause or waiver from being included in a plan document or other agreement with plan participants, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H8916EAA36C4A4FB9AF7779665A46652E" style="OLC">
<section id="HC0BF1E763DF941499C0233DEF1D329E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Employee and Retiree Access to Justice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HECFA0A04C61F4CBBB8EA976B334AB84D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unenforceable arbitration clauses, class action waivers, representation waivers, and discretionary clauses</header> <subsection id="HC709908FBE9143B3A67F84108206FABE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 502 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1132">29 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H0D69714E7DB040AAA96861CC7AE3251A" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H0E8E3A9624EF4DD2A205ECFA341C0773"><enum>(n)</enum>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA71FC12233724BA0B76780C223A909BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In any civil action brought by, or on behalf of, a participant or beneficiary pursuant to this section or with respect to a common law claim involving a plan or plan benefit, notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text> <subparagraph id="H79E19851C9A84501B25A2D3535F43ABF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>no predispute arbitration provision shall be valid or enforceable if it requires arbitration of a matter related to a claim brought under this section;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44A07C913CDC4DCE9CDA20B3E6A4EAD0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>no postdispute arbitration provision shall be valid or enforceable unless—</text> <clause id="H855B69FCF0F044C9BFB2A7A5E37F2727"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the provision was not required by any person, obtained by coercion or threat of adverse action, or made a condition of participating in a plan, receiving benefits under a plan, or receiving any other employment, work, or any employment-related or work-related privilege or benefit;</text></clause>
<clause id="H7437D47F46BF4ADABED76EB834253B5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>each participant or beneficiary agreeing to the provision was informed, through a paper notice, in a manner reasonably calculated to be understood by the average plan participant, of the right of the participant or beneficiary under subparagraph (C) to refuse to agree to the provision without retaliation or threat of retaliation;</text></clause> <clause id="H5F3E77343EA744AC8E1F1FE65AF53695"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each participant or beneficiary agreeing to the provision so agreed after a waiting period of not fewer than 45 days, beginning on the date on which the participant or beneficiary was provided both the final text of the provision and the disclosures required under clause (ii); and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC49E0670480A4FFC911411F9FCD04C6F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each participant or beneficiary agreeing to the provision affirmatively consented to the provision in writing;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04D6B281C8154779BDF74669026F3777" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>no covered provision shall be valid or enforceable, if prior to a dispute to which the covered provision applies, a participant or beneficiary undertakes or promises not to pursue, bring, join, litigate, or support any kind of individual, joint, class, representative, or collective claim available under this section in any forum that, but for such covered provision, is of competent jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6AE168C668C946EE9A0BBF5422767300" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no covered provision shall be valid or enforceable, if after a dispute to which the covered provision applies arises, a participant or beneficiary undertakes or promises not to pursue, bring, join, litigate, or support any kind of individual, joint, class, representative, or collective claim under this section in any forum that, but for such covered provision, is of competent jurisdiction, unless the covered provision meets the requirements of subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD387F4D360B5404FB2B0EB61A3535353" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">no covered provision related to a plan other than a multiemployer plan shall be valid or enforceable that purports to confer discretionary authority to any person with respect to benefit determinations or interpretation of plan language, or to provide a standard of review of such determinations or interpretation by a reviewing court in an action brought under this section that would require anything other than de novo review of such determinations or interpretation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC9EF6E3FB21B48F7AE8D335F777FAF40" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB11F66C9C35438C93EBE5647E6FA415"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>covered provision</quote> means any document, instrument, or agreement related to a plan or plan benefit, regardless of whether such provision appears in a plan document or in a separate agreement;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9D310D45912F4946B3D4B1966CC9E9B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>predispute arbitration provision</quote> means a covered provision that requires a participant or beneficiary to arbitrate a dispute related to the plan or an amendment to the plan that had not yet arisen at the time such provision took effect;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC848F3EA135A4425ADA665C16DB07EED"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>postdispute arbitration provision</quote> means a covered provision that requires a participant or beneficiary to arbitrate a dispute related to the plan or an amendment to the plan that arose before the time such provision took effect; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H14B0A66E75BF4365A7BED3DB93389C35"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <quote>retaliation</quote> means any action in violation of section 510.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA6E9C92548E49D58D0820D48668296B" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6D6A03CAD77B442FA375FF772367E6D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any dispute as to whether a covered provision that requires a participant or beneficiary to arbitrate a dispute related to a plan is valid and enforceable shall be determined by a court, rather than an arbitrator, regardless of whether any contractual provision purports to delegate such determinations to the arbitrator and irrespective of whether the party resisting arbitration challenges the arbitration agreement specifically or in conjunction with other terms of the contract containing such agreement.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC065F405D7A14D8E9F0E9FA423945E11" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, a dispute shall be considered to arise only when a plaintiff has actual knowledge (within the meaning of such term in section 413) of a breach or violation giving rise to a claim under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1386E78A6F764BBBBDA42363579EA9A3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Labor may promulgate such regulations as may be necessary to carry out the amendment made by subsection (a), including providing for the form and content of notices required pursuant to such amendment.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H50984E8EE75F4595A3CDEDA077F6B97A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on mandatory arbitration clauses, class action waivers, representation waivers, and discretionary clauses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 402 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1102">29 U.S.C. 1102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HC49499A0B11E4B01AF3B84A3EBE83BE2" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H6EAC6F72BB414A669154450E040CF048"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCFF17982275143959F4872093BFCB85F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No covered person may—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB433D038393744EE9A789FE4BE2F798D" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require participants or beneficiaries to agree to a predispute arbitration provision as a condition for participation in, or receipt of benefits under, a plan;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H388FE9E4183E4BBE8B71CDEE0F1794BC" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to a postdispute arbitration provision with a participant or beneficiary with respect to a plan or plan benefit unless the conditions of clauses (i) through (iv) of section 502(n)(1)(B) are satisfied with respect to such provision; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A673F8132B6458D8A634386B313D82E" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>agree to any other covered provision with respect to a plan or plan benefit under any circumstances under which such provision would not be valid and enforceable under subparagraphs (C) through (E) of section 502(n)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD00D73675484257B6D4B62D970E785F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3540F3D22254404CB77DE7ACD37C87BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <quote>covered person</quote> means—</text> <clause id="HF08104DE1D65496BAC82C3A5CBDD0B9B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a plan;</text></clause>
<clause id="H2DD0BE91B371499E80CADAF9EF0E8A9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a plan sponsor;</text></clause> <clause id="HF2F079A264C6429AAC73597AC033D289"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an employer; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HC2B47F4EF3C84E0EA128C620EDBCC377"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a person engaged by a plan for purposes of administering or operating the plan; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83B3E5F41E4F45D1BECC190A6B0A9C7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <quote>covered provision</quote>, <quote>predispute arbitration provision</quote> and <quote>postdispute arbitration provision</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 502(n)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H26D487B56DE6404AA65B1BF22232136C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header>
<subsection id="HEB2C63B7A5644EE08BD9C3B156173652"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendments made by sections 2 and 3 shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply with respect to any dispute or claim that arises or accrues on or after such date, including any dispute or claim to which a provision predating such date applies, regardless of whether plan documents have been updated in accordance with such amendments.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5E0706C3839844A7A7BDD5D094A849B3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement with respect to plan document updates</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no person shall be deemed to be in violation of such amendments on account of plan documents that have not been updated in accordance with such amendments until after the beginning of the first plan year that begins on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, provided that such person acts in accordance with such amendments during the period in which the plan documents have not been updated.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


