<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H36859044153B4665B7A0030E0EF86C64" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1505 RH: Bonding Reform and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 453</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1505</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–629]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210302">March 2, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H000324">Mr. Hastings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 2, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Mineral Leasing Act to make certain adjustments to the regulation of surface-disturbing activities and to protect taxpayers from unduly bearing the reclamation costs of oil and gas development, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HCE43F8E73FF94692B2C6832BE50705DF"><section id="H476A22BF7123486BBC3AC89C1C333360" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be referred to as the <quote><short-title>Bonding Reform and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2021</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H61B9E4838AA74FA28FB7B71D10FD282B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Surface disturbance and reclamation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 17(g) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/226">30 U.S.C. 226(g)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H331FF71B4ED44BC9934FDB14E9089679" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="HCAA9782F8165422D906B471471796C97"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Bonding requirements</header><paragraph id="HD9C0B6EF4E014F00A28DAE919DBBE28A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H7B1FEE5C80DE4A61A9DF71677B4F4BE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Interim reclamation plan</header><text>The term <term>Interim Reclamation Plan</term> means an ongoing plan specifying reclamation steps to be taken on all disturbed areas covered by any lease issued under this Act that are not needed for active operations. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DC15A1671894A499B9CDA0AC72375D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final reclamation plan</header><text>The term <term>Final Reclamation Plan</term> means a plan describing all reclamation activity to be conducted for all disturbed areas, including locations, facilities, trenches, rights-of-way, roads, and any other surface disturbance covered by a lease issued under this Act prior to final abandonment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1BDAACBBB904D548216FCB87CFF1968"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Operator</header><text>The term <quote>operator</quote> means, with respect to an oil or gas operation, any entity, including the lessee or operating rights owner, that has stated in writing to a relevant authority that such entity is responsible for any portion of such operation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BFB0AAAFF8F4E9DB66304572F2ED727"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text><clause id="H329E98366B5D40AABDFFB67D617B96F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior for public lands administered by such Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="H20C5C5D979CC461983D888FAA80F3656"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture for forest service lands.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9851DDBA7D3749C7B7F46D0F4549E039"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall regulate all surface-disturbing activities conducted pursuant to any lease issued under this Act, and shall determine reclamation and other actions as required in the interest of conservation of surface resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38DBAD28823F4542A63118E780DFE9A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reclamation plans required</header><subparagraph id="HFF338260F5DA49C1802ECB4999FA0841"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Analysis and approval required</header><text>No permit to drill on an oil and gas lease issued under this Act may be granted without the analysis and approval by the Secretary concerned of both an interim reclamation plan and a final reclamation plan covering proposed surface-disturbing activities within the lease area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFD1D2C202D54F70A3E5F5730BF3109C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plans of operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All Federal plans or permits submitted pursuant to this Act with the potential to create surface disturbance shall include an Interim and Final Reclamation Plan. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FFD8B7A93644AA081D968BE5BBD9438"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Secretarial Review</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall review each Interim Reclamation Plan at regular intervals and shall require such plans to be amended as warranted, subject to the approval of such Secretary. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3079C15BC724295A7681804088DB223"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Bonding</header><subparagraph id="H066F2296061149F48770FCFA8002435B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="H6E4C071F979945F4A760B4B7AA3C8A2C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Regulation</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bonding Reform and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2021</short-title>, the Secretary concerned shall, by regulation, require that an adequate bond, surety, or other financial arrangement be established prior to the commencement of surface-disturbing activities on any lease under this Act.</text></clause><clause id="H9D14D77F5EF54B94A838347EDE8E1F2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Amount of bond</header><text>In determining the adequacy of a bond, surety, or other financial instrument required by regulation under clause (i), the Secretary shall find that such arrangement is adequate if it is not less than the greater of—</text><subclause id="HB286647353F74A7091B784133169F1FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount necessary for—</text><item id="H8C1FD2C3A799452D845625F97AD50F21"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the complete and timely reclamation of the lease tract;</text></item><item id="H701E5DE4AB9847F08BEB8C6B5D903037"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the restoration of any lands or surface waters adversely affected by lease operations after the abandonment or cessation of oil and gas operations on the lease; or</text></item><item id="H277D2D7FB91E4183975896F65D39B6E7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>in the case of an idled well, the total plugging and reclamation costs for each idled well controlled by the same operator; </text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB2703A4C86004189995928404D9734E8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>$150,000 in the case of an arrangement for an individual surface-disturbing activity of each entity on an oil or gas lease; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1A12791C1ACF4A20A35619551FE4C362"><enum>(III)</enum><text>$500,000 in the case of an arrangement for all surface-disturbing activities of each entity in a State.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H41711D1950BE450C9C3BE3448FFFE9F9"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><subclause id="H8931B5796FFC41C5B859FB4FC019F39D"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the application of clause (ii), the Secretaries concerned shall jointly at least once every three years, at the beginning of the fiscal year, adjust the dollar amounts in clause (ii) to account for inflation based on the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumer published by the Department of Labor.</text></subclause><subclause id="H9DDD64ACB31E41FD8DE6D8242EDEA71C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If any amount as adjusted under subclause (I) is not a multiple of $1,000, such amount shall be rounded to the next higher multiple of $1000.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED05498344C1484BAB0F3E63FE447D13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not issue or approve the assignment of any lease under the terms of this section to any person, association, corporation, or any subsidiary, affiliate, or person controlled by or under common control with such person, association, or corporation, during any period in which, as determined by the relevant Secretary, such entity has failed or refused to comply in any material respect with the reclamation requirements and other standards established under this section for any prior lease to which such requirements and standards applied.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6AA0FF56F55466AB30ED57DE4FE0FC2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notice and opportunity for compliance</header><text>Prior to making a determination not to issue or approve the assignment of a lease under subparagraph (B) with respect to an entity the Secretary concerned shall provide such entity with adequate notification and an opportunity to comply with such reclamation requirements and other standards and shall consider whether any administrative or judicial appeal is pending. Once the entity has complied with the reclamation requirement or other standard concerned each oil or gas lease may be issued to such entity under this Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DB22CFCF0E2474893F70D82CEA318A0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Review upon transfer</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall review the adequacy of a bond, surety, or other financial instrument anytime a lease or well under this Act is transferred. The Secretary shall find such bond, surety, or other financial instrument adequate if such arrangement—</text><clause id="H5A7CE84511A141E3B7D6F20E3BF4CA23"><enum>(i)</enum><text>meets the requirement described in subparagraph (A)(ii); and</text></clause><clause id="H2F2A9AEB9FA14376831A5063B797CA1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not for a lesser amount than the amount maintained by the current operator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD145E353FE224A4F847A108C3B158A73"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Requiring higher bond amounts</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall, at any time that such Secretary determines that a bond, surety, or other financial instrument required by a regulation issued pursuant to subparagraph (A) no longer meets the requirements of clause (ii) of such subparagraph, increase the required amount of such financial arrangement to the level required by subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B9D9139F92247C990DA95F65EF6E003"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Phasing-in bond increases</header><text>With respect to a bond increased under subparagraph (E), the Secretary concerned shall require the operator to meet the following deadlines in posting the amount of the increase that results from the operation of such paragraph:</text><clause id="H2B5087E86D0A43E9BAE173DA23FF778A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>25 percent of the increase by not later than 1 year after the date on which the determination was made under subparagraph (D).</text></clause><clause id="HB83165DEFC7840CA906EDA0AA72BBA86"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>75 percent of the increase by not later than 2 years after such date.</text></clause><clause id="H67D0015BAE894D939EE9DE780F6699FD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>100 percent of the increase by not later than 3 years after such date.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7825428A6AE34ED5B0E7F90EBD497D34"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Bonding Reform and Taxpayer Protection Act of 2021</short-title>, the Secretary of the Interior and the Secretary of Agriculture shall, by regulation, establish uniform standards for all Interim and Final Reclamation Plans. The goal of such plans shall be the restoration of the affected ecosystem to a condition approximating or equal to that which existed prior to the surface disturbance. Such standards shall include restoration of natural vegetation and hydrology, habitat restoration, salvage, storage and reuse of topsoils, erosion control, control of invasive species and noxious weeds and natural contouring.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF52078C879B548CAA2E09B34159CFAB7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not approve final abandonment and shall not release any bond required by this Act until the standards and requirement for final reclamation established pursuant to this Act have been met.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A80809EF9B540EB90F90D4BF702B02D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Financial assurances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary concerned shall not release the financial assurance established for a lease until the operator has paid the inspection fees required under section 4 for the lease covered by the financial assurance instrument.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98558A7A02034A48AE75781AB6A14C3A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Bond Adequacy Review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct bond adequacy reviews as required under paragraph (4)(D) in accordance with Bureau of Land Management Instruction Memorandum No. 2019-014, dated November 15, 2018.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H923CB870F3E547209D9BA17423B1B9C8"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Orphaned well fee</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall collect a per barrel of oil equivalent fee of not less than $0.10 on oil and gas produced from Federal lands for the use of plugging and reclamation of orphaned wells.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HCAC2BE46319649ADB1616F227ADA5DC4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Changes to the BLM Permit Processing Improvement Fund</header><subsection id="H90861BE269B94C6EBEF806B77881175E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Name of fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 35(c)(2)(B) of the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/191">30 U.S.C. 191(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>BLM Permit Processing Improvement Fund</quote> and inserting <quote>BLM Administration and Accountability Fund</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H21C708CBCDA64BDD8EB246DBFF4ADDAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 35(c)(3)(A) of such Act (30 191(c)(3)(A)) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6CE4D533F2AF4808914726DBF07498B2" display-inline="yes-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><text>Such coordination and processing shall include—</text><clause id="HA440C127207C4FBAA122F677D2E48071"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the coordination and review process for financial assurances for oil and gas leases and bond releases for oil and gas leases;</text></clause><clause id="HC2CE3E1C60EE4C91BE0315046DBF9B6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the inventory of orphaned wells and coordinate the processing of requests for delays in the permanent closure of inactive wells; and</text></clause><clause id="H89E00BEA33304734AC0B04C8038FD4F5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>coordination and processing related to environmental and cultural resources reviews applicable to oil and gas activities.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H4A51482CE8B142C2958D35D11D130D89"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inspection fees</header><subsection id="H44F55F3268394F8199ECA866FF38A052"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 108 of the Federal Oil and Gas Royalty Management Act of 1982 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1718">30 U.S.C. 1718</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H449D3A95A10D42CCBC3611AF05CE7AA7" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H1907FDEC50BA4A6A8BD36B1465587DD3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inspection fees</header><paragraph id="HF28BB42993564DB68EE901A63F31DA8E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (5), the designated operator under each oil and gas lease on Federal or Indian lands, or each unit and communitization agreement that includes one or more such Federal or Indian leases, that is subject to inspection under subsection (b) and that is in force at the start of the fiscal year 2021, shall pay a nonrefundable annual inspection fee in an amount that, except as provided in paragraph (2), is established by the Secretary by regulation and is sufficient to recover the full costs incurred by the United States for inspection and enforcement with respect to such leases. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7190DF44A341469696EE5A547F664606"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>Until the effective date of regulations under paragraph (1), the amount of the fee shall be—</text><subparagraph id="HA524DD81102B4272A5631F35B238A156"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$700 for each lease or unit or communitization agreement with no active or inactive wells, but with surface use, disturbance or reclamation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0CDFDFBCCF54E568D723492F17A088B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$1,225 for each lease or unit or communitization agreement with 1 to 10 wells, with any combination of active or inactive wells;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H805A9ECE28244F67AE6DCE143986F33E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$4,900 for each lease or unit or communitization agreement with 11 to 50 wells, with any combination of active or inactive wells; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9270AF73F654E47B34D4642B1F067DC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$9,800 for each lease or unit or communitization agreement with more than 50 wells, with any combination of active or inactive wells.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3B09B5B65164361B232BA250FE4D74B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Due date</header><text>Payment of the fee under this section shall be due, annually, not later than 30 days after the Secretary provides notice of the assessment of the fee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D37C02E5B874E39BA3DB5373187BB40"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>If the designated operator fails to pay the full amount of the fee as prescribed in this section, the Secretary may, in addition to utilizing any other applicable enforcement authority, assess civil penalties against the operator under section 109 in the same manner as if this section were a mineral leasing law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6D1E431E1741A6B10A4FB9945F6ED6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exemption for Tribal operators</header><text>An operator that is a Tribe or is controlled by a Tribe is not subject to paragraph (1) with respect to a lease, unit, or communitization agreement that is located entirely on the lands of such Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA035D6A169DD4A51AA047092F4E5B515"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the application of paragraph (2), the Secretaries shall at least once every three years, at the beginning of the fiscal year, adjust the dollar amounts in paragraph (2) to account for inflation based on the Consumer Price Index for all urban consumer published by the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA5775C8356E348FA827AD97510D7245F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment for fiscal year <enum-in-header>2022</enum-in-header></header><text>The Secretary of the Interior shall assess the fee under the amendment made by subsection (a) for fiscal year 2022, and provide notice of such assessment to each designated operator who is liable for such fee, by not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9D1792F899A64DD0BF79E5BCDE0C9962"><enum>5.</enum><header>Bonding Equity for National Wildlife Refuge System Lands</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4 of the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5D297467A91C46959DBEAC27FBA25879"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (h) through (o), as subsections (i) through (p), respectively; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4146DD76C3584685A0161D868828DE44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (g) the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC5F4ADC8A25649D69BA6EC2DE7B956FB" display-inline="no-display-inline" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HII00"><subsection id="H661C588C8CD64904AB7890A761147E77"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reclamation, Damages, and Financial Assurance for oil and gas operations on Refuge Lands</header><paragraph id="H82D5ECCF50944B52BAE3F7E4111A8741"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall obtain adequate financial assurances from non-Federal entities to repair potential damages to refuge resources, prior to the commencement of surface-disturbing activities as part of the development of non-Federal minerals below refuge surface estate, including—</text><subparagraph id="H8ECBC52344EE4D828E9A07B581AA48D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure the complete and timely reclamation of the land, and the restoration of any lands or surface waters adversely affected by operations after the abandonment or cessation of oil and gas operations on the land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38DAE821324E44DDBF9378540027E1DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to meet potential response and assessment costs and other damages to refuge resources as a result of oil and gas operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7F4EAB95592475093EB17E4E2C2F6B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Financial assurances forfeited by a non-Federal entity under this subsection shall be retained and available to the Secretary, without further appropriation, and shall remain available until expended, for—</text><subparagraph id="HFF1B8779D9AF4E1090F130586AF7B901"><enum>(A)</enum><text>plugging and abandoning wells;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04A2CB9E8A324B43AE5B8555DDB79637"><enum>(B)</enum><text>removing structures, equipment, materials, and other infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F0D947B6C5C4E0FB9027D0C563DC81F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>response costs and damage assessments conducted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6314A61E3D142D79021DAC3AB23D21A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>restoration, replacement, or acquisition of the equivalent refuge resources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48221B79519949009AE27A32C8B2D172"><enum>(E)</enum><text>monitoring and studying affected refuge resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

