<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFC7385524077488D904ABE8C9E084E4E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7801 IH: To amend the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to allow the Secretary of Commerce to establish a Coastal and Estuarine Resilience and Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7801</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220517">May 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 to allow the Secretary of Commerce to establish a Coastal and Estuarine Resilience and Restoration Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAE2CCCAA8C5B453EA3EE48B088533E9E" style="OLC"><section id="H3C9A0E89931F420FB33DAC2207CF34BD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Coastal and Estuarine Resilience and Restoration Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 307A of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1456-1">16 U.S.C. 1456–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFBC095AA3A444811A4B91F3943C964EB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking the heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="traditional">Coastal and Estuarine Resilience and Restoration Program</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87A3DF1C65604B948DDF9C7C83268C62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H482EEDA67311452A99CFF87A11D5BEA7" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7882199CBF16496E9748FCB800FF094E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may conduct a Coastal and Estuarine Resilience and Restoration Program, in cooperation with State, regional, and other units of government and the National Estuarine Research Reserves, for the purposes of—</text><paragraph id="HAAFA78BE6CD4448E9AE941121CCC8D8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>protecting important coastal and estuarine areas that—</text><subparagraph id="H7019A4102008436C9E0521B9D8B08C6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have significant conservation, recreation, coastal access, ecological, historical, or aesthetic value;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H280E770FA6134AC99F9C387354DF8069"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are threatened by conversion from their natural, undeveloped, or recreational state to other uses; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7FDA20D0D9B4C9189E173420D2CDD5D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>could be managed or restored to effectively conserve, enhance, or restore ecological function or mitigate climate change; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBD82B6700B3402E83DCDB51288BBECE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">restoring developed property in vulnerable coastal and estuarine areas to a natural state to restore ecological function, allow for shoreline migration, and protect coastal communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA0B2827DF0C46799F1327FA88CEA2DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HA835EA5E319441EA9CE5F7DAE56BF047"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (7) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H8FA8CD1464884BBF8D6AF6DC5FFD8244" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HD57A16B0014644ADBB4CD2CF8F7EB760"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Priority shall be given to lands that—</text><subparagraph id="H409F23F728D84AC78AC4791151E420C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">can be effectively managed and protected and that have significant recreation, ecological, historical, cultural, aesthetic, or community protection value;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D1BE0681F73461D876C9B266F8167D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the maximum extent practicable, benefit communities that may not have adequate resources to prepare for or respond to coastal hazards or to access coastline, including low-income communities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A0D84B1D84A4C499A9CF1B3F6C6C5BD"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1D5BED470A574986BC9D97C83F73C94E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are under an imminent threat of conversion to a use that will degrade or otherwise diminish their natural, undeveloped, or recreational state;</text></clause><clause id="H81EE3D49E3E04337B5BADB6A242A12B1" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>serve to mitigate the adverse impacts caused by coastal population growth in the coastal environment;</text></clause><clause id="H1F8033FDBC714EA2950EC98D57334B1E" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>are within or adjacent to a national estuarine research reserve designated under section 315, a national wildlife refuge, or a national estuary program, or are proposed for designation as such a reserve or other such protected area; or</text></clause><clause id="H94C66B35FE4D401BA8965F2B9938967C" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are under threat due to climate change or may serve to mitigate the adverse effects of climate change, including through the storage of blue carbon, and to facilitate inland migration of coastal ecosystems in response to sea level rise.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58D818A65E904370B28F25675ED43E1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), by striking <quote>triennially</quote> and inserting <quote>every 5 years</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4B86EA7FF194B8BACFAF4C2A5790441"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text><subparagraph id="H979CCD73664F46C3854794DCC5B44805"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(B), by inserting <quote>for any territory of the United States that is unable to provide such match,</quote> after <quote>community,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BFF720F1BBC49E6A494CAEEFC736EFC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><clause id="H86097DFCDFC8428998312BBBEEE78CFF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i), by striking <quote>meets the criteria set forth in section 2(b)</quote> and inserting <quote>the goals set forth in subsection (b)</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H6C2711FAF58044E2AB409223D7B7FA8F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking subparagraph (B) and redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B);</text></clause><clause id="H7237B97C734C40F88E9A98DE1B35F19E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) (as so redesignated), by striking <quote>described in (A)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in subparagraph (A)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H765726EE653E4CD583F0BBD9E2EDA991" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H223D0DBFADE5447CBAE3EBFA9AF41122" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HC6BF4CA1444A4483AD9E8D95251FF614" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The value of ecosystem services that the acquired land provides, including as a buffer for storm surge, habitat for economically valuable species, and as blue carbon sink.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA51E5B0C6969449FB4F9AC053DABCD5D"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (g), by striking <quote>15</quote> and inserting <quote>20</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H713F9536A9384F839641EB9A88D1A74E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking the second sentence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B0A612F1C8E404FBE4728165FA78251"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (l), by striking <quote>fiscal years 2009 through 2013</quote> and inserting <quote>fiscal years 2022 through 2026</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5862BF3D7DCD400FA570DEBC39DFC2FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to National Estuarine Research Reserve System program</header><subsection id="HDE8167D7E5254AFD9E9DDB0ADB8585CE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of additional reserves</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall designate not less than 5 new national estuarine reserves under section 315 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1461">16 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref>). In making such designations, the Administrator shall prioritize designations to achieve the following with respect to the National Estuarine Research Reserve System:</text><paragraph id="HE9D3BB3417C74F6EB48B6D5DA8077FC2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Full representation of biogeographic regions, States, and Territories.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14720E822912452397EC71D7A1A0E092"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The presence of a national estuarine reserve in each coastal State or Territory (as that term is defined in that Act).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0970E9D2D4BF4BDABC9CA2D581FF9FAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidelines for tracking and modeling the impacts of climate change</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 315(c) of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1461">16 U.S.C. 1461(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3607EB01D61C4B469B19C3542A5FB220"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating paragraphs (3) through (5) as paragraphs (4) through (6); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE59BB0A1231141BA84E3C6C516187B40"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="HCD964E266A114D0EBEDB4A1FA56D6905" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE516A7A7D73947F48C93C5927C0C6582"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the establishment of coordinated long-term data monitoring and methods throughout the System for tracking and modeling the impacts of climate change on estuarine systems, including impacts on lake levels and sea levels;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD99B6EBDF69C4139997E9B325CE83D5D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Land acquisition and construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 315 of the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1461">16 U.S.C. 1461</external-xref>) is amended by striking (g) and adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="traditional" id="H1A3A030A81BE45C6BAFB42EE1EF7FDFC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3217FC148195466997F951403E7A3BD0"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Land Acquisition and construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may use funds authorized under section 318 for land acquisition and the construction and renovations of facilities required to meet delivery of System programs and services, or to meet changing needs of program under this title. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEA687FEAFC464179A24EAFC4AFB0B0FA" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Requirements for use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In using funds under subsection (g), the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H4755127A5BEB4A9EB739CE69171CA2AE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide science-based information and technical assistance to coastal stakeholders and decisionmakers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53C5DB3E6F9646F9A11C4E053B360690" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>leverage the capabilities of nationwide protected area networks to address challenging coastal management issues such as climate change and vulnerability of coastal ecosystems and communities to coastal hazards;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF50E02EAFFD463F9CB4159C0D0E9C56" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serve as living laboratories and preferred places for National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration research and fellowships on coastal and estuarine systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75781B9380AE41D58013876967C0A02C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>serve as critical sentinel sites for detecting environmental change and developing and demonstrating adaptation and mitigation strategies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BF12ACD9D384329B555C40353610783" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify priority places for land acquisition, especially those lands required to enhance resilience to environmental change; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14DA17E4EB1F45DE8F084ABF3AA4CC4D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>engage coastal communities, stakeholders, and the public in education programs to increase scientific literacy of coastal environments, and to develop and train capable environmental stewards.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8132C9C2EE04E27A9EC804B55A2419B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Systemwide Elements of the National Estuarine Research Reserve System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall coordinate systemwide programs and activities in the System including—</text><paragraph id="H8BF59950B263424983254065D4076ADC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the centralized management and dissemination of data from System observation and monitoring networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD79D2091825A4E0394F5617FF1F2BBAD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a competitive grant program employing the collaborative research model on coastal research and management priorities to be conducted at research reserve sites focused on the priorities determined by the Secretary; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5667E40A3A1D4594A4781153C486E003" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establish the Margaret A. Davidson Graduate Research Fellowship Program to address key coastal management questions and the coastal research and management priorities of the Reserve System and its place-based sites to help scientists and communities understand the coastal challenges that may influence future policy and management strategies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H093DE2B6A7ED47C8837129D095260F4F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Place-Based Program Elements of the National Estuarine Research Reserve System</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each National Estuarine Research Reserve shall establish and maintain place-based program elements that include—</text><paragraph id="HD1EC993A3B974D27BA61BE45EB7DDA75"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a research, monitoring, and observation network that detects environmental change and informs suitable adaptation and mitigation strategies where appropriate, and that supports systemwide activities stated in subsection (e);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15278F5D7538426196CDEC873B60A234"><enum>(2)</enum><text>education, outreach, and interpretive programs that communicate the value and changing dynamics of coastal systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE939E0AE641648DA907EF06F219AE415"><enum>(3)</enum><text>stewardship programs that provide science-based tools, habitat management, and restoration and that provide resources and information to inform coastal management;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF415589442B84E5D9A1079BF83F5699D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coastal training programs that provide technical assistance to coastal communities, resource managers, and coastal decisionmakers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9A50ABA5E3C4407A0CACF3B8EB9CAD1" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the lands and facilities that support such accessible research, monitoring, stewardship, education, and coastal training activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB32642DF218E4A46BB6510FC368580F5"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $47,000,000 for each of fiscal year 2022 through 2026 to provide financial assistance under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8E20C550001942539BC64F8DD9064FB0"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="HFC8FF8874B4E421A96F10C444B95ACE6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collaborative research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>collaborative research</term> means the engagement of local decisionmakers and stakeholders directly in the research process so that their knowledge and needs will inform research questions, data analysis, and use of the products generated by the research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C199E62F644D7FA69A69540B0C5E58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sentinel site</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sentinel site</term> means a site with long-term research and monitoring capability to detect, document, and respond to emerging environmental changes that impact natural and human systems. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

