<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H38F247BFEACD4B6580305CA63BB8F5D6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6916 IH: Ending Dependence on Russian Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6916</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220303">March 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000061">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Keystone XL Pipeline and direct the President to take certain actions relating to the importation into the United States from Russia, and the exportation from the United States, of oil and gas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF10F0D1470FC48158D9DC91764973B17" style="OLC"><section id="HFFBE886EAB18491987121E6F647B6141" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ending Dependence on Russian Energy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC163BDC49D3345359F7F21ABBDDAFD44"><enum>2.</enum><header>Keystone XL Pipeline authorization; importation and exportation of oil and gas</header><subsection id="H0B34FAE706D141C292DD91A7E37EE060"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Keystone XL Pipeline authorization</header><paragraph id="H3CEDA801C7954A9C98ED10FE20706FBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P., may construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline facilities at the international border of the United States and Canada at Phillips County, Montana, for the import of oil from Canada to the United States described in the Presidential Permit of March 29, 2019 (84 Fed. Reg. 13101).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCAB0B56051D46EB847FA34B818B3599"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No Presidential permit required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Presidential permit (or similar permit) under any Executive order shall be required for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of the pipeline facilities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA08940C795A7493FA14EF11EE9B41BC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on importation from Russia of oil and gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall prohibit the importation of any oil or natural gas originating from Russia into the customs territory of the United States (as such term is defined in General Note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7418674E076F4BCF8B845EFAFDA1240E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduced restrictions on exportation from United States of oil and gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, the President shall seek to reduce restrictions on the exportation of any oil or natural gas originating from the United States.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

