<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HA1A13900941F4F0FBC25AAB729F1B987" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 6267 ENR: To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 15 Chestnut Street in Suffern, New York, as the “Sergeant Gerald T. Jerry Donnellan Post Office”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6267</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To designate the facility of the United States Postal Service located at 15 Chestnut Street in Suffern, New York, as the <quote>Sergeant Gerald T. <quote>Jerry</quote> Donnellan Post Office</quote>.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCB570890C7754771BCA24C6552B8301C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD13DAB6A55C04D42A70A32364062308F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Sergeant Gerald T. <quote>Jerry</quote> Donnellan Post Office</header> 
<subsection id="H089311C80ABE4C4B825D0338349964BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility of the United States Postal Service located at 15 Chestnut Street in Suffern, New York, shall be known and designated as the <quote>Sergeant Gerald T. <quote>Jerry</quote> Donnellan Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8323291598B3428FA079102FA2C79271"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the facility referred to in subsection (a) shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Sergeant Gerald T. <quote>Jerry</quote> Donnellan Post Office</quote>.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


