<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7091FAD120B14A7490195E2E7321177A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9424 IH: Creating Access to Residency Education Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9424</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221205">December 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants for graduate medical education partnerships in States with a low ratio of medical residents relative to the general population.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H30EC07CA03024DBB8E08939468708042" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6364BD7F8B064DD59F29BA0408240E02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Creating Access to Residency Education Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H48BD58EFE8E2496B93C27580172E849A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Graduate medical education partnerships in States with a low ratio of medical residents relative to general population</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317U (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-23">42 U.S.C. 247b–23</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HD75B70775E9F4D3791B39EEFCBB8CB85" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H63841FBC9F284AB5B3B76A3B81D7498E"><enum>317V.</enum><header>Graduate medical education partnerships in States with a low ratio of medical residents relative to general population</header> 
<subsection id="HB48BC07B4CA040858C245ABDEE6C021A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Administrator</quote>) shall make grants to, or enter into contracts with, eligible entities to support the creation of new medical residency training programs or slots within existing programs in States in which there is a low ratio of medical residents relative to the general population.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34A5141290CB492BB11C79FDBABAB9F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive Federal funding under this section, an entity must—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7AED4037ADA44278C4492A3375D1D08"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be located in a State in which there are fewer than 44 medical residents per population of 100,000; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H639FB8E309B14E41B7DFA11821C14880"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be a public or nonprofit teaching hospital or an accredited graduate medical education training program.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC62B23D9CA3141CD86C70FCEA27AFE3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In supporting the creation of new medical residency training programs or slots through a grant or contract under this section, an eligible entity may enter into a partnership with a State, local government, community health center, local health department, hospital, or other organization deemed by the entity to be appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HBD3C4A1FA6444855B04B95B78116E1B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Matching funds</header><text>An agreement awarding a grant or contract under this section shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF979F8182E5F4B1B865E0A9E66F1A61C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of a new or existing medical residency training program in the field of primary care—</text> <subparagraph id="H8A436D1585EA4682BF063F6A4B4FA69F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require the entity awarded such grant or contract to provide one-third of the cost of the slots to be funded through the agreement; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB5D4E7CF1014AA1B682404815764313"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent and in the amounts made available in advance in appropriations Acts, require the Administrator to provide the remaining two-thirds of the cost of such slots; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9333F4A20B114445B159DFC47CD842D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of a new or existing medical residency training program in any other field—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H996ACEE3D50241F98BB6C13C775485F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require the award recipient to provide one-half of the cost of the slots to be funded through the agreement; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H545DA7521BB84DEF9AD2DADDF43CB2A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent and in the amounts made available in advance in appropriations Acts, require the Administrator to provide the remaining one-half of the cost of such slots.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6FD2ED54C2DE45F589CCA5A0AF5E5D96"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Administrator shall establish application processes for eligible entities to receive funding under this section, including multiyear commitments to ensure the continued funding of graduate medical education slots for residents in training.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H957B2EE7518F4685A2B3187CA751727C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the Administrator shall define the term <term>primary care</term>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB563A3D124764E899DFD0EC750BF4FA6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

