<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F6D5C9C34CB4DADAF054B01EEA0B4CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7669 IH: Drug Shortages Shelf Life Extension Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7669</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220506">May 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require guidance on extending expiration dates for certain drugs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA7324FBEE2B646B7948130D740A6D88B" style="OLC">
<section id="H94DDEB982AFA4B93806BDBAE6DBBDA2D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Drug Shortages Shelf Life Extension Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB47F140B64F94B72A436A4F9405E06F7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extending expiration dates for certain drugs</header> <subsection id="H184BF6B418F440B5A67C1656E247379B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall issue draft guidance, or revise existing guidance, to address recommendations for sponsors of applications submitted under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/355">21 U.S.C. 355</external-xref>) or section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) regarding—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE40216C2EAEE46A3A3F33C883213B8A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the submission of stability testing data in such applications, including considerations for data requirements that could be streamlined or reduced to facilitate faster review of longer proposed expiration dates; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H811424930AEE4FEA933BD3AFBEC235E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing in the labeling of drugs the longest feasible expiration date scientifically supported by such data, taking into consideration how extended expiration dates may—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3121F8B3A8BF418B8F8211C5D47BE365"><enum>(A)</enum><text>help prevent or mitigate drug shortages; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA59E28D57D65433C88632DDEA0B1990E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affect product quality; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H367F6C7A721443F0A06662DB5A97102A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use of innovative approaches for drug and combination product stability modeling to support initial product expiration dates and expiration date extensions.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9244A1EDB6B24BC185A4EE7D4A11654B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and again 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7E10739EEB9A485FAC3886D25EBF9579"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of drugs for which the Secretary has requested the manufacturer make a labeling change regarding the expiration date; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF07977BDC8A4B2F86C999699B6483D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for each drug for which the Secretary has requested a labeling change with respect to the expiration date, information regarding the circumstances of such request, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H54F643BD888841279741AF322E9E1996"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and dose of such drug;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68C3EAD34F9C4BBA8E4A8E533280B828"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the rationale for the request;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA207482DEA204552A2515B8ECBBF908D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the drug, at the time of the request, was listed on the drug shortage list under section 506E of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/356e">21 U.S.C. 356e</external-xref>), or was at risk of shortage;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB4D580DEAF84F7988413EE6373687EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the request was made during a public health emergency declared under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48ECDABFC66F4133AE9E92035D8A9B8C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the manufacturer made the requested change by the requested date, and for instances where the manufacturer does not make the requested change, the manufacturer’s justification for not making the change, if the manufacturer agrees to provide such justification for inclusion in the report. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

