<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H373FD205AF7E41D4876790FD60543402" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7991 IH: Keeping Russia’s Energy and Military Liable for Invading its Neighbors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7991</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220608">June 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit contracting with persons that have business operations with the Government of the Russian Federation or the Russian energy sector, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H436BE399D52E4BE2B8266E681E669644" style="OLC"><section id="H6529432D2FDB40CDBE1EED6DE62EE692" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Keeping Russia’s Energy and Military Liable for Invading its Neighbors Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>KREMLIN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H87B2C198C0D045D694A1CF22A633BEB7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on contracting with persons that have business operations with the Government of the Russian Federation or the Russian energy sector</header><subsection id="HC4AA69D95AB44E23865F62E396BBAD51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided under subsections (b), (c), and (d), the head of an executive agency may not enter into a contract for the procurement of goods or services with any person that has business operations with—</text><paragraph id="H4E148B2F3CB3406DAEDF757437463428"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an authority of the Government of the Russian Federation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H031566C8EDEA4C58BCD8F1BEF572F5BB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a fossil fuel company that operates in the Russian Federation, except if the fossil fuel company transports oil or gas—</text><subparagraph id="H7CA3014E227940BFA53F3ED25EF3A5B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through the Russian Federation for sale outside of the Russian Federation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F70A1DBB24D4AF08C354BE2B27887BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that was extracted from a country other than the Russian Federation with respect to the energy sector of which the President has not imposed sanctions as of the date on which the contract is awarded.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBA33E628898C4DBD9DF3B8C65533D597"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HEA1C5471B849493B8516137C7AAE0C06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) does not apply to a contract that the head of an executive agency and the Secretary of State jointly determine—</text><subparagraph id="H15940A611F694925B0D906F0C300CDA6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is necessary—</text><clause id="HF45A06D6ACCF4CA9A1EB7C74B5B9DF02"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of providing humanitarian assistance to the people of Russia; or</text></clause><clause id="H2730255ED1414A988FA5B3A1D6B0A6F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of providing disaster relief and other urgent life-saving measures; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC20F0BDF916548AB8CEFB8D656EAD588"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17641AF75E6E4C8A84418A34CE9AC0B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of an executive agency shall notify the appropriate congressional committees of any contract entered into on the basis of an exception provided for under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB13E01928F34423EB4C02A8F99E2E189" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Office of foreign assets control licenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to a person or entity that has a valid license to operate in Russia issued by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury or is otherwise authorized to operate notwithstanding the imposition of sanctions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2466C4C31EC34E4F9CA658D70102F65A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>American diplomatic mission in Russia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to contracts related to the operation and maintenance of the United States Government’s consular offices and diplomatic posts in Russia.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D332120CA7949AC9B376B59581890A9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and apply with respect to any contract entered into on or after such effective date.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5912C240D7A84F01B7A292C8326C2C9E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall terminate on the date on which the President submits to the appropriate congressional committees a certification in writing that contains a determination of the President that the Russian Federation—</text><paragraph id="H177C375D37C540B1815FB057B93E558C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has reached an agreement relating to the withdrawal of Russian forces and cessation of military hostilities that is accepted by the free and independent Government of Ukraine; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78875BB4E37748159EBA85E15176CB98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>poses no immediate military threat of aggression to any North Atlantic Treaty Organization member; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7779F77943FF41C0B4E11379FB5629DB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recognizes the right of the people of Ukraine to independently and freely choose their own government.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8B0E79BC52146BB8ECB9182ED969904"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H50C3A8C624D4444DB28411E9423C68DA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA1B5F349C5D940939CE094B1E264E334"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Oversight and Reform, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3154674203634854908520E0334AB848" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86863E9EADA2452B9E08D3D083F2A778"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Business operations</header><text>The term <term>business operations</term> means engaging in commerce in any form, including acquiring, developing, maintaining, owning, selling, possessing, leasing, or operating equipment, facilities, personnel, products, services, personal property, real property, or any other apparatus of business or commerce. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37311DFE86C14508A26C0F744C4D0F39"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3958DDD337C473D9C11D5908460130F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fossil fuel company</header><text>The term <term>fossil fuel company</term> means a person that—</text><subparagraph id="HA037D4AFA10D495F8DED94B403940314"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carries out oil, gas, or coal exploration, development, or production activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6645FEE8B4F4EA3A6629980538E1A1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">processes or refines oil, gas, or coal; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H702A457D5EC04229BB6275DDA587F69A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transports, or constructs facilities for the transportation of, Russian oil, gas, or coal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F9373762CD44611ACF9A1625EA560DC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Government of the Russian Federation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Government of the Russian Federation</term> includes the government of any political subdivision of Russia, and any agency or instrumentality of the Government of the Russian Federation. For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>agency or instrumentality of the Government of the Russian Federation</term> means an agency or instrumentality of a foreign state as defined in section 1603(b) of title 28, United States Code, with each reference in such section to <quote>a foreign state</quote> deemed to be a reference to <quote>Russia</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC54CF0006D794FDBA4E80CFEF90D90C8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H01A627E1697F4FFA995F9AB758859A6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a natural person, corporation, company, business association, partnership, society, trust, or any other nongovernmental entity, organization, or group;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F11B399CB6F4AF4BCA59E6A9EA85506"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any governmental entity or instrumentality of a government, including a multilateral development institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(3) of the International Financial Institutions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/262r">22 U.S.C. 262r(c)(3)</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E4AECEEE2014EC59DD68BEAEDF1F148"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any successor, subunit, parent entity, or subsidiary of, or any entity under common ownership or control with, any entity described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

