<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF6E90EBC63144E8FA1C5FF1BDBE55E3C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7005 IH: Protecting Americans’ Savings Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7005</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220309">March 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct a study on the effects of inflation on the savings of individuals in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBC969D6C046C4B82B85094B303C6948F" style="OLC"><section id="H71B0ED330C1E40A0BA34EF637367778C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Americans’ Savings Act of 2022</short-title></quote> . </text></section><section id="H9664626325764DCB9E43B7A75F6454C9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HECE3729D358A4B94BDFBE175E9E4717F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>High inflation erodes the earnings and savings of hard-working individuals across the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEB88BB132C84FA49FEF21DF6B8B8ABF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Consumer Price Index rose 7.5 percent from January 2021 to January 2022, which is the largest increase in a 12-month period in over 30 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5BC82698F3042078570CA1D497FED33"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The current environment, where high inflation is paired with low interest rates, pushes real savings yields deep into negative territory.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C44B1F22E384F649A3AB24AA9B49BBB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>While the yield of a 1-year Treasury bill in January 2022 was 0.5 percent, the real yield of the bill was negative 7 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A1A675640CA4E97AD5AF539A05C1A0C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Negative savings returns adversely affect all who save, especially retirees and those who rely on savings to build wealth or to prepare for large expenses, such as college tuition or a down payment on a home.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H9DABFABE64A2447EAE2AF24711BB08AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on impact of inflation on savings</header><subsection id="HECD66547A4B14E279ADB0A906F1CFB85"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall conduct a study to—</text><paragraph id="HED6FA0E35FFA4DBCA135669DAB11B7F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine the effects of inflation on the real value of savings and the incentive to save for individuals in the United States, including an analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="HC944691E4634438A9DE10FD737972F66"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether low or negative real returns affect savings rates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A7F0558324D48FBB69E0CEF8E8B8F5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how negative real interest rates affect individuals living on fixed incomes, such as retirees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D2106E0622845D2AD96F4C84D134BD0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how negative real interest rates affect economic mobility;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6978F8F5CD644972A4ECD308655F1451"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the aggregate loss of purchasing power of savings that is attributed to inflation with respect to common savings tools, including Treasury bonds, bills, and notes, interest on savings accounts, money market accounts and funds, and certificates of deposit; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H887DE23199144C7788F71F183F6F9FF2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how inflation will affect savings returns over the next 5 years; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H940D898A09D84189A7AF9560992CDB3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess the feasibility and impact of raising the current limit, per individual, on purchases of inflation-protected Series I bonds issued by the Department of the Treasury.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4003FF67CA7A4FC4AEA2A711C1D13380"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report on the results of the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

