<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H153EB850F0EB486A9362A7154E64DCB4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7952 IH: Valley Forge Park Realignment Permit and Promise Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7952</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of the Interior to issue a right-of-way permit with respect to a natural gas distribution pipeline within Valley Forge National Historical Park, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5E1BAEE6FE347BEB9CB7A214DB9D86F" style="OLC"><section id="HE202C8736DF14A42A0F7E341C3D78F47" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Valley Forge Park Realignment Permit and Promise Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H465151E0BC7F4821BC591D1B1F5CCBFF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Right-of-way permit for pipeline segment at Valley Forge NHP</header><subsection id="HA3E0ABBAF7614BEC9D31DCE7B335F410"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary may issue a right-of-way permit pursuant to part 14 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act), for the covered pipeline segment if the covered pipeline segment is relocated to a proposed realignment of Valley Forge Park Road and North Gulph Road within the Park. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2BD74B40D3EA4BED8E6ED5759F01C3F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="H3956D9C5D78244698FA666D8A850AC18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No expansion, upgrade, or improvement</header><text>A right-of-way permit issued under subsection (a) shall not allow expansion, upgrade, or improvement of the covered pipeline segment except as may be required by law for safe operation and maintenance of the pipeline.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98C7606843CB41BD95EB7561E8D7F06B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of authority</header><text>The authority to grant a right-of-way permit under subsection (a) shall apply only to the covered pipeline segment and shall not apply to any other part of the natural gas distribution pipeline system or any other pipeline system within the Park. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77AD5ADC905444CEA275BA46DC9E78EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional terms and condition</header><text>The Secretary may include any additional terms and conditions in the right-of-way permit issued under subsection (a) as the Secretary determines necessary. </text></subsection><subsection id="H65DBBB9B253544F4AA68B1CD57610246"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H89448CDF402945FB8F69AA7F3D29471D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered pipeline segment</header><text>The term <term>covered pipeline segment</term> means the portions of the natural gas distribution pipeline (including all appurtenances used in the operation of such pipeline) within the Park—</text><subparagraph id="H3D4B91104F6C4C35ADDDC44CBF0A6E52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>existing on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1EABF3CCB394451BFD8D2FC9EA18B4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are located under, along, or adjacent to the segments of North Gulph Road and Valley Forge Park Road (SR3039 and SR0023 respectively, as those roads were aligned on January 21, 2022) that are between—</text><clause id="HA64B6A594BC04AB290F50C3508044246"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the intersection of North Gulph Road with Richards Road; and</text></clause><clause id="H31FF193316454EA8B766192FF46FD682"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a point on Valley Forge Park Road located 500 feet northwest of its intersection with County Line Road.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4FA611F7F543BBAB35920EA69565C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Park</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Park</term> means Valley Forge National Historical Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA85F7DB8E92444708D3A08B8B036EB8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

