<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H011D5D2CDF8F41A39BC7930D8486508F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6967 IH: Chance to Compete Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6967</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Hice of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To implement merit-based reforms to the civil service hiring system that replace degree-based hiring with skills- and competency-based hiring, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H48D7C15AC5454D528858D1A1822D1F5D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HCE263B9E56AB426DAE0DDF1E3733FEE7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chance to Compete Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6708863123FA4DF6947DB88D3E78C257"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header> <subsection id="H5097B8150A7B4F528D46CA8023F49FF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Terms defined in section 3304 of title 5, United States Code</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the terms <term>agency</term>, <term>Director</term>, <term>examining agency</term>, <term>Office</term>, <term>subject matter expert</term>, and <term>technical assessment</term> have the meanings given those terms in subsection (c)(1) of section 3304 of title 5, United States Code, as added by section 3(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8C3F30904074F87BBCB0FD0AEC5D359"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>In this Act, the term <term>competitive service</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2102 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3272D54BB62A43058868E2E7AC98193A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Defining the term <term>examination</term> for purposes of hiring in the competitive service</header> <subsection id="HFDCB8DEF6C9C4C0189784A3B626FEC2B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Examinations; technical assessments</header> <paragraph id="HEE9F5F8CCC254E798FBDEBEC4D44F830"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3304 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3ED1B02571E94008A4A9C4B5CD282F63"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (f) as subsections (d) through (g), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEE4C855300E949EC8572680C0F06A2FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7582348684D543849A45B9E4BB373D3D"> 
<subsection id="H65F372D112F94F2BAEA7BF5EFEDFA22F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Examinations</header> 
<paragraph id="HD732305696244700AC75DA27FF337522"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header> 
<subparagraph id="HCA047E4822314377B58B412026207A40"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Examination defined for purposes of this chapter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this chapter, the term <term>examination</term>—</text> <clause id="H95C5478FFDE946DD857A37DBEC736FBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means an opportunity to directly demonstrate knowledge, skills, abilities, and competencies, through a passing score assessment;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H21E2F36741394C4889E613706074A9EB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>includes a résumé review that is—</text> <subclause id="HF770457176334BF69A93625FC02E2D8A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conducted by a subject matter expert; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H83356BC7B1DF40A7A27A05744B9C42E8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>based upon indicators that—</text> <item id="H6ED2BE41A0FF433AA2E9E1B60A7EEADF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>are derived from a job analysis; and</text></item> 
<item id="HACCEB2AC540A4496B4787BCC5F6105B1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>bear a rational relationship to performance in the position for which the examining agency is hiring; and</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE95C0D2D051A4855B4A36D682B8A15D4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on and after the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Chance to Compete Act of 2022</short-title>, does not include a self-assessment from an automated examination, a résumé review (except as provided in clause (ii)), or any other method of determining the experience or level of educational attainment of an individual, alone.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5CDCEBBF13A347AB8653AE62AAA5A147"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <clause id="H0557539C4BB24B1598537828C408D4DD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>agency</term> means an agency described in section 901(b) of title 31;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC8A82DEB0AF04267A740C5B095523D1C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office;</text></clause> <clause id="HF925AC40BAC64013B50B06DBE98390A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>examining agency</term> means—</text> 
<subclause id="HCE79DDB0B1E3441796B4CD4D2DC7551E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Office; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE23A2DE0595A425E9249F4E197835683"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an agency to which the Director has delegated examining authority under section 1104(a)(2) of this title; </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H9F4714AF0A37421FB1D707BC1D9E2842"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Personnel Management;</text></clause> <clause id="HAB83E0CCA85D4889AE33BA2BF94130B8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the term <term>passing score assessment</term> means an assessment that an individual can pass or fail;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H6970A76D9E8F4D318CD7AB839905FC62"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the term <term>subject matter expert</term> means an employee or selecting official—</text> <subclause id="HBA29B963C53F4F29B771446FCDB38657"><enum>(I)</enum><text>who possesses understanding of the duties of, and knowledge, skills, and abilities required for, the position for which the employee or selecting official is developing or administering an assessment; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H44E08DE0B89E4F90B5A97AF66E2367EC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>whom the delegated examining unit of the agency that employs the employee or selecting official designates to assist in the development and administration of technical assessments under paragraph (2); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H56E3B6D8C80E4D0F89C05571A1E6A949"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the term <term>technical assessment</term> means an assessment developed under paragraph (2)(A)(i) that—</text> 
<subclause id="H802D89A1131F4F118105E8AAF62073E3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>allows for the demonstration of job-related technical skills, abilities, and knowledge;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5F22AAB173B345DA988D12B8FCAA5B53"><enum>(II)</enum> <item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCE488D967925453CA42A47C7A9B1D42F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>is based upon a job analysis; and</text></item> 
<item id="H1A410B94664D4B0C9B17DB17C26B2FE8" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is relevant to the position for which the assessment is developed; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HB4FC657371884D4988635A46C4B440AD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>may include—</text> 
<item id="H37919C16E9F14E218E49F1E8079D2920"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a structured interview;</text></item> <item id="H35B45A3D362541DDAB0520E9208459A6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a work-related exercise;</text></item> 
<item id="H2F1298BA91BE49C8B827B761A13C48D3"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a custom or generic procedure used to measure an individual’s employment or career-related qualifications and interests; or</text></item> <item id="H2D19334E39404D1C9BDCBBA036D2F358"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>another assessment that meets the criteria under subclauses (I) and (II).</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0938641D24FA41A8B23C2D250EF50FFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assessments</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC5ED1DD50A66421E8386133010419BDD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of conducting an examination for a position in the competitive service, a subject matter expert who is determined by the subject matter expert's agency to be an expert in the subject and job field of the position, as affirmed and audited by the Chief Human Capital Officer or Human Resources Director (as applicable) of that agency, may—</text> <clause id="H901CBDAA55934CF69989B6404B760507"><enum>(i)</enum><text>develop, in partnership with human resources employees of the examining agency, a position-specific assessment that is relevant to the position; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE2CE9B1DE1DA4E5D917907AFDB1529D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>administer the assessment developed under clause (i) to—</text> <subclause id="HF9DA4D98D33040D29DADEB583ADBDE8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>determine whether an applicant for the position has a passing score to be qualified for the position; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HDA5C1442445C4DBFB03E4913A9C9A17B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>rank applicants for the position for category rating purposes under section 3319.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H713F5D62078A4EFB81250138D02105AB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Sharing and customization of assessments</header> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HB3A3DEBBF4BE469FA00BCE8063A9C075"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Sharing</header><text>An examining agency may share a technical assessment with another examining agency if each agency maintains appropriate control over examination material.</text></clause> 
<clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3E1F976F59D443A3A6C7CEB1185EFF86"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Customization</header><text>An examining agency with which a technical assessment is shared under clause (i) may customize the assessment as appropriate, provided that the resulting assessment satisfies the requirements under part 300 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></clause> <clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H9E725090098C436A83671735FF234A44"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Platform for sharing and customization</header> <subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H9E5718E0C9054666B3BE71BA9D5F6B55"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall establish and operate a platform on which examining agencies can share and customize technical assessments under this subparagraph.</text></subclause> 
<subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H231C22C3017F4213A23DCE71BF87BA6D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Chance to Compete Act of 2022</short-title>, the Director shall issue guidance to examining agencies on how to efficiently and effectively share assessments using the platform established under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H978A8E02763442B4AAB52C005243EE9D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Adoption of determinations by other agencies</header><text>For purposes of sections 3318(b) and 3319(c), an appointing authority, other than the appointing authority requesting a certificate of eligibles, that selects an individual from that certificate in accordance with such section 3318(b) or 3319(c) may adopt the determination described in subparagraph (A) of this paragraph of a subject matter expert employed by the requesting appointing authority instead of administering an additional technical assessment of the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC523BE1EC43A4ECE8047946DB4022CDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternative ranking and selection procedures</header><text>Section 3319(a) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>To be placed in a quality category under the preceding sentence, an applicant shall be required to have passed an examination in accordance with section 3304(b), subject to the exceptions in that section.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90C826674B134C1EA620FEC902E41CBC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>Section 3330a(a)(1)(B) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 3304(f)(1)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3304(g)(1)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H52D2CBA854174F2C91E4E5D7EFCF1A81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of passing score assessment requirement</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director and the head of any other examining agency shall eliminate the use of any examination for the competitive service that does not satisfy the definition of the term <term>examination</term> in subsection (c)(1)(A) of section 3304 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2A152B88AD5446C3B3C95DE3070E291E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>OPM reporting</header> <paragraph id="H10E2EB0E825A4E59A2BF286E92E683F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public dashboard</header> <subparagraph id="H3F573568BF6A4F79AC51332E12059DCA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall maintain and periodically update a publicly available dashboard that, with respect to each position in the competitive service for which an examining agency examined applicants during the applicable period, includes—</text> 
<clause id="HF3021B142C3543E09E5C3DCB7A0C16A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the type of assessment used, such as—</text> <subclause id="H7E8777B82B35430A98D588C1175C5494"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a behavioral off-the-shelf assessment;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7F24A6B2AFBE46B4BA6E8395384A406A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a résumé review conducted by a subject matter expert;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H14C6E60EA311499785B329D168C054C4"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an interview conducted by a subject matter expert;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H063242CA32EF4FDDB06DAAC33B48046E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a technical off-the-shelf assessment; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H65AABA4EC98444D0B4B769609294B2D4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a cognitive ability test;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HB3FBEBFEA40A4BECA7165CF663BB3456"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether or not the agency selected a candidate for the position; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBC206C2C531B47A5841F1EFCBB230D22"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the hiring authority used to fill the position.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H073391B0361A41C58D6F9784ADE0F26C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timing</header> 
<clause id="H04ED66D88C1A4FC7821D949F12A50AB6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Initial data</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall update the dashboard described in subparagraph (A) with data for positions in the competitive service for which an examining agency examined applicants during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on the date of submission of the report.</text></clause> <clause id="H13E0716A044F474DAEB85071E6575FD1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Subsequent updates</header><text>Not later than October 1 of each fiscal year beginning after the date on which the dashboard is initially updated under clause (i), the Director shall update the dashboard described in subparagraph (A) with data for positions in the competitive service for which an examining agency examined applicants during the preceding fiscal year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC0C1AA0701804B658CD6887DB731B7A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual progress report</header> 
<subparagraph id="HE826EBC439D14016BB33AFDCF27F5294"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each year, the Director, in accordance with subparagraphs (B) and (C), shall make publicly available and submit to Congress an overall progress report that includes summary data of the use of examinations (as defined in subsection (c)(1)(A) of section 3304 of title 5, United States Code, as added by subsection (a) of this section) for the competitive service, including technical assessments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3C1B3627338C4E0A814E5BF40DD0637F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Categories; baseline data</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Director shall—</text> 
<clause id="HEF4BEF5774144700ABE756A5997F8CD2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>break the data down by applicant demographic indicator, including veteran status, race, gender, disability, and any other measure the Director determines appropriate; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8B8FCE81E1CA48C89F67F80B0C3E76F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use the data available as of October 1, 2020, as a baseline.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H99A3AACB10294D55A1E55A5023FB8C46"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Director may only make publicly available and submit to Congress data relating to examinations for which—</text> <clause id="HFBAE215442A74963889505173B86D823"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the related announcement is closed;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBFAEF35B07014B5AB91FCF7A9D131048"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>certificates have been audited; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0E206280D07A41DEA00B08A84630DA38"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>all hiring processes are completed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5F7DBAEAA384424A44499D0EEF85FD7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HFE5240F06BB349DF983175CD89827FEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assesses the implementation of this section and the amendments made by this section;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF3C9A1FB5139409297AD0E0CC247640A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assesses the impact and modifications to the hiring process for the competitive service made by this section and the amendments made by this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7C3AFEF9571427F83A6807A9EA94852"><enum>(3)</enum><text>makes recommendations for the improvement of the hiring process for the competitive service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H368A691435644DA293EB28503C7B9B7B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Amendments to Competitive Service Act of 2015</header> 
<subsection id="H0ECDEB7459C947B5AE38C9C7F0D21E37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Platforms for sharing certificates of eligibles</header><text>Section 3318(b) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC7DB6B815D734747AC2B6B00E6A5031A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>240-day</quote> and inserting <quote>1-year</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5381237145C4C99B63669E3EE0F95CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (5) as paragraph (6); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC970B96D227B409498DEF401772F116F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4155A174C3CE4F0A9AA11124A00AE372"> 
<paragraph id="H7D84361EBBCC4ADC8052EB61A639A52F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Platform for sharing résumés of individuals on certificates of eligibles</header><text>The Director of the Office shall establish and operate a platform on which an appointing authority can share, with other appointing authorities and the Chief Human Capital Officers Council established under section 1303 of the Chief Human Capital Officers Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/1401">5 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/296">Public Law 107–296</external-xref>), the résumés of individuals who are on a certificate of eligibles requested by the appointing authority. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7EE5506982BD4E818151DA1EEB892A17"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Maximizing sharing of applicant information</header><text>Section 2 of the Competitive Service Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/137">Public Law 114–137</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 310) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3F6A095E12794729AC067B5DADBC7DD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H62CDAF349E45450A8AD76E0AEAEAEB71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF035F3E4A764F87A02E5496026752F5"> 
<subsection id="H888AA46353F84B279E8A211C8629FF9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maximizing sharing of applicant information</header> 
<paragraph id="HDF753BC3287F4681BEB03A7A8B795D5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6A77569054E4BE1933ED931A55DD340"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the terms <term>agency</term>, <term>Director</term>, and <term>Office</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 3304(c)(1) of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA19CF07C74542EA9E383DAF4B32BD45"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>competitive service</term> has the meaning given the term in section 2102 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DF6714B8C8A4B749871E9EE704A122A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximizing sharing</header><text>The Director shall maximize the sharing of information among agencies regarding qualified applicants for positions in the competitive service, including by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D8ED07AA0A4438E875CAA63F222A3D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing for the delegation to other agencies of the authority of the Office to host multi-agency hiring actions to increase the return on investment on high-quality pooled announcements; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFF699B34D8984E8DA77204F23FF8E5E4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sharing certificates of eligibles and accompanying résumés for appointment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H912F1539C8FB490F9B5431E9E3B46A76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendment of implementing regulations</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall promulgate regulations to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF187C6FDDC7C468A8BA8852E0197058B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Modernizing and reforming the assessment and hiring of Federal job candidates</header> <subsection id="H6091E148039D449388D5DFDA413BCDA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3308 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7B87848F0C72482AB684F4B542CE7754"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>scientific, technical, or professional</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7D394AA42124A898903A6C306DC44DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>legally</quote> before <quote>performed</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H066B5D523507460A96120EA41732710E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>in a jurisdiction in which the duties of the position are to be performed</quote> after <quote>a prescribed minimum education</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB0551DB149D14DAE83744EA3F53D4258"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header> <paragraph id="HE47DB65813F94020866F696C6F01D671"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Regulations and guidance documents</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall amend all regulations and guidance documents as necessary to implement the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2212A05DE8E24827853727B243199E84" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Hiring practices</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director and the head of any other examining agency shall amend the hiring practices of the Office or the other examining agency, respectively, in accordance with the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H99FD0F38CBA84289BCA249D840EE34B1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Talent teams</header> <subsection id="H715A2EFDDD8D483C8B1548617451F26D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal agency talent teams</header> <paragraph id="H7FB5057D3C684F5B8D13198CCEE52A84"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency may establish 1 or more talent teams (referred to in this section as <term>agency talent teams</term>), including at the component level.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0531832AFEE4BDEB9A1754535CD5E23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency talent team shall provide hiring support to the agency and other agencies, including by—</text> <subparagraph id="HD480C73939BA4F6AB80FB214C083749A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving examinations (as defined in subsection (c)(1)(A) of section 3304 of title 5, United States Code, as added by section 3(a));</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7180E2D0F8C24911999CD184D32E2348"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating writing job announcements for the competitive service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F3E9E062A4043A5BF4E54C3C6289AC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>sharing high-quality certificates of eligibles; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4FFB08FD2261462B9EAA8BD09DF008ED"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitating hiring for the competitive service using examinations (as defined in such subsection (c)(1)(A)) and subject matter experts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5FF8B17A3B724534871BBC399EA71FCC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office of Personnel Management</header><text>The Director may establish a Federal talent team to support agency talent teams in facilitating pooled hiring actions across the Federal Government, providing training, and creating technology platforms to facilitate hiring for the competitive service, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1B69990BCAAC4783B962A98B7BEBC36B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development of technical assessments; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0DDA710CF534C3C9FFBF23AE3869D51" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sharing of certificates of eligibles and accompanying résumés under sections 3318(b) and 3319(c) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 

