<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2A1DE8A421424331BA590FCC3D49202A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7576 IH: Securing Semiconductor Supply Chains Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7576</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000615">Mr. Pence</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require SelectUSA to coordinate with State-level economic development organizations to increase foreign direct investment in semiconductor-related manufacturing and production.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB577EDB795064D2F8E6E7BF28F141102" style="OLC"><section id="H3EC1E6D2008844E1AA431D670A0AC04A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Semiconductor Supply Chains Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEA7B6EF3CC074B19B74531D4EB9097C4"><enum>2.</enum><header>SelectUSA defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>SelectUSA</term> means the SelectUSA program of the Department of Commerce established by Executive Order 13577 (76 Fed. Reg. 35,715).</text></section><section id="H712DACBB4D7E4CBEBE6104934502B2C6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H3FD1BD926489450BAEF2C483917E2BF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Semiconductors underpin the United States and global economies, including manufacturing sectors. Semiconductors are also essential to the national security of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40B6E800C11C45A88A44FCAE7F27A5C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A shortage of semiconductors, brought about by the COVID–19 pandemic and other complex factors impacting the overall supply chain, has threatened the economic recovery of the United States and industries that employ millions of United States citizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCB9A1B3A3EC4970B3E5FE696E9DA2B4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Addressing current challenges and building resilience against future risks requires ensuring a secure and stable supply chain for semiconductors that will support the economic and national security needs of the United States and its allies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF923F01766544619956B5C773B3C4DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The supply chain for semiconductors is complex and global. While the United States plays a leading role in certain segments of the semiconductor industry, securing the supply chain requires onshoring, reshoring, or diversifying vulnerable segments, such as for—</text><subparagraph id="HB9E15B4A76B24771B7EBD67E6C870242"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fabrication;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5028DC16CB4A46EB866425E28CCECA3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advanced packaging; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4DE9471D3A644EC82232348FD02C7CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>materials and equipment used to manufacture semiconductor products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEB9436E36DB446CBD3FEAC141D1F45F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Government can leverage foreign direct investment and private dollars to grow the domestic manufacturing and production capacity of the United States for vulnerable segments of the semiconductor supply chain.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08BB5AD41EB246DB96FE55E4F3544909"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The SelectUSA program of the Department of Commerce, in coordination with other Federal agencies and State-level economic development organizations, is positioned to boost foreign direct investment in domestic manufacturing and to help secure the semiconductor supply chain of the United States.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H911F7B1A2F7D46768FCC4C87539B6E39"><enum>4.</enum><header>Coordination with State-level economic development organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Executive Director of SelectUSA shall solicit comments from State-level economic development organizations—</text><paragraph id="H453887CEC5B54CEB965868B4AE468276"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to review—</text><subparagraph id="HCBBF104BA57245968F1C3A1C63D46DC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>what efforts the Federal Government can take to support increased foreign direct investment in any segment of semiconductor-related production;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6938C928E46448449CF2F2D411ED5A4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>what barriers to such investment may exist and how to amplify State efforts to attract such investment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H017030C4AF6C4B1582CDDFBE74403648"><enum>(C)</enum><text>public opportunities those organizations have identified to attract foreign direct investment to help increase investment described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69A8D91833954E659327E2AE15BD8B70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>resource gaps or other challenges that prevent those organizations from increasing such investment; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF33172402F9548408CB66C4909A73B71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to develop recommendations for—</text><subparagraph id="H94A476DE2C1844F090305DF4F9DF8486"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how SelectUSA can increase such investment independently or through partnership with those organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CDA3D86E4E340579314BDF36F610525"><enum>(B)</enum><text>working with countries that are allies or partners of the United States to ensure that foreign adversaries (as defined in section 8(c)(2) of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1607">47 U.S.C. 1607(c)(2)</external-xref>)) do not benefit from United States efforts to increase such investment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HDABA3DA6FD774D579A2FFC93D2A9DB85"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on increasing foreign direct investment in semiconductor-related manufacturing and production</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Executive Director of SelectUSA, in coordination with the Federal Interagency Investment Working Group established by Executive Order 13577 (76 Fed. Reg. 35,715; relating to establishment of the SelectUSA Initiative), shall submit to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H209B29EFA6904DDAA069CB963AC1A555"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a review of the comments SelectUSA received from State-level economic development organizations under section 4;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8DA929753CD48A58FED1182EED201BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of activities SelectUSA is engaged in to increase foreign direct investment in semiconductor-related manufacturing and production; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AF05CEC9C934CB4BC23BF2CDA68B856"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of strategies SelectUSA may implement to achieve an increase in such investment and to help secure the United States supply chain for semiconductors, including by—</text><subparagraph id="H3C6FBD5904C847B48FCF3E836EA351D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>working with other relevant Federal agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADFEAFDC8691485BB1F2FB9EE89E56FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>working with State-level economic development organizations and implementing any strategies or recommendations SelectUSA received from those organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

