<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7EE85AFF38B24A7F853E338E2443819E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7269 IH: No Obscene Teaching in Our Schools Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7269</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220329">March 29, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the disbursement of Federal funds to schools that violate any State law relating to materials that are harmful to minors, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H632CD445EE564760A7D0C556BDD187FE" style="OLC">
<section id="HF51F024D395F450AA9190196F2F5197C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Obscene Teaching in Our Schools Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NOT in Our Schools Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9B048F0E1147465C93B396FF6EE3D9A8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibiting federal funds to certain schools</header> <subsection id="H05613636516E411A98CAF1635FA4A8C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header> <paragraph id="HC4F23DBF60D34D368A7E40A3A19EF726"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be provided to an elementary school or secondary school that is in violation of any law of the State in which the school is located that is related to materials that are harmful to minors.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3D71E6CE7CA49999FBE8ABF5E861EDC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>529 education savings plan account programs</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law and to the extent permitted under State law, a State educational agency may either return the Federal funds that were dedicated to the violating school or, at the request of the parents or legal guardian of eligible children, a State educational agency may create and carry out a 529 education savings plan account program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6C67D5B853B04AE8B910E73D97A48A78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="HBFC39CCC468B47958E5F0E59384537F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>529 education savings plan account</header><text>The term <quote>529 education savings plan account</quote> means a qualified tuition program (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">section 529(b)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEF3D1142E8054195A2254B9DC1F2B1BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible child</header><text>The term <quote>eligible child</quote> means a child who attends, or otherwise would be attending, an elementary school or secondary school that receives (or is eligible to receive) Federal funds and is determined to be in violation of any law of the State in which the school is located that is related to materials that are harmful to minors.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8AA9D375415848B286A92B582A33C356"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Home school</header><text>The term <quote>home school</quote> means a home school as defined by the laws of the State in which the eligible child resides.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HEFEC0B9A1E214B5FBBF75F209500B9CC"><enum>3.</enum><header>529 account funding for homeschool and additional elementary and secondary expenses</header>
<subsection id="HAE6230DB112B44E8A1A16B214BC24FCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/529">Section 529(c)(7)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89AABC03AEBC4A5A981FC2A926B6ACE2"> <paragraph id="H2019C88E8BAD435185635144F0086FA3"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Treatment of elementary and secondary tuition and resources</header><text>Any reference in this section to the term <term>qualified higher education expense</term> shall include a reference to the following expenses in connection with enrollment or attendance at, or for students enrolled at or attending, an elementary or secondary public, private, or religious school:</text>
<subparagraph id="HD25C3C8E85DC4E858AC817C6E7DB5EA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tuition.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H298AC561C4CC40C9BF62AF6B6E0A8F2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Curriculum and curricular materials.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF9234F5C253D4B40ABB3404ACA0AF9F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Books or other instructional materials.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18A38F0BB35E4ABEBE3C31041F498EEC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Online educational materials.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H21A908DDA8DB4D0CA4C66759F4FEC21A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Tuition for tutoring or educational classes outside of the home, including at a tutoring facility, but only if the tutor or instructor is not related to the student.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB973AEC18EA4610B0C9E93FECA3A731"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Fees for a nationally standardized norm-referenced achievement test, an advanced placement examination, or any examinations related to college or university admission.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H147782EA673A49EC8E02D2021545F0A7"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Fees for dual enrollment in an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9C806F31929242A4A7B1E0490F4FFA19"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Educational therapies for students with disabilities provided by a licensed or accredited practitioner or provider, including occupational, behavioral, physical, and speech-language therapies.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term shall include expenses for the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) through (H) in connection with a homeschool (whether treated as a homeschool or a private school for purposes of applicable State law).</continuation-text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H80B4F6E34F074A84A7D2C76585AF09C2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to distributions made after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H33F90A9BECE34059ACA8CAB6A2250655"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> A State that creates and carries out a 529 education savings plan account program under this Act shall submit an annual report to Congress no later than July 1 of the following year. The report shall include schools found in violation of State law related to materials deemed harmful to children, the nature and details of the violation, the number of eligible children participating in the 529 program under this Act, and the use of the Federal funds for qualified expenses.</text></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


