<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEBD48296419B4A86B1467FA13D204309" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7583 IH: Support International Criminal Investigations for Ukraine Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7583</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow funding for the International Criminal Court, require the Secretary of State to submit a report on United States policy relating to the investigation of the International Criminal Court with respect to the Situation in Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8BB378E30ADD45EBA309ED7DABAE90DE" style="OLC"><section id="H19B70F0A1C654111AC6D8E1515ED98DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Support International Criminal Investigations for Ukraine Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBAECD8C0436C4017AD83190DF8633BD9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of Policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H577BA1B1D71D42ED9C41D73191D6D267"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to support the Investigation into the Situation in Ukraine being conducted by the International Criminal Court (ICC), including by providing material support and participating in international efforts to collect and preserve evidence that may be relevant for prosecution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4868D4D4E2014343A85ECBBEF5328581"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in general and consistent with United States foreign policy priorities, to provide material and technical support including for the collection and preservation of evidence to ICC investigations of war crimes, crimes against humanity, genocide, or crimes of aggression;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E69E66D792345939102525BB3C1A40F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to pursue a policy of constructive engagement with the ICC; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BB1BD31AD42485C8818DD249E7F0F42"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to take steps required for the United States to become a state party to the Rome Statute of the International Criminal Court.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H70FF17D249E64BF99795408309EA0C24"><enum>3.</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7401(b) of title 22, United States Code, is hereby repealed. </text></section><section id="HF6F685F46D594E129E3F0B092B7DA100"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report setting forth the Administration’s policy review of the United States position on the International Criminal Court’s Investigation into the Situation in Ukraine, including—</text><paragraph id="H5A6C6E82365D452D98133F8FCF9FB81D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations as to the provision of material support to such investigation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9597E798BEE141F69DF2DD52520A04E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national security and foreign policy benefits of formally providing material support to such investigation and other investigations.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

