<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5254043DA9BD4BCB9929642CD1965AD6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8410 IH: Coast Guard Intelligence Operations Improvement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8410</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220718">July 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize certain expenditures relating to intelligence and counterintelligence activities of the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2722F7CA1A2342359EF5552F0AC78A6F" style="OLC"><section id="HF03626E88579421EB796D839652CE2A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coast Guard Intelligence Operations Improvement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H307820C499DA4D66B8A8184B11AF4ECF" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization relating to certain intelligence and counterintelligence activities of Coast Guard</header><subsection id="HC5815FC6E49342EB971FBBAA76120B2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), and consistent with the policies, procedures, and coordination required pursuant to section 811 of the Counterintelligence and Security Enhancements Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3381">50 U.S.C. 3381</external-xref>) and section 902 of the Counterintelligence Enhancement Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3382">50 U.S.C. 3382</external-xref>), the Commandant of the Coast Guard may expend amounts made available for the intelligence and counterintelligence activities of the Coast Guard to conduct such an activity without regard to any other provision of law or regulation relating to the expenditure of Government funds, if—</text><paragraph id="H0F85E2AF4BDC412F9F7CFC810CF10FB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the object of the activity is of a confidential, extraordinary, or emergency nature; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0CE5038B8FE4185A1DC8F29FE79F830"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">following each such expenditure, the Commandant submits to the congressional intelligence committees a certification that the object of the activity conducted was of a nature described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1CDC6C5CB2EB4359BDDF5E0275901820"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available for a fiscal year for the intelligence and counterintelligence activities of the Coast Guard, not more than five percent may be expended during the fiscal year under subsection (a) to conduct such activities in accordance with such subsection unless, for each intended expenditure in excess of such percentage—</text><paragraph id="HA7901F1B2FD54F2A915E80E24CA632B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commandant submits to the congressional intelligence committees a notification of the intent to expend the amounts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E9EFD1EC816449B8AC83111D2A4F0A9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a period of 30 days has elapsed following the date on which the Commandant submits such notification.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D3FDCE931B8426B83221205DE6BC94B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H826CDC08355C4F2880B205639C17BB9B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than December 1 of each year, the Commandant shall submit to the congressional intelligence committees a report on all expenditures during the preceding fiscal year under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H088F13BB69E448179CEC58EE6C39FEBB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, for each individual expenditure covered by such report that is in excess of the percentage specified in subsection (b) for the relevant fiscal year, the following: </text><subparagraph id="H925B907A6F81400FAC0EA27098F14C9B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A detailed description of the purpose of such expenditure.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37996D19E29E4303AF17A9E660AC474E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The amount of such expenditure. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3120BEA174704152857E4AB9E6C718E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An identification of the approving authority for such expenditure. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23BA461504834E6C9F8B840450855DD4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A justification as to why other authorities available to the Coast Guard could not be used for such expenditure. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C9B95AE77164667A789EF4A66CCCE2B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other matters the Commandant considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D79DFFC76E4477793771B6199D2C3B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional intelligence committees defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>congressional intelligence committees</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB700094A9D4C40E698685762427631C8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall cease to have effect on the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

