<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H48E35A5DFA77447CBB1E9F1343B55BD3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7121 IH: Protecting our Pharmaceutical Supply Chain from China Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7121</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001109">Ms. Cheney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to maintain a list of the country of origin of all drugs marketed in the United States, to ban the use of Federal funds for the purchase of drugs manufactured in the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H48D54074554341C9BCECDA54C795BE8C" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H84033E9AE2C245ACB6367688C3525ADC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting our Pharmaceutical Supply Chain from China Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5A8EA56EABC44D1EBDC8BC84BF7BE304"><enum>2.</enum><header>Country of origin of drugs</header> <subsection id="H484679C7BFDD476F9FF5D5BD4CE8B531"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter A of chapter V of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/351">21 U.S.C. 351 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H62A208D568DE45F2BF5D791457EDC1FE"> 
<section id="HA2F767CB298D4D7CA040940B0D9CCE97"><enum>524B.</enum><header>Registry of drugs produced outside the United States</header> 
<subsection id="H5708CEB8E0CD499DA6D0DA0E6800AA33"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall compile and maintain a list of all drugs approved under subsection (c) or (j) of section 505 of this Act or licensed under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act, and any active ingredients in such drugs, that—</text> <paragraph id="H948951F09389494CB3486AFD453628F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>are manufactured outside of the United States; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA265C239202948F1A1060890C1B4020A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are determined by the Secretary to be critical to the health and safety of consumers in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBE811C785B51432BA2EDF0E3998B0F01"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional list</header><text>In conjunction with the list described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall compile and maintain a list of drugs included on such list that are exclusively produced in, or use active or inactive ingredients produced in, the People’s Republic of China. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE449367294B048B0996703E0CBAC649F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The list described in subsection (a) shall, with respect to each drug included on the list, provide information about the supply chain of the drug, including each step in the supply chain that occurs prior to importation of the drug into the United States.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H38BB06EC72684A3884ADB30B05B5B229"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal health program purchase of drugs</header> <paragraph id="H229818FD8CE94FDB88E80EAF570BD4AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and any other Federal health care program (as defined in section 1128B(f) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7b(b))), with respect to the purchase of a drug by such agency or program, the following shall apply:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H38B3C41AF296498F963C92D46FE96D36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Beginning on January 1, 2023, such agency or program may purchase only drugs for which 60 percent or more of the active pharmaceutical ingredients are manufactured in countries described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1121207B18304839A9CC5D15D813BCCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Beginning on January 1, 2024, such agency or program may purchase only drugs for which 100 percent of the active pharmaceutical ingredients are manufactured in countries described in paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA631B6593B1845E48D7169F6C3DECDD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Countries described</header><text>The countries described in this paragraph are countries—</text> <subparagraph id="HFCE27D9CE22C40418EBE0F685A43CB0B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other than the People’s Republic of China; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6B36D3D7CB7D4811A420F6993A85863C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that meet the health and safety standards of the Food and Drug Administration. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7457448CBB7E4B25925A7BFB9F0645D4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waivers</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services may issue waivers of the requirements under paragraph (1) for any agency or program that is unable to meet such requirements and demonstrates a need for the waiver. No waiver may be issued under this paragraph for drugs that are purchased on or after January 1, 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDA58DC33F524034A3571345F0910330"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Labeling requirement</header><text>Section 502 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/352">21 U.S.C. 352</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D9AA4E5EF814BBB81CADD032B2C1B8C"> <subsection id="H6C4E8D629CD54F3DA063A7F86115D1BB"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>If it is a drug and its labeling does not specify the country of origin of each active ingredient contained in the drug.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7C585C4E026A4BBAB68F1EDD26AE61BF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Temporary 100 percent expensing for pharmaceutical and medical device manufacturing property</header> 
<subsection id="H643B667C9A1D4331938E5A2B605D1D43"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/168">section 168(k)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, in the case of any qualified pharmaceutical and medical device manufacturing property which is placed in service after December 31, 2019, and before January 1, 2027—</text> <paragraph id="HEA169EA744F6421FAF7D93C3BB0B1A1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such property shall be treated as qualified property (within the meaning of such section),</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72E452BAC2AF43C6BEF5A991A57E7E5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the applicable percentage otherwise determined under section 168(k)(6) of such Code with respect to such property shall be 100 percent, and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD347142C29044C3E93BBF730DB37B84D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>paragraph (8) of such section shall not apply.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H29B0675ECB8F46FF89E37C8A487DF510"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualified pharmaceutical and medical device manufacturing property</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>qualified pharmaceutical and medical device manufacturing property</term> means any tangible property placed in service in the United States as part of the construction or expansion of property for the manufacture of drugs (as defined in section 201(g) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(g)</external-xref>)) or medical devices (as defined in section 201(h) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(h)</external-xref>)).</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

