<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4ED60A3F28FC46009BAB8170293DE31E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>104 HR 7858 IH: Digital Platform Commission Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7858</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a new Federal body to provide reasonable oversight and regulation of digital platforms.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE8F33556AE44A70BB8607AFBDCF9089" style="OLC"><section id="HD3DCC1327C0046D78E40633C040B9E76" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HE8E1B87A9F9342D28F713211CEB1629C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Digital Platform Commission Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H18D1FDDFCBEB4E5C868F4973506D2405"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HD3DCC1327C0046D78E40633C040B9E76" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDE69F35E671E47B09C5E31E2162C96B2" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings; sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF3FDB2C61F6B4657AB368C31F93BE41D" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8008FBA9C2FD4F189D0D71C4443A908E" level="section">Sec. 4. Establishment of Federal Digital Platform Commission.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H81EEF9CD1A5D409FB87697E798DF97A0" level="section">Sec. 5. Jurisdiction.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA1EC601E50CF4AB7A5786E23529BB701" level="section">Sec. 6. Organization and general powers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBE09C34F8B6349BAA576BD40B6578B02" level="section">Sec. 7. Organization and functioning of the Commission.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HBB5BD18AD490442AA475C292C56D83A6" level="section">Sec. 8. Code Council.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H37A24AAC08DD4A57B21AE2A30C584CD5" level="section">Sec. 9. Rulemaking authority, requirements, and considerations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H399AC5993C90460E940285536D92BE7B" level="section">Sec. 10. Systemically important digital platforms.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H039A8D070FBF4FFF9AB10AD36741C59F" level="section">Sec. 11. Merger review.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD7E187B6E3644A4687FA845422D0008E" level="section">Sec. 12. Petitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H085963F1AC334234A0AB273509E2FE3F" level="section">Sec. 13. Research.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF80ED2E26E7B4367AA4F1AC6BB7590E7" level="section">Sec. 14. Investigative authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD9DD7E4D2E6543328CCDC7ABEBA2F8E3" level="section">Sec. 15. Enforcement by private persons and governmental entities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE64C2579789541C9832C5D8C27FD95FD" level="section">Sec. 16. Proceedings to enjoin, set aside, annul, or suspend orders of the Commission.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HD10806DD84CF43D9B3AF2AE164BB89CE" level="section">Sec. 17. Report to Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0BD5877486CE46FEA22EA808D5372904" level="section">Sec. 18. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HDE69F35E671E47B09C5E31E2162C96B2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="H9565192FFD38473284788224FB04B6E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H59E124F2D6C14BC78AF1A285E3661668"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In the United States and around the world, digital platforms and online services play a central role in modern life by providing new tools for communication, commerce, entrepreneurship, and debate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E615EF3A5A146B3B70E5BC05EEF4044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States takes pride in the success of its technology sector, which leads the world in innovation and dynamism, provides valuable services to the people of the United States, and supports thousands of good-paying jobs in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H690CF4B695F84FD890556D2A33D27955"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In recent years, a few digital platforms have benefitted from the combination of economies of scale, network effects, and unique characteristics of the digital marketplace to achieve vast power over the economy, society, and democracy of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB597F3B8CD3A47C1A1D7B915F9927F83"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The last time Congress enacted legislation to meaningfully regulate the technology or telecommunications sector was the Telecommunications Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/104">Public Law 104–104</external-xref>; 110 Stat 56.), years before many of today’s largest digital platforms even existed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF42FECA773D64BDF942CF3DE9A8FF1BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Digital platforms remain largely unregulated and are left to write their own rules without meaningful democratic input or accountability.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E28B3B3F67648168767FF0072C62BDC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The unregulated policies and operations of some of the most powerful digital platforms have at times produced demonstrable harm, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCF29C897B83C4AFB8FE4DBC4637C42B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>undercutting small businesses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BB491EDE4E84C1BB8B17B5832581F3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>abetting the collapse of trusted local journalism;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A71A623D5FC44299A15BED229DEDF1A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enabling addiction and other harms to the mental health of the people of the United States, especially minors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H891B4B2C25AC40AEAEC5792722A0DDD7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>disseminating disinformation and hate speech; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70CD5504BD8D49EDBB79A558F80459ED"><enum>(E)</enum><text>undermining privacy and monetizing the personal data of individuals in the United States without their informed consent; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA420FAE23469494DAB99DCF64C83A422"><enum>(F)</enum><text>in some cases, radicalizing individuals to violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B48EEC899C3435FB7EBD2A0D1BF58EB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The failure of the United States Government to establish appropriate regulations for digital platforms cedes to foreign competitors the historic role played by the United States in setting reasonable rules of the road and technical standards for emerging technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A3B36A6CE9843678453D7B1E0673F87"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Throughout the history of the United States, Congress has often responded to the emergence of powerful and complex new sectors of the economy by empowering sector-specific expert Federal regulators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F00148DE1A04D20BCD53B50E1147E55"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Throughout the history of the United States, the Federal Government has established reasonable regulation, consistent with the First Amendment to the Constitution of the United States, to promote a diversity of viewpoints, support civic engagement, and preserve the right of citizens to communicate with each other, which is foundational to self-governance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A9BC3A595C145B1AD4F6C0723944F50"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The unique power and complexity of several digital platforms, combined with the absence of modern Federal regulations, reinforces the need for a new Federal body equipped with the authorities, tools, and expertise to regulate digital platforms to ensure their operations remain consistent, where appropriate, with the public interest.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5CF362E6682490599B90FE007EC41E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Federal agency established under this Act should—</text><paragraph id="H252599A402D24F65B5681CADFC0ABA28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop appropriate regulations and policies grounded in the common law principles of the duty of care and the duty to deal, insofar as those principles are relevant and practical; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD877AE1EB0014FF79F4E2052B50DB58E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>adopt, where relevant and practical, a risk management regulatory approach that prioritizes anticipating, limiting, and balancing against other interests the broad economic, societal, and political risks of harm posed by the activities and operations of a person or class of persons.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF3FDB2C61F6B4657AB368C31F93BE41D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph id="HC8D207783E724800A010B61635BBD353"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Algorithmic process</header><text>The term <term>algorithmic process</term> means a computational process, including one derived from machine learning or other artificial intelligence techniques, that processes personal information or other data for the purpose of determining the order or manner in which a set of information is provided, recommended to, or withheld from a user of a digital platform, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9B8BA66D33054607A46C69A6A46B6FE5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of commercial content;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7D5165BC13433D9C2E57ACC41F3273"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the display of social media posts; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E63BAAD20E54560A28C1C3812522A66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the display of search results or rankings; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H727B7ED6E96A43659903FE09F86E5F05"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other method of automated decision making, content selection, or content amplification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D4F1B0BE15B458EB2883B6D9011FB7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <term>Commission</term> means the Federal Digital Platform Commission established under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A8F6ED74D2B4E4D8AEC07463E8FC4B3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the Code Council established under section 8(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B25504CF9BF47C18CD6D4AAF7FF0BC9" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Digital platform</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBEA64E0571A34D57976983B62F02C4EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>digital platform</term> means an online service that serves as an intermediary facilitating interactions—</text><clause id="H8FEB087F37EC48EC801C7EDA2E75D298" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>between users; and</text></clause><clause id="H5CF6C1E12B6F429FB66C02996E8A84BE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>between users and—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H782EB6F3C74F49CA9A8E793EF268FA72"><enum>(I)</enum><text>entities offering goods and services through the online service; or</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H9CDCBE68C81748D6BC068E6C1AAC3C2D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the online service with respect to goods and services offered directly by the online service.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA452F989C5AD4C6D8E50A2F163910B27"><enum>(B)</enum><header>De minimis exception</header><clause commented="no" id="HF4A2D45A51FF4B2781B23A1A4FBE08AB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A)(ii)(II), the term <term>digital platform</term> does not include an entity that offers goods and services to the public online if the offering of goods and services online is a de minimis part of the entity's overall business.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HCE0F7E6209284C26AE7A1E7A71B732AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Online services that do not qualify for de minimis exception</header><text>Notwithstanding clause (i), if an online service described in subparagraph (A)(ii)(II) is owned by an entity but is offered through an affiliate, partnership, or joint venture of, or is otherwise segregable from, the entity—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H354E55511C7640F087AAE2FAB0FFAF47"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the online service shall be considered a digital platform; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H48B97FA42DE04AA596EFE4C0695E1322"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the entity shall not be considered a digital platform.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2F916696DEC94C7EB07DD3754C3AC1CD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Small digital platform businesses</header><clause commented="no" id="H909FB8CE6828450890C0A6C46166E361"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>digital platform</term> does not include a small digital platform business, except as provided in clause (iii).</text></clause><clause id="H6A71F01C6BE34B02B3229C52AD3663C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>SBA rulemaking</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall by regulation define the term <term>small digital platform business</term> for purposes of clause (i). </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H637FED5A6AE3479492C21F77DF2F3C70"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Non-applicability to systemically important digital platforms</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to a systemically important digital platform.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3B9CAAE81E0C461D8B998C6C16203C16"><enum>(D)</enum><header>News organizations</header><text>The term <term>digital platform</term> does not include an entity whose primary purpose is the delivery to the public of news that the entity writes, edits, and reports.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H3238E7B6927343B4A859E44A74FA0DBB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Immediate family member</header><text>The term <term>immediate family member</term>, with respect to an individual, means a spouse, parent, sibling, or child of the individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A70C5479BD54968BB2165B72680B5EF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Online service</header><text>The term <term>online service</term> includes a consumer-facing website, back-end online-support system, or other facilitator of online transactions and activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FD2E4B8097C4D0587051C957FAB6C0B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Systemically important digital platform</header><text>The term <term>systemically important digital platform</term> means a digital platform that the Commission has designated as a systemically important digital platform under section 10.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8008FBA9C2FD4F189D0D71C4443A908E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Federal Digital Platform Commission</header><subsection id="H4345BB4C84834FB4939C514F74E43CB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a commission to be known as the <quote>Federal Digital Platform Commission</quote>, which shall—</text><paragraph id="H165D4ECFC7954BFBBE2C1A20C1BE0CBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be constituted as provided in this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H257D07A0B4B14D7B9CAB43E8CA234BFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>execute and enforce the provisions of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3468181853840BEB7EA0613C1095A27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes of Commission</header><text>The purpose of the Commission is to regulate digital platforms, consistent with the public interest, convenience, and necessity, to promote to all the people of the United States, so far as possible, the following:</text><paragraph id="HDD92A89D105246828BB9912E280857A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Access to digital platforms for civic engagement and economic and educational opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF20C02CA305E4B28A48474CC10457041"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Access to government services and public safety.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA9426DD65054258B9FF797A6F0B3069"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Competition to encourage the creation of new online services and innovation, and to provide to consumers benefits such as lower prices and better quality of service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA38458ED8B4B6D8D8B56E24ADADBC3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Prevention of harmful levels of concentration of private power over critical digital infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E5F7026D3C2459798220C52CB656A85"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A robust and competitive marketplace of ideas with a diversity of views at the local, State, and national levels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE503E23BB5FC417588460CFD77025AAE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Protection for consumers from deceptive, unfair, unjust, unreasonable, or abusive practices committed by digital platforms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ED1CE47425E4115A4EB9E00D21FCF64"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Assurance that the algorithmic processes of digital platforms are fair, transparent, and safe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4F63F54BA8F4A1C9CDDEFD6AC8065FA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed to modify, impair, or supersede the applicability of any antitrust laws.</text></subsection></section><section id="H81EEF9CD1A5D409FB87697E798DF97A0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><subsection id="H7FFE479D93844F62AB765A237E98583A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plenary jurisdiction</header><text>The Commission shall have jurisdiction over any digital platform, the services of which—</text><paragraph id="H95210D410EA94F5A97964F8D37A41B5D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>originate or are received within the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD63AF12E91724AB482E7FF9F7B80733B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affect interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF1A832768AAB412CBC432DFAD7DC4430"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provisions relative to systemically important digital platforms</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the earliest date as of which not fewer than 3 Commissioners have been confirmed, the Commission shall determine whether to issue rules, with input from the Code Council as appropriate, to establish for systemically important digital platforms—</text><paragraph id="H18C5E726FEBA4BEAB7DB0A040B3A57B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>commercial and technical standards for—</text><subparagraph id="H0CE6E7B176564130982CDCF1FAC628EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data portability; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88C2DB60EA3D45DE95BDC619B4E6CF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interoperability, which shall be defined as the functionality of information systems to—</text><clause id="H9AB9F2BD566D416C9EA995723638D52D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exchange data; and</text></clause><clause id="HE6E41C8C61D64E5490C1B6319C2F1003"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enable sharing of information;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H313A775541824013939CAFD5A9D10DC1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requirements for recommendation systems and other algorithmic processes of systemically important digital platforms to ensure that the algorithmic processes are fair, transparent, and without harmful, abusive, anticompetitive, or deceptive bias;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C8DDE78ADC8475CAE1D884856BB640F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>transparency requirements for terms of service, including content moderation policies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H589B7471793248D48AA5C21670F7A270"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requirements for regular public risk assessments of the distribution of harmful content on a systemically important digital platform and steps the systemically important digital platform has taken, or plans to take, to mitigate those harms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2375F449F61424987E1BAF21D238020"><enum>(5)</enum><text>transparency and disclosure obligations to enable—</text><subparagraph id="HD02F507825ED4D55A95223AAB955CA3A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversight by the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13DDD5892CEF477B8F6A504083F42034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>third-party audits to ensure the accuracy of any public risk assessments required under paragraph (4); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976241EEB17F41E385F3E8C393E3D164"><enum>(C)</enum><text>trusted third-party research in the public interest; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA08BD809F28048B49EAC8D12950E6C33"><enum>(6)</enum><text>commercial and technical standards to ensure accessibility to individuals with a disability, as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>), including to provide the ability for an individual who has a hearing impairment, speech impairment, or vision impairment to engage with systemically important digital platforms in a manner that is functionally equivalent to the ability of an individual who does not have a hearing impairment, speech impairment, or vision impairment to engage with systemically important digital platforms.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H448C3E08A10A4DCC95700FC19E244B04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Forbearance</header><paragraph id="H938E4CC2F238468A96DFB38501DD05B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may forbear from exercising jurisdiction over a digital platform or class of digital platforms based on size, revenue, market share, or other attributes the Commission determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90C2CCAE80794FDD8B4301B8AAF8B535"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Flexibility</header><text>The Commission may reassert jurisdiction over a digital platform or class of digital platform over which the Commission forbore from exercising jurisdiction under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA1EC601E50CF4AB7A5786E23529BB701"><enum>6.</enum><header>Organization and general powers</header><subsection id="HB84FB5CEE70F465C916EBF28BC81422D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 5 Commissioners appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate, one of whom the President shall designate as chair.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7794832894844EA7BADCB2AC63CD25DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><paragraph id="H9E5EA1E78F344F9989E543785C348072"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Citizenship</header><text>Each member of the Commission shall be a citizen of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0677A6559821480DA18819F4F1B2D7E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><subparagraph id="HB1B867AC544C4F93A5C1D1AC44901EE9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), no member of the Commission or person employed by the Commission, and no immediate family member thereof, shall—</text><clause id="HD6685C628C83436FA63338F9FEE1F9AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be financially interested in—</text><subclause id="HCC734185F75D4FE9839E120F222DF405"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any person significantly regulated by the Commission under this Act; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB8581489C7B54130AA4A839C870A1849"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a third party in direct and substantial competition with a person described in subclause (I); or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H61C58FAA335E425E87E39637F660A606"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be employed by, hold any official relation to, or own any stocks, bonds, or other securities of, any person or third party described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB2529E5FC0DF4D68A2E3854756600299"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Significant interest</header><text>The prohibitions under subparagraph (A) shall apply only to financial interests in any company or other entity that has a significant interest in activities subject to regulation by the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H413F16B3A0E74470990F07655B45F4D3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver</header><clause id="H9A887104FAB748C9A056E23F609E6989"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to section 208 of title 18, United States Code, the Commission may waive, from time to time, the application of the prohibitions under subparagraph (A) to persons employed by the Commission, or immediate family members thereof, if the Commission determines that the financial interests of a person that are involved in a particular case are minimal.</text></clause><clause id="H4B7C720BC74040EAA237E36EC04D88B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No waiver for Commissioners</header><text>The waiver authority under clause (i) shall not apply with respect to members of the Commission.</text></clause><clause id="H8C716F61BDA74E0A859DEF99CCF947E2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>If the Commission exercises the waiver authority under clause (i), the Commission shall publish notice of that action in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAD0FEBC14BA471CB7EA3EDB016AB73D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of significant interest</header><text>The Commission, in determining for purposes of paragraph (2) whether a company or other entity has a significant interest in activities that are subject to regulation by the Commission, shall consider, without excluding other relevant factors—</text><subparagraph id="H7D19525CACA745DD9EB4E7DDA7A57195"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the revenues, investments, profits, and managerial efforts directed to the related activities of the company or other entity, as compared to the other aspects of the business of the company or other entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE9AF88D771F4F94BFD88005BBEEB09F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which the Commission regulates and oversees the activities of the company or other entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2CEB26E4C0F47B8818EE10A8F874A60"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the degree to which the economic interests of the company or other entity may be affected by any action of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE76D6C6A99804C1AA43A91832B1321CF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the perceptions held by the public regarding the business activities of the company or other entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90C28BB0FF7B40C9BE57DDE62F32EF60"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No other employment</header><text>A member of the Commission may not engage in any other business, vocation, profession, or employment while serving as a member of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DF9F9DB57D94E9D9CEDABC0B74C337B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Political parties</header><text>The maximum number of commissioners who may be members of the same political party shall be a number equal to the least number of commissioners that constitutes a majority of the full membership of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB6EBE63FBE3440DA7819F55F4AE935C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Term</header><paragraph id="HCCBBFD77629E45F08EAB667D9215433F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A commissioner—</text><subparagraph id="H6200C4BE0E26428E84F6A2E8B2234E26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be appointed for a term of 5 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE933A2895AF4C69897142943CFCF678"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may continue to serve after the expiration of the fixed term of office of the commissioner until a successor is appointed and has been confirmed and taken the oath of office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36B7AEAFF9894590BEE224B86CB68465"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Filling of vacancies</header><text>Any person chosen to fill a vacancy in the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="H1A734CA25DE743D2AE51D4C983CE6D1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be appointed for the unexpired term of the commissioner that the person succeeds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B77FB49D9C64CC497053A06EF2CDDEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>except as provided in subparagraph (C), may continue to serve after the expiration of the fixed term of office of the commissioner that the person succeeds until a successor is appointed and has been confirmed and taken the oath of office; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71FD03C0CC624C7FA94E1F2B47E328F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may not continue to serve after the expiration of the session of Congress that begins after the expiration of the fixed term of office of the commissioner that the person succeeds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38990A5935844570AD137FF85B9EE254"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect of vacancy on powers of Commission</header><text>Except as provided in section 9(e) (relating to repeal of prior rules), no vacancy in the Commission shall impair the right of the remaining commissioners to exercise all the powers of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD8C0AA91FF84737AD10373743181C8A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Salary of Commissioners</header><paragraph id="H7A25977D90E74667810682BD6251FA8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Commissioner shall receive an annual salary at the annual rate payable from time to time for grade 16 of the pay scale of the Securities and Exchange Commission, payable in monthly installments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FBD73C75CE94B61BE546DED8423844E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Chair of the Commission, during the period of service as Chair, shall receive an annual salary at the annual rate payable from time to time for grade 17 of the pay scale of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80A8EA15C5264053A59D7CF4F6ADBFAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Principal office</header><paragraph id="H3F8A63D4BF98474F8A04F465F45242FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General sessions</header><text>The principal office of the Commission shall be in the District of Columbia, where its general sessions shall be held.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H013C2E289B764CEDB061F54EF405CD58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special sessions</header><text>Whenever the convenience of the public or of the parties may be promoted or delay or expense prevented thereby, the Commission may hold special sessions in any part of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25932892A1EC4225B55ABE3DC7090FA9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Employees</header><paragraph id="H05E316EF904F4AFDB3454E50F90CE0A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may, subject to the civil service laws and the Classification Act of 1949, as amended, appoint such officers, engineers, accountants, attorneys, inspectors, examiners, and other employees as are necessary in the exercise of its functions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02F7AB537E2E49DFA1AB633CB401FDF5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Assistants</header><subparagraph id="HB7C48682088646D6901286FD25FD3223"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Professional assistants; secretary</header><text>Without regard to the civil-service laws, but subject to the Classification Act of 1949, each commissioner may appoint professional assistants and a secretary, each of whom shall perform such duties as the commissioner shall direct.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28A555B883B44599A9DC7D87F2DDA044"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administrative assistant to Chair</header><text>In addition to the authority under subparagraph (A), the Chair of the Commission may appoint, without regard to the civil-service laws, but subject to the Classification Act of 1949, an administrative assistant who shall perform such duties as the Chair shall direct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AA25CEE76E34B659A9D93C23C09FFDE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of volunteers to monitor violations relating to online services</header><subparagraph id="HF570C2B537334A099C88A1C76763E37E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Recruitment and training of volunteers</header><text>The Commission, for purposes of monitoring violations of any provision of this Act (and of any regulation prescribed by the Commission under this Act), may—</text><clause id="H5170069D51AE407A85DE2E2ED2B6E76A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>recruit and train any software engineer, computer scientist, data scientist, or other individual with skills or expertise relevant to the responsibilities of the Commission; and</text></clause><clause id="H8D5476C1B70D4409B04580BFBF429C6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>accept and employ the voluntary and uncompensated services of individuals described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76CD6055677C48048B70432A44DAAE85"><enum>(B)</enum><header>No limitations on voluntary services</header><text>The authority of the Commission under subparagraph (A) shall not be subject to or affected by—</text><clause id="H47F3809CD06B484CBDD875DEF813088F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>part III of title 5, United States Code; or</text></clause><clause id="H015EB83040E44439976699B4AE2BD4CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>section 1342 of title 31, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51850394C0B34CFE9B1FC10DAA9843EA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No Federal employment</header><text>Any individual who provides services under this paragraph or who provides goods in connection with such services shall not be considered a Federal or special government employee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F41533B3F05484BADC354ADDCCBE294"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Broad representation</header><text>The Commission, in accepting and employing services of individuals under subparagraph (A), shall seek to achieve a broad representation of individuals and organizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A306B89CB94496EAE053D38BE14437C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Rules of conduct</header><text>The Commission may establish rules of conduct and other regulations governing the service of individuals under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23964E2948A54F58B89917CFAF8C641B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Regulations for personnel practices</header><text>The Commission may prescribe regulations to select, oversee, sanction, and dismiss any individual authorized under this paragraph to be employed by the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H145D0BCEA9F9491EA22094B62FE37A45"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expenditures</header><paragraph id="H6253BB2F16614768A3B21635E1B28772"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may make such expenditures (including expenditures for rent and personal services at the seat of government and elsewhere, for office supplies, online subscriptions, electronics, law books, periodicals, subscriptions, and books of reference), as may be necessary for the execution of the functions vested in the Commission and as may be appropriated for by Congress in accordance with the authorizations of appropriations under section 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B0B748D9D30423D8AD9EEBBF2DE8DC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>All expenditures of the Commission, including all necessary expenses for transportation incurred by the commissioners or by their employees, under their orders, in making any investigation or upon any official business in any other places than in the city of Washington, shall be allowed and paid on the presentation of itemized vouchers therefor approved by the Chair of the Commission or by such other members or officer thereof as may be designated by the Commission for that purpose.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECC672C018724F349E7940EE8CF36886"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gifts</header><subparagraph id="H55A1163015DF4748AC2109DCE22F011A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in furtherance of its functions the Commission is authorized to accept, hold, administer, and use unconditional gifts, donations, and bequests of real, personal, and other property (including voluntary and uncompensated services, as authorized by section 3109 of title 5, United States Code).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABA1BC63DE3740BEAC3D65C6CC0CF5C7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Taxes</header><text>For the purpose of Federal law on income taxes, estate taxes, and gift taxes, property or services accepted under the authority of subparagraph (A) shall be deemed to be a gift, bequest, or devise to the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD52937491FA4FAE87318ECDDF3A5E2F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Regulations</header><clause id="H8B50ED8A47224418954CAC10EBBA8184"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall promulgate regulations to carry out this paragraph.</text></clause><clause id="H5D83D00BD98F40E287BEEE9E8BCEDB44"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><text>The regulations promulgated under clause (i) shall include provisions to preclude the acceptance of any gift, bequest, or donation that would create a conflict of interest or the appearance of a conflict of interest.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0EAE5B40458849C6AB870A68661E9973"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Quorum; seal</header><paragraph id="H6CB8D5BED63E40D6AA871F01B6F424A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>Three members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBB66DB85AE64DD3B1456C5090AD32E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Seal</header><text>The Commission shall have an official seal which shall be judicially noticed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0AC46A71929A4E23917C676732581081"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Duties and powers</header><text>The Commission may perform any and all acts, including collection of any information from digital platforms under the jurisdiction of the Commission as the Commission determines necessary, without regard to any final determination of the Office on Management and Budget under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), make such rules and regulations, and issue such orders, not inconsistent with this Act, as may be necessary in the execution of its functions. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEE60F1EB706F4E7394C9DBEF51F231F0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Conduct of proceedings; hearings</header><paragraph id="H28223C580CD346CC84FA09DA159D3DA9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may conduct its proceedings in such manner as will best conduce to the proper dispatch of business and to the ends of justice.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABA69C8833944815B477589DFA6D1211"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><text>No commissioner shall participate in any hearing or proceeding in which he has a pecuniary interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC573A5D4C4CD45A5BF9869E8E2362933"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Open to all parties</header><text>Any party may appear before the Commission and be heard in person or by attorney.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43D821E9E8A54DE9B20895B84BE97340"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Record of proceedings</header><subparagraph id="H7D80B80F4C764A079CA505BE8C935FC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HFC518793EE5541DDA25F2F36ECACDD4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>every vote and official act of the Commission shall be entered of record; and</text></clause><clause id="H5B20CF6CB66F4F8C8D230FFD1C289156"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Commission shall endeavor to make each proceeding public, while recognizing the occasional need for private convening and deliberation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H165E41455B744521AA1FF74654138218"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Defense information</header><text>The Commission may withhold publication of records or proceedings containing secret information affecting the national defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE116159380D4F9CBE39BE827B494C6F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Record of reports</header><text>All reports of investigations made by the Commission shall be entered of record, and a copy thereof shall be furnished to the party who may have complained, and to any digital platform or licensee that may have been complained of.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F1D0A3FFC874E24A07BE4950F15B341"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Publication of reports; admissibility as evidence</header><text>The Commission shall provide for the publication of its reports and decisions in such form and manner as may be best adapted for public information and use, and such authorized publications shall be competent evidence of the reports and decisions of the Commission therein contained in all courts of the United States and of the several States without any further proof or authentication thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC15B89F567C44F0786D009AA8B3DAFA6"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Compensation of appointees</header><text>Rates of compensation of persons appointed under this section shall be subject to the reduction applicable to officers and employees of the Federal Government generally.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA86AA68140B644898549A36E304B1FCB"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header><text>The Commission shall enter into memoranda of understanding with the Federal Communications Commission, the Federal Trade Commission, and the Department of Justice to ensure, to the greatest extent possible, coordination, collaboration, and the effective use of Federal resources concerning areas of overlapping jurisdiction.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBE09C34F8B6349BAA576BD40B6578B02"><enum>7.</enum><header>Organization and functioning of the Commission</header><subsection id="H37C4C733813149F4BCF5048E854E0F8B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Chair; duties; vacancy</header><paragraph id="H4A47DD2690CC4FA6A8AB4E68998E1247"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The member of the Commission designated by the President as Chair shall be the chief executive officer of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21E555B8AFFA4CCD9782EE9CD0E23289"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Chair of the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="HACDA7832400E445C842F1D7EF5983335"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preside at all meetings and sessions of the Commission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ED43312B7D043FA9954334E3B27A800"><enum>(B)</enum><text>represent the Commission in all matters relating to legislation and legislative reports, except that any commissioner may present the commissioner's own or minority views or supplemental reports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H96C401F529FC43CF9C89AA0E83CE80D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>represent the Commission in all matters requiring conferences or communications with other governmental officers, departments, or agencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H640342354EA54190A640AE6196CBE1BE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>generally coordinate and organize the work of the Commission in such manner as to promote prompt and efficient disposition of all matters within the jurisdiction of the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C97DA52301B4A3BBF80D476B9A5E0B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>In the case of a vacancy in the office of the Chair of the Commission, or the absence or inability of the Chair to serve, the Commission may temporarily designate a member of the Commission to act as Chair until the cause or circumstance requiring the designation is eliminated or corrected.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEA8322F78C84CADB7FE0088923AF19D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Organization of staff</header><paragraph id="H51CDB35D7777428F95C064E1AA74BCB8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From time to time as the Commission may find necessary, the Commission shall organize its staff into—</text><subparagraph id="H5139E58D0DC94DFE988AA1BD3E60F248"><enum>(A)</enum><text>bureaus, to function on the basis of the Commission’s principal workload operations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H147D1A738812410685228BEC26122601"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such other divisional organizations as the Commission may determine necessary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H798F14EB3D9643F4B79C5520EB622BCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Integration</header><text>The Commission, to the extent practicable, shall organize the bureaus and other divisions of the Commission to—</text><subparagraph id="H4E37298A35F349C087D469C51C158535"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote collaboration and cross-cutting subject matter and technical expertise; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE82C9F94825B4D3E8F9DB65DA0D47B7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>avoid organization silos.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6247F7BED5C647E3936FB76DED4B484D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>Each bureau established under paragraph (1)(A) shall include such legal, engineering, accounting, administrative, clerical, and other personnel as the Commission may determine to be necessary to perform its functions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24269A69329C43549302096BEF863CFC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expert personnel</header><text>The Commission shall prioritize, to the extent practicable, the hiring of staff with a demonstrated academic or professional background in computer science, data science, application development, technology policy, and other areas the Commission may determine necessary to perform its functions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H456333C46A654C179BE9452E882E111C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Delegation of functions; exceptions to initial orders; force, effect, and enforcement of orders; administrative and judicial review; qualifications and compensation of delegates; assignment of cases; separation of review and investigative or prosecuting functions; secretary; seal</header><paragraph id="H63D6E4FB9CEF4D02A002F365632E71EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Delegation of functions</header><subparagraph id="HB8B3D313EA664B6A838E72B07314BCBF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>When necessary to the proper functioning of the Commission and the prompt and orderly conduct of its business, the Commission may, by published rule or by order, delegate any of its functions to a panel of commissioners, an individual commissioner, an employee board, or an individual employee, including functions with respect to hearing, determining, ordering, certifying, reporting, or otherwise acting as to any work, business, or matter; except that in delegating review functions to employees in cases of adjudication (as defined in the Administrative Procedure Act), the delegation in any such case may be made only to an employee board consisting of 2 or more employees referred to in paragraph (7).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H779D83C8E368492C84BC4C8B212994A5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minimum vote</header><text>Any rule or order described in subparagraph (A) may be adopted, amended, or rescinded only by a vote of a majority of the members of the Commission then holding office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H082483B7FB024692BD9B28E21BEDB968"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Force, effect, and enforcement of orders</header><text>Any order, decision, report, or action made or taken pursuant to a delegation under paragraph (1), unless reviewed as provided in paragraph (3), shall have the same force and effect, and shall be made, evidenced, and enforced in the same manner, as orders, decisions, reports, or other actions of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H035A3A81B42D4DA8B7C6E6F5482DB149"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative and judicial review</header><subparagraph id="H36514351211947289E8B0E77E4639429"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Aggrieved persons</header><text>Any person aggrieved by an order, decision, report or action described in paragraph (1) may file an application for review by the Commission within such time and in such manner as the Commission shall prescribe, and every such application shall be passed upon by the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73BD48F527CD4746B87851983A1606D7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initiative of Commission</header><text>The Commission, on its own initiative, may review in whole or in part, at such time and in such manner as it shall determine, any order, decision, report, or action made or taken pursuant to any delegation under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70715D6C966F4F07B1CF89ADA9EAB885"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Review</header><subparagraph id="HB6E83B9FF6E142838F1C581C3D4EF491"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In passing upon an application for review filed under paragraph (3), the Commission may grant, in whole or in part, or deny the application without specifying any reasons therefor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C37229253D348FB870EEAF23A1BA1B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Questions of fact or law</header><text>No application for review filed under paragraph (3)(A) shall rely on questions of fact or law upon which the panel of commissioners, individual commissioner, employee board, or individual employee has been afforded no opportunity to pass.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F59EF16B81A4E63AA0C446BB944E80F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant of application</header><text>If the Commission grants an application for review filed under paragraph (3)(A), the Commission may—</text><subparagraph id="H5B9B7C06DA36476E88659C41B9F65FC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affirm, modify, or set aside the order, decision, report, or action; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB152D0A3BE7401286D7333B5B819A41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>order a rehearing upon the order, decision, report, or action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDFBDE998445438C8266A68DBD0FDD5F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Application required for judicial review</header><text>The filing of an application for review under paragraph (3)(A) shall be a condition precedent to judicial review of any order, decision, report, or action made or taken pursuant to a delegation under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BEABFE824A14BD2AAF72AF0BAA67378"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualifications and compensation of delegates; assignment of cases; separation of review and investigative or prosecuting functions</header><subparagraph id="H1603550F49C34D6DABB2A9B570BA2FFE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Qualifications of delegates</header><text>The employees to whom the Commission may delegate review functions in any case of adjudication (as defined in the Administrative Procedure Act)—</text><clause id="HD0D55ED2683E45978F5C64C16B9AD340"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be qualified, by reason of their training, experience, and competence, to perform such review functions; and</text></clause><clause id="HE144258EE5B545788DB5757C24971452"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall perform no duties inconsistent with such review functions.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94CC7241CF0F44BC98D60AC4731499D7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>An employee described in subparagraph (A) shall be in a grade classification or salary level commensurate with the important duties of the employee, and in no event less than the grade classification or salary level of the employee or employees whose actions are to be reviewed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB549464C7AFE46C19B38D731C806F674"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Separation</header><text>In the performance of review functions described in subparagraph (A), employees described in that subparagraph—</text><clause id="HEC9BFEEC4AE34A0D9097A306B4DE0B27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be assigned to cases in rotation so far as practicable; and</text></clause><clause id="H6ECEC690B01D4C85BB99B6F2484715A2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not be responsible to or subject to the supervision or direction of any officer, employee, or agent engaged in the performance of investigative or prosecuting functions for any agency.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C691822F7F74010AAA4A12DF21A24AD"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary; seal</header><text>The secretary and seal of the Commission shall be the secretary and seal of each panel of the Commission, each individual commissioner, and each employee board or individual employee exercising functions delegated pursuant to paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1018454FACE3409589312A90213D84AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>Meetings of the Commission shall be held at regular intervals, not less frequently than once each calendar month, at which times the functioning of the Commission and the handling of its workload shall be reviewed and such orders shall be entered and other action taken as may be necessary or appropriate to expedite the prompt and orderly conduct of the business of the Commission with the objective of rendering a final decision in a timely fashion.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE2A16386FE80463AB45270417170EBB2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Managing Director</header><paragraph id="HA505E47713C84064B7292B714DE1613B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall have a Managing Director who shall be appointed by the Chair subject to the approval of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24064A2D232A44D38A0FB11489EEF7F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Managing Director, under the supervision and direction of the Chair, shall perform such administrative and executive functions as the Chair shall delegate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA2D2658E39C4531A4C5ADF66BBD01F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Pay</header><text>The Managing Director shall be paid at a rate equal to the rate then payable for grade 15 of the pay scale of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBB5BD18AD490442AA475C292C56D83A6" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Code Council</header><subsection id="HA65DA7265F434F8088158AE67D078028" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish a Code Council that shall develop proposed voluntary or enforceable behavioral codes, technical standards, or other policies for digital platforms through the code process under subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="H690604A8EF0F4216845C60535EFE8FD3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H493A5F22F4834FE293C073A85C920CC3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall consist of 18 members, of whom—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC20063E706EE44DA8553720FB50C3C02"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">6 shall be representatives of digital platforms or associations of digital platforms, not fewer than 3 of whom shall be representatives of systemically important digital platforms or associations that include systemically important digital platforms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H35DA2BA6357C42FBBAEE57A0139EAB4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">6 shall be representatives of nonprofit public interest groups, academics, and other experts not affiliated with commercial enterprises, with demonstrated expertise in technology policy, law, consumer protection, privacy, competition, disinformation, or another area the Chair determines relevant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H58884B40364D45C288FF7401AF18A403"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">6 shall be technical experts in engineering, application development, computer science, data science, machine learning, communications, media studies, and any other discipline the Chair determines relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6AE7BFDAF3D4B21888D6E48475FE939" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair shall appoint each member of the Council, subject to approval by the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CDE28C2AB854C78A2D2983644B8DA77" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE3C537B77ACC40EF857B2EBC1E44B03B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A member of the Council shall be appointed for a term of 3 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H93B9A3D311CE4A4B931C583BB88E326A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Staggered terms</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms of members of the Council shall be staggered such that one-third of the membership of the Council changes each year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1233740D938340F0A3EF6BC489448A0B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall meet publicly not less frequently than once a month.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBEFC304106A24A329EC5B03816C176C2" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Chair and Vice Chair</header><paragraph commented="no" id="HC43B56E664E7437AABFC41150C25C2DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be a Chair and Vice Chair of the Council—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD0E3351D5031426CBA0BB170769827CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one of whom shall be a member described in subparagraph (A) of subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H27321C7E103F46A0A94DEB080567638B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one of whom shall be a member described in subparagraph (B) of subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H29C08ABBFD9C4B788B1B203170F7C837"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual rotation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair or Vice Chair for a calendar year shall be a member described in a different subparagraph of subsection (b)(1) than the member who served as Chair or Vice Chair, respectively, for the preceding calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H210991A7EF7C4B849A30C8A7CB9E36D1" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Code process</header><paragraph id="H7F3D9DC7EBB041DB875218C6BA13E81D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may, at any time, initiate a process to develop a voluntary or enforceable behavioral code, technical standard, or other policy for digital platforms or a class of digital platforms.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H478B1EF6178D4DF8BD756DD26E1F904A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initiation based on petition or Council vote</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may initiate the process described in paragraph (1) if—</text><subparagraph id="H3D83CCF1A5D948B094BE64586762B7AB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Commission receives a petition from the public, including from a digital platform or an association of digital platforms; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95E1A498CE06413F94A16A2B584F4C07" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Council votes to initiate the process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H247A6BDC3417448BAA52333AA3BE7009" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Council examination and vote</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the process described in paragraph (1) is initiated, the Council—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H405DCA8F1FC14B8CB0590A2A0C033550"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall consider and develop, if appropriate, a proposed behavioral code, technical standard, or other policy for digital platforms or a class of digital platforms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3D402B2EB9AF446491E452E53789EBBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in considering and developing a proposed code, standard, or policy under subparagraph (A), shall—</text><clause commented="no" id="HEDC107A41D3E499A97E28CECDA971682"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow for submission of feedback by any interested party; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HDC528DDC7E464EDDB7CC94C42D68BAFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make available to the public a factual record, developed during the consideration and development of the proposed code, standard, or policy, that includes any submission received under clause (i);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H31018ABAB55A4190A5CCCA513441B6D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not earlier than 180 days and not later than 360 days after the date on which the process is initiated, shall vote on whether to submit a recommendation for the proposed code, standard, or policy to the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD0E3EFA8A7BE496E962E0D413653E6D3"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may submit minority views along with a recommendation under subparagraph (C), as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD57811C13A44B699563BDB7934E090"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public review; Commission examination and vote</header><text>Upon receipt of a recommendation for a proposed behavioral code, technical standard, or other policy from the Council under paragraph (3), the Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF5EC377C13114EB6B0507F7B17BB0B30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allow for submission of comments on the proposed code, standard, or policy by any interested party for a period of not fewer than 45 days and not more than 90 days, and publicly disclose any comments received;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3CBCB31254DB4351A6DC0B8062CFE368"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the proposed code, standard, or policy, along with comments received under subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF777BF0D179E442AA29303DC7BE9DA94"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine whether to adopt, reject, or adopt with modifications the proposed code, standard, or policy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7D1C1B185C29420EACCFEFCF373C57E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide a public rationale for the determination under subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCDBFD95988EC4F3FA8D66542C7FD1B66"><enum>(E)</enum><text>promulgate rules to carry out the determination under subparagraph (C) in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBDE242A7DEC42769D965EA9A7C4F8AD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Updates</header><text>Not less frequently than once every 5 years, the Commission shall review and update, as necessary, any behavioral code, technical standard, or other policy established by rule under paragraph (4). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D803154C843483A8B24FC03B8037C06" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to affect the authority of the Commission to promulgate rules under section 9.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4746268F3BFE455199F81FB37E245C4D" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><paragraph id="H29FBA6012F3F4BD5B9DB01079B79A86D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Citizenship</header><text>Each member of the Council shall be a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A095B211BA9443B8EE16C87A9FAED37" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conflicts of interest</header><subparagraph id="H79006D19E667439284E991BCEAC2973B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), no member of the Council other than a member appointed under subsection (b)(1)(A) shall—</text><clause id="H583E8E1758CB46EB8BCD8A25C4AC4D1B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be financially interested in any company or other entity engaged in the business of providing online services;</text></clause><clause id="HAFFA5DFB690A48489BCD1565F56D188E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be financially interested in any company or other entity that controls any company or other entity specified in clause (i), or that derives a significant portion of its total income from ownership of stocks, bonds, or other securities of any such company or other entity; or</text></clause><clause id="HBC5F9B5C6703423E8BBD4D601A747DE3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be employed by, hold any official relation to, or own any stocks, bonds, or other securities of, any person significantly regulated by the Commission under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72B1E8602AC7422CB91FF1FE81B87226" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Significant interest</header><text>The prohibitions under subparagraph (A) shall apply only to financial interests in any company or other entity that has a significant interest in activities subject to regulation by the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39DD72C22F3945C3975990C44DBF648C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver</header><clause id="H0963808940164FD9945BCD077FAEBB9B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to section 208 of title 18, United States Code, the Commission may waive, from time to time, the application of the prohibitions under subparagraph (A) to a member of the Council if the Commission determines that the financial interests of the member that are involved in a particular case are minimal.</text></clause><clause id="HDB4C8279BA0745C28D42F4EA06699FEA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>If the Commission exercises the waiver authority under clause (i), the Commission shall publish notice of that action in the Federal Register.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA1CC09B4DC74A418329A2CC5B405E4B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of significant interest</header><text>The Commission, in determining for purposes of paragraph (2) whether a company or other entity has a significant interest in activities that are subject to regulation by the Commission, shall consider, without excluding other relevant factors—</text><subparagraph id="H5CF4911224EB40D8986AE792EB6A7BF1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the revenues, investments, profits, and managerial efforts directed to the related activities of the company or other entity, as compared to the other aspects of the business of the company or other entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB91828FAC5A447B98D4FB4C9D09892EB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent to which the Commission regulates and oversees the activities of the company or other entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2497718BD54241DB8EC0C2CEDA78A11C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the degree to which the economic interests of the company or other entity may be affected by any action of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H902083F263F74EB8A434FC42DB6EFE4E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the perceptions held by the public regarding the business activities of the company or other entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCD024392872741A2AB6CE317D225C4F9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to authorize the Council to promulgate rules.</text></subsection></section><section id="H37A24AAC08DD4A57B21AE2A30C584CD5"><enum>9.</enum><header>Rulemaking authority, requirements, and considerations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The Commission—</text><paragraph id="H0E6E63569FE840D79BD6107964C8169D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may promulgate rules to carry out this Act in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3B543713FAF495EA8CB28359E4CE9CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall tailor the rules promulgated under paragraph (1), as appropriate, based on the size, dominance, and other attributes of particular digital platforms.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H399AC5993C90460E940285536D92BE7B"><enum>10.</enum><header>Systemically important digital platforms</header><subsection id="H25B0C75242FE46B88D133F359CE9679C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation of SIDPS; rulemaking authority</header><text>The Commission may—</text><paragraph id="H5110547F1EB84AE296E3F743F856CBF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>designate systemically important digital platforms in accordance with this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97BD276B2EA24750802166229C5392A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promulgate rules specific to systemically important digital platforms, consistent with the purposes of the Commission under section 4(b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4672822F3CB444E693A5E63B70A7DDBD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory criteria</header><text>The Commission shall designate a digital platform a systemically important digital platform if the platform—</text><paragraph id="HC6A85C8943CC46029E2E9717CB98700A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is open to the public on one side;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9527103F91494FEA9A15AC99DC1AC892"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has significant engagement among users, which may take the form of private groups, public groups, and the sharing of posts visible to some or all users;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06633FDFA57A442886FDE32E876CB506"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conducts business primarily at the interstate or international level, as opposed to the intrastate level; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01CB9D1B79F14556B6FBA7CAEA7879AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has operations with significant nationwide economic, social, or political impacts, as defined by the Commission for purposes of this paragraph through notice-and-comment rulemaking under section 553 of title 5, United States Code, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H8491E8F31D35464B88E5481D41A3882B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the ability of the platform to significantly shape the national dissemination of news;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFD1FF718AF044988239B6A90AE4680D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability of the platform to cause a person significant, immediate, and demonstrable economic, social, or political harm by exclusion from the platform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0241730D7E14565BC38E0F90CCD3FF3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the market power of the platform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68B7B34002364FFA9E7E5EDA850A33AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of unique daily users of the platform; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A2283246F1E44EFB283E689B29F8600"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the dependence of business users, especially small business users, on the platform to reach customers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD882E654E2F492F9983A15488FB19C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual and other reports</header><paragraph id="HCB59FD03B07B42F8B5FCA044AE2064C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority to require reports</header><text>The Commission may—</text><subparagraph id="HE587863A7BD04400B613E8E9D9AD8BAC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require annual reports from systemically important digital platforms subject to this Act, and from persons directly or indirectly controlling or controlled by, or under direct or indirect control with, any such platform;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BFC6C6A378F4FBA807471125969A027"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prescribe the content expected in such reports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A6B703D8AD04145984318E437C138E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prescribe the manner in which such reports shall be made; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6BD2C5082E3413EB067DFF17B3BD23F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require from such persons specific answers to all questions upon which the Commission may need information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DE1784E7C6642B1A85571CC56B2FDBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><subparagraph id="H3450690FE5A44CB38269F2C38E1B6281"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Time period covered; filing</header><text>A report under paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H75F1C56618E64A62B2224D38138D2A5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be for such 12 months’ period as the Commission shall designate; and</text></clause><clause id="H09041AA546D0492B8880F6BCA4ED6D16"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be filed with the Commission at its office in Washington not later than 3 months after the close of the year for which the report is made, unless additional time is granted in any case by the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1643023276B4EAE91CD245BF5842C5F" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to meet deadline</header><text>If a person subject to this subsection fails to make and file an annual report within the time specified under subparagraph (A), or within the time extended by the Commission, for making and filing the report, or fails to make specific answer to any question authorized by this subsection within 30 days after the time the person is lawfully required so to do, the person shall forfeit to the United States—</text><clause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE40504C4BC2649E88BF4CD1B598E481B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>$10,000 for each day the person continues to be in default with respect thereto, for the first 30 days of such default; and</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HEF0C05A1CF214A5B96FDC60AFF0BA813"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount determined appropriate by the Commission for each subsequent day that the person continues to be in default with respect thereto, which may not exceed 1 percent of the total global revenue of the person during the preceding year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H039A8D070FBF4FFF9AB10AD36741C59F"><enum>11.</enum><header>Merger review</header><subsection id="H25AC4D1E94004F26981B4279C2B6DA35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (c), no digital platform shall be transferred or disposed of in any manner, voluntarily or involuntarily, directly or indirectly, or by transfer of control of any operator of such digital platform, to any person except upon application to the Commission and upon finding by the Commission that the public interest, convenience, and necessity will be served thereby. The Commission may grant or deny the application, or grant the application with conditions if the Commission finds that such conditions serve the public interest, convenience, or necessity.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F9FA084A0CB40018466AF126BD5DD40"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Commission shall issue rules that specify the procedures for review of applications under subsection (a), which may include procedures that are tailored to transactions of different sizes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H854053FF675F4510A683031C94E082C3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>The Commission may issue rules to exempt from review certain classes of digital platforms on the basis of size, or such other criteria as the Commission considers appropriate in the public interest, convenience, and necessity to achieve the purposes described in section 4(b).</text></subsection></section><section id="HD7E187B6E3644A4687FA845422D0008E"><enum>12.</enum><header>Petitions</header><subsection id="HB90FF5A2F74F47179005EBE1CD751907"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Petition for forbearance</header><paragraph id="H7EAAD05DF6634E2EB0DAA37FB3C48B64"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><subparagraph id="H3BE4BE7533CE4B00B59FAC2D1EF5628D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any digital platform or association of digital platforms may submit a petition to the Commission requesting that the Commission forbear the application and enforcement of a rule promulgated under this Act, including a behavioral code of conduct, technical standard, or other policy established by rule under section 8.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BCD121C60204D6F91D7805A333C4A44"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><clause id="H474149B95A1F40BB92CB64A8AAEE97C5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the Commission shall make a petition submitted under subparagraph (A) available to the public.</text></clause><clause id="H380490A9F97B4897A0D5D0201B189D6B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Commission may waive the requirement under clause (i) if the Commission makes the rationale for the waiver available to the public..</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE57E86F11B34C2E89D40A6ABA187278"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dismissal without prejudice</header><subparagraph id="HD624849EDEF1445D8BC322E0470AE089"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any petition submitted under paragraph (1) shall be deemed dismissed without prejudice if the Commission does not grant the petition within 18 months after the date on which the Commission receives the petition, unless the Commission extends the 18-month period under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51ABD2FE79444C38B0735C4392444661" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Commission may extend the initial 18-month period under subparagraph (A) by an additional 3 months.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A7826EEB7E48A6AB899C93CBCF78EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Scope of grant authority; written explanation</header><text>The Commission may grant or deny a petition submitted under paragraph (1) in whole or in part and shall explain its decision in writing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07EFA6A80F4B4738BF0E8F25EBD1D2C6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice and comment requirements</header><text>Section 553 of title 5, United States Code, shall apply to any determination of the Commission to forbear the application and enforcement of a rule under paragraph (1) of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE16393179E7047968B7515C114444D57" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State enforcement after Commission forbearance</header><text>A State commission may not continue to apply or enforce any rule, including any behavioral code, technical standard, or other policy established by rule, that the Commission has determined to forbear from applying under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H085963F1AC334234A0AB273509E2FE3F" commented="no"><enum>13.</enum><header>Research</header><subsection commented="no" id="HCF3033DFC9EE426F93DCF035D1D3A1D6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to carry out the purposes of this Act, the Commission shall establish an office with not fewer than 20 dedicated employees to conduct internal research, and collaborate with outside academics and experts, as appropriate, to further the purposes of the Commission under section 4(b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB73A34E3FC224CACBEF7C56AD098D911"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research grants</header><paragraph id="H4E60FB68B61D46AB82727E78A4050B4C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The office established under subsection (a) may competitively award grants to academic institutions and experts to conduct research consistent with the purposes of the Commission under section 4(b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E9AE5000B304EB29EE277B3FC7EB2BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>A recipient of a grant awarded under paragraph (1) shall make the findings of the research conducted using the grant publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7D720229F5F41F488D02DEE6E7FC0ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot research program for sensitive data</header><text>The Commission shall by rule establish a pilot program that allows vetted, nonprofit, financially disinterested academic institutions and experts to access data and other information collected from a digital platform by the Commission for the purposes of research and analysis consistent with the public interest, while—</text><paragraph id="H452B06A26AEF4C42B5D3CE2E2B821FA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensuring that no personally identifiable information of any user of the digital platform is publicly available; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7D2D1B4279F402EA7BD5316C4806614"><enum>(2)</enum><text>making every effort to—</text><subparagraph id="HA2E703ECA8CE4F66AFB4AAD1C780F6B3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>avoid harm to the business interests of the digital platform; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA535D9EAA007433F9FF9DAC82423A23F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure the safety and security of the private data and other information of the digital platform.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF80ED2E26E7B4367AA4F1AC6BB7590E7"><enum>14.</enum><header>Investigative authority</header><subsection id="HB7FB94AA02ED436085D0769A28F7E034"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may inquire into the management of the business of digital platforms subject to this Act, and shall keep itself informed as to the manner and method in which that management is conducted and as to technical and business developments in the provision of online services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H693FCABDC37A4ED1A601E511F2E40FDB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission may obtain from digital platforms subject to this Act and from persons directly or indirectly controlling or controlled by, or under direct or indirect control with, those platforms full and complete information necessary, including data flows, to enable the Commission to perform the duties and carry out the objects for which it was created.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD9DD7E4D2E6543328CCDC7ABEBA2F8E3"><enum>15.</enum><header>Enforcement by private persons and governmental entities</header><subsection id="H90A9F6E5ECF240AB96A95C26D97A8507"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Recovery of damages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person claiming to be damaged by any digital platform subject to this Act may—</text><paragraph id="H31C698CD961F43AC8938F3FD0DBC60C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make complaint to the Commission under subsection (b); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEA5951AA69F4CF59FF9794B9B254596"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">bring a civil action for enforcement of this Act, including the rules promulgated under this Act, in any district court of the United States of competent jurisdiction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83A5195594EC49308AE30845D34EDBEA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Complaints to the Commission</header><paragraph id="HBEE4FB85CACC4E5789865F879374D342"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H6E5DA7973C24416F9CEED7A5386776E5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Any person, any body politic or municipal organization, or any State attorney general or State commission, complaining of anything done or omitted to be done by any digital platform subject to this Act, in contravention of the provisions thereof, may apply to the Commission by petition which shall briefly state the facts, whereupon a statement of the complaint thus made shall be forwarded by the Commission to the digital platform, which shall be called upon to satisfy the complaint or to answer the complaint in writing within a reasonable time to be specified by the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE5A17B15626453F8B4EDD832DC76FAF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief of liability</header><text>If a digital platform described in subparagraph (A) within the time specified makes reparation for the injury alleged to have been caused, the platform shall be relieved of liability to the complainant only for the particular violation of law thus complained of.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B09666C9DC14A0A82FD5FB10421AF6C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Investigation</header><text>If a digital platform described in subparagraph (A) does not satisfy the complaint within the time specified or there shall appear to be any reasonable ground for investigating the complaint, the Commission shall investigate the matters complained of in such manner and by such means as the Commission determines proper.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A8099B8F0F3453195A0FA5863A9890E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Direct damage not required</header><text>No complaint shall at any time be dismissed because of the absence of direct damage to the complainant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE8E5597FFA0546FFB7D8D6CDB865E6F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Order</header><subparagraph id="HB33533F6A4324897AC3DAF0F384E7988"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall, with respect to any investigation under this subsection of the lawfulness of a charge, classification, regulation, or practice, issue an order concluding the investigation not later than 180 days after the date on which the complaint was filed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA106DB09BB824FC384B69FB1CEE49210"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Final order</header><text>Any order concluding an investigation under subparagraph (A) shall be a final order and may be appealed under section 16.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E7BD1B21674EB19C9EEB5CAE35C749"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Orders for payment of money</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, after hearing on a complaint under this paragraph, the Commission determines that any party complainant is entitled to an award of damages under this Act, the Commission shall make an order directing the digital platform to pay to the complainant the sum to which the complainant is entitled on or before a day named.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DC0BA28C360470F865D1CEE9C9062D4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by State attorneys general</header><text>If the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by any person who violates this Act or a rule promulgated under this Act, the attorney general of the State, as parens patrie, may bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in any district court of the United States of competent jurisdiction for enforcement of this Act, including the rules promulgated under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAACBC0C3B37443C7A29A086EB959B698" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Liability of digital platform for acts and omissions of agents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In construing and enforcing the provisions of this Act, the act, omission, or failure of any officer, agent, or other person acting for or employed by any digital platform or user, acting within the scope of his employment, shall in every case be also deemed to be the act, omission, or failure of the platform or user as well as that of the person.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE64C2579789541C9832C5D8C27FD95FD"><enum>16.</enum><header>Proceedings to enjoin, set aside, annul, or suspend orders of the Commission</header><subsection id="H9B8F6D06CC0B40C7AD452F1AD9E61040"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Right To appeal</header><text>An appeal may be taken from any decision or order of the Commission, by any person who is aggrieved or whose interests are adversely affected by the decision or order, to the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia or the United States court of appeals for the circuit in which the person resides.</text></subsection><subsection id="H176E9563E2874939A52407AB1ED67202"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Filing notice of appeal; contents; jurisdiction; temporary orders</header><paragraph id="H3C86E2CFA8364A079770310C3BDC6A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Filing notice of appeal</header><text>An appeal described in subsection (a) shall be taken by filing a notice of appeal with the appropriate United States court of appeals not later than 30 days after the date on which public notice is given of the decision or order complained of.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ABAD57442C64CE5913F99BA6B5CEBE4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A notice of appeal filed under paragraph (1) shall contain—</text><subparagraph id="H6E8D294054214F4C9D970766A34B8085"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a concise statement of the nature of the proceedings as to which the appeal is taken;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AE62FCE6CE8417BA5F24E9539597B24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a concise statement of the reasons on which the appellant intends to rely, separately stated and numbered; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5D5590A56FF4542ABF9C9FA30BC7A8D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>proof of service of a true copy of the notice and statements upon the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7A029C7A7AA4B22971B4650C76F57A3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Jurisdiction</header><text>Upon the filing of a notice of appeal with a United States court of appeals under paragraph (1), the court—</text><subparagraph id="H534E7F18D17D4DCFB1B33C7FC5827C3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall have jurisdiction of the proceedings and of the questions determined therein; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F55D5CE0AE147B5A7D8A319F8486280"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall have power, by order, directed to the Commission or any other party to the appeal, to grant such temporary relief as the court may deem just and proper.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H109AE910920147A5AC66A5BF584BBAF5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Temporary orders</header><text>An order granting temporary relief issued by the court under paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H3B5ADFF977204DF0AF66F3A23BCDE317"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be affirmative or negative in scope and application so as to permit—</text><clause id="HF1054077E0CE45EF9A0A8959B894DE83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the maintenance of the status quo in the matter in which the appeal is taken; or</text></clause><clause id="H5A4B59C7CCA34309BDB0F04E9F9C7F17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the restoration of a position or status terminated or adversely affected by the order appealed from; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H765EAE416BD24D5CAFAA78DFF003C3CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall, unless otherwise ordered by the court, be effective pending hearing and determination of the appeal and compliance by the Commission with the final judgment of the court rendered in the appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9065B5708F14D9589EA290637B5EE99"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to interested parties; filing of record</header><paragraph id="H41FA70A6013D46D3BDCD58860E0E4EDA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Notice to interested parties</header><text>Not later than 5 days after filing a notice of appeal under subsection (b), the appellant shall provide, to each person shown by the records of the Commission to be interested in the appeal, notice of—</text><subparagraph id="HA0BF741C12F3471490984F0E5A54F236"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the filing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H695F953CE8EA495DB3F1E26A7832A221"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the pendency of the appeal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H384885B6078845348B52A3424DE547EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Filing of record</header><text>The Commission shall file with the court the record upon which the order complained of was entered, as provided in section 2112 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52CC83CAF4F348B5AD6B85F78A90CDC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Intervention</header><paragraph id="H05106C900E124E3CAF2173A6AC029541"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Right to intervene</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the filing of an appeal described in subsection (a), any interested party may intervene and participate in the proceedings had upon the appeal by filing with the court—</text><subparagraph id="HCF86DC7967D5407C82DAD491AC1302E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a notice of intention to intervene and a verified statement showing the nature of the interest of the person; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27DDADCF09AC43FBAA8694A986DC6516"><enum>(B)</enum><text>proof of service of true copies of the notice and statement described in subparagraph (A) upon—</text><clause id="HBBC4C8E64F73487C8D00CB3E9019E6DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the appellant; and</text></clause><clause id="H0AA53615FFE74BFF9A766AC8D9AA7273"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Commission.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H490A7E83FBE14A0A918F15F22C9C5129"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interested party</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), any person who would be aggrieved or whose interest would be adversely affected by a reversal or modification of the order of the Commission complained of shall be considered an interested party.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AAF95A551DF4E4BB5E2CB661F107D92"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Record and briefs</header><text>The record and briefs upon which an appeal described in subsection (a) shall be heard and determined by the court shall contain such information and material, and shall be prepared within such time and in such manner, as the court may by rule prescribe.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE42A614ED7284F9BB6D278C23B661E24"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Time of hearing; procedure</header><text>The court shall hear and determine an appeal described in subsection (a) upon the record before it in the manner prescribed by section 706 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5B3B839EBC554A1583DA2D6F73E575C7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Remand</header><text>If the court renders a decision and enters an order reversing the order of the Commission—</text><paragraph id="HB6CA7D2954644F2E8DCA4F1873DC0FDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the court shall remand the case to the Commission to carry out the judgment of the court; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE961116D1CDA42728AAF43EC1C788D38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Commission, in the absence of proceedings to review the judgment under paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (i), shall forthwith give effect to the judgment, and unless otherwise ordered by the court, shall do so upon the basis of—</text><subparagraph id="HDB7149FEE586422180108375B4E27F2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proceedings already had; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H099C72B9173546C89AD91B2BC7EF129D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the record upon which the appeal was heard and determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E889907CC9D4D2284B370944B3F26D0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Judgment for costs</header><text>The court may, in its discretion, enter judgment for costs in favor of or against an appellant, or other interested parties intervening in the appeal, but not against the Commission, depending upon the nature of the issues involved in the appeal and the outcome of the appeal.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFBE7AA48AABB4A0B95E5AF33C1606516"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Finality of decision; review by Supreme Court</header><text>The judgment of a court of appeals under this section shall be final, subject to review by the Supreme Court of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HA0A9711B21674BA1BE52BEF8A41A77F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>upon writ of certiorari on petition therefor under section 1254 of title 28, United States Code, by—</text><subparagraph id="H81270FFBD1404CA6B46F01C249A9AE18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the appellant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3700EAEB930C4AFABB8FE56DA8FFE602"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Commission; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6989150BB0EE4F4598DED86E6A9B3935"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any interested party intervening in the appeal; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAEF34F613024663A17A746C5F1B52A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by certification by the court of appeals under such section 1254.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD10806DD84CF43D9B3AF2AE164BB89CE"><enum>17.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><subsection id="H05196E5A4276488BBF052C69EC32FC28"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not earlier than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall establish an independent panel to—</text><paragraph id="HD3BBEA42F0574D7DA8D5EE245117308C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">comprehensively study the policies, operations, and regulations of the Commission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD78ADCEF7F1343728AC6EC3E5B138411"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit an in-depth report to the congressional committees of jurisdiction, including the <committee-name committee-id="SSCM00">Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives</committee-name>, that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H0F14C12182E04D5AAC7B55A480F2252D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the effectiveness of the Commission in achieving the purposes under section 4(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54EAC343B8314EF088AFD6712272406D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommended reforms to strengthen the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC44F8DECBC4348DA996E929D2CA8247B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a recommendation regarding whether the Commission should continue in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5B08B9A7A3E147078F8B746E4857DAD7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The independent panel established under subsection (a) shall consist of 10 members, of whom—</text><paragraph id="HE647860CAF1F4FD1A043088235AB0574"><enum>(1)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the President;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00E95FC08C4B49AC84C6C48215606476"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D910132A0604AFE9E3FC5AFF79A8779"><enum>(3)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA704340D4B144902980BEF9B9B2E0F25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B6654559F743FE8B68EFC97A9A0894"><enum>(5)</enum><text>2 shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0BD5877486CE46FEA22EA808D5372904"><enum>18.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission to carry out the functions of the Commission—</text><paragraph id="HA4627185D3C3429DBF4FD54BB3893838"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H147AE586A5634A549CDB1F1990C81D00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CF3867668204D33988FF7F73064B80B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$300,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF14F458F8C93494FA090DB5AB3F30B5B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$450,000,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF647BA1799D44495A9820623A4FF25D3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2027 through 2032.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

