<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB76B6E591E3449A393C96DFB8AFD9EE9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8266 IH: Housing Innovation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8266</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an Office of Housing Innovation in the Department of Housing and Urban Development to assist in exploring and developing new approaches for increasing and diversifying the supply of housing and for meeting the challenges of housing shortages, housing affordability, and traffic congestion, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H076A94CC8F384910BD82470D9DADE1F1" style="OLC"><section id="HA40ABF10A0AB4F8B9C9D7189C4692C10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Innovation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8B2A4770D4AA48578C9215065078DE11"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HB1F2B1121B5940B2877360D4FDD2652E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>housing should be considered a critical component of our national infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58F8C5FCF6094E4696BD9EE5996FB787"><enum>(2)</enum><text>existing shortages of affordable housing options in many regions are contributing to long commutes, financial stress, environmental pollution, and public health risk;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C735B568A3441E1AF8E43BA1E71C0F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>new approaches in the planning, design, and construction of housing need to be explored for diversifying housing options available to the workforce; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H273C19DEC5264092B5344DF6A02B91C6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">greater coordination of existing Federal resources across agencies could significantly expand and diversify the supply of housing.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2CA09711E8D4486AAC981CD40142E410"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Housing Innovation; Assistant Secretary</header><subsection id="H138471B4C4424FEEBFD8EEBCF2CA49DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary for Housing Innovation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 4(a) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3533">42 U.S.C. 3533(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF7F436118E41465C9E6F4E4FDA2BFF4C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>7 Assistant Secretaries</quote> and inserting <quote>9 Assistant Secretaries</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64428DE5E64B4A32855286DE00E0CB17"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1E275A109CE457AA760A2A24FB780D2" style="OLC"><subsection id="H57C0C3CC4C9E491B8781682DC48FAC4D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Office of Housing Innovation</header><paragraph id="H2A69930E9061462FB43F32130A2CB20C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be in the Department an Assistant Secretary for Housing Innovation, who shall be appointed by the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C5776B61A7249E18A605DE2F5892292"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Department the Office of Housing Innovation, which shall be headed by the Assistant Secretary for Housing Innovation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55991C1CD497495BA384DDB4DD06B07F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Assistant Secretary of Housing Innovation shall have primary responsibility within the Department for—</text><subparagraph id="HFE6CBDD90B89427BA1C830BE7F7EE7D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accumulating and disseminating information regarding innovative practices and successful case studies of new approaches for increasing and diversifying the supply of housing, especially in urban metropolitan regions and surrounding rural regions that are facing challenges of housing shortages, housing affordability, and traffic congestion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C70451319A43B781559E16864D0C42"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carrying out activities, including administering the grant programs under the <short-title>Housing Innovation Act of 2022</short-title>, to encourage partnerships in exploring and developing innovative solutions to the challenges to housing supply referred to in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77E4DCF249294A7A99B0A006F92881BA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinating with other offices within the Department, including the Office of Housing, the Office of Policy Development and Research, and the Office of Community Planning and Development, and other Federal agencies, including the Department of Transportation, to recommend policies that address workforce housing needs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC700254798E3416980FFB4AE179AAE1D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing technical assistance to local governments in undertaking or preparing for planning and policy reforms to increase housing units and housing supply diversity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1ADA3A0697C4D3A82892152C7778A18"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the staff of the Office of Housing Innovation includes, at all times—</text><subparagraph id="H5463E56906E44CE7BDBB1F7ECE11223E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">two detailees from the Department of Transportation, who shall include—</text><clause id="H97B53722DF924101AF2CC50EE7DA3223"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one having expertise in transit issues or active transportation issues, or both; and</text></clause><clause id="H6234941A177749B781DD3F4A644933DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one from the Build America Bureau having expertise on the Transportation Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act (TIFIA) program and the Railroad Rehabilitation and Improvement Financing (RRIF) program;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7396E8E9EB994B7697EFAE5E2F8827B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one detailee from the Environmental Protection Agency having expertise on the public health impacts of housing and community development; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC6A18EB94AD4DD8B55D14E7A504710A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>one detailee from the Department of Energy having expertise on renewable energy and energy efficiency upgrades for low- and moderate-income communities.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">The Secretary shall consult with the heads of the agencies referred to in this paragraph to provide for such details and such details shall be made on a reimbursable basis.</continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H716ECA5530424D239B2A550B5364C7D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amendments to title 5, United States Code</header><paragraph id="HA8432AF058C2462CB5654B5A8FD4C1D5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Positions at level iv of Executive Schedule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, is amended in the undesignated item relating to Assistant Secretaries of Housing and Urban Development by striking <quote>(8)</quote> and inserting <quote>(9)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9ED1118ABF74832B02BF054E412F995"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Paragraph (1) of section 4(a) of the Department of Housing and Urban Development Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3533">42 U.S.C. 3533(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>7</quote> and inserting <quote>8</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB14D7A7D7BF8414AAC41ED998E3A9E56"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for necessary salaries and expenses of the Office of Housing Innovation of the Department of Housing and Urban Development $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2023 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></subsection></section><section id="H910C41606C9B4D8C91BBAEB3AA23611E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grants for local planning for housing</header><subsection id="H50D6F71219784F24A3F2DA7041454A11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), acting through the Assistant Secretary of Housing Innovation, shall carry out a program to make grants under this section to eligible localities for undertaking planning efforts and associated regulatory reforms that address the housing needs of such areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF921119F9A314195A703BAF124FFA60B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible localities</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>eligible locality</quote> means a unit of general local government that is located within an urbanized area, as such term is defined by the United States Census Bureau of the Department of Commerce.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA33E8B70F5D64E479439E0CABFB80484"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Local plans developed using amounts from grants under this section shall address all of the following goals:</text><paragraph id="H29FC0C48E66E43399F5D4BBF13DC856B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Increasing the supply of housing units within the jurisdiction of the grantee or within certain defined areas within such jurisdiction, including neighborhoods around existing or planned transit facilities and job centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B33267883F84E24AE5F0449ADA3C89D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving the affordability of the housing supply within the jurisdiction of the grantee or within certain defined areas within such jurisdiction, including neighborhoods around existing or planned transit facilities and job centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H707C86D177AD4345814E7D907E923574"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Diversifying the housing supply within the jurisdiction of the grantee or within certain defined areas within such jurisdiction to include more multifamily housing options or newer and less common forms of housing, such as multifamily housing focused on smaller private spaces and more shared amenities, micro-unit housing, housing developments that incorporate co-working spaces, and housing for students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H959F4770FAD94FA9AF01B8120FAEC368"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improving commute times to job sites, reducing congestion, or reducing vehicle miles traveled within the region in which the locality is located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4AE3C2F610584EC59FF15910C91A0023"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that amounts from a grant under this section shall be used only for costs associated with a housing planning process that addresses the goals in subsection (c), including public outreach, community meetings, preparation of planning documents, and research and studies in support of such planning efforts.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32B936C65D14415D9696EE99C534212C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants to eligible localities submitting applications under subsection (g) that are selected to receive grants under a competition based on criteria established by the Secretary, which shall include the following criteria:</text><paragraph id="H2BFBB600FF764E0486AF77A172B6E9DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the eligible locality outlines a planning process that will facilitate progress toward the goals under subsection (c), including the potential changes or updates to local policies and regulations (such as zoning ordinances, parking requirements, general plans, and specific plans) that such a planning process will aim to affect.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7328276E023648BA96BC3433430E8DE2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the eligible locality demonstrates how the planning process will address the needs of the metropolitan region within which the eligible locality is located by providing housing for the existing and projected workforce demand.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09A647D493154F919FB23DB6479B8756"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the eligible locality provides details of the planning actions it intends to take, including public outreach activities and actions for consideration for formal policy adoption of planning elements and recommendations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AC2602B331B42568B80FD097FBD6B45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The extent to which the eligible locality specifies a timeline for completion of its planning process, including potential dates for consideration for formal policy adoption by the local governing body.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H183588897D91464085E4FB4436F68E1A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the eligible locality demonstrates collaboration with regional planning efforts and coordination with the relevant metropolitan planning organization that manages regional planning for the area within which the locality is located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56DEA3A2F5D046A0B6E9ED2F33936C73"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on amount</header><text>A grant under this section for an eligible locality may not exceed $2,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E9D9E473FC241CF8D54586AD8A31813"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for eligible localities to submit applications to the Secretary for grants under this section, which shall contain such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC976C4048B104BFBA90C050ACA3B9E4E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Grants for research and pilot projects</header><subsection id="H25732DDC8E534A4C911D5382AA2E4C18"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Housing Innovation, shall carry out a program to make grants under this section to eligible partnerships for the purposes of carrying out research and pilot studies to support, inform, and advise local governments on their plans for new housing and community development.</text></subsection><subsection id="H826CDDD30D9145D9A22F5032B3BF32CF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible partnerships</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>eligible partnership</quote> means a partnership of entities and institutions that includes at least one of the following entities:</text><paragraph id="H65F4DD29CFFF470F9843D573DFD7F3B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A unit of local government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEFFB368517D460585792496596D5331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A college, university, or other research institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H321A81D7CBE64C39BF260C07558DC79C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A nonprofit organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H086C686900D54F25AC928FC1B88465B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Amounts from a grant under this section may only be used for research and pilot studies that are designed to study and investigate activities and measures for improving housing and commuting for the workforce in a community, including—</text><paragraph id="HFD095CB21A9E49B4B3205C8FF23F5B22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>measures to improve the commuting experience between transit stations and homes (commonly referred to as the <quote>last mile</quote>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36B6F50370FF4CD6AFB3345E40037AB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>programs for accommodating higher education students within the community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A80092F407A4362AE223EB49A57905C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>programs for facilitating home-sharing for elderly residents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H668621D179EB4D0787F7E08D114CC567"><enum>(4)</enum><text>plans and measures for integrating business and commercial activity with residential neighborhoods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62B9225A7791469CA51B552CE47F9CF3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>plans and measures for increasing transportation options improving mobility within residential neighborhoods;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8770BA49BE6849D597E2228848025535"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs for learning and disseminating information about modular building techniques and other approaches to reducing housing construction costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C1D12262F104B5FA4E38848390A44E9"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plans or programs for improving public health through changes in the built environment, such as safer streets that are more conducive and welcoming to pedestrian activity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69CCF77865B448AF86EFD376ED5EBC19"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures to evaluate the impact of housing development in the community on the long-term social mobility and economic prospects of residents; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H197F8B2C64DC4EAAB0EA3324B0D721D0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>such other measures, plans, and activities as applicants may propose, but only if the Secretary approves such proposals as consistent with the goals under section 4(c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A91696B4C6146B4B60DA639E35B217F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitations on amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section for an eligible partnership may not exceed the lesser of—</text><paragraph id="H9EDFFA9A6FCA4040BF9B532CE055CAD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$500,000; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H039A7657E4A64496925853BCECFD5A4D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case only of an eligible partnership that has previously received a grant under this section, the amount that the eligible partnership certifies, as the Secretary shall require, that the partnership will contribute from non-Federal sources for activities described in subsection (c) that are assisted with such grant amounts.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H200270FA2B204BBCA305ECB8F7A4AAAD"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grants for education activities</header><subsection id="H6D516DEB75EB40B8BA268DDDA1786591"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Housing Innovation, shall carry out a program under this section to make grants to partnerships that include at least one academic institution for providing support for educational and community outreach programs that are focused on issues related to housing, community development, and regional planning.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1EE408CA53A41F1BBCEB772A9807A15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations on amount</header><text>A grant under this section for a partnership may not exceed the lesser of—</text><paragraph id="HB10963B926B14089B0EEFBBAE061B7AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$200,000; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1CEA2E3AE8B407E9E3A383B89D7F90E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case only of a partnership that has previously received a grant under this section, the amount that the partnership certifies, as the Secretary shall require, that the partnership will contribute from non-Federal sources for educational and community outreach programs described in subsection (a) that are assisted with such grant amounts.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDAB6C87BE54B40898F4BA6C21E30809C"><enum>7.</enum><header>GAO review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 3-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a review of grant programs under sections 4, 5, and 6 of this Act to analyze the effectiveness of such programs and shall submit a report containing the results of such review and any conclusions resulting from such review to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></section><section id="H0A761F08DD3F4D979B1158DC7D0F1DE9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may issue any regulations necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section><section id="H21889F880BFC4703B7C03E8788098437"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HEB22F859F40648889A8996BE288000A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out this Act $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2029 of which, in each fiscal year—</text><paragraph id="HB19EE25ADD504C2EA6573880F009A78C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>90 percent shall be available only for grants under section 4;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25091CB525AC4981B014E4DD980CC919"><enum>(2)</enum><text>5 percent shall be available only for grants under section 5; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD798A8D06C804D9692F7F01491AA0A74"><enum>(3)</enum><text>5 percent shall be available only for grants under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11BCBFE26A4C48E5AD799E74812AA2B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Source of funding</header><text>It is the sense of the Congress that the funding to carry out this Act provided pursuant to subsection (a) should not result in a reduction of Federal funding for any existing affordable housing program or programs.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

