<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1C6DD293F58A442E818DF63E59E2F04F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 9010 IH: Taiwan Policy Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9010</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000292">Mr. Johnson of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000589">Mr. Gooden of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for United States policy toward Taiwan.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE88EC02B8C5341EEB9FFB21452551C70" style="OLC"><section id="HA66B021FCD0343F999E2411C01E12515" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H53C37854CCE7493786E1C4A880AFFFFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Taiwan Policy Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4340593CABAC4DB9BEAAB04F87DC5D36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HA66B021FCD0343F999E2411C01E12515" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB3339CB6FA1247149FFB852759140FB7" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3706FF04EE6846488C0E40BEA015B7C5" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H61FE89486DBC4CF7958D09FB0AC1AEAE" level="title">Title I—United States policy toward Taiwan</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8B2A3D76B30C4C4196824223B38A8DB1" level="section">Sec. 101. Declaration of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE7315F1276154E69ABECE63B22480DE2" level="section">Sec. 102. Treatment of the Government of Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H261A75B91D75471A87D5DB06C7E11ED3" level="section">Sec. 103. Reauthorization of Taiwan Assurance Act of 2020.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB4224B1DDA9E49E4B335CDDA1EA8FBA0" level="section">Sec. 104. Prohibition on maps depicting Taiwan as part of the territory of the People’s Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H22DF5B71ABC448F69962CB5C9016CF3F" level="section">Sec. 105. Taiwan symbols of sovereignty.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE629DE9D0AE1408DA2F0E96417BD949F" level="section">Sec. 106. Designation and references to Taiwan Representative Office.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H04A659F3C8DF4826874CFAACC0A9C8EB" level="section">Sec. 107. Clarifying amendments.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H06FFA25B98A849EEBD2A283770E4487D" level="section">Sec. 108. Senate confirmation of the Director of the Taipei office of the American Institute in Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H21908A681B1E4B4293757625BCA834EF" level="title">Title II—Implementation of an enhanced defense partnership between the United States and Taiwan</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE6276233E495407792540B431914A95E" level="section">Sec. 201. Increasing the strategic clarity of United States policy towards Taiwan’s defense.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB2D4BA673A974CA7A35B0196472E0C5E" level="section">Sec. 202. Security assistance to modernize Taiwan’s security capabilities to deter and defeat aggression by the People's Republic of China.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1168F25DB868411CAF57269C5D12E977" level="section">Sec. 203. Anticipatory planning and annual review of the United States strategy to defend Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5B43B1F9D0624B7DB5CB370F550D529E" level="section">Sec. 204. Joint assessment.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9228A0414BB54399B8C627BCAF4D24C9" level="section">Sec. 205. Requirements regarding definition of counter intervention capabilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H95C9C0BE8F0C4E77907B72A0F7B2AF78" level="section">Sec. 206. Comprehensive training program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFD86E77036C3485D91E895D7F07EE612" level="section">Sec. 207. Joint exercises with Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H77C0B13C6D3E4225992AA89923A5B6D8" level="section">Sec. 208. Assessment of Taiwan’s needs for civilian defense and resilience.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2B0419DDCC924B5EAA94BA8EEAF65586" level="section">Sec. 209. Annual report on cooperation between the National Guard and Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF79B41AB978B4A52AE3D39DC923A2107" level="section">Sec. 210. Prioritizing excess defense article transfers for Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFF5B00BCF6F74A99B56BCB3191689B68" level="section">Sec. 211. Fast-tracking sales to Taiwan under the Foreign Military Sales program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H775D5D5727724831A3988DA0B7BFD9D9" level="section">Sec. 212. Arms export delivery solutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5A0F67FAAE234309AB5A9036C94738C6" level="section">Sec. 213. Whole-of-government deterrence measures to respond to the People's Republic of China's force against Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6937B522EB6942B89B55D8BE602AC62D" level="section">Sec. 214. Increase in annual regional contingency stockpile additions and support for Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3E34C435F5B541EAA7B8BBD9518B978A" level="section">Sec. 215. Emergency drawdown authority of Taiwan Strait contingencies.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA7AE4DBDA19F4B45A38C15EC9FAE5A71" level="section">Sec. 216. Designation of Taiwan as a major non-NATO ally.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC979AB57A398416782152341B26A4838" level="title">Title III—Countering People’s Republic of China’s aggression and influence campaigns</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA7C43899A7E94D6AB7C0A1E138F2060E" level="section">Sec. 301. Strategy to respond to influence and information operations targeting Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H8C1F5BB6ED2F4CFD941A1DF61EAA003B" level="section">Sec. 302. Strategy to counter economic coercion by the People's Republic of China targeting countries and entities that support Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H53978E1C97DE459D850D2F032D15B85B" level="section">Sec. 303. Shared planning for the defense of Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3FB09BB194AF4770B9A69F1DD4B40D16" level="title">Title IV—Inclusion of Taiwan in international organizations</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H793A735233144747867753B1AF7838D9" level="section">Sec. 401. Participation of Taiwan in international organizations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H98BD5DA14CFC456D920DBB1E8BD74E08" level="section">Sec. 402. Clarification regarding United Nations General Assembly Resolution 2758 (XXVI).</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H86B644717A584288B9D4E262A36AA885" level="section">Sec. 403. Participation of Taiwan in the Inter-American Development Bank.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2134789848DC4E64AD49F9BEA4C38750" level="section">Sec. 404. Plan for Taiwan's participation in the Inter-American Development Bank.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3971FF8E954E4CDF87B7F412179E8A2B" level="section">Sec. 405. Report concerning member state status for Taiwan at the Inter-American Development Bank.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFF7493BFB9E44625A8BFF40D0A7CEC47" level="section">Sec. 406. Support for Taiwan admission to the IMF.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE99FDDCD36F546A191208083212B0359" level="section">Sec. 407. Meaningful participation of Taiwan in the International Civil Aviation Organization.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0192E83C68704738BEB5708CF4D5198E" level="title">Title V—Enhanced development and economic cooperation between the United States and Taiwan</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H833E1DC052724C0DAEAA9B75A78309B3" level="section">Sec. 501. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H54E034CA8EF942A29ECBC4DE7B0FBEFD" level="section">Sec. 502. Sense of Congress on a free trade agreement and bilateral tax agreement with Taiwan, the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, and CBP Preclearance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H044965E3B4624519B0B3B06BC639BD83" level="section">Sec. 503. Sense of Congress on United States-Taiwan development cooperation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7D62C6CD561D4F5F963A00153B4C6FD1" level="section">Sec. 504. Report.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC15BAEAD2F7E447F9194E8C3854AD6A1" level="title">Title VI—Taiwan Fellowship Program</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6A21415499864B99A1F84D5FCB5E13D2" level="section">Sec. 601. Taiwan Fellowship Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4BA62A678C094E07A1B41BFD761AF751" level="title">Title VII—Miscellaneous provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H92A05407E8D446BB94B607E676633951" level="section">Sec. 701. Invitation of Taiwanese counterparts to high-level bilateral and multilateral forums and exercises.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA3BA00923B3F4B58941737399D7EB2BF" level="section">Sec. 702. Report on Taiwan Travel Act.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1A8FD0918E0B49B2BEC973985D989ED8" level="section">Sec. 703. Authorization of Global Cooperation and Training Framework.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA9DFC90DBFE44AFCB63CE2E3BB894E9D" level="section">Sec. 704. Prohibitions against undermining United States policy regarding Taiwan.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H6C644332025C403D9516FA48090A10DB" level="section">Sec. 705. Amendments to the Taiwan Allies International Protection and Enhancement Initiative (Taipei) Act of 2019.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2E489EBEB2EF454C8DDDD9664C510A2A" level="section">Sec. 706. Rule of construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HED44F2F94E0545AAAC4B89E670C81AAC" level="section">Sec. 707. Consolidation of reports.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HB3339CB6FA1247149FFB852759140FB7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H7014641FA3A94716916A15C1528E317D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since 1949, the close relationship between the United States and Taiwan has been of enormous benefit to both parties and to the Indo-Pacific region as a whole.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E91DB4806EE45D896015E711C47F394"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>) has enabled the people of the United States and the people of Taiwan to maintain a strong and important relationship that promotes regional security, prosperity, and shared democratic values.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC65B683E68B40B784922B2B05B71EDF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The security of Taiwan and the ability for the people of Taiwan to determine their own future is fundamental to United States interests and values.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC396C062519B4B798DAE129D9550DEF6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States and the American Institute in Taiwan facilitate critical consular relations that—</text><subparagraph id="H4A02E0F9359542539B143341972522B1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>protect the interests of the people of the United States and the people of Taiwan; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63CE2BF735F341E28A5E23DEB76F097A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strengthen people-to-people ties.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H27F583E742BF4AF9B00A4D5FE03E0FB3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Increased engagement between public officials, commercial interests, civil society leaders, and others enhances United States-Taiwan relations and its economic, security, and democratic dimensions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F6C0F4B8ABE474982160B7C6AFBAD65"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Taiwan serves as a critical partner on regional and transnational issues, such as public health, climate change, critical and emerging technologies, cybersecurity, trade, and freedom of navigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0798E03C291C40728F7513145DC3A5BA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Taiwan exemplifies a thriving democracy consisting of more than 23,000,000 people who value their suffrage, free markets, right to due process, freedom of expression, and other individual liberties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A9D72DA9B8642EE8185DE131C674C5A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>President Xi Jinping of the People’s Republic of China (referred to in this Act as the <quote>PRC</quote>) continues to repeat his desire to stifle the freedom of Taiwan, as evidenced by his July 2021 proclamation, in which he stated, <quote>All sons and daughters of China, including compatriots on both sides of the Taiwan Strait, must work together and move forward in solidarity, resolutely smashing any Taiwan independence plots.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9579ECDA2E2E46F28C85CB33F06C8AAC"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As President Xi Jinping consolidates his power in the Chinese Communist Party (referred to in this Act as the <quote>CCP</quote>), he is escalating the PRC’s campaign of coercion and intimidation against Taiwan, as evidenced by—</text><subparagraph id="H52901BCF1E7C4A4B8AFA84B02036C5C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the accelerated preparations made by the PRC and its People’s Liberation Army (referred to in this Act as the <quote>PLA</quote>) for an offensive attack against Taiwan, such as the PLA's January 2022 incursion of nearly 40 fighters, bombers, and other warplanes into Taiwan’s air defense identification zone;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H668BCB5D70564D7380AEF477D49B7E55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the PLA’s growing offensive preparations in the Taiwan Strait, such as amphibious assault and live-fire exercises and record-scale incursions into Taiwanese air space;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976774D2F48342CD8DC5997C7FCF98A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Foreign Ministry’s diplomatic efforts to isolate Taiwan, such as abusing its position in international institutions and multilateral fora to exclude Taiwanese participation despite Taiwan’s demonstrated expertise in relevant subjects, such as public health;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91875A6B6605474EA4DCFB733441C340"><enum>(D)</enum><text>threats and actions to compromise Taiwan’s economy and critical suppliers, such as draconian export controls and the <quote>31 Measures</quote> intended to lure Taiwanese talent to mainland China and away from Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B7761FBFAB642B5AB815529ACECDFC3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>persistent and targeted cyberattacks, numbering nearly 20,000,000 per month, which are intended to compromise Taiwan’s critical infrastructure and inflict civilian harm;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9092E8C78C9D44DDBD7C32CCB06F4FEE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>political and economic pressure on other countries who seek closer ties with Taiwan, such as recent export controls related to Lithuania after Lithuania announced a permanent Taiwanese Representative Office in Lithuania.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF81979FDC7334F2C9F734B39EB71B37E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>On multiple occasions, through both formal and informal channels, the United States has expressed its concern for the PRC’s destabilizing activities in the Taiwan Strait and on the international stage that aim to subvert Taiwan’s democratic institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1501929CBCD0465E9DFEEF9F883BDBBE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Indo-Pacific Strategy of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="H3D16E58EDA9E4423BCDA5249B79C081D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies Taiwan as an important leading regional partner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32E69576D8164D758870F5AE94F673DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seeks to bolster Taiwan’s self-defense capabilities; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H535A458E40714566B41C441379F08703"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reaffirms that Taiwan’s future must be determined peacefully and in accordance with the wishes and best interests of the people of Taiwan. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD560EAD12B4B4A1EB21748F918756E3C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The PRC considers stifling the freedom of Taiwan as a critical and necessary step to displacing the United States as the preeminent military power in the Indo-Pacific and continues its modernization campaign to enhance the power-projection capabilities of the PLA and its ability to conduct joint operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEF581F1B9124913A4ECE0520A211DDD"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Taiwan maintains a modern, ready, self-defense force that adheres to the highest democratic principles and benefits from continued state-of-the-art security assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H634A2358AD964BDC954CE8BFE93F90DE"><enum>(14)</enum><text>It is a vital national security interest of the United States to defend Taiwan for the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="H897BC169077C4A21AC59246AFC7F1C09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mitigating the PLA’s ability to project power and establish contested zones within the First and Second Island Chains and limiting the PLA’s freedom of maneuver to conduct unconstrained power projection capabilities beyond the First Island Chain in order to protect United States territory, such as Hawaii and Guam;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49301A4743634B829DFA9D914D1F7B2E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>defending the territorial integrity of Indo-Pacific allies, such as Japan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CF15D1FB7224532976E38BC346D63B7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>deterring other countries and competitors from exercising force as a means to revise the established status quo;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBEED186C64C4786AA59240E7B6AFE5B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>championing democratic institutions and societies in the Indo-Pacific region and throughout the world; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF40D9D5AE604AA2872D6C669540F87A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>maintaining a rules-based international order that—</text><clause id="H00FFF58953574180960944EACF3B3591"><enum>(i)</enum><text>constrains authoritarian powers;</text></clause><clause id="HE0871766895F40E5B4E16DD6B810088C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enshrines collective security;</text></clause><clause id="H7EA78778E9E94507B7FBB3A67016AC56"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promotes democracy and respect for human rights and fundamental freedoms; and </text></clause><clause id="H8147785413BF45799F2C79962A7CF0C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>promotes peace and prosperity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H3706FF04EE6846488C0E40BEA015B7C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H9007873CD8024C4684E587DB6A5EBDEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided in this Act, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H34CB720002A542628C0E3C9AE3432624"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAS00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7EEFDE249DD4292A04C9194AF11E048"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Armed Services of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H644F94A1FB0849658CAC33599B7C8415" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSAP00">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H80A769894FF04368B924156945373C43"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H947733CC257C4640B39B28569A4AE527"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9218053445A743C19766E36F750ECA2B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA9473FA156843EABCD4F160262D4CCD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>People’s Liberation Army; PLA</header><text>The terms <term>People’s Liberation Army</term> and <term>PLA</term> mean the Armed Forces of the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HDD678BB2F4A246B19732618DF6B8E904"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Republic of China</header><text>The term <term>Republic of China</term> means the East Asia island country commonly known as <quote>Taiwan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H571025A0B10A49329EAE4BAF23DD53A4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sharp power</header><text>The term <term>sharp power</term> means the coordinated and often concealed application of disinformation, media manipulation, economic coercion, cyber-intrusions, targeted investments, and academic censorship that is intended—</text><subparagraph id="HF204109DB5514F17B22E06BE0AC6D6D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to corrupt political and nongovernmental institutions and interfere in democratic elections and encourage self-censorship of views at odds with those of the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02BA7F3D6E0D46708366377781A74EAB" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to foster attitudes, behavior, decisions, or outcomes in Taiwan and elsewhere that support the interests of the Government of the People's Republic of China or the Chinese Communist Party. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><title id="H61FE89486DBC4CF7958D09FB0AC1AEAE" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>United States policy toward Taiwan</header><section id="H8B2A3D76B30C4C4196824223B38A8DB1"><enum>101.</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H9E44D1B9D142490EB8D8C561FE668666"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support the security of Taiwan, the stability of cross-Strait relations, and the freedom of the people of Taiwan to determine their own future, and to strenuously oppose any action by the PRC to use force to change the status quo of Taiwan; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79F448893AC2438A85F18D6B99FFFFE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to cooperate with Taiwan as an important partner of the United States in promoting a free and open Indo-Pacific;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H112DEF896A494E059ECF0649525C5290"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to deter the use of force by the PRC to change the status quo of Taiwan by coordinating with allies and partners to identify and develop significant economic, diplomatic, and other measures that will deter and impose costs on any such use of force and support and cooperate with Taiwan to implement, resource, and modernize its military capabilities, including an effective defense strategy, through security assistance and increases in defense spending; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD220986A5EF040A4BF2F6406AE630FC3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to strengthen cooperation with the military of Taiwan under the framework of the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Six Assurances, with consideration of the ongoing military buildup in China and the military balance in the Taiwan Strait, and to transfer defense articles to Taiwan to enhance its capabilities, including its efforts to undertake defensive operations and maintain the ability to deny PRC coercion and invasion; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H249830C2D3494A7199B8B3970586AEAD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to urge Taiwan to increase its own investments in military capabilities, including those that support the implementation of an effective defense strategy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H981F010CA87D486A8E93B39182B544F3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to advance and finalize key provisions of the United States-Taiwan Trade and Investment Framework Agreement and deepen economic ties between the United States and Taiwan and advance the interests of the United States by negotiating a bilateral free trade agreement as soon as possible, which will include appropriate levels of labor rights and environmental protections; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE9611701AA3450C848C60F7D012EDE1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to include Taiwan as a partner in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DA385A16E664671937E0309C0DBEDF0"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to welcome Taiwan's meaningful participation in important international organizations, including organizations that address global health, civilian air safety, and efforts to counter transnational crime and bilateral and multilateral security summits, military exercises, and economic dialogues and forums; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ADF9A61BAAF44058CA869A7A1115B89"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to support the Government of Taiwan as a representative democratic government, constituted through free and fair elections that reflect the will of the people of Taiwan and promote dignity and respect for the democratically elected leaders of Taiwan, who represent more than 23,000,000 citizens, by using the full range of diplomatic and other appropriate tools available to promote Taiwan’s international space; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77933E379AFD43EA90EA69BA6AFF8764"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to ensure that distinctions in practice regarding United States relations with Taiwan are consistent with the longstanding, comprehensive, strategic, and values-based relationship the United States shares with Taiwan, and contribute to the peaceful resolution of cross-Strait issues; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF730981753AB4E5FBA96DEF5E3D39AC8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>to create and execute a plan for enhancing our relationship with Taiwan by forming a robust partnership that—</text><subparagraph id="HC328416229024CE39F7ADF596E73DE61"><enum>(A)</enum><text>meets current geopolitical challenges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B0B71165C98456FAFD2AD82C48CAB37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fully accounts for Taiwan’s democratic status; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D7FB8B700E4490D88D25467C9980802"><enum>(C)</enum><text>remains faithful to United States principles and values, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act and the Six Assurances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HE7315F1276154E69ABECE63B22480DE2"><enum>102.</enum><header>Treatment of the Government of Taiwan</header><subsection id="HF9BE9601CA054B51A8014B82076E2046" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and other Federal departments and agencies shall—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HB7E50CEED9BD4C7E917EF66AF9E1CAED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engage with the democratically elected government of Taiwan as the legitimate representative of the people of Taiwan; and </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H11938568EA204303BDDA55F842631ACD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>end the outdated practice of referring to the government in Taiwan as the <quote>Taiwan authorities</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H75292D6138DC494E8D2CE91356491658"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No restrictions on bilateral interactions</header><text>Notwithstanding the continued supporting role of the American Institute in Taiwan in carrying out United States foreign policy and protecting United States interests in Taiwan, the United States Government shall not place any undue restrictions on the ability of officials of the Department of State or other Federal departments and agencies to interact directly and routinely with their counterparts in the Government of Taiwan.</text></subsection></section><section id="H261A75B91D75471A87D5DB06C7E11ED3"><enum>103.</enum><header>Reauthorization of Taiwan Assurance Act of 2020</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 315 of the Taiwan Assurance Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H0BCA8FD9BAD2405DBE97987F48F76263"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by adding at the end before <quote>; and</quote> the following: <quote>and any successor document or related document disseminating such policies</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA20052ACA2F64FD7BC2A0A8385E90916"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H64643AFB9CD14F6C857CFFB41F3D243A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HBBDC0AF4E42E432FB082A7113486ECEA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Periodic reviews</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For as long as the Department of State’s guidance that governs relations with Taiwan described in subsection (a) remains in effect, the Secretary of State shall conduct periodic reviews as described in subsection (a) and submit updated reports as described in subsection (c) not less frequently than every two years following the submission of the initial report described in subsection (c).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HB4224B1DDA9E49E4B335CDDA1EA8FBA0"><enum>104.</enum><header>Prohibition on maps depicting Taiwan as part of the territory of the People’s Republic of China</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds authorized or appropriated for the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Millennium Challenge Corporation, the United States Development Finance Corporation, or the Peace Corps may be used to create, procure, or display any map that depicts Taiwan, Kinmen, Matsu, Penghu, Wuqiu, Green Island, or Orchid Island as part of the territory of the People’s Republic of China. </text></section><section id="H22DF5B71ABC448F69962CB5C9016CF3F"><enum>105.</enum><header>Taiwan symbols of sovereignty</header><subsection id="HE2F0E0C167264E4EB6C78587E200C052"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this section, the term <term>official purposes</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HE24D8245D73A46A7A0A3809DBD8D38FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the wearing of official uniforms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09FA37B9197849C5895B195DFF64B893"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conducting government-hosted ceremonies or functions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9C336E85F84487A8AB48D1678F98568" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>appearances on Department of State social media accounts promoting engagements with Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E079601D581451DB709ADB30F1390DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall rescind any contact guideline, internal restriction, section of the Foreign Affairs Manual or the Foreign Affairs Handbook, or related guidance or policies that, explicitly or implicitly, including through restrictions or limitations on activities of United States Government personnel, limits the ability of members of the Armed Forces of the Republic of China (Taiwan) and government representatives from the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office to display, for official purposes, symbols of Republic of China sovereignty, including—</text><paragraph id="H87A8953B881445A2B1DBDADF4135F174"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the flag of the Republic of China (Taiwan); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B97C1191BCD4EAF9947462517AFA522"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the corresponding emblems or insignia of military units.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE629DE9D0AE1408DA2F0E96417BD949F"><enum>106.</enum><header>Designation and references to Taiwan Representative Office</header><subsection id="H8217C3CA2ABA4EAFA8D85BCA7BD7A085"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States, consistent with the Taiwan Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/8">Public Law 96–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Six Assurances—</text><paragraph id="H7A39EA06D1FB430E8A59D08E06319EEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide the people of Taiwan with de facto diplomatic treatment equivalent to foreign countries, nations, states, governments, or similar entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB18BFEE48B4F4A65A023B72D85D3B9E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to rename the <quote>Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office</quote> in the United States as the <quote>Taiwan Representative Office</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78D7CB548D5949AC9C8A7F7FDD54D057"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Renaming</header><text>The Secretary of State shall seek to enter into negotiations with the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office to rename its office in Washington, DC, the <quote>Taiwan Representative Office</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE70D887776FD4FF0806F063FEDD65F02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>If the negotiations under subsection (b) result in the renaming of the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office as the Taiwan Representative Office, any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States Government to the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office shall be deemed to be a reference to the Taiwan Representative Office, including for all official purposes of the United States Government, all courts of the United States, and any proceedings by such Government or in such courts.</text></subsection></section><section id="H04A659F3C8DF4826874CFAACC0A9C8EB"><enum>107.</enum><header>Clarifying amendments</header><subsection id="H1F4E3C479611431DB5D03CFBCE307020"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Asia Reassurance Initiative Act of 2018</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 209(a)(2) of the Asia Reassurance Initiative Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/3301">22 U.S.C. 3301</external-xref> note) is amended by striking “, the 3 joint communiques,”. </text></subsection><subsection id="HBF8707CBBEE14D3FB9D77EA386B972E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Taiwan Assurance Act of 2020</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 312(6) of the Taiwan Assurance Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and in accordance with the United States <quote>One China</quote> policy</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H06FFA25B98A849EEBD2A283770E4487D"><enum>108.</enum><header>Senate confirmation of the Director of the Taipei office of the American Institute in Taiwan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The appointment of an individual to the position of Director of the American Institute in Taiwan’s Taipei office shall be subject to the advice and consent of the Senate. Upon Senate confirmation, such individual shall have the title of Representative.</text></section></title><title id="H21908A681B1E4B4293757625BCA834EF" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Implementation of an enhanced defense partnership between the United States and Taiwan</header><section id="HE6276233E495407792540B431914A95E"><enum>201.</enum><header>Increasing the strategic clarity of United States policy towards Taiwan’s defense</header><subsection id="HD38F45B5970B4A749F9C5EBC614863B4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deterrence of people’s liberation army aggression</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to provide Taiwan arms conducive to deterring acts of aggression by the People’s Liberation Army.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEAEA62DB6CA74087A3D84559CFCC4DC8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of defense articles and services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to make available to Taiwan such defense articles and services in such quantity as may be necessary to enable Taiwan to implement a strategy to deny and deter acts of coercion or aggression by the People’s Liberation Army.</text></subsection><subsection id="H51254066493D45D397916E67F906C1B4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act, nor the President’s action in extending diplomatic recognition to the People’s Republic of China, nor the absence of diplomatic relations between the people of Taiwan and the United States, nor the lack of formal recognition of Taiwan by the United States, and any related circumstances, may be construed to constitute a legal or practical obstacle to any otherwise lawful action of the President or of any United States Government agency that is needed to advance or protect United States interests pertaining to Taiwan, including actions intended to strengthen security cooperation between the United States and Taiwan or to otherwise deter the use of force against Taiwan by the People’s Liberation Army.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB2D4BA673A974CA7A35B0196472E0C5E"><enum>202.</enum><header>Security assistance to modernize Taiwan’s security capabilities to deter and defeat aggression by the People's Republic of China</header><subsection id="H4F06F2E655A8492C887833E7F384DC41" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Taiwan security programs</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall use the authorities under this section to strengthen the United States-Taiwan defense relationship, and to support the acceleration of the modernization of Taiwan’s defense capabilities required to deter or, if necessary, to defeat an invasion of Taiwan by the People’s Republic of China. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC805A68532FE48C3A3CB0725AB2F55E5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report on advancing the defense of Taiwan</header><paragraph id="H152523DDA85546DE8C463138975709E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H782F7E5787894715B6BB29CD7219A1C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB7DE51852134F02A7045CF82D7F13A8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</committee-name></text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B1A36F2F5414B2A8766DC9C333C03E0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 7 years, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that describes steps taken to enhance the United States-Taiwan defense relationship and Taiwan’s modernization of its defense capabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AB013213F8D4856B2465AEF614A408D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>Each report required under paragraph (2) shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H9586CBA56F5C4115A725D2E785E980EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an assessment of the commitment of Taiwan to implement a military strategy that will deter and, if necessary, defeat military aggression by the People’s Republic of China, including the steps that Taiwan has taken and the steps that Taiwan has not taken towards such implementation; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59772C9D9DD54FC0ABB7CFE4816EA10A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of the efforts of Taiwan to acquire and employ within its forces counter intervention capabilities, including—</text><clause id="HCB6888A609CD4E6A8ACA214BD1404AB2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>long-range precision fires;</text></clause><clause id="HDA35FE7BBF9A4BD38C1334EC25D53F20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>integrated air and missile defense systems;</text></clause><clause id="H14CCA6D651594FD78D1C287D072BA1CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>anti-ship cruise missiles;</text></clause><clause id="HEB58642AAF07477EAFDE6443E36AAAFD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>land-attack cruise missiles;</text></clause><clause id="HFC0AB854C74D4A4CBED7CA3CF37E5998"><enum>(v)</enum><text>coastal defense;</text></clause><clause id="HF502BB5DC2CA460B8A6689C82C188B08"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>anti-armor;</text></clause><clause id="H86BEF1B29E15414EA45AE9414947F282"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>undersea warfare;</text></clause><clause id="H11986A77BD7C409D95574AFF9E41249B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>survivable swarming maritime assets;</text></clause><clause id="H2ADC7D62B1D0453EA63B69950A8A86F8"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>manned and unmanned aerial systems;</text></clause><clause id="HACBF60E878B94A0093871F394670F5BB"><enum>(x)</enum><text>mining and countermining capabilities;</text></clause><clause id="H3297BEB81A7A466BB865B80FCC48804B"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities;</text></clause><clause id="H7E18983C1B8044E1B0176143F6AA7547"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>command and control systems; and</text></clause><clause id="H5277DC32479242E5A73B0D53FCBA030D"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>any other defense capabilities that the United States and Taiwan jointly determine are crucial to the defense of Taiwan, in accordance with the process developed pursuant to section 203(a);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97B34DEE258A4A8F8A6B50A3EF46DCE0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an evaluation of the balance between conventional and counter intervention capabilities in the defense force of Taiwan as of the date on which the report is submitted;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H166A7E720FA54516AF914C7711A95214"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an assessment of steps taken by Taiwan to enhance the overall readiness of its defense forces, including—</text><clause id="H9DF13C4246F14DAEB20FFA1D81896360"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the extent to which Taiwan is requiring and providing regular and relevant training to such forces;</text></clause><clause id="H7859B166457E439BBA618078DDCA695E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the extent to which such training is realistic to the security environment that Taiwan faces; and</text></clause><clause id="HF7264FA1C03B4962A787517DE9D0A3B8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the sufficiency of the financial and budgetary resources Taiwan is putting toward readiness of such forces;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FBEC1AE295E4AEC8E8825981D6D1AE8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of steps taken by Taiwan to ensure that the All-Out Defense Mobilization Agency can recruit, train, equip, and mobilize its forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3466CC846555463884A2E595CCDB468B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an evaluation of—</text><clause id="HC3FBD1E5133C4D21AB39BA7A1A8363BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the severity of manpower shortages in the military of Taiwan, including in the reserve forces;</text></clause><clause id="HD85AA771D13E41AAAA5C28378B6BA6C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the impact of such shortages in the event of a conflict scenario; and</text></clause><clause id="HD142899ACDDC4C15A93CD9AB6ABC3761"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the efforts made by the Government of Taiwan to address such shortages;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE79E9C454A494197C38214D96B2D3B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an assessment of the efforts made by Taiwan to boost its civilian defenses, including any informational campaigns to raise awareness among the population of Taiwan of the risks Taiwan faces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD02F8CD7AE3847EFAF1D551AE24D5D1B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an assessment of the efforts made by Taiwan to secure its critical infrastructure, including in transportation, telecommunications networks, and energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H830977EF006348E4818D3B1EF776F95A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an assessment of the efforts made by Taiwan to enhance its cybersecurity, including the security of civilian government and military networks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC36D74A107824EB8817E848D11B6A1E7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>an assessment of any significant gaps in any of the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (I) with respect to which the United States assesses that additional action is needed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H519A911AE57B4FA2850D126A203A93F6"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a description of cooperative efforts between the United States and Taiwan on the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (J); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCADDAE9922CC48BDA0F0D48A4BB41917"><enum>(L)</enum><text>a description of any resistance within the Government of Taiwan and the military leadership of Taiwan to— </text><clause id="H86C2FE77A5C34D22B7F89BA9CFC71726"><enum>(i)</enum><text>implementing the matters described in subparagraphs (A) through (I); or</text></clause><clause id="H9EF7F22D16524A808D38447DD757A028"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>United States support or engagement with regard to such matters.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1130841D06B341E3B38492B78180FA46"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (2) shall be submitted in classified form, but shall include a detailed unclassified summary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H507FB0E80B3347C1B187ECC68FF8046A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sharing of summary</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly share the unclassified summary required under paragraph (4) with the government and military of Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4069A2944204013BFD393EFAA7C6D37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To provide assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall use amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (i) to provide assistance to the Government of Taiwan under subsection (d). </text></subsection><subsection id="HCAA84215DA5B4DF58CA750759219838F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Foreign Military Financing Program established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall establish a Foreign Military Financing Program to provide assistance, including equipment, training, and other support, to enable the Government and military of Taiwan—</text><paragraph id="HB713FDB64D35425B951DFEB3789BE289"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to accelerate the modernization of defense capabilities that will enable Taiwan to delay, degrade, and deny attempts by People’s Liberation Army forces—</text><subparagraph id="H9925B169D9FB4736989FA43B94878B2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to conduct coercive or grey zone activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93081C771FB94BE795C415F3A1033D97"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to achieve maritime control over the Taiwan Strait and adjoining seas;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H156C3B6C777D46DABF4F79CCFC8940AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to secure a lodgment on any Taiwanese islands and expand or otherwise use such lodgment to seize control of a population center or other key territory in Taiwan; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF41911BDCDE46FFA0F4B1104A242687"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent the People’s Republic of China from decapitating, seizing control of, or otherwise neutralizing or rendering ineffective the Government of Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B5BF7692AC94811AA0707897AB7F9AA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regional contingency stockpile</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (i)(1), not more than $100,000,000 may be used during each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2032 to maintain a stockpile (if established under section 212), in accordance with section 514 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h</external-xref>), as amended by section 211. </text></subsection><subsection id="H83374B8BBE214D3FB49E051D113224D9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><paragraph id="HBD465B47490C4F9FA40FBE0C3D7150DC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual spending plan</header><text>Not later than December 1, 2022, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit a plan to the appropriate committees of Congress describing how funds appropriated pursuant to subsection (i)(2) will be used to achieve the purposes described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H916CA905F038488EA2232F26E417E8CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Amounts appropriated for each fiscal year pursuant to subsection (i)(2) shall be made available for the purpose described in such subsection after the Secretary of State certifies to the appropriate committees of Congress that Taiwan has increased its defense spending relative to Taiwan’s defense spending in its prior fiscal year, excepting accounts in Taiwan’s defense budget related to personnel expenditures, (other than military training and education and any funding related to the All-Out Defense Mobilization Agency). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4C34BC5406E49B7ADD38545611153E9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remaining funds</header><subparagraph id="HA088EEDE6DB74519AD2EA6BEF3C67600"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), amounts appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to subsection (i)(2) that are not obligated and expended during such fiscal year shall be added to the amount that may be used for Foreign Military Financing to Taiwan in the subsequent fiscal year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8066212710046B7B03034981355F16E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (i)(2) that remain unobligated on September 30, 2027 shall be rescinded and deposited into the general fund of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED57D01EE939400CB28AA7F680AD5621"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Defense articles and services from the United States inventory and other sources</header><paragraph id="H9A2793D2E0444ADDBE087BD66A78EEED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to assistance provided pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, may make available to the Government of Taiwan, in such quantities as the Secretary of State considers appropriate to provide assistance to the Government of Taiwan under subsection (d)—</text><subparagraph id="HD68AA54DA3AF491ABFBF0424883DE9FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>weapons and other defense articles from the United States inventory and other sources; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5252C47CB8DC41DBA303DA0FF34F11F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>defense services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BFAF2731C2040CFBE851DD7AB7E5D1F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Replacement</header><text>The Secretary of State may use amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (i)(2) for the cost of replacing any item provided to the Government of Taiwan pursuant to paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H949E02CA83304E008C963C28E399EEEB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Foreign military financing loan and loan guarantee authority</header><paragraph id="HC580F9929D284CC4A15C78FEF2C51E2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Direct loans</header><subparagraph id="H2B477CC35EA8476A868B27C573C6CC07"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 23(c)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>), during fiscal years 2023 through 2027, the Secretary of State may make direct loans available for Taiwan pursuant to section 23 of such Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF3F9F6BBB8415997F276A800078D62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum obligations</header><text>Gross obligations for the principal amounts of loans authorized under subparagraph (A) may not exceed $2,000,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF045FAC8387941268AFC83BFDA9A6D71"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Source of funds</header><clause id="H9BFB245D36ED4016A8F283AB921AA131"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Defined term</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>cost</term>—</text><subclause id="H7D6085B6089544738625705640857A98"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has the meaning given such term in section 502(5) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a(5)</external-xref>); </text></subclause><subclause id="H4FC07F6C4BB44560BB489E2702125DE3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall include the cost of modifying a loan authorized under subparagraph (A); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB4763FFDADBA47F28BE492C8BB7E495C"><enum>(III)</enum><text>may include the costs of selling, reducing, or cancelling any amounts owed to the United States or to any agency of the United States.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7F178C213E674FAF93CBCE5D3AFAB75F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (i)(1) may be made available to pay for the cost of loans authorized under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF5249BD85043A497C0030E34C692B5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Fees authorized</header><clause id="HCA4A1CFB7ACF414E83BBB3CD808BBF24"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Government of the United States may charge fees for loans made pursuant to subparagraph (A), which shall be collected from borrowers through a financing account (as defined in section 502(7) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a(7)</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H785D341F1D8444F78BF0264696E15F35"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation on fee payments</header><text>Amounts made available under any appropriations Act for any fiscal year may not be used to pay any fees associated with a loan authorized under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H691BAA0EEF6C4A0A9734F02737FF2B27"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Repayment</header><text>Loans made pursuant to subparagraph (A) shall be repaid not later than 12 years after the loan is received by the borrower, including a grace period of not more than 1 year on repayment of principal.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H468053E65940461B9B99C9969DC00DAA"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Interest</header><clause id="H622BB87B02684374BEA3933920A53D7D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding section 23(c)(1) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763(c)(1)</external-xref>, interest for loans made pursuant to subparagraph (A) may be charged at a rate determined by the Secretary of State, except that such rate may not be less than the prevailing interest rate on marketable Treasury securities of similar maturity.</text></clause><clause id="H61BCD932921B4EE3A713B1392CF2696F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Treatment of loan amounts used to pay interest</header><text>Amounts made available under this paragraph for interest costs shall not be considered assistance for the purposes of any statutory limitation on assistance to a country.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H614F0BF28C694169880843DE4CEF9F16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Loan guarantees</header><subparagraph id="H9E357288A2E3494F9175243481AAF8D9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to subsection (i)(1) may be made available for the costs of loan guarantees for Taiwan under section 24 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2764">22 U.S.C. 2764</external-xref>) for Taiwan to subsidize gross obligations for the principal amount of commercial loans and total loan principal, any part of which may be guaranteed, not to exceed $2,000,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93CAB7E9CA8B4AC28FDDC8D927732120"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Maximum amounts</header><text>A loan guarantee authorized under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H3ECE4E2B1C894C748429AD0CB761878A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not guarantee a loan that exceeds $2,000,000,000; and</text></clause><clause id="H224654A1F7C247A2BFB2EDE40F70BC22"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not exceed 80 percent of the loan principal with respect to any single borrower.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CBAA8F860844EE18CC2127F67047FDF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Subordination</header><text>Any loan guaranteed pursuant to subparagraph (A) may not be subordinated to—</text><clause id="H4EE6093E4A3C40828F7A6B41BDE6383D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>another debt contracted by the borrower; or </text></clause><clause id="H1228D173DF38424AA3CC0EEAB05624FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other claims against the borrower in the case of default.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C28BE3135784426A47FDB7E6D0A6CD1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Repayment</header><text>Repayment in United States dollars of any loan guaranteed under this paragraph shall be required not later than 12 years after the loan agreement is signed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF43F7525180C4BE89621C5C52B6D970C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>Notwithstanding section 24 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2764">22 U.S.C. 2764</external-xref>), the Government of the United States may charge fees for loan guarantees authorized under subparagraph (A), which shall be collected from borrowers, or from third parties on behalf of such borrowers, through a financing account (as defined in section 502(7) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/661a">2 U.S.C. 661a(7)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H692F208B5A94447BB7B547A725CB0C65"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Treatments of loan guarantees</header><text>Amounts made available under this paragraph for the costs of loan guarantees authorized under subparagraph (A) shall not be considered assistance for the purposes of any statutory limitation on assistance to a country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H32AFB3CFDF9A4249B2AFE1CFE1961DE2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notification requirement</header><text>Amounts appropriated to carry out this subsection may not be expended without prior notification of the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H074343E9ECB544EEB75EC9992734B3BE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H2ABF0DEEC0D440098E5E9ACDD57FCACC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise authorized to be appropriated for Foreign Military Financing, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State for Taiwan Foreign Military Finance grant assistance—</text><subparagraph id="HAF53AA068A074B06AF6795E2B4224E6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$250,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66CACEC56C73470DACFFED48248C51A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$750,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06B205FB371C40FB818C1C5A2FBF542D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$1,500,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H650797FF2E964126A44EEE201A79F75B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0401BC1084324321AE4A005B60C585D7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>$2,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68C22CC27A4B43AFA073DB5DE4FA07BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training and education</header><text>Of the amounts authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall use not less than $2,000,000 per fiscal year for 1 or more blanket order Foreign Military Financing training programs related to the defense needs of Taiwan. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF986EFFFD5DD440C8B10168D815C43F2"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Sunset provision</header><text>Assistance may not be provided under this section after September 30, 2032. </text></subsection></section><section id="H1168F25DB868411CAF57269C5D12E977" commented="no"><enum>203.</enum><header>Anticipatory planning and annual review of the United States strategy to defend Taiwan</header><subsection id="H353028BFA53B46AE98B872DAF66EFBB2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 10 years, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text><paragraph id="HB7ABAC97745548C39964E08FC019633D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a classified review of the United States strategy to defend Taiwan; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCD4979B60314B608E505CA10AE119AE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>share the results of such review with the Chairman and Ranking Member of the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H56FAEF389FFB47DA8AAD45F2547A77AA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The review conducted pursuant to subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H720D17613B214BDEBE62F477C6A77655" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of Taiwan’s current and near-term capabilities, United States force readiness, and the adequacy of the United States strategy to enable the defense of Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B568F32EFA4518AAB27D5C475F6C63" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a detailed strategy of denial to defend Taiwan against aggression by the People’s Liberation Army, including an effort to seize and hold the island of Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39AED39AFBC94398BA7C0A73A04BC731" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a comprehensive assessment of risks to the United States and United States interests, including readiness shortfalls that pose strategic risk;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4E7E193588C40E1A630481A62250E12" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a review of indicators of the near-term likelihood of the use of force by the People’s Liberation Army against Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB382681876E1447BA791041EC4529708" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a list of military capabilities, including capabilities that enable a strategy of denial, that—</text><subparagraph id="H2BF06AEFD16E468E9BE1D21F2816E83E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>would suit the operational environment and allow Taiwan to respond effectively to a variety of contingencies across all potential phases of conflict involving the People’s Liberation Army; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF59D19A5AF654729A613FA7FB6F7BEE2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>would reduce the threat of conflict, thwart an invasion, and mitigate other risks to the United States and Taiwan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5B43B1F9D0624B7DB5CB370F550D529E" commented="no"><enum>204.</enum><header>Joint assessment</header><subsection id="HBD2CC44CE0164224932F84A3369E55F7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall establish and maintain a joint consultative mechanism with Taiwan that convenes on a recurring basis—</text><paragraph id="H7BBE43FC051B4EA9A04F808FA843CAAD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop a joint assessment of, and coordinate planning with respect to, the threats Taiwan faces from the People’s Republic of China across the spectrum of possible military action; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78AF5064F7B24730A4BAA5DD2BA9C5D8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to identify nonmaterial and material solutions to deter and defeat such threats.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0B1673CAEAD441E3BDD8726D7AECD745" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Integrated priorities list</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall develop with Taiwan—</text><paragraph id="H2CBCD6990BAF4483AF18FE32E127E295" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an integrated priorities list;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H764655B02E1F44C4B2A85AA009FDA557" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant plans for acquisition and training for relevant nonmaterial and material solutions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D559E8A522C40EFB9AD925015DBEB4D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other measures to appropriately prioritize the defense needs of Taiwan to maintain effective deterrence across the spectrum of possible military action by the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5CAB08B223B1406EAB79F6EE9986FF19" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress that describes the joint assessment developed pursuant to subsection (a)(1).</text></subsection></section><section id="H9228A0414BB54399B8C627BCAF4D24C9"><enum>205.</enum><header>Requirements regarding definition of counter intervention capabilities</header><subsection id="H64CE8CF2446943358413743B55E45335"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HA8151BE7980140F9937239B963223113"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure that requests by Taiwan to purchase arms from the United States are not prematurely rejected or dismissed before Taiwan submits a letter of request or other formal documentation, particularly when such requests are for capabilities that are not included on any United States Government priority lists of necessary capabilities for the defense of Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D0EE9D270845F1B15C4FCC3CEB9DC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure requests by Taiwan to purchase arms from the United States are evaluated with full consideration of the United States strategy to defend Taiwan pursuant to section 203 and the joint consultative mechanism with Taiwan pursuant to section 204; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF490179EF13F4450BB5BF07CA97FB96C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure close consultation among representatives of Taiwan, Congress, industry, and the Executive branch about requests referred to in paragraph (1) and the needs of Taiwan before Taiwan submits formal requests for such purchases.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80D45587BE4244B0868A02306A8A26AC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Not later than 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall jointly submit to the appropriate committees of Congress—</text><paragraph id="HA46E6C41875046D789BD15D7041E62D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of categories of counter intervention capabilities and a justification for each such category; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0107651E4014B97878677DD3697B949"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the degree to which the United States has a policy of openness or flexibility for evaluating requests by Taiwan to purchase arms from the United States that may not fall within the scope of counter intervention capabilities included in the list required under paragraph (1), due to considerations such as—</text><subparagraph id="H94562A4AA4CF43B8A5335F37960B319D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>joint planning of respective mission roles between the United States, Taiwan, and other parties in the event of conflict concerning Taiwan; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04C829C9221E4273B1FC98B2FCF4164C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the evolution of defense technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5B634B8743C54D779A73E7201428FA8A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the identification of new concepts of operation or ways to employ certain capabilities; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F354319E3C444BB365F2BAE7C6A361"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other factors that might change assessments by the United States and Taiwan of what constitutes counter intervention capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H95C9C0BE8F0C4E77907B72A0F7B2AF78" commented="no"><enum>206.</enum><header>Comprehensive training program</header><subsection id="HC0F3626178DC4A7C98B4A9C1326843C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense shall establish or expand a comprehensive training program with Taiwan designed to—</text><paragraph id="HA3773E35408B4E9B9FF4E919CED7F785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enhance interoperability and capabilities for joint operations between the United States and Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECE682FCE48146138E2EDF53E65AAF01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance rapport and deepen partnership between the militaries of the United States and Taiwan, and foster understanding of the United States among individuals in Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H453AB1125A3C44668B5EC5F34F6C30F1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve Taiwan’s defense capabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C17792A190548E2BE5798F372BAAED9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>train future leaders of Taiwan, promote professional military education, civilian control of the military, and protection of human rights.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DCCC9BC26384DBCA972541B6E70A7E3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The training program required by subsection (a) should prioritize relevant and realistic training, including as necessary joint United States-Taiwan contingency tabletop exercises, war games, full-scale military exercises, and an enduring rotational United States military presence that assists Taiwan in maintaining force readiness and utilizing United States defense articles and services transferred from the United States to Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC8ACAF5E7D3341EA9EACB2242FDA1B82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of participation of taiwan in the international military education and training program</header><text>Taiwan is authorized to participate in the International Military Education and Training program for the purposes described in subsection (a) and to carry out the elements described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD38EFB09A82E4ECABF19AD067C80D5FE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 3 years, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a classified report that describes all training provided to the Armed Forces of Taiwan in the prior fiscal year, including—</text><paragraph id="H39260D25FD274E0D914809594F7DA87F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of advancements in United States-Taiwan military interoperability pursuant to such training;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5362DB7327974632A6F7B011CDC76802"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of increasing familiarization of the militaries of the United States and Taiwan with each other pursuant to such training;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE6B3E6BAB84101A13FD8CCF9610C4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improvements to Taiwan’s defense capabilities pursuant to such training; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H531A305807874EAC80C970FB1C57D5CC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an identification of all requests from Taiwan for further training.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFD86E77036C3485D91E895D7F07EE612"><enum>207.</enum><header>Joint exercises with Taiwan</header><subsection id="H1F374F15A873478D86CB791C29D45F0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HCCF8E1A9008A4179A2C95A7E56C9B494"><enum>(1)</enum><text>joint military exercises with Taiwan are an important component of improving military readiness and joint operability of both countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A8BA414A09F4A24A97F2DA6B833BDC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Commander of United States Indo-Pacific Command, and other commands in the United States Indo-Pacific Command area of responsibility, already possess the legal authority to carry out such exercises; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44EFB0B81316453BBAF82B251250FAF1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should better use existing authorities to improve the readiness and joint operability of United States and Taiwanese forces.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H649D9D8393914F36B19B207059B91B18"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority recognized</header><text>The Commander of United States Indo-Pacific Command is authorized to carry out military exercises with Taiwan that—</text><paragraph id="H0BB64ECC0C4C4232BB5ED067B0359D8D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include multiple warfare domains and make extensive use of the military common operations network used by United States, allied, and Taiwanese forces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44EED7E89AC74E67B88AFAEA8AC467AD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practical, incorporate the cooperation of 2 or more combatant and subordinate unified commands; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD611B019B38E4BABAE4431E23FA333CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>present a complex military problem and include a force presentation of a strategic competitor.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H77C0B13C6D3E4225992AA89923A5B6D8"><enum>208.</enum><header>Assessment of Taiwan’s needs for civilian defense and resilience</header><subsection id="H6A5BA9EF11DC40B3B91C26474C266133"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment required</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit a written, classified assessment of Taiwan’s needs in the areas of civilian defense and resilience to the appropriate committees of Congress, the <committee-name committee-id="SLIN00">Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate</committee-name>, and the <committee-name committee-id="">Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA311FD999464C6CA6640C68AF27E54C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The assessment required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="HF09FF808EA3B477A86FB14EDA97D3BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyze the potential role of Taiwan’s public and civilian assets in defending against various scenarios for foreign militaries to coerce or conduct military aggression against Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H527651AD010540FC8139460AAA5F837E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carefully analyze Taiwan’s needs for enhancing its defensive capabilities through the support of civilians and civilian sectors, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC56DA9EC25B74CE198807761B55AD56C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>greater utilization of Taiwan’s high tech labor force;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4F794192626484DAA65D509C12EEB4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the creation of clear structures and logistics support for civilian defense role allocation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4053214784B5400D875B34B02D689FB0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recruitment and skills training for Taiwan's defense and civilian sectors; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74F74E8437ED4F148A14D3C7E4A85128"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategic stockpiling of resources related to critical food security and medical supplies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA99BAEC6605401A9545E941B3B0C13B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other defense needs and considerations at the provincial, city, and neighborhood levels;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88F6F3972DA149FA891975ED08F13CC2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>analyze Taiwan’s needs for enhancing resiliency among its people and in key economic sectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39F39684E8DE4DFBBBDA28F9AED64A52"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify opportunities for Taiwan to enhance communications and strengthen cooperation between the military, other government departments, civilian agencies, and the general public, including—</text><subparagraph id="H88AD1195E5AE4D288988C78948920577"><enum>(A)</enum><text>communications infrastructure necessary to ensure reliable communications in response to a conflict or crisis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6D2CE621FB94AAAAC96929F8803F10C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a plan to effectively communicate to the general public in response to a conflict or crisis; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5810EA59756A47E586A069F25543D6C2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify the areas and means through which the United States could provide training and assistance to support the needs discovered through the assessment and fill any critical gaps where capacity falls short of such needs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFFDE87A40324F6EB77D16A35AFA8E2E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form of report</header><text>Notwithstanding the classified nature of the assessment required under subsection (a), the assessment shall be shared with appropriate officials of the Government of Taiwan to facilitate cooperation. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7B13468F904442F1A36EF48B1DA3EB54"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H3A7283A66E714FE0A95BEA6F43E7838A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to complete the assessment required under subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HB8EFB197B13B41048F00AA5E27E0FE01"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$500,000 for the Department of State; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47E08BAD3DF8485297221E4E1B5164AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$500,000 for the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BAD0A8DF57A476CA0E3E45F1F6478B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Transfer authority</header><text>The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Defense are authorized to transfer any funds appropriated to their respective departments pursuant to paragraph (1) to the Director of National Intelligence for the purposes of facilitating the contributions of the intelligence community to the assessment required under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2B0419DDCC924B5EAA94BA8EEAF65586"><enum>209.</enum><header>Annual report on cooperation between the National Guard and Taiwan</header><subsection id="HD1F9D7F50A6E45E48BC113AD1F19B287"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than February 15, 2023, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees (as defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code) a report on the feasibility and advisability of enhanced cooperation between the National Guard and Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB852153411DC481996303C6AC4CB6101"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Each report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H26EE88A6FBB14E1A8F6607E6303E381F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the cooperation between the National Guard and Taiwan during the preceding calendar year, including mutual visits, exercises, training, and equipment opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22F67EC826884DFC8EE13BC3BD64CB9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An evaluation of the feasibility of enhancing cooperation between the National Guard and Taiwan on a range of activities, including—</text><subparagraph id="H35669865BCB64B4BAC7AD7476F07F54A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>disaster and emergency response;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21AAC51EA94B4151BF22B964F0AAD27F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cyber defense and communications security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H162BF91B0CBC46E7AF5370C9BFCAAD5B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>military medical cooperation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51E05EF8C1E74B07A78168B64B943115"><enum>(D)</enum><text>cultural exchange and education of members of the National Guard in Mandarin Chinese; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD47733D55C84331A4AA287C932BF6B2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>programs for National Guard advisors to assist in training the reserve components of the military forces of Taiwan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44685933A67C4C138723FD66D5CEE868"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations to enhance such cooperation and improve interoperability, including through familiarization visits, cooperative training and exercises, and co-deployments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57ED0546877C4E5F8B5FF8F093E3C520"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other matter the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF79B41AB978B4A52AE3D39DC923A2107"><enum>210.</enum><header>Prioritizing excess defense article transfers for Taiwan</header><subsection id="HBCF55610F106410694A73063ACF2A91F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States Government should appropriately prioritize the review of excess defense article transfers to Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H22B1C8FF2CEF43E7B6FB2434F17FB6B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Five-Year plan</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="HB075AFFC39CB44EA9CB0FD181C5D6645"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop a 5-year plan to appropriately prioritize excess defense article transfers to Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H139E684A21F04BC2BB1890F71B55D856"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress that describes such plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD660F7BC8CC345AD9E5D57BBFAC28E2F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required coordination</header><text>The United States Government shall coordinate and align excess defense article transfers with capacity-building efforts of Taiwan. </text></subsection><subsection id="HA80BBD18B8E148EBA97A694A2B725539"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transfer authority</header><paragraph id="H8B53FCA6523E41C4BA660A1DE9AE0184"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 516(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(c)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and to the Philippines</quote> and inserting <quote>, to the Philippines, and to Taiwan</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91716B3220A94653A51700A4486CD3D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of taiwan</header><text>With respect to the transfer of excess defense articles under section 516(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961, as amended by paragraph (1), Taiwan shall receive the same benefits as the other countries referred to in such section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFF5B00BCF6F74A99B56BCB3191689B68"><enum>211.</enum><header>Fast-tracking sales to Taiwan under the Foreign Military Sales program</header><subsection id="HA5737C7FD8F04B3DA99FF3B9DEB4270D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prioritized processing and prohibition on bundling of foreign military sales requests from taiwan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall appropriately prioritize and expedite the processing of requests from Taiwan under the Foreign Military Sales program consistent with the Arms Export Control Act and in furtherance of the Taiwan Relations Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7010C95C8F3A49C7B2E0B78016042333"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of Special Defense Acquisition Fund</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, shall seek to utilize the Special Defense Acquisition Fund established under chapter 5 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2795">22 U.S.C. 2795 et seq.</external-xref>) to expedite the procurement and delivery of defense articles and defense services for the purpose of assisting and supporting the Armed Forces of Taiwan. </text></subsection><subsection id="H4893E08293484CECB5527DAFACBC2027"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 10 years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress that describes the steps that have been taken to carry out subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H775D5D5727724831A3988DA0B7BFD9D9"><enum>212.</enum><header>Arms export delivery solutions</header><subsection id="HF329855812DB4C70A46AD746648A79E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H29F8EA0D27B347959137B3B9B1B0C9A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prioritizing the defense needs of United States allies and partners in the Indo-Pacific is a national security priority; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BF8C7CA6FE44ED1A3063D169AE6381A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sustained support to key Indo-Pacific partners for interoperable defense systems is critical to preserve—</text><subparagraph id="HDACADA34154748C5ADF6F572231DC344"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the safety and security of American persons;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36056AAF22534942AC3614833E4756F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the free flow of commerce through international trade routes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF37E6A678404AC8ABDA7CABE548F052"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the United States commitment to collective security agreements, territorial integrity, and recognized maritime boundaries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DF4FC86BC7E4B1C9159293560DDB797"><enum>(D)</enum><text>United States values regarding democracy and commitment to maintaining a free and open Indo-Pacific; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E74B37F25864A28912AF68F2513B130"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Taiwan’s defense capability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA45C5BF5E9284E829A67BF042C86DE8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than March 1, 2023, and annually thereafter for a period of five years, the Secretary of State, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Defense, shall transmit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report with respect to the transfer of all defense articles or defense services that have yet to be completed pursuant to the authorities provided by—</text><paragraph id="HC9BB117DC99D42228B7324435E7F7DDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 3, 21, or 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2753">22 U.S.C. 2753</external-xref>, 2761, or 2776); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB0DD42C380D4E6FAC9D612938C19BFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 516(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(c)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1291E514D9C24BBD9CBBC4EB972FA1FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H390A4C6CD1814203B82F34EE87FBBA6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A list of all approved transfers of defense articles and services authorized by Congress pursuant to sections 25 and 36 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2765">22 U.S.C. 2765</external-xref>, 2776) with a total value of $25,000,000 or more, to Taiwan, Japan, South Korea, Australia, or New Zealand, that have not been fully delivered by the start of the fiscal year in which the report is being submitted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70B0EC992D90470BB785785961A00547"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The estimated start and end dates of delivery for each approved and incomplete transfer listed pursuant to paragraph (1), including additional details and dates for any transfers that involve multiple tranches of deliveries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DAF920BB6CB4A70B91AAC6F93D1AE0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>With respect to each approved and incomplete transfer listed pursuant to paragraph (1), a detailed description of—</text><subparagraph id="H7847F02CD1B14EC885D682D8942C0BD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any changes in the delivery dates of defense articles or services relative to the dates anticipated at the time of congressional approval of the transfer, including specific reasons for any delays related to the United States Government, defense suppliers, or a foreign partner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H034D510D65574D43B36DF6A992804C96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the feasibility and advisability of providing the partner subject to such delayed delivery with an interim capability or solution, including drawing from United States stocks, and the mechanisms under consideration for doing so as well as any challenges to implementing such a capability or solution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H932ECF6ADCBF46A8B12FABDC8EA3410D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>authorities, appropriations, or waiver requests that Congress could provide to improve delivery timelines or authorize the provision of interim capabilities or solutions identified pursuant to subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68BFEF1176194144AA304E1DF271E9DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of which countries are ahead of Taiwan for delivery of each item listed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA4DA4D084924D7A9CF978A906F79BE1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of ongoing interagency efforts to support attainment of operational capability of the corresponding defense articles and services once delivered, including advance training with United States or Armed Forces of partner countries on the systems to be received. The description of any such training shall also include an identification of the training implementer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0DB3C3996C484CB20DFBB1B6F5140E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>If a transfer listed pursuant to paragraph (1) has been terminated prior to the date of the submission of the report for any reason—</text><subparagraph id="HC3FAC363C31F4F2D9A6C8804CA4FDB32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the case information for such transfer, including the date of congressional notification, delivery date of the Letter of Offer and Acceptance (LOA), final signature of the LOA, and information pertaining to delays in delivering LOAs for signature;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE95AD68C73C4136B4A39AC61B9C4FAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the reasons for which the transfer is no longer in effect; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H981FA6F488634F8DBA2CE31953E682DF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impact this termination will have on the intended end user and the consequent implications for regional security, including the impact on deterrence of military action by countries hostile to the United States, the military balance in the Taiwan Strait, and other factors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFB727848394CE98EEDC18138811790"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A separate description of the actions the United States is taking to expedite deliveries of defense articles and services to Taiwan, including in particular, whether the United States intends to divert defense articles from United States stocks to provide an interim capability or solution with respect to any delayed deliveries to Taiwan and the plan, if applicable, to replenish any such diverted stocks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD6A871344274A03ADC9321C04303912"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A description of other potential actions already undertaken by or currently under consideration by the Department of State and the Department of Defense to improve delivery timelines for the transfers listed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F65747133EC493BAD514900AD27E419"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HCCB33B41B4FD491F909437B85C39C5E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F920A18148D43628822F48020CB1CD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD59745D470CF48A992EEDEB79B60A47B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5A0F67FAAE234309AB5A9036C94738C6"><enum>213.</enum><header>Whole-of-Government deterrence measures to respond to the People's Republic of China's force against Taiwan</header><subsection id="H661410E56776420BA8DFCAC4D2011C49"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Whole-of-Government review</header><text>Not later than 14 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall convene the heads of all relevant Federal departments and agencies to conduct a whole-of-government review of all available economic, diplomatic, and other strategic measures to deter the use of force by the People’s Republic of China to change the status quo of Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H63A02BB1895E450489FB2980464710D8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State, the Secretary of the Treasury, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Commerce, the Director of National Intelligence, and any other relevant heads of Federal departments and agencies shall provide a detailed briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress regarding—</text><paragraph id="H0FB65DAC47AA4FF4B521BDA461B7A883"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all available economic, diplomatic, and other strategic measures to deter the use of force by the People's Republic of China, including coercion, grey-zone tactics, assertions, shows of force, quarantines, embargoes, or other measures to change the status quo of Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E3DD8825A354CAA8DA39157BDDEAB04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts by the United States Government to deter the use of force by the People’s Republic of China to change the status quo of Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H557C31CE1DD74491AE45586FEC239A09"><enum>(3)</enum><text>progress to date of all coordination efforts between the United States Government and its allies and partners with respect to deterring the use of force to change the status quo of Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83996C4C3EFF48B9B3DFDCE6B0BAF91C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordinated consequences with allies and partners</header><text>The Secretary of State shall—</text><paragraph id="H41070EA2321A40D9A2D57E7CD2200F82"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with United States allies and partners to identify and develop significant economic, diplomatic, and other measures to deter the use of force by the People’s Republic of China to change the status quo of Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10CE0971D33A40CC879A0E1141A5BD17"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">announce in advance, the severe multilateral consequences that would be imposed on the People’s Republic of China immediately after it engaged in any such use of force.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6937B522EB6942B89B55D8BE602AC62D"><enum>214.</enum><header>Increase in annual regional contingency stockpile additions and support for Taiwan</header><subsection id="H7E222F687C4046178180AE6BDEAE55DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 514(b)(2)(A) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$200,000,000</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>$500,000,000 for any of the fiscal years 2023, 2024, or 2025.</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA05602A8FBC3418A8BA4B926CE1CA33E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to section 514 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h</external-xref>), the President may establish a regional contingency stockpile for Taiwan that consists primarily of munitions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H48CA8BEABB5B4EB892EAFBD7CF1619EC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of Taiwan among other allies eligible for defense articles</header><text>Chapter 2 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2311">22 U.S.C. 2311 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6954B2E6DB5D4795BFEC490CE76CF055"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 514(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321h">22 U.S.C. 2321h(c)(2)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>Taiwan,</quote> after <quote>Thailand,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF32BF7CD38F64B759A5E487EF05FA703"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 516(c)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(c)(2)</external-xref>), by inserting <quote>to Taiwan,</quote> after <quote>major non-NATO allies on such southern and southeastern flank,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0A7F488C7DE44B1A60F4FA62F18BEC1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for 7 years, the President shall provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress regarding the status of a regional contingency stockpile established under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section><section id="H3E34C435F5B541EAA7B8BBD9518B978A"><enum>215.</enum><header>Emergency drawdown authority of Taiwan Strait contingencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President should use the presidential drawdown authority under sections 506(a) and 552(c) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2318">22 U.S.C. 2318(a)</external-xref> and 2348a(c)) to provide security assistance and other necessary commodities and services to Taiwan in support of Taiwan’s self-defense.</text></section><section id="HA7AE4DBDA19F4B45A38C15EC9FAE5A71"><enum>216.</enum><header>Designation of Taiwan as a major non-NATO ally</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 517 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321k">22 U.S.C. 2321k</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H169803D216794F61BA4BA3DDEBD9D748"><subsection id="H4C628CF9D32B4D68BEA64FAFFBBFBD37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional designations</header><paragraph id="HA83FB710CBC141A3A30A998F8314192A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taiwan is designated as a major non-NATO ally for purposes of this Act, the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2751">22 U.S.C. 2751 et seq.</external-xref>), and section 2350a of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B6D5FE67DA4502BA64EE1C9A22C92C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of termination of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall notify Congress in accordance with subsection (a)(2) before terminating the designation specified in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title><title id="HC979AB57A398416782152341B26A4838" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Countering People’s Republic of China’s aggression and influence campaigns</header><section id="HA7C43899A7E94D6AB7C0A1E138F2060E"><enum>301.</enum><header>Strategy to respond to influence and information operations targeting Taiwan</header><subsection id="H3E0CEFFDD5A74CE39A0CC49F481EBADC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State shall develop and implement a strategy to respond to—</text><paragraph id="H91D4157D3AB34FECB283CC922FC33F20"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">covert, coercive, and corrupting activities carried out to advance the Chinese Communist Party’s <quote>United Front</quote> work, including activities directed, coordinated, or otherwise supported by the United Front Work Department or its subordinate or affiliated entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37D73460D1C443588D93E32DFA542846"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information and disinformation campaigns, cyber attacks, and nontraditional propaganda measures supported by the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party that are directed toward persons or entities in Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1C96A7EB97B46E3A1EAB7C18AFF6906"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include descriptions of—</text><paragraph id="H3D67B295D7C140F7B4407E1B7C8BD23F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the proposed response to propaganda and disinformation campaigns by the People’s Republic of China and cyber-intrusions targeting Taiwan, including—</text><subparagraph id="HEB3E0FB69F724D9D9EE23C8FCE55264D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assistance in building the capacity of the Government of Taiwan and private-sector entities to document and expose propaganda and disinformation supported by the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the Chinese Communist Party, or affiliated entities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD37DE8D836E4721AC3CE7C38250E1E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assistance to enhance the Government of Taiwan’s ability to develop a whole-of-government strategy to respond to sharp power operations, including election interference; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H669A7D1EFFF74C50A3CF47CA2634F69F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>media training for Taiwan officials and other Taiwan entities targeted by disinformation campaigns;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDDDED45BF874C4B8FA2ABBB2317CAB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the proposed response to political influence operations that includes an assessment of the extent of influence exerted by the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party in Taiwan on local political parties, financial institutions, media organizations, and other entities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C4152568096420EA9984ECF32DECBB9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support for exchanges and other technical assistance to strengthen the Taiwan legal system’s ability to respond to sharp power operations; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F3315E1901B470CAA663F3537D19761"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the establishment of a coordinated partnership, through the American Institute in Taiwan's Global Cooperation and Training Framework, with like-minded governments to share data and best practices with the Government of Taiwan regarding ways to address sharp power operations supported by the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12D4FB4DC3C040DCA2D8DC4416D9B0EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">programs carried out by the Global Engagement Center to expose misinformation and disinformation in the Chinese Communist Party’s propaganda.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8C1F5BB6ED2F4CFD941A1DF61EAA003B"><enum>302.</enum><header>Strategy to counter economic coercion by the People's Republic of China targeting countries and entities that support Taiwan</header><subsection id="H956B0A8A04E14C25A3CC55482560FB02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a description of the strategy being used by the Department of State to respond to the Government of the People’s Republic of China’s increased economic coercion against countries which have strengthened their ties with, or support for, Taiwan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE3DAD9D37CE046099B6C524280960E36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assistance for countries and entities targeted by the People's Republic of China for economic coercion</header><text>The Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Department of Commerce and the Department of the Treasury shall provide appropriate assistance to countries and entities that are subject to trade restrictions and other forms of economic coercion by the People's Republic of China.</text></subsection></section><section id="H53978E1C97DE459D850D2F032D15B85B"><enum>303.</enum><header>Shared planning for the defense of Taiwan</header><subsection id="HD87EFDAF24AF45B5A987542E4F0DDA3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, acting through the American Institute in Taiwan, as appropriate, shall seek to establish a framework with Taiwan’s Ministry of National Defense and other entities, as appropriate, for robust, continuous, shared defense planning and force development that includes regular dialogues at appropriate levels throughout the United States Government.</text></subsection><subsection id="H68765193EA36435DA251AFECDC70E0F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the framework described in subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H01EF182F5E0443008C081D08320563C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>outlining pathways for the advancement of shared priorities to meet current and emerging security challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BBF049B56E74B54B400D7FC2A48A1F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developing common threat perceptions and perceptions surrounding escalation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34AE8C3752BD47738321D65B74D335F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>developing a common understanding of potential conflict scenarios, including their likelihood, predictability, and political import, and a shared conception on the means required to deter such aggression and the risk tolerance for employing such means;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BD4391550784C0A8D45D4871489CE28"><enum>(4)</enum><text>delineating further how the United States and Taiwan can collaborate to advance the military capabilities and readiness of Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C47C11F6C844B3B90969DBE3E48A617"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ensuring unified planning and role clarity for various contingencies involving the People’s Republic of China and Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D05F890F2274B83A9287826C2A45E49"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensuring the Armed Forces of Taiwan have the appropriate systems, munitions, capabilities, and training for maximum deterrent effect within a combined deterrence;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA9961244EDE44C881E25E11F95BA2C6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensuring Taiwan’s existing and new systems and capabilities are integrated into a combined deterrence effort for maximum deterrent effect;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EB64492D2DB42C9993ED7CEBC798475"><enum>(8)</enum><text>aligning Taiwan’s defense budgeting priorities with the overall combined deterrence effort;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8F27E07FCB6461ABC5FA2984606E980"><enum>(9)</enum><text>ensuring that systems and capabilities between Taiwan and the United States support complementary missions and achieve interoperability, as appropriate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC92B3A735B44823B3B24B5FAF5F5E02"><enum>(10)</enum><text>strengthening cooperation on cybersecurity to deter malicious cyber activities against Taiwan’s security systems and critical infrastructure, to attribute such activities, and to defend against adversaries effectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0C27C6D18B64451BDBF1DFC45E3D7C8"><enum>(11)</enum><text>strengthening cooperation on information operations to counter People’s Republic of China disinformation campaigns;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF77B8EBC15E84CA5AC8EF65CAAA6A966"><enum>(12)</enum><text>developing closer partnership of defense intelligence communities in support of military planning and defensive operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADE3470893464CC9907AF2857C0DF166"><enum>(13)</enum><text>ensuring appropriate counterintelligence measures for other elements of the framework. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C9E76A0B1934604B04829CDD42E8774"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall provide Taiwan with such technical assistance, including with respect to budgeting, as is necessary to ensure productive operation of the framework described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H09EE361EA38C49ECA14C691442B7C32A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Inclusion of additional allies and partners</header><text>The Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall seek to, as appropriate, coordinate with or include additional allies and partners in the framework described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCC57FEF913FA44EDB37BBD42C0663585"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HC685182F39D54F7B81EB604C298F3DF4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the progress in establishing the framework described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61E9E1CA5CEE43C9BB8E996E49031483"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="HC4E8B6512A8E418393CEBC52AED5961B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the structure of the framework.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADE4E052B56548B4935F52D12DC0B647"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The effectiveness of the framework in establishing a unified defense posture.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9098F79387484F79BB7D7FED7B9CC5C6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Obstacles to the creation of the framework, either political or procedural, with respect to the Secretaries counterparts in Taiwan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E1923728B0C4B0AB313D1A3CC35DAD4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Progress made in establishing shared defense planning for various Taiwan Strait contingencies.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB49F50F2E528441FB182789442304F13"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A description and assessment of the effectiveness of counterintelligence measures taken to ensure the needed secrecy for joint planning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53484B0000F04DB59E0CD49E99D93CB6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The effectiveness of incorporating third parties into the framework.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0DBE38D6A74410E8F5C78F6A43CF12A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of State submit the report required by paragraph (1), the Secretaries shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an evaluation of the progress and effectiveness of the framework that includes the elements listed in paragraph (2) and a discussion of the effectiveness of the framework in rationalizing Taiwan’s arms procurement in relation to producing a maximally deterrent posture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCA6D8E3CA3B4F26B0E0664D8F800695"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) and the evaluation required by paragraph (3) shall be submitted in classified form, with an unclassified summary if appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H896D723A91DE4AFBA38199F5C02350B4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H3E2D6434F86C4047A8CDD14619494F87"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</text><clause id="HA9BF9EE16D524E188272C894923F2123"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="HEE8E3C38D40B49B9BE6DD4A5178394EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1918701E5EF5486A842B9558782619AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Combined deterrence effort</header><text>The term “combined deterrence effort” means the development and operation of complementary deterrent postures by the United States, Taiwan, and other like-minded countries, as appropriate, to maintain peace and stability in the area of Taiwan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H3FB09BB194AF4770B9A69F1DD4B40D16" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>Inclusion of Taiwan in international organizations</header><section id="H793A735233144747867753B1AF7838D9"><enum>401.</enum><header>Participation of Taiwan in international organizations</header><subsection id="H805B14F6B462423F9A3769D0494E1CFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to promote Taiwan’s inclusion and meaningful participation in international organizations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA0ABEBCDEA5D4C14B1939F53FEDE9C7E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Support for meaningful participation</header><text>The Permanent Representative of the United States to the United Nations and other relevant United States officials shall actively support Taiwan’s meaningful participation in all appropriate international organizations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA58F0C895AB24F9BB9B70FB59E4889BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><paragraph id="H5EDA428D09064CA1B2A70D2F51B2DBCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the People's Republic of China’s efforts at the United Nations and other international bodies to block Taiwan’s meaningful participation and inclusion; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C268FB2AE0C4E34B44E7BEA49F6FC82"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommends appropriate responses that should be taken by the United States to carry out the policy described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H98BD5DA14CFC456D920DBB1E8BD74E08"><enum>402.</enum><header>Clarification regarding United Nations General Assembly Resolution 2758 (XXVI)</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(a) of the Taiwan Allies International Protection and Enhancement Initiative (TAIPEI) Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/135">Public Law 116–135</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HABD2533464804992B83832565CB40DE0"><paragraph id="H404B286D8C194E43B98C7EF98D05D7C1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>United Nations General Assembly Resolution 2758 (1971)—</text><subparagraph id="H6BE2FA8F4E1D47F8A5B4AEDA3171F199"><enum>(A)</enum><text>established the representatives of the Government of the People’s Republic of China as the only lawful representatives of China to the United Nations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H817278E743F542A8A72EF8D665D3EF67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>did not address the issue of representation of Taiwan and its people in the United Nations or in any related organizations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8EAC8B3B36A048E3BB001589952287E9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>did not take a position on the relationship between the People’s Republic of China and Taiwan or include any statement pertaining to Taiwan’s sovereignty.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63B3373C5B9F4B9687735AD0B13DEA68"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The United States opposes any initiative that seeks to change Taiwan’s status without the consent of the people of Taiwan.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H86B644717A584288B9D4E262A36AA885"><enum>403.</enum><header>Participation of Taiwan in the Inter-American Development Bank</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H4A7E728191E34172A87C43D6909FF541"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States fully supports Taiwan’s participation in, and contribution to, international organizations and underscores the importance of the relationship between Taiwan and the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1F31DB8B27D40EEBDC7B9A06170FE19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>diversifying the donor base of the Inter-American Development Bank (referred to in this title as the <quote>IDB</quote>) and increasing allied engagement in the Western Hemisphere reinforces United States national interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3A398BFFEB140368EDC8255C4E42991"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Taiwan’s significant contribution to the development and economies of Latin America and the Caribbean demonstrate that Taiwan’s membership in the IDB as a non-borrowing member would benefit the IDB and the entire Latin American and Caribbean region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C8A4EEC2C1D47CDB528D296E4D8FC08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>non-borrowing membership in the IDB would allow Taiwan to substantially leverage and channel the immense resources Taiwan already provides to Latin America and the Caribbean to reach a larger number of beneficiaries.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2134789848DC4E64AD49F9BEA4C38750"><enum>404.</enum><header>Plan for Taiwan's participation in the Inter-American Development Bank</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, is authorized—</text><paragraph id="H222764A3F0754F3699BC34B9AE1D1F83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to initiate a United States plan to endorse non-borrowing IDB membership for Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49EE0CB7C2634EFEAD951F7CBF0B39D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to instruct the United States Governor of the IDB to work with the IDB Board of Governors to admit Taiwan as a non-borrowing member of the IDB.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3971FF8E954E4CDF87B7F412179E8A2B"><enum>405.</enum><header>Report concerning member state status for Taiwan at the Inter-American Development Bank</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than April 1 of each year thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit an unclassified report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that— </text><paragraph id="H1FB90E7C5E5040BB960DE9C3A620331C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the United States plan to endorse and obtain non-borrowing membership status for Taiwan at the IDB;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H995B2F1A72144DB386099A85ADAB9848"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes an account of the efforts made by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury to encourage IDB member states to promote Taiwan’s bid to obtain non-borrowing membership at the IDB; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70ED3667ACA54316BB4A2AD549140B7E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies the steps that the Secretary of State and the Secretary of the Treasury will take to endorse and obtain non-borrowing membership status for Taiwan at the IDB in the following year.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFF7493BFB9E44625A8BFF40D0A7CEC47"><enum>406.</enum><header>Support for Taiwan admission to the IMF</header><subsection id="H759D8C575B764B72A445CB56B9AC536B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Governor of the International Monetary Fund (in this section referred to as the “Fund”) shall use the voice and vote of the United States to vigorously support—</text><paragraph id="H7E881D07B8D84BDD9472AAE552161602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the admission of Taiwan as a member of the Fund;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACE66A09B35410DAC0B43C79ADA03E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>participation by Taiwan in regular surveillance activities of the Fund with respect to the economic and financial policies of Taiwan, consistent with Article IV consultation procedures of the Fund;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AFB6381D59A4BC1B0AC2A64FED7B845"><enum>(3)</enum><text>employment opportunities for Taiwan nationals, without regard to any consideration that, in the determination of the United States Governor, does not generally restrict the employment of nationals of member countries of the Fund; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E69F5ED287F41A0A7930917752ED0E3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the ability of Taiwan to receive appropriate technical assistance and training by the Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0AB34710310481597963A2A7972BFF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may waive any requirement of subsection (a) for 1 year at a time on reporting to Congress that providing the waiver will substantially promote the objective of securing the meaningful participation of Taiwan at each international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7F1ECF1D798542DB81E489B6672BC03C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall have no force or effect on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="H4454213FBF4D4C658FABB20CE131CE7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date of approval by the Board of Governors of the Fund for the admission of Taiwan as a member of the Fund; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4E9D461B9654B7E8E257E0D5D53470B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE99FDDCD36F546A191208083212B0359"><enum>407.</enum><header>Meaningful participation of Taiwan in the International Civil Aviation Organization</header><subsection id="H88D0B915B56B461D90A3FB6CAD435FA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H18AF6FBB4FAA406497F79DBB4D5F4692"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the International Civil Aviation Organization (ICAO) should allow Taiwan to meaningfully participate in the organization, including in ICAO triennial assembly sessions, conferences, technical working groups, meetings, activities, and mechanisms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA059C7105824142A0AC2E9A38805650"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Taiwan is a global leader and hub for international aviation, with a range of expertise, information, and resources and the fifth busiest airport in Asia (Taoyuan International Airport), and its meaningful participation in ICAO would significantly enhance the ability of ICAO to ensure the safety and security of global aviation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ECC0AC934D24D778D967F34991BAFF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coercion by the Chinese Communist Party and the People’s Republic of China has ensured the systematic exclusion of Taiwan from meaningful participation in ICAO, significantly undermining the ability of ICAO to ensure the safety and security of global aviation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB041CA6183BE4ACAAE4DCD67E1D89459"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan for taiwan’s meaningful participation in the international civil aviation organization</header><text>The Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, is authorized—</text><paragraph id="HD694260E84F6456E9F290D5B51CD9476"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to initiate a United States plan to secure Taiwan’s meaningful participation in ICAO, including in ICAO triennial assembly sessions, conferences, technical working groups, meetings, activities, and mechanisms; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA62E65239CDC4BCDB7FDE4374D9ACE33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to instruct the United States representative to the ICAO to—</text><subparagraph id="H197C14DA25584B23B1B034C14A927C83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use the voice and vote of the United States to ensure Taiwan’s meaningful participation in ICAO, including in ICAO triennial assembly sessions, conferences, technical working groups, meetings, activities, and mechanisms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1458EC078A5D4FF9974314FA385E4E66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to secure a vote at the next ICAO triennial assembly session on the question of Taiwan’s participation in that session.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F62AC7558B04FB4A96A966BC5C6D2A0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report concerning taiwan’s meaningful participation in the international civil aviation organization</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not later than April 1 of each year thereafter for the following 6 years, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Secretary of Commerce, shall submit an unclassified report to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives that—</text><paragraph id="H1D159278D12C4AA0AC2AB6784931FD7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the United States plan to ensure Taiwan’s meaningful participation in ICAO, including in ICAO triennial assembly sessions, conferences, technical working groups, meetings, activities, and mechanisms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC228FB5BDF4C410CB6973F793319222D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes an account of the efforts made by the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce to ensure Taiwan’s meaningful participation in ICAO, including in ICAO triennial assembly sessions, conferences, technical working groups, meetings, activities, and mechanisms; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE39DBB33C241B0A0E6CCADD2ACCF29"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies the steps the Secretary of State and the Secretary of Commerce will take in the next year to ensure Taiwan’s meaningful participation in ICAO, including in ICAO triennial assembly sessions, conferences, technical working groups, meetings, activities, and mechanisms.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H0192E83C68704738BEB5708CF4D5198E" style="OLC" commented="no"><enum>V</enum><header>Enhanced development and economic cooperation between the United States and Taiwan</header><section id="H833E1DC052724C0DAEAA9B75A78309B3" commented="no"><enum>501.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HB2455C06A0AA495B8463A5DAF3AC6673" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taiwan has been an important trading partner of the United States for many years, accounting for $114,000,000,000 in two-way trade in 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5051C3E7ADEF40E6A3E5D443AE2BBF79" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Taiwan has demonstrated the capacity to hold a strong economic partnership with the United States. Along with a robust trading profile of goods and services, Taiwan supports an estimated 208,000 American jobs and its cumulative investment in the United States is at least $13,700,000,000, numbers that will only increase with a comprehensive bilateral trade agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF46C4C66C304BD0B2DF143B5A394AEF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In addition to supplementing United States goods and services, Taiwan is a reliable partner in many United States industries, which is not only critical for diversifying United States supply chains, but is also essential to reducing the United States reliance on other countries, such as China, who seek to leverage supply chain inefficiencies in their path to regional and global dominance. Such diversification of United States supply chains is critical to our national security. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA728195510940C491D7D60947E379EB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The challenges to establishing an agreement with Taiwan, such as reaching an agreement on agricultural standards, must not prevent the completion of a bilateral trade agreement. Taiwan has already taken steps to further the progress towards such an agreement by announcing its intent to lift restrictions on United States pork and beef products, which will greatly increase the accessibility of American farmers and ranchers to Taiwan markets. In light of this important development, the United States should immediately move forward with substantial negotiations for a comprehensive bilateral trade agreement with Taiwan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA9C5CB524034EAAAEA1684E60BF3223" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A free and open Indo-Pacific is a goal that needs to be actively pursued to counter China’s use of unfair trading practices and other policies to advance its economic dominance in the Indo-Pacific region. An agreement with Taiwan would—</text><subparagraph id="HD6D5C2CD528E49C8BA76BF551957246F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">help the United States accomplish this goal by building a network of like-minded governments dedicated to fair competition and open markets that are free from government manipulation; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F02C0A7A91F4E6DBD979CC64DA58D55" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage other nations to deepen economic ties with Taiwan. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23A87737EA104AF28EC6652D66160646" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since November 2020, Taiwan and the United States have engaged in the U.S.-Taiwan Economic Prosperity Partnership Dialogue, covering a broad range of economic issues including—</text><subparagraph id="H7AE1F659330741C09DA7A6E6EBE342FD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5G networks and telecommunications security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6359B679F6324F7E85F69F55AF72F459" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supply chains resiliency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D84A853238C4444880C1F0D64E4DA3D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">infrastructure cooperation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DAA788E281A41D28E77ED366DE21CA8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">renewable energy; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFDC688483334A46A9E063FA822C4D40" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">global health; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4B5E65858AE4B6FA970962EE174170A" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">science and technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H203AD3F6AC67418389A05F45170F0AC6" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A trade agreement between the United States and Taiwan would promote security and economic growth for the United States, Taiwan, and the entire Indo-Pacific region.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A1D7893BC1649F7B04978689DBC9440" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Excluding Taiwan from the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework would— </text><subparagraph id="HB2C79F4EEDA043568CF444A69DE78768" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create significant distortions in the regional and global economic architecture; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE7C4E6080FC4F00B737E10B9A933F20" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">run counter to the United States economic interests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D9F63F6EC614966A72B9403A31AC64F" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Taiwan is the United States largest trading partner with whom we do not have an income tax treaty or agreement. Taiwan has such agreements with 34 countries, including countries that have trade agreements with the United States and do not maintain diplomatic relations with Taiwan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H348458CDEF794AB8B4D2DE700CD7754B" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The American Chamber of Commerce in Taipei, in its <quote>2022 Taiwan White Paper</quote>, called for the United States and Taiwan to continue exploring an income tax agreement to boost bilateral trade and investment by reducing double taxation and increasing economic efficiency and integration. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H54E034CA8EF942A29ECBC4DE7B0FBEFD" commented="no"><enum>502.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on a free trade agreement and bilateral tax agreement with Taiwan, the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework, and CBP Preclearance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HC02DC543B2DA48A0A0B74860A470498F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States Trade Representative should resume meetings under the United States and Taiwan Trade and Investment Framework Agreement with the goal of reaching a bilateral free trade agreement with Taiwan; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFD960B1980C4B308FF56275EFD410C4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Trade Representative should undertake efforts to assess whether the Agreement Concerning Digital Trade, signed at Washington October 7, 2019, and entered into force January 1, 2020, between the United States and Japan, provides a model for a similar agreement between the United States and Taiwan to strengthen economic ties with Taiwan in key sectors; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34E6FA2E63A847009EE340C53EBD4AF0" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Trade Representative and the Secretary of Commerce should undertake efforts to assure Taiwan’s engagement and participation in the Indo-Pacific Economic Framework; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D9C867502FB445A8C755954048FD106" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should utilize and expand Preclearance programs to meet the needs of the United States travel and tourism industry, including by prioritizing the establishment of Preclearance facilities with Indo-Pacific allies and partners, including Taiwan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F8C6C7CFD5B4347B7EDD761B88306AC" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States should—</text><subparagraph id="HB6BDA299B1184F848B077BDB4468727C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>begin negotiations on an income tax agreement between the American Institute in Taiwan and the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74CA4E1D38D0475795AB299814E5BAE3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>work on a congressional-executive agreement to establish such an income tax agreement. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H044965E3B4624519B0B3B06BC639BD83" commented="no"><enum>503.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on United States-Taiwan development cooperation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H45832228FFCC42D99709AAA810391231" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and Taiwan share common development goals in a wide range of sectors, including public health, agriculture, food security, democracy and governance, and education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4832322D6524166AF8CA93A5E8B7AA6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhanced cooperation between the United States and Taiwan would better advance these goals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04A0C46F6FB740A3971F58915F60AF59" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Agency for International Development should explore opportunities to partner with Taiwan on projects in developing countries related to inclusive economic growth, resilience, global health, education, infrastructure, humanitarian assistance, disaster relief, and other areas.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7D62C6CD561D4F5F963A00153B4C6FD1" commented="no"><enum>504.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H0B396C8D7AB1482FB3699823FBA366C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall submit a report to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><paragraph id="HF493D378D87A4DC487470D021A03BD28" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyzes the feasibility and advisability for the establishment of a preclearance facility in Taiwan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA61F6AA5E8A94801A592E5405445331A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the plan for the establishment of a preclearance facility in Taiwan or in other countries in the Indo-Pacific region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE8A62B16DD64FFB84E96587C9845834" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the impacts that preclearance operations in Taiwan will have on—</text><subparagraph id="H1F2CC002CDFF48BABAAA9736924652C7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the security partnership between the United States and Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAA234711C834911B2A73D8485529D6D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>trade between the United States and Taiwan, including the impact on established supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H394C1642D31E4A12BCBB8C3172262872" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the tourism industry in the United States, including the potential impact on revenue and tourist-related commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A73F989870C46EEB3AAAAE9D34985FA" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>United States and foreign passengers traveling to the United States for business-related activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA78B29C46E741A1A0C2947FC0DE3357" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>cost savings and potential market access by expanding operations into the Indo-Pacific region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6714D168C764A9EA7EAD7A819B9D18F" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>opportunities for government-to-government collaboration available in Taiwan after preclearance operations are established; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF481397438754AC7A3A0D8303E38751C" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>U.S. Customs and Border Patrol international and domestic port of entry staffing; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E50FD48FD04DFBB9494F7EFF8C8B0B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>includes country-specific information on the anticipated homeland security benefits and the security vulnerabilities associated with conducting preclearance operations in Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11C38D6D42764A898E02F4B5DB93E41E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H3EDCBA1522EC4454B7793E43252F2CC8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs, the Committee on Finance, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate</committee-name>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55C18E93E01D403EB525B12874E03DD3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives.</committee-name></text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HC15BAEAD2F7E447F9194E8C3854AD6A1"><enum>VI</enum><header>Taiwan Fellowship Program</header><section id="H6A21415499864B99A1F84D5FCB5E13D2" commented="no"><enum>601.</enum><header>Taiwan Fellowship Program</header><subsection id="H04CC6E27627C4B8BB263FDB44C2DF1D5" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="H8018937A838945C09824C4C429AF0C0F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency head</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency head</term> means, in the case of the executive branch of United States Government, or in the case of a legislative branch agency specified in paragraph (2), the head of the respective agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2BCC2B8789E4FD0ACB10141C7208AED" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency of the United States Government</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency of the United States Government</term> includes the Government Accountability Office, the Congressional Budget Office, the Congressional Research Service, and the United States-China Economic and Security Review Commission of the legislative branch, as well as any agency of the executive branch.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H220E47041DF64FFF8C33668780D00500" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBAF79374893546719D301949A156D440" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the Senate</committee-name>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB6966D9729B486785F3C238C8520CCF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate</committee-name>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FA6843968EE4B6CAA736B9539267C14" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives</committee-name>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55BD546B3EDC4E03836930811B4F0F40" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives</committee-name>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H52FB3F87E291439EBA976A765BFF17C3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Detailee</header><text>The term <term>detailee</term> means an employee of an agency of the United States Government on loan to the American Institute in Taiwan, without a change of position from the agency at which such employee is employed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB97CCC45F3140C2B4F2338C734D5240" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Implementing partner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>implementing partner</term> means any United States organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from tax under section 501(a) of such Code that—</text><subparagraph id="HE642677D771B44909667A2C32CA602BF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is selected through a competitive process;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H635C7B43A8F6471AAB37B0C35CB9E434" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">performs logistical, administrative, and other functions, as determined by the Department of State and the American Institute of Taiwan, in support of the Taiwan Fellowship Program; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AB5793E592541089D1E2BB026E1D3C1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enters into a cooperative agreement with the American Institute in Taiwan to administer the Taiwan Fellowship Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9CC495A15DAF46C0AE21294AD7CF625D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Taiwan Fellowship Program</header><paragraph id="H6E6BF9B501C447DC871368C9A8B4704B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall establish the <quote>Taiwan Fellowship Program</quote> (hereafter referred to in this section as the <quote>Program</quote>) to provide a fellowship opportunity in Taiwan of up to two years for eligible United States citizens through the cooperative agreement established in paragraph (2). The Department of State, in consultation with the American Institute in Taiwan and the implementing partner, may modify the name of the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC705FF5543084C27877A8B87154DA690" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><subparagraph id="H53F7A618E81245F9BC9850A63C95AD22" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The American Institute in Taiwan shall use amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to subsection (f)(1) to enter into an annual or multi-year cooperative agreement with an appropriate implementing partner.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AADBDE7C7734EBAB486D76392C0D211" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fellowships</header><text>The Department of State, in consultation with the American Institute in Taiwan and, as appropriate, the implementing partner, shall award to eligible United States citizens, subject to available funding—</text><clause id="HB43C96C57C5B4E5882A1B9846B8BB61D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not fewer than five fellowships during the first two years of the Program; and </text></clause><clause id="HDBB7EEAAF3D54CEF99A57046111C3315" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not fewer than ten fellowships during each of the remaining years of the Program. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD91B1E1339A04C1CA6C76FC734540EF4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>International agreement; implementing partner</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the American Institute in Taiwan, in consultation with the Department of State, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6BA02FE8EB1D426FA82708A24E9660B9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>begin negotiations with the Taipei Economic and Cultural Representative Office, or with another appropriate entity, for the purpose of entering into an agreement to facilitate the placement of fellows in an agency of the governing authorities on Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06C28214747147E7A94FFF82BFEDA603" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>begin the process of selecting an implementing partner, which—</text><clause id="H01B24C2F3E9E43E3AB4FAC9D90451178" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall agree to meet all of the legal requirements required to operate in Taiwan; and </text></clause><clause id="H2D29A8C620E1449C9209A71AC5D419AB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be composed of staff who demonstrate significant experience managing exchange programs in the Indo-Pacific region.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9E579A2AB5A4AC49AB0817E3236DB2E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Curriculum</header><subparagraph id="H18602CF802A0409582587197E749794E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First year</header><text>During the first year of each fellowship under this subsection, each fellow should study—</text><clause id="HD844B30D4E2D453CA405C827C2C0AA56" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Mandarin Chinese language;</text></clause><clause id="H2ACFAA2D99F6410EBB7F09768E71EDE4" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the people, history, and political climate on Taiwan; and</text></clause><clause id="HAD9B6BF023574601A50C1CF503DD8891" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the issues affecting the relationship between the United States and the Indo-Pacific region.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93FB3ED1E02542EDA2FF315FD0196C7A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Second year</header><text>During the second year of each fellowship under this section, each fellow, subject to the approval of the Department of State, the American Institute in Taiwan, and the implementing partner, and in accordance with the purposes of this Act, shall work in— </text><clause id="HC7EB8F91C6614D35AEC8EF5DDADBA918" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a parliamentary office, ministry, or other agency of the governing authorities on Taiwan; or</text></clause><clause id="HA7848DC7550F4350B34C1A267551E2E8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an organization outside of the governing authorities on Taiwan, whose interests are associated with the interests of the fellow and the agency of the United States Government from which the fellow had been employed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2776175A133475AA5EDC49703B36703" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Flexible fellowship duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any requirement under this section, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the American Institute in Taiwan and, as appropriate, the implementing partner, may award fellowships that have a duration of between nine months and two years, and may alter the curriculum requirements under paragraph (4) for such purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9982A8B2A82F4E86B8F77C6343769D56" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Program shall terminate ten years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3E28E9B6A824CCC8E8ED714987C9D1A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program requirements</header><paragraph id="HE4D78DB0DB274985B47550947E240785" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A United States citizen is eligible for a fellowship under this section if he or she—</text><subparagraph id="HDA5A4146B7B845B99E2537CA2C2A74D7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an employee of the United States Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3241E697B30E4EDA82A3F0299A714991" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has received at least one exemplary performance review in his or her current United States Government role within at least the last three years prior to the beginning of the fellowship;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FF29C89E24C49CD995E2504610695DE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has at least two years of experience in any branch of the United States Government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F1BD2A62B284FA8B87FFB36678F9E21" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has a demonstrated professional or educational background in the relationship between the United States and countries in the Indo-Pacific region; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DF24199921B47D6A7353218465E7948" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has demonstrated his or her commitment to further service in the United States Government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H408307FE28E4492D8823FD182AA0F230" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Responsibilities of fellows</header><text>Each recipient of a fellowship under this section shall agree, as a condition of such fellowship—</text><subparagraph id="HBAAE9773648F4D699E8796713975640A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to maintain satisfactory progress in language training and appropriate behavior in Taiwan, as determined by the Department of State, the American Institute in Taiwan and, as appropriate, its implementing partner;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C87BD495B244D32ADA5B5BFE89586AF" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to refrain from engaging in any intelligence or intelligence-related activity on behalf of the United States Government; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1C16637B6CB4C9F9B1205AFEC570D83" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to continue Federal Government employment for a period of not less than four years after the conclusion of the fellowship or for not less than two years for a fellowship that is one year or shorter.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE851BA6EFF4119B9A8858015130E44" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities of implementing partner</header><subparagraph id="H6B4FD1518CCF4336AF0865C1D530534C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selection of fellows</header><text>The implementing partner, in close coordination with the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan, shall—</text><clause id="H579755B8B227478988B9E322E05CA3D4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text> make efforts to recruit fellowship candidates who reflect the diversity of the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H81C3BA6C6D02432783C769AB28DBE9BE" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>select fellows for the Program based solely on merit, with appropriate supervision from the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan; and</text></clause><clause id="H41C49042127046309AB7E27F44A7D1FE" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prioritize the selection of candidates willing to serve a fellowship lasting one year or longer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3262097A34642A692CDAAE5680EB209" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>First year</header><text>The implementing partner should provide each fellow in the first year (or shorter duration, as jointly determined by the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan for those who are not serving a two-year fellowship) with—</text><clause id="H5DDDDD95D8814EE6A5B3DE5369A43161" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intensive Mandarin Chinese language training; and</text></clause><clause id="H3DB3CAD526834F9FAE0C89F2315A6FFB" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">courses in the politic, culture, and history of Taiwan, China, and the broader Indo-Pacific.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53CC4D6D22B44B50837D62158E0B49EC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Waiver of required training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of State, in coordination with the American Institute in Taiwan and, as appropriate, the implementing partner, may waive any of the training required under subparagraph (B) to the extent that a fellow has Mandarin Chinese language skills, knowledge of the topic described in subparagraph (B)(ii), or for other related reasons approved by the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan. If any of the training requirements are waived for a fellow serving a two-year fellowship, the training portion of his or her fellowship may be shortened to the extent appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAD34591746743919E23524DB4EC1407" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Office; staffing</header><text>The implementing partner, in consultation with the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan, shall maintain an office and at least one full-time staff member in Taiwan—</text><clause id="H05BB371C6B2F4664B76E7011A5ACB024" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to liaise with the American Institute in Taiwan and the governing authorities on Taiwan; and </text></clause><clause id="H9D718CE6A99544A69F8317AB30D79F2B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to serve as the primary in-country point of contact for the recipients of fellowships under this section and their dependents. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0048AD7DC3814E6D96E3FC08A9FA5D00" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Other functions</header><text>The implementing partner should perform other functions in association in support of the Program, including logistical and administrative functions, as prescribed by the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB951C3BFFD334DACA2505A6F84D6FF78" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><subparagraph id="H46961C344C0340659347E84B1A7F7FB3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any fellow who fails to comply with the requirements under this section shall reimburse the American Institute in Taiwan for—</text><clause id="H0B73DE2024014C71B60FDB9D1527DF3A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal funds expended for the fellow’s participation in the fellowship, as set forth in subparagraphs (B) and (C); and</text></clause><clause id="HDC4023F6242648DF84BAD2093EC45B71" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interest accrued on such funds (calculated at the prevailing rate).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC23C0EF69944B4A99C40CB36F3CCDBA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Full reimbursement</header><text>Any fellow who violates subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (2) shall reimburse the American Institute in Taiwan in an amount equal to the sum of—</text><clause id="HAC3AA4D2E9334280A8A9E08C528D59D7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all of the Federal funds expended for the fellow’s participation in the fellowship; and</text></clause><clause id="H0A2D4C40F56C42FF920C05C0C496EF1E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interest on the amount specified in clause (i), which shall be calculated at the prevailing rate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H330F1ECEEAC34D72902EED4439E8615B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pro rata reimbursement</header><text>Any fellow who violates paragraph (2)(C) shall reimburse the American Institute in Taiwan in an amount equal to the difference between—</text><clause id="H4C11D0718DC74845B88088259A411799" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount specified in subparagraph (B); and<pagebreak></pagebreak></text></clause><clause id="H3CCEE1B166954AAD93A305B5D8016BD9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the product of—</text><subclause id="H1F3E134A7A2F47DFB511FB0B80F24A93" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the amount the fellow received in compensation during the final year of the fellowship, including the value of any allowances and benefits received by the fellow; multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="HC855BF3B9A534F8CB9072BA1036A6098" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the percentage of the period specified in paragraph (2)(C) during which the fellow did not remain employed by the United States Government.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H500DBE8A537645ED90B491C11AFF658E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the selection of the first class of fellows under this Act, and annually thereafter for ten years, the Department of State shall offer to brief the appropriate congressional committees regarding the following issues:</text><subparagraph id="HEEFCB20252C3439C86011B4B3446A2BC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the performance of the implementing partner in fulfilling the purposes of this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF66CA4B3473E4B8986D7079CDBFCEF3C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of applicants each year, the number of applicants willing to serve a fellowship lasting one year or longer, and the number of such applicants selected for the fellowship.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H191DC4017B2A451CAF8CC03165B14738" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The names and sponsoring agencies of the fellows selected by the implementing partner and the extent to which such fellows represent the diversity of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9515E8683CA4387BEAD46CA9C2D6E2E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The names of the parliamentary offices, ministries, other agencies of the governing authorities on Taiwan, and nongovernmental institutions to which each fellow was assigned.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA6680A540184B5796C8D0CC9C3B673B" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any recommendations, as appropriate, to improve the implementation of the Program, including added flexibilities in the administration of the program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88C13BF803574CCBBB0F0494D2B1B575" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An assessment of the Program’s value upon the relationship between the United States and Taiwan or the United States and Asian countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66E3384EE122462C93478C698B3529DF" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Annual financial audit</header><subparagraph id="H4EDB4DDE33434276ABA18586C3B88067" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The financial records of any implementing partner shall be audited annually in accordance with generally accepted auditing standards by independent certified public accountants or independent licensed public accountants who are certified or licensed by a regulatory authority of a State or another political subdivision of the United States. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE46727DED2146E39EEABA7A05F55A80" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Location</header><text>Each audit under subparagraph (A) shall be conducted at the place or places where the financial records of the implementing partner are normally kept. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BB1C504137046E191016C1855819E8A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Access to documents</header><text>The implementing partner shall make available to the accountants conducting an audit under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H17761EB8A2AC4C08B17CD1B243B44362" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all books, financial records, files, other papers, things, and property belonging to, or in use by, the implementing partner that are necessary to facilitate the audit; and</text></clause><clause id="H9891E79F98864BA48EC51052CC0D2D3E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>full facilities for verifying transactions with the balances or securities held by depositories, fiscal agents, and custodians.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F8327A3172C4AB5A9F61C793757723A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report</header><clause id="H3D5A6F56E5CE46B0BAEE87669D62213A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than six months after the end of each fiscal year, the implementing partner shall provide a report of the audit conducted for such fiscal year under subparagraph (A) to the Department of State and the American Institute in Taiwan. </text></clause><clause id="HF3F5385674C849489A9CD8CE47A32577" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each audit report shall—</text><subclause id="H0EA3D97992B34E7A9375649163A9194E" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>set forth the scope of the audit;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFA60BF18E63847D98C920F0A92788579" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>include such statements, along with the auditor’s opinion of those statements, as may be necessary to present fairly the implementing partner’s assets and liabilities, surplus or deficit, with reasonable detail;</text></subclause><subclause id="H61DC29D282EF4CE38E48CF63EDC9137D" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>include a statement of the implementing partner’s income and expenses during the year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H5B438410CDBB40C39F4BED52A19C39E4" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>include a schedule of—</text><item id="H9A32858EB9EF4B6684AA8C0AE9E7E353" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all contracts and cooperative agreements requiring payments greater than $5,000; and </text></item><item id="H713E4A24A6D14E88A279FFAD19CF9AD4" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>any payments of compensation, salaries, or fees at a rate greater than $5,000 per year. </text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HED3CEC8F35314A26910948CFB225D246" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Copies</header><text>Each audit report shall be produced in sufficient copies for distribution to the public.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H136AC0520CBE4134AA787CE7D9182B0D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Taiwan fellows on detail from Government service</header><paragraph id="HC239E73911324A1393613D5BAFE885A6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HA72137A8A2A54982A18F482BCF5E376D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Detail authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With the approval of the Secretary of State, an agency head may detail, for a period of not more than two years, an employee of the agency of the United States Government who has been awarded a fellowship under this Act, to the American Institute in Taiwan for the purpose of assignment to the governing authorities on Taiwan or an organization described in subsection (b)(4)(B)(ii).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F9BD603B52F4750B1A2F0214F932618" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each detailee shall enter into a written agreement with the Federal Government before receiving a fellowship, in which the fellow shall agree—</text><clause id="HA7EF03809CA744FCBB57780495B19D2F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to continue in the service of the sponsoring agency at the end of fellowship for a period of at least four years (or at least two years if the fellowship duration is one year or shorter) unless such detailee is involuntarily separated from the service of such agency; and</text></clause><clause id="HA0793C1519934A1FA70B93AFFD7C8D1B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to pay to the American Institute in Taiwan any additional expenses incurred by the United States Government in connection with the fellowship if the detailee voluntarily separates from service with the sponsoring agency before the end of the period for which the detailee has agreed to continue in the service of such agency.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H814AC08F7669456295DFB1F53420D3FC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The payment agreed to under subparagraph (B)(ii) may not be required of a detailee who leaves the service of the sponsoring agency to enter into the service of another agency of the United States Government unless the head of the sponsoring agency notifies the detailee before the effective date of entry into the service of the other agency that payment will be required under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H360796D829F04878BFA95E3E44957F43" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Status as Government employee</header><text>A detailee—</text><subparagraph id="H38300D64286E40EFA76859D2FA8AD6DE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is deemed, for the purpose of preserving allowances, privileges, rights, seniority, and other benefits, to be an employee of the sponsoring agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA82DF833E31B478E9A6A75BDC3C7F67E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is entitled to pay, allowances, and benefits from funds available to such agency, which is deemed to comply with section 5536 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3949F862082F41A59D1A8D3E95C05AA9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be assigned to a position with an entity described in subsection (b)(4)(B)(i) if acceptance of such position does not involve—</text><clause id="H9F534525395F4C00A476189EBF2B3AEA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the taking of an oath of allegiance to another government; or </text></clause><clause id="H90834E4A785B4871B2BA385B3EDF8BD7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the acceptance of compensation or other benefits from any foreign government by such detailee. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H68FC9CE67CDD4822A70D3A02F7B61A4E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Responsibilities of sponsoring agency</header><subparagraph id="H8385B003DD164A839D0B3353B1237E15" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The agency of the United States Government from which a detailee is detailed should provide the fellow allowances and benefits that are consistent with Department of State Standardized Regulations or other applicable rules and regulations, including—</text><clause id="H5438B0598CF044D1B0241DD0CC81A14D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a living quarters allowance to cover the cost of housing in Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="H3A8558D306BB4A4C94838FD23666ABAC" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a cost-of-living allowance to cover any possible higher costs of living in Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="HE7E5F31C358E40D684741922535F8A9E" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a temporary quarters subsistence allowance for up to seven days if the fellow is unable to find housing immediately upon arriving in Taiwan;</text></clause><clause id="HB1399C052FD648E98A6B1A84C1C0E88F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an education allowance to assist parents in providing the fellow’s minor children with educational services ordinarily provided without charge by public schools in the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H9CD3845DC35B4E218A69032CC6177486" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>moving expenses to transport personal belongings of the fellow and his or her family in their move to Taiwan, which is comparable to the allowance given for American Institute in Taiwan employees assigned to Taiwan; and</text></clause><clause id="HD5858FCB86AD47B39F3F41D24331DD1C" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>an economy-class airline ticket to and from Taiwan for each fellow and the fellow’s immediate family.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4A2A7234EFE4790A1A8D911E55FC48F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Modification of benefits</header><text>The American Institute in Taiwan and its implementing partner, with the approval of the Department of State, may modify the benefits set forth in subparagraph (A) if such modification is warranted by fiscal circumstances. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H799D2283FF2B4B149431CE2A44B1AFC5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No financial liability</header><text>The American Institute in Taiwan, the implementing partner, and any governing authorities on Taiwan or nongovernmental entities in Taiwan at which a fellow is detailed during the second year of the fellowship may not be held responsible for the pay, allowances, or any other benefit normally provided to the detailee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF67F578C3E4C5FABDEC72A3B010F71" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>Fellows may be detailed under paragraph (1)(A) without reimbursement to the United States by the American Institute in Taiwan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96D70A9E334E4F6194DD4EE7E2AB7233" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Allowances and benefits</header><text>Detailees may be paid by the American Institute in Taiwan for the allowances and benefits listed in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE975798500514738A23D37F5402725B0" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year prior to the sunset of the Program pursuant to subsection (b)(6), the Comptroller General of the United States shall transmit to the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="H0920F5C7ED6144C9AD8565DF85EDF77E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An analysis of United States Government participants in the Program, including the number of applicants and the number of fellowships undertaken, and the places of employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD391C231EDF425BBB33BB0008B4892E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the costs and benefits for participants in the Program and for the United States Government of such fellowships.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ED8A5CE93CF42FAB55B8F733F159793" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An analysis of the financial impact of the fellowship on United States Government offices that have detailed fellows to participate in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2631F4AF8F664EAF935AFFFB58E541D5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations, if any, on how to improve the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAD7C9B83A7F498BA19C7D871E82B9B6" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H8DB2C83019704FF7932FD81E444BC655" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the American Institute in Taiwan—</text><subparagraph id="HE3B3008045584A4F9CE97BEB74F7597B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for fiscal year 2023, $2,900,000, of which $500,000 should be used by an appropriate implementing partner to launch the Program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABCDF5D1AEF84FAFBD696B4D1E1C7C73" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2024, and each succeeding fiscal year, $2,400,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H96DEA446F6E649A7AEC99ED1E727D3F4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private sources</header><text>Subject to appropriation, the implementing partner selected to implement the Program may accept, use, and dispose of gifts or donations of services or property in carrying out such program, subject to the review and approval of the American Institute in Taiwan.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="H4BA62A678C094E07A1B41BFD761AF751" style="OLC"><enum>VII</enum><header>Miscellaneous provisions</header><section id="H92A05407E8D446BB94B607E676633951"><enum>701.</enum><header>Invitation of Taiwanese counterparts to high-level bilateral and multilateral forums and exercises</header><subsection id="HBF8CF46F41484E09BA40097E025A8F6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to invite Taiwanese counterparts to participate in high-level bilateral and multilateral summits, military exercises, and economic dialogues and forums.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5F12715A43F248158C081F591DD76397"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H640E9AF025C640D9B718249105D50C73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States Government should invite Taiwan to regional dialogues on issues of mutual concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B5450DF39784ABE8DEAB561CEE17D00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Government and Taiwanese counterparts should resume meetings under the United States-Taiwan Trade and Investment Framework Agreement and reach a bilateral free trade agreement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C8025041BBF4423BB9C673EB82CE893"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States Government should invite Taiwan to participate in bilateral and multilateral military training exercises;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7AC0C1D492418E9A8E958B924426E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States Government and Taiwanese counterparts should engage in a regular and routine strategic bilateral dialogue on arms sales in accordance with Foreign Military Sales mechanisms; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F13CBA3DC9245FBB7B5A8A2094B36B5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States Government should support export licenses for direct commercial sales supporting Taiwan’s indigenous defensive capabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA3BA00923B3F4B58941737399D7EB2BF"><enum>702.</enum><header>Report on Taiwan Travel Act</header><subsection id="H5E3555FABC5A4E04AF549F6F938BC533"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List of high-Level visits</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for the following 5 years, the Secretary of State, in accordance with the Taiwan Travel Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/135">Public Law 115–135</external-xref>), shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees—</text><paragraph id="HE1B49499DE01450BB91A4126DE7EE851"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of high-level officials from the United States Government who have traveled to Taiwan; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D913BF55F874BB4A3415F4217563C06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of high-level officials of Taiwan who have entered the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC81088DD0ABF442782C9F9953DD1689B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for a period of 5 years, the Secretary of State shall submit a report on the implementation of the Taiwan Travel Act to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1A8FD0918E0B49B2BEC973985D989ED8"><enum>703.</enum><header>Authorization of Global Cooperation and Training Framework</header><subsection id="HA94D0B7B549B40FBA397D09AA251B543"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Global cooperation and training framework</header><paragraph id="H450C32E370E1424390FF2B8E4F1193B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State is authorized to conduct training programs, workshops, and other activities with the government of Taiwan pursuant to the Memorandum of Understanding between the United States and Taiwan signed in 2015 on the Global Cooperation and Training Framework.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE68E94BCA1884E2BA57D91BBD7AA0843"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that Global Cooperation and Training Framework activities that promote ties between the United States, Taiwan, and other democratic partners, or that undergird Taiwan’s diplomatic relationships, or that counter malign authoritarian activities, are particularly beneficial to our shared interests, and that examples of such activities in 2019 include—</text><subparagraph id="HFD5582E0B0434742ACE4CD3B6266CE06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the <quote>Good Energy Governance in the Indo-Pacific</quote> workshop, co-hosted by Japan and Australia;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B08FEF7779F4C2DAA47C16CE1768E8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the <quote>International Austronesian Languages Revitalization Forum</quote>, co-hosted with Japan and held in Palau, a nation that maintains diplomatic relations with Taiwan; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F45C09D90D3484F880ECAB582EE5A3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the <quote>Defending Democracy through Media Literacy II</quote> workshop, which focused on addressing and countering disinformation in democratic elections and was co-hosted by Japan and Sweden; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2AE83C8EB59447A93EA034CFB402474"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the <quote>Anti-Corruption in the Public and Private Sections</quote> workshop, which focused on promoting clean governance, preventing corporate governance, and preserving competitiveness through trade secret protection, and co-hosted by Japan. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73EDE7B43D704B848EAFE5B096770216"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2023 through 2026 for the Global Cooperation and Training Framework.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA9DFC90DBFE44AFCB63CE2E3BB894E9D"><enum>704.</enum><header>Prohibitions against undermining United States policy regarding Taiwan</header><subsection id="HF09153B02AD742A1B941431DF19A4232"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that the efforts by the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party to compel private United States businesses, corporations, and nongovernmental entities to use language mandated by the People’s Republic of China (referred to in this section as the <quote>PRC</quote>) to describe the relationship between Taiwan and the PRC are an illegitimate attempt to enforce political censorship globally.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C11618758E34C0D90489D55F26DB972"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the United States Government, in coordination with United States businesses and nongovernmental entities, should formulate a code of conduct for, and otherwise coordinate on, interacting with the Government of the PRC and the Chinese Communist Party and their affiliated entities, the aim of which is—</text><paragraph id="HF4575AF9270D4ECBA59107083A69BC51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to counter PRC operations that threaten free speech, academic freedom, and the normal operations of United States businesses and nongovernmental entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BBCDDCFA5A745AABEEDC94F97C89B32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to counter PRC efforts to censor the way the world refers to issues deemed sensitive to the PRC Government and Chinese Communist Party leaders, including issues related to Taiwan, Tibet, the Tiananmen Square Massacre, and the mass internment of Uyghurs and other Turkic Muslims, among many other issues.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7F9AA7AB97B4BA3B629969CF6484435" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition against recognizing the People's Republic of China's claims to sovereignty over Taiwan</header><paragraph id="H774E6FBBC76D46F8B31C067250CA1F89" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><subparagraph id="HE711DF6386B740E29CCBEE8198C59D38" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues related to the sovereignty of Taiwan are for the people of Taiwan to decide through the democratic process they have established;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H631E7440DA784445A63E5D2B8BADB5B9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the dispute between the PRC and Taiwan must be resolved peacefully and with the assent of the people of Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDED5EE96B18C4B9298440647A561877F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the 2 key obstacles to peaceful resolution are—</text><clause id="H9414BEE452104924826240B7CFBA8604" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the authoritarian nature of the PRC political system under one-party rule of the Chinese Communist Party, which is fundamentally incompatible with Taiwan’s democracy; and</text></clause><clause id="H628B1000D4AF47D7993DE071A5625C77" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the PRC’s pursuit of coercion and aggression towards Taiwan, in potential violation of the third United States-PRC Joint Communiqué, which was completed on August 17, 1982;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H788DF5B5D8344738A15A49AD5816DEA7" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any attempt to coerce or force the people of Taiwan to accept a political arrangement that would subject them to direct or indirect rule by the PRC, including a <quote>one country, two systems</quote> framework, would constitute a grave challenge to United States security interests in the region.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A365368F3A14B34B22C431478B03F6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States to oppose any attempt by the PRC authorities to unilaterally impose a timetable or deadline for unification on Taiwan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29E8C6E9E7A449738099316FFC953B4C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on recognition of PRC claims without the assent of people of Taiwan</header><text>No department or agency of the United States Government may formally or informally recognize PRC claims to sovereignty over Taiwan without the assent of the people of Taiwan, as expressed directly through the democratic process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBAF03CF294CD400C88BDE23222792566"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Strategy To protect United States businesses and nongovernmental entities from coercion</header><paragraph id="H5843904C5A124E0EA340DFB1CE6247E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Treasury, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall submit an unclassified report, with a classified annex, if necessary, on how to protect United States businesses and nongovernmental entities from PRC operations, including coercion and threats that lead to censorship or self-censorship, or which compel compliance with political or foreign policy positions of the Government of the People’s Republic of China and the Chinese Communist Party. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60E411A663AD408DB4E46AFFC08BB307"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H54B8E51CD6D645CFAC88E1AE1CFEE42E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information regarding efforts by the PRC Government to censor the websites of United States airlines, hotels, and other businesses regarding the relationship between Taiwan and the PRC;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EE37E9B5CE548A281C6E91CFD4DDD17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information regarding efforts by the PRC Government to target United States nongovernmental entities through operations intended to weaken support for Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB951CA894B88401CA2DDCC507696A7D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information regarding United States Government efforts to counter the threats posed by Chinese state-sponsored propaganda and disinformation, including information on best practices, current successes, and existing barriers to responding to such threat; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C1279563D224310B7352E2170B3F59D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>details of any actions undertaken to create the code of conduct described in subsection (b), including a timetable for the implementation of such code of conduct.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6C644332025C403D9516FA48090A10DB"><enum>705.</enum><header>Amendments to the Taiwan Allies International Protection and Enhancement Initiative (Taipei) Act of 2019</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Taiwan Allies International Protection and Enhancement Initiative (TAIPEI) Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/135">Public Law 116–135</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE50EA21942904CB8BFF317F3464BD4AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 2(5), by striking <quote>and Kiribati</quote> and inserting <quote>Kiribati, and Nicaragua,</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DCE29B466D946A1B2BCD350F3B5B8DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 4—</text><subparagraph id="HEAE49C71F7DA4850990ADB150D1E0012"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>should be</quote> and inserting <quote>is</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A3A479EEF7B4FF9905C3CF950FCBF2D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADE8BB26BB2442A3B61CDB937EA579D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4AE123FC53854A40A9B3983633A5B617"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD91599E8A2DD43138A72BEA0F9C63DA2"><paragraph id="H962E4CED7DD04C749CD5AB2B2B477B56"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support Taiwan’s diplomatic relations with other governments and countries.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02BF7146EF344391AE9FF2DE86B60154"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 5—</text><subparagraph id="H7C20EBC3E4C547E38A7D0601F7DA3694"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="HFFCB0DB69D604C01A8212DCBD387F9EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></clause><clause id="HD4E639827232406594F109E133AAB4BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H01459D03DD494516A3AB6DB632542A61"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4976E96052D640548BE36AFD1077601B"><paragraph id="H24ABB1053D8D40A8AA7B8AEE1661CC21"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify why governments and countries have altered their diplomatic status vis-a-vis Taiwan and make recommendations to mitigate further deterioration in Taiwan’s diplomatic relations with other governments and countries.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE04E86EDE9D4DECAE8646266DEDC440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for five years, the Secretary of State shall report</quote> and inserting <quote>90 days after the date of the enactment of the Taiwan Policy Act of 2022, and annually thereafter for a period of 7 years, the Secretary of State shall submit an unclassified report, with a classified annex,</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1877CBF55DA4458B0DDB5AE63CB74A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1013F6BD79340D5B2C33E8FB3B04E70"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC66741A83754C668BE644A2FEE03080"><subsection id="H8A642E5ED03A48618C26201093F62C6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Briefings</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the Taiwan Policy Act of 2022, and annually thereafter for a period of 7 years, the Department of State shall provide briefings to the appropriate congressional committees on the steps taken in accordance with section (a). The briefings required under this subsection shall take place in an unclassified setting, but may be accompanied by an additional classified briefing.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H2E489EBEB2EF454C8DDDD9664C510A2A" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>706.</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text><paragraph id="H300E43428F7B4AA8AFE91DF2CCB5B9A3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to restore diplomatic relations with the Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71F8834DE1A3477487BF9212A96E27C9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to alter the United States Government’s position with respect to the international status of the Republic of China.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HED44F2F94E0545AAAC4B89E670C81AAC"><enum>707.</enum><header>Consolidation of reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any reports required to be submitted under this Act or any amendment made by this Act that are subject to deadlines for submission consisting of similar units of time may be consolidated into a single report. </text></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

