<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5171748046CD422F922A12255B417B3B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7097 IH: Telehealth Treatment and Technology Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7097</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220316">March 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To facilitate the provision of telehealth services through interstate recognition of health care professionals’ licenses, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H52B2C2B772B24743BBCB082C1E0A8C48" style="OLC"><section id="HAF154427F47F46119237A11BAC5CD77E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Telehealth Treatment and Technology Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>3T Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7C6DE4DEE4604C8A93D4C14FD11176DC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of telehealth and Interstate treatment</header><subsection id="HDAA81619EC5541F2A63A6E6520AFB542"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of Federal or State law or regulation regarding the licensure or certification of health care providers or the provision of telehealth services, a health care professional may practice within the scope of the individual’s license, certification, or authorization described in subsection (i)(1)(A) through telehealth in any State, the District of Columbia, or any territory or possession of the United States, or any other location designated by the Secretary, based on the licensure, certification, or authorization of such individual in any one State, the District of Columbia, or territory or possession of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H644FEA398B7945AEBDCB045F9C73AD6C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope of telehealth services</header><text>Telehealth services authorized by this section include services provided to any patient regardless of whether the health care professional has a prior treatment relationship with the patient, provided that, if the health care professional does not have a prior treatment relationship with the patient, a new relationship may be established only via a written acknowledgment or synchronous technology.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8CCC027999B44A498FCABDD5E49851B9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initiation of telehealth services</header><text>Before providing telehealth services authorized by this section, the health care professional shall—</text><paragraph id="HE356340C6B7A427090D0B2A770FD3F04"><enum>(1)</enum><text>verify the identification of the patient receiving health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H81A322E9C2D64CF9B97AD082DC44C5DF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>obtain oral or written acknowledgment from the patient (or legal representative of the patient) to perform telehealth services, and if such acknowledgment is oral, make a record of such acknowledgment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27D299180280432DA4471E7D43D1FB66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>obtain or confirm an alternative method of contacting the patient in case of a technological failure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C7DEEE3605642C8B44B88E1364C2DCE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Written notice of provision of services</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 30 days after first providing services pursuant to this section in a jurisdiction other than the jurisdiction in which a health care professional is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized, such health care professional shall provide written notice to the applicable licensing, certifying, or authorizing authority in the jurisdiction in which the health care professional provided such services. Such notice shall include the health care professional’s—</text><paragraph id="H8CDAFC439E3B4F19AF94906A0E967967"><enum>(1)</enum><text>name;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4B2D1E479B4404688C9CEAFACC07276"><enum>(2)</enum><text>email address;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5C0DD5123A14513B6D7353600A2BE3E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>phone number;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC8E2D9633074D5FA99EC9179A9C08B6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State of primary license, certification, or authorization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD572A48113304E2E80BD13CAF95EBF38"><enum>(5)</enum><text>license, certification, or authorization type, and applicable number or identifying information with respect to such license, certification, or authorization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H535FE913D36C4708AA2BF3A4AB4A2483"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Nothing in this section authorizes a health care professional to—</text><paragraph id="H05651B0237AD4ADA9E14CC00E46D1E6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>practice beyond the scope of practice authorized by—</text><subparagraph id="HBFFED77D2331488E8D85FE3B3FDBC91E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any State, District of Columbia, territorial, or local authority in the jurisdiction in which the health care professional holds a license, certification, or authorization described in section 3(1)(A); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48121458F824CA195A4DFB1E31EC913" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any State, District of Columbia, territorial, or local authority in the jurisdiction in which the patient receiving services is located;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0309C31D02D49C1A79A25448F4AA493"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide any service or subset of services prohibited by any such authority in the jurisdiction in which the patient receiving services is located;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF218A7DFFC604B08B9720E2A69304EE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide any service or subset of services in a manner prohibited by any such authority the jurisdiction in which the patient receiving services is located; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D8CA440F3E34517B505C00AC794FD3A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide any service or subset of services in a manner other than the manner prescribed by any such authority in the jurisdiction in which the patient receiving services is located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62B83401CAA24663AC905DC12F42FC10"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Investigative and disciplinary authority</header><text>A health care professional providing services pursuant to the authority under this section shall be subject to investigation and disciplinary action by the licensing, certifying, or authorizing authorities in the jurisdiction in which the patient receiving services is located. The jurisdiction in which the patient receiving services is located shall have the authority to preclude the health care provider from practicing further in its jurisdiction, whether such practice is authorized by the laws of such jurisdiction or the authority granted under this section, and shall report any such preclusion to the licensing authority in the jurisdiction in which the health care provider is licensed, certified, or authorized.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA2501D4F0875425087CADE639753B625"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Multiple jurisdiction licensure</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, a health care professional shall be subject to the requirements of the jurisdiction of licensure if the professional is licensed in the State, the District of Columbia, or territory or possession where the patient is located.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7C58C6507164A2CB238D43D70624716"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Interstate licensure compacts</header><text>If a health care professional is licensed in multiple jurisdictions through an interstate licensure compact, with respect to services provided to a patient located in a jurisdiction covered by such compact, the health care professional shall be subject to the requirements of the compact and not this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H478DD35F51ED476388C908A4FA51D8FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H89ECDC36162948FDB91363A48A141705"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>health care professional</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H5D325590B745462281879EF84D99F206"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has a valid and unrestricted license or certification from, or is otherwise authorized by, a State, the District of Columbia, or a territory or possession of the United States, for any health profession, including mental health; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F775F8AFF08406EAE65F4246B2AB889"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not affirmatively excluded from practice in the licensing or certifying jurisdiction or in any other jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18BC99D265E24316A75F935967E79A15"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51AA6569105B4B26AC15981260FBD787"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>telehealth services</term> means use of telecommunications and information technology (including synchronous or asynchronous audio-visual, audio-only, or store and forward technology) to provide access to physical and mental health assessment, diagnosis, treatment, intervention, consultation, supervision, and information across distance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5A8A1F969E324A96B56BD5B837C68C25" section-type="subsequent-section" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Revision of HIPAA regulations to ensure patient access to telehealth services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall revise the HIPAA privacy regulation (as defined in section 1180(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320d-9">42 U.S.C. 1320d–9(b)(3)</external-xref>)) to ensure that, with respect to services furnished by a health care provider via telehealth on or after the first day following the end of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>), such provider may so furnish such services using any non-public facing audio or video communication product (as such term is used for purposes of the notice entitled <quote>Notification of Enforcement Discretion for Telehealth Remote Communications During the COVID–19 Nationwide Public Health Emergency</quote> as published by the Office of Civil Rights of the Department of Health and Human Services).</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

