<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="HD7220A0C7867462C875E44497F2E49F9"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9036 IH: Peer-to-Peer Suicide Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9036</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to facilitate peer-to-peer suicide prevention programs for middle school and high school students, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H22992B660A694F949200A8C57D2A9E6D" style="OLC"><section id="H599D4EDBEDAC436987916AC2E2CF79AF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Peer-to-Peer Suicide Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H627CA1EDA05E40C38C17B3896FC94402" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Peer-to-peer suicide prevention grant program</header><subsection id="H657E34D9392646D183177710DB997109"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall establish a program (in this section, referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities for the purpose of facilitating peer-to-peer suicide prevention programs for middle school and high school students.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD9785D8037EA4256B4F1F6105CCF197E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the Program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40286A97C89D4643B70786E4EAC56BC3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><text>An eligible entity may only use grant amounts provided under the Program to—</text><paragraph id="HA29B216F1AFC4D018871D371ABB6FCA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist an existing peer-to-peer suicide prevention program; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD0007D84A8445B8AE093CD3524038FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a new peer-to-peer suicide prevention program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB396EBAB7C2A46308C0913C873D68467"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal programs</header><text>An eligible entity that receives a grant under the Program may combine such grant with other Federal funds awarded to support the activities carried out with the grant.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9E70CDAC9BED42A0BC2C2DEDEFFFC0D9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Awarding of grants</header><paragraph id="H2592FB4A9FEC41FAB66B21ABD3CF6D2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H620CF5CD2DEE4F1BA90A39B3FA84F8E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Eligible entities not previously awarded a grant under the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF6FF79E5A0140439763D8BD6C35A34D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entities proposing to use grant amounts to establish a new peer-to-peer suicide prevention program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC872B8E852EA4EFE86082EBD6DB28168"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entities that demonstrate the ability to provide peer-to-peer suicide prevention programming that is evidence-informed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C0684E223B74197B9D574DB2B122A98"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Eligible entities that demonstrate the ability to provide peer-to-peer suicide prevention programming that is culturally and linguistically competent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97D5CB97B20E40B594092710554C1749"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Peer-to-peer suicide prevention programs focused primarily on student, rather than teacher, training.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA105CE8ACF4F4BBD9DD8D4E2F51D3027"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded to an eligible entity under the Program may not exceed $5,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47F0BFEF480446EE9A44D8AD31E52CBA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination with SAMHSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall consult with the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration for purposes of developing the Program and selecting eligible entities to receive grants under Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE44CD05A412F493D8C151E73AE2EDDE2"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation process</header><text>The Secretary shall develop and implement a process to evaluate the performance of eligible entities that receive grants under the Program. The Secretary shall ensure that the evaluation process incorporates input from students.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBD371F87029E49AC8AE615D2861E0724"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Health and Human Services (acting through the Administrator of the Substance Abuse and Mental Health Services Administration) shall carry out a program to provide technical assistance to eligible entities applying for and receiving grants under this section, which shall include the development and dissemination of best practices for peer-to-peer suicide prevention programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H90BC7C4984B849EF888E07EFCAB8FC88"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000 each fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32DEAE83976D461E90EADBAC51036334"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HF7A1AA79880C4432AC6EF8EDF2CA6CE2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means any of the following that serve at least one school that provides education at the middle school or high school level:</text><subparagraph id="HE1D8320E0F444D69A76961866BAC6671" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A local educational agency (including a charter school that is a local educational agency).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC1557D3223C4E24871E504EA047E51D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An Indian Tribe (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)) or a Tribal educational agency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03F18DE41078468FA02240905A6D52F9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Bureau of Indian Education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H618AC547C4864F44A210C8F53497BAED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>ESEA Terms</header><text>The terms <quote>high school</quote> and <quote>local educational agency</quote> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6D60FAE20D5492AA57FA948436F8325"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Peer-to-peer suicide prevention program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>peer-to-peer suicide prevention program</quote> means a program that—</text><subparagraph id="HD3D456D9AA3749CB81127A558187D61B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides students and adult advisors the knowledge and skills necessary to recognize and appropriately respond to the signs of suicide and depression;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F08E841FC9F4B298A41A20639ED6972"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes an in-person training component, when practicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBB00B83312E4C1C9A340B6881C248A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is student-led.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H913EF4D440294D83AE2B66EAF4E68202"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

