<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFCE429345FED4D328CCCEFFBA310F74B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9171 IH: To reimburse the State of Texas for Operation Lone Star, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9171</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221011">October 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To reimburse the State of Texas for Operation Lone Star, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H68132E427A0B4D21B28DDE4995EEA439" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H60B6C052AD9C483D8907641C4A7941D2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Reimbursement to the State of Texas for Operation Lone Star</header> 
<subsection id="H0B52E83B006742DC98DBAAD8C54B9C4D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available to the Department of Homeland Security for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall reimburse the State of Texas for the expenses incurred by Texas with carrying out Operation Lone Star that were incurred in fiscal years 2021 and 2022, in accordance with subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEF609A84D404C4BB832B9E2D8E27755"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be reimbursed under subsection (a), the Governor of Texas shall submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security a detailed list of expenses referred to in such subsection. Such list shall be submitted at such time, in such manner, and containing such other information as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC8A7A94EF494450DAFADDD9498806FB7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in coordination with the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, shall submit to Congress a report detailing the reasons why the Department of Homeland Security has not been able to secure the southern border.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

