<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H6BB92F0937D54B6B97BD8FF1D2BCA606" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7289 RH: Federal PFAS Research Evaluation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 313</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7289</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–406]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220330">March 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 30, 2022</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the National Academies to study and report on a Federal research agenda to advance the understanding of PFAS, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSY00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HAF1A40CA73C24AC88ED4F56065944491"><section id="H0F4DA3CF2EEB4DF8A79689967D936619" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal PFAS Research Evaluation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC08FB619C378470B9FAED5DF23707E80"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HFE8E482AB0834EABA2C1F0C4C0B910F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Perfluoroalkyl and polyfluoroalkyl substances (PFAS) are a group of man-made chemicals that have been used in a wide range of products since the 1940s including firefighting foam, carpeting, packaging, and cookware. There are more than 5,000 types of registered PFAS compounds. This chemical class is not currently regulated at the Federal level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31967D6236D1489E9A66B28936FDCD33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>PFAS have been detected in air, water, soil, food, biosolids, and more. They can accumulate and remain in the body for a long time, and potentially lead to serious health effects including cancer, low infant birthweight, liver and kidney issues, reproductive and developmental problems, and more.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04F2FF06EBE349CCAAFB5A2DB8663C31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>There remains much unknown about PFAS toxicity, human and environmental health effects, exposure pathways, as well as effective removal, treatment, and destruction methods, and safe alternatives to PFAS.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE372E4586643478CA0F6F005BAA346B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Federal research efforts have been fragmented at various agencies and struggled to effectively address the full scope of challenges presented by PFAS.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D16E6F604E94B48AA682C2AF0FF0CF3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Regulatory action and cleanup depend on scientific analysis of toxicity data, decision making on how best to deal with PFAS, and understanding the significance of the many exposure pathways that exist. A consensus study by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine would help inform decisions by Federal and State Governments, industry, and other stakeholders on how to best address PFAS.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H78D13F034C4548789138E2C8BD695260"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Academies reports</header><subsection id="H0FF9F6760AEE410596AD07A5022540F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research assessments of PFAS</header><paragraph id="HBE96246DD9BA4E00A9459AF90EA8F572"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in consultation with the Director of the National Science Foundation, the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the National Institutes of Health, and other Federal agencies with expertise relevant to understanding PFAS exposure, behavior, and toxicity, shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies to conduct a study and submit a report in accordance with this subsection to further address research and knowledge gaps identified by the Federal Government Human Health PFAS Research Workshop held on October 26 and 27, 2020, and identify research and development needed to identify, categorize, evaluate, and address individual or total PFAS.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BE670053AA447AF86F76133910D43A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Study and report on human exposure estimation</header><subparagraph id="HF5C13D73CE184F11A0C52EA2A512AFA8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The study required to be conducted under paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum—</text><clause id="HCB3DB9A440DD4E6F8C313B86564EBB89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consider life-cycle information on the manufacture, use, and disposal of PFAS-containing products to identify potential human exposure sources, including occupational exposures, and potential exposure pathways for the public;</text></clause><clause id="H090A544A93E24AEFA0D8780B6ADC9805"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluate the fate and transport of PFAS and their breakdown products;</text></clause><clause id="H704A5854EE374C678CBFAE266D79476B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if feasible, estimate human exposure to individual or total PFAS to determine relative source contributions for various exposure pathways (such as air, water, soil, or food);</text></clause><clause id="H944EB1E28056498CA071120AD552B608"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>determine the range of solubility, stability, and volatility of PFAS most likely to be found in the environment and the resulting prevalence in animals and humans;</text></clause><clause id="HA5FE110A858A431AB1CCB42426C1F402"><enum>(v)</enum><text>give consideration as to whether chemical category-based approaches would be appropriate for evaluating PFAS toxicity and exposure;</text></clause><clause id="H7844BCA653D3494695ACFC0D67FA45B7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>identify research needed to advance exposure estimation to individual or total PFAS; and</text></clause><clause id="H604B2D76F55544D081A247F00C6C88E8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>identify research needed to advance toxicity and hazard assessment of individual or total PFAS.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03DB6401C70344A3A506A79100AC2EE9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date on which the agreement described in paragraph (1) is finalized, the National Academies shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings and recommendations of the study described in subparagraph (A) and shall make such report available on a publicly accessible website.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6F2D310FA274CB6BD43EB7A64936988"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research assessment of management and treatment alternatives for PFAS contamination in the environment</header><paragraph id="HDC7DDC46F9684194AC9A709B2229E367"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Director of the National Science Foundation, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and other Federal agencies with expertise relevant to the development of PFAS alternatives and the management and treatment of PFAS, shall jointly enter into an agreement with the National Academies to conduct a study and submit a report in accordance with this subsection to better understand the research and development needed to advance the understanding of the extent and implications of human and environmental contamination by PFAS, how to manage and treat such contamination, and the development of safe alternatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79F131CF96A14795A259670A39DD8005"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of study</header><text>The study described in paragraph (1) shall, at a minimum, include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HECA26C2CF1394097A4E102F6C1AFBA24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the best available strategies for PFAS treatment, site remediation, and safe disposal, including demonstration or pilot projects related to destruction methods and alternative materials or tools for firefighters.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63899800B3B24843836685AA93254EEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the research gaps relating to such issues, including consideration of emerging or future PFAS and potential classification methods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H125FA6AC0326410A9A394174C3355953"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Recommendations on how the Federal Government can best address the research needs identified pursuant to subparagraph (B) through increased collaboration or coordination of existing and new programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD658FDE9A6D04CB4A57CC72795E00872"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Recommendations on how research can best incorporate considerations of socioeconomic issues into the development of research proposals and the conduct of research.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98841B421F2B4E81AA4D3D7F5557DC0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date on which the agreement described in paragraph (1) is finalized, the National Academies shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings and recommendations of the study described in paragraph (2) and shall make such report available on a publicly accessible website.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H030D921FA77C403F94D6EE876A1FE643"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000 to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H58FD7AC9706547FC945E7FD104CEF501"><enum>4.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after submission to Congress of latest of the National Academies reports under section 3, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in coordination with all relevant Federal agencies, shall submit to Congress an implementation plan for increased collaboration and coordination of Federal PFAS research, development, and demonstration activities. In preparing such an implementation plan, the Director shall take into consideration the recommendations included in the reports in section 3.</text></section><section id="HF3F2A016DFDB43D0B43E0BB8A2651FEE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4FC58C2CD0D6420DACBE7033D5ACE3CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National Academies</header><text>The term <term>National Academies</term> means the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6658529DCEA24F0CBDE4EC43ECF5EDE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>PFAS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>PFAS</term> means per- and polyfluoroalkyl substances, including mixtures of such substances.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220713">July 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

