<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89F3809FC513441B996401270A94F70D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7849 IH: Conserving Lobstering And Whales Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7849</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against tax for the purchase of certain adaptive gear required to prevent the entanglement of right whales.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA9C07732CD4A4009BC569BBBC420B1CA" style="OLC"><section id="H391D50E15CFD422D9580BB134DDAA8E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Conserving Lobstering And Whales Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLAW Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H85B246CB1EF842DB9A7F93B811DD4681"><enum>2.</enum><header>Adaptive gear required to prevent right whale entanglement</header><subsection id="H4959D22755F044C3AB801B3CC9D1869C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><paragraph id="H2D6569C177EC455E93CDC2107DC20111"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H25B8E49966EA474282B55B16552D6729" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H8A08830F62274F35800F0461F75F51AB"><enum>45U.</enum><header>Adaptive gear required to prevent right whale entanglement</header><subsection id="HE05C7EF5FB2C4347BCB710B6F3E9FAC2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 38, in the case of an eligible lobstering business, the right whale entanglement prevention credit determined under this section for any taxable year is an amount equal to 30 percent of the amounts paid or incurred by the taxpayer for the taxable year for the purchase of any adaptive gear required by State or Federal law or regulation to prevent the entanglement of right whales in the course of the trade or business of lobstering.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFF3E6301A7CF415A858F5F6457CE7F41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible lobstering business</header><paragraph id="HD080CA72398A49A195DBDA9035A3EE8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>eligible lobstering business</quote> means any person—</text><subparagraph id="HB59B31BE2C804F0B9E7C7DE599084E33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>engaged in the trade or business of lobstering, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AC8FDF941A648E89E3CCD1A565B9EA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that submits a return of tax with respect to such taxable year that includes each of the following, as applicable, but in any case not less than 1 of—</text><clause id="HBD2F6956687C49C5AE7644178D015B33"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State commercial lobster license for such person, and</text></clause><clause id="H58F148861FB642949DB862A775CE0E76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a Federal vessel identification number for each vessel used by such person in the course of the trade or business of lobstering.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BA665C015E34285BAA0E807E124F49A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Controlled groups</header><text>All persons which are treated as a single employer under subsections (a) and (b) of section 52 shall be treated as a single taxpayer for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5062793CA15B438A92A52FA1A27E78FD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adaptive gear</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>adaptive gear</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HEE77CE00D9FC4D38902DF4F2B8C9CF13"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">gear required by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as part of the Atlantic Large Whale Take Reduction Plan, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6C77499EE442049AA656F2CFECDCD6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>equipment used for electronic vessel tracking required by the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission for North Atlantic right whale risk reduction.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6609E314B064A9A81920E871CCA61D1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credit made part of general business credit</header><text>Section 38(b) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (32), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (33) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9B110FE146EB4C00BAB0530824FB01A8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H9386F84F26B44514A525A5E053355ADF"><enum>(34)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of an eligible lobstering business, the right whale entanglement prevention credit determined under 45U(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H915C47AFFFED48589DEC75E28D4221DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H80A1DB7201FD46D78D0C9BA36C69036F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 45U. Adaptive gear required to prevent right whale entanglement.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49BAEC42FB75452E888CB2A51F12259B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Direct pay option</header><paragraph id="H9CAD5F16E861485793F4537BF326ECB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/65">chapter 65</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H7FC1C3D67BDE410BA7E89C1601243536" style="OLC"><section id="HBBB9E6C49D9E4B7CA686051E565E1B32"><enum>6431.</enum><header>Elective payment of right whale entanglement prevention credit</header><subsection id="H1D5DE7DC0F4E4F238FF74AB6113CAEFC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a taxpayer making an election (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may provide) under this section with respect to any portion of the right whale entanglement prevention credit determined under section 45U(a), such taxpayer shall be treated as making a payment against the tax imposed by subtitle A for the taxable year equal to such amount.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE5E1E8FD1794B6481B1DA81F12EA845"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text>The payment described in subsection (a) shall be treated as made on the later of the due date of the return of tax (determined without extensions) for such taxable year or the date on which such return is filed.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1C61CAB2E85429C869D0865BF5B0927"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exclusion from gross income</header><text>Gross income of the taxpayer shall be determined without regard to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0FC1B184FA6B43B582E0E5F841DABB3B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Denial of double benefit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Solely for purposes of section 38, in the case of a taxpayer making an election under this section, the right whale entanglement prevention credit determined under section 45U(a) shall be reduced by the amount of the portion of such credit with respect to which the taxpayer makes such election.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA430C3BFCFC841E699AF23657A43F769"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of chapter 65 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H20B6B3DDBF6E4CFD8ACD3F0204FA1567" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6431. Elective payment of right whale entanglement prevention credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA6070407DA04D11881ED78D0DFE7D59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

