<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H5C5563E9D9B64E0EB6A50B35C7C3DFBC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3128 RH: American Fisheries Advisory Committee Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 458</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3128</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–635]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210511">May 11, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000600">Mrs. Radewagen</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the American Fisheries Advisory Committee to assist in the awarding of fisheries research and development grants, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H904865766C9942948C35192C274D8918" style="OLC"><section id="HDD44024BF0304FE9952C50E2AAABA84F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Fisheries Advisory Committee Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H64378E9CE5AA4DD7B4C35924DE5E3640"><enum>2.</enum><header>American Fisheries Advisory Committee</header><subsection id="HB5AB9AD08E3B45E5B08A38EAC452BA04"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Section 2 of the Act of August 11, 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/713c-3">15 U.S.C. 713c–3</external-xref>), is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5928A58AD0FA41A5B124BB3C2BC4CE40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD57D074995ED49DFBDA3398D840FEDCE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H89477AE6C91F42DBA99648FF1E03999E" style="OLC"><subsection id="H0D65CA7B46B14B0199D29673A411DFB7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>American Fisheries Advisory Committee</header><paragraph id="H1D8BD993C6534397934B835D33FC0B2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HD856D9FD7894485B8A08AA8B6F5C194B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee</header><text>The term <term>Committee</term> means the American Fisheries Advisory Committee established under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0053BBC130CB4F7C9FFBA8C1DB6FA012"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fishing community</header><text>The term <term>fishing community</term> means harvesters, marketers, growers, processors, recreational fishermen, charter fishermen, and persons providing them with goods and services.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAC30EE797F74851BFFDC7D65C45CF72"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Marketing and promotion</header><text>The term <term>marketing and promotion</term> means an activity aimed at encouraging the consumption of seafood or expanding or maintaining commercial markets for seafood.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H532CBECB96C24121B64A4D879ABFA4A1"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Processor</header><text>The term <term>processor</term> means any person in the business of preparing or packaging seafood (including seafood of the processor’s own harvesting) for sale.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33FCF8AB3B9045E7B55EABC6BF35FCFE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Seafood</header><text>The term <term>seafood</term> means farm-raised and wild-caught fish, shellfish, or marine algae harvested in the United States or by a United States flagged vessel for human consumption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED441584ECB645099F847B324FEEFC7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>American Fisheries Advisory Committee Act of 2021</short-title>, the Secretary shall establish 6 regions within the American Fisheries Advisory Committee as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HEBF60A64041F4F97A5423BF8D0348F3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Region 1 shall consist of Alaska, Hawaii, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the Territories of Guam and American Samoa.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H11622AE25EE24DBC8FBC3C483C172183"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Region 2 shall consist of Maine, New Hampshire, Massachusetts, Rhode Island, and Connecticut.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBA4F04430874772B882F32C504FEF30"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Region 3 shall consist of Texas, Alabama, Louisiana, Mississippi, Florida, Arkansas, Puerto Rico, and the Territory of the Virgin Islands of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5F77697DD6246289E9C18796E81E62F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Region 4 shall consist of California, Washington, Oregon, and Idaho.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58AF62C0C93F44A49570F2A2C35F9F17"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Region 5 shall consist of New Jersey, New York, Delaware, Maryland, Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, and Georgia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H228C2C4D734C47879059F8A1F2805A19"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Region 6 shall consist of Michigan, Minnesota, Wisconsin, Illinois, Indiana, Ohio, and Pennsylvania.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF2F593AD101445592887EA4B02E11F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Committee shall be composed of the following members:</text><subparagraph id="H27B7B6CB086A482091F48B2CE82AB06C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Regional representation</header><text>Each of the regions listed in subparagraphs (A) through (F) of paragraph (2) shall be represented on the Committee by 3 members—</text><clause id="H03E178991ED94C8CA9ED5F6F48BA44D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who are appointed by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="H7F64B97FD30A41B6A4E9948A00D03920"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who reside in a State or territory in the region that the member will represent;</text></clause><clause id="H977A756B17514536A2547D27C450316E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>of which—</text><subclause id="HD1A24075DABB4DBBA12C13F782D04872"><enum>(I)</enum><text>one shall have experience as a seafood harvester or processor;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6BA5A96573D342559CC57ADBFDC5A837"><enum>(II)</enum><text>one shall have experience as recreational or commercial fisher or have experience growing seafood; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HDBF98AB9CFBD4E55BB1B5F16661ECAB6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>one shall be an individual who represents the fisheries science community or the relevant Regional Fishery Management Council; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE76355DE370C47E68C1EC7D7412F6B5D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>that are selected so that the members of the Committee have experience or expertise with as many seafood species as practicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D3A982832F848569468E4DACFA29AAC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>At-large members</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint to the Committee at-large members as follows:</text><clause id="HBB66B4CF3CC74DE2917806193E4321CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>One individual with experience in food distribution, marketing, retail, or food service.</text></clause><clause id="H0E25394BF1B04D9FB83C8ED5F8A395B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>One individual with experience in the recreational fishing industry supply chain, such as fishermen, manufacturers, retailers, and distributors.</text></clause><clause id="H8A77CD8429FE4591B65AD91B24E5AD10"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>One individual with experience in the commercial fishing industry supply chain, such as fishermen, manufacturers, retailers, and distributors.</text></clause><clause id="HCC6E67D10EB44D06B8A8CAA506327DA2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>One individual who is an employee of the National Marine Fisheries Service with expertise in fisheries research.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC97D9C658C76446287AA2F390AB303E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Balanced representation</header><text>In selecting the members described in subparagraphs (A) and (B), the Secretary shall seek to maximize on the Committee, to the extent practicable, a balanced representation of expertise in United States fisheries, seafood production, and science.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F376A2EC3154CFA9D79E549F10D6835"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Member terms</header><text>The term for a member of the Committee shall be 3 years, except that the Secretary shall designate staggered terms for the members initially appointed to the Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4489652C1804F42A3212E32E54D6403"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Committee shall be responsible for—</text><subparagraph id="H6D28BCD39AED41D2801B089EA1CD3618"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifying needs of the fishing community that may be addressed by a project funded with a grant under subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13761501D2734B1D9B22B742941A5250"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing the request for proposals for such grants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H839785A40E35472486FD3FF097AE46CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reviewing applications for such grants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62F804422FF54115ACFD8435BC0EF7A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>selecting applications for approval under subsection (c)(2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78F5DB7234454A47B5B94D52967CF61A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Committee shall elect a chair by a majority of those voting, if a quorum is present.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA76A7C60294A4D95001D5826CD6214"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A simple majority of members of the Committee shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number may hold hearings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71C2E6F1A60940F28A41577C58C9E111"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="H9C0F559877D442F498575B921F893688"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Committee shall meet not more than 2 times each year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H939BCF3BA7744440B1A1334C94AB5016"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Location</header><text>The meetings of the Committee shall rotate between the geographic regions described under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C55061519A5471FA6C6DDE732640DB2"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Minimizing costs</header><text>The Committee shall seek to minimize the operational costs associated with meetings, hearings, or other business of the Committee, including through the use of video or teleconference.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC467BA92DD654ABC9C2FDEB5F1498E48"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Designation of staff member</header><text>The Secretary shall designate a staff member to coordinate the activities of the Committee and to assist with administrative and other functions as requested by the Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8032E9C83B847BA99CDD6C4F2697D9D"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Per diem and expenses and funding</header><subparagraph id="H0357040B1E284D6BB59051132BF2C8E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Committee shall serve without compensation, but shall be reimbursed in accordance with section 5703 of title 5, United States Code, for reasonable travel costs and expenses incurred in performing duties as a member of the Committee.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC73DEC414064422E925A8BD826173A6F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The costs of reimbursements under subparagraph (A) and the other costs associated with the Committee shall be paid from funds made available to carry out this section (which may include funds described in subsection (f)(1)(B)), except that no funds allocated for grants under subsection (f)(1)(A) shall be expended for any purpose under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H204321CE3BB942C1926CC50AF0341A33"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Conflict of interest</header><text>The conflict of interest and recusal provisions set out in section 302(j) of the Magnuson-Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852(j)</external-xref>) shall apply to any decision by the Committee and to all members of the Committee as if each member of the Committee is an affected individual within the meaning of such section 302(j), except that in addition to the disclosure requirements of section 302(j)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1852">16 U.S.C. 1852(j)(2)(C)</external-xref>), each member of the Committee shall disclose any financial interest or relationship in an organization or with an individual that is applying for a grant under subsection (c) held by the member of the Committee, including an interest as an officer, director, trustee, partner, employee, contractor, agent, or other representative.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC41B2265D60F45EF985397FFA2211255"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Technical review of applications</header><subparagraph id="H5CECC2B6D01F49E79832939200F3DFDA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Prior to review of an application for a grant under subsection (c) by the Committee, the Secretary shall obtain an independent written technical evaluation from 3 or more appropriate Federal, private, or public sector experts (such as industry, academia, or governmental experts) who—</text><clause id="H2999038723394EDF8B13DA3EA382DFBE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>have subject matter expertise to determine the technical merit of the proposal in the application;</text></clause><clause id="H966496B977204A55B15EBC943B666C96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall independently evaluate each such proposal; and</text></clause><clause id="H1D2A9797FC274F5E9C628238E0BC9DD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall certify that the expert does not have a conflict of interest concerning the application that the expert is reviewing.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57A1BB252B974333B93CEEFBC7153520"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>American Fisheries Advisory Committee Act of 2021</short-title>, the Secretary shall issue guidance related to carrying out the technical evaluations under subparagraph (A). Such guidance shall include criteria for the elimination by the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration of applications that fail to meet a minimum level of technical merit as determined by the review described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1B6E291365A4BE1AAD14BB1022C61BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Role in approval of grants</header><text>Section 2(c)(3) of the Act of August 11, 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/713c-3">15 U.S.C. 713c–3(c)(3)</external-xref>), is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF1F8D61F06F248A19D1346F6176084C7" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HC7DBD04EA8C446E493955957A2F1C8C0" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE1E855E9D91A488385D737673988DF00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>No application for a grant under this subsection may be approved unless the Secretary—</text><clause id="HB8DFF7701476470B8C85AD9593EE70A6" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is satisfied that the applicant has the requisite technical and financial capability to carry out the project; and</text></clause><clause id="H3BB3A8FF8FEA4A76989B307812A68FF5" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on the recommendations of the American Fisheries Advisory Committee established in subsection (e), evaluates the proposed project as to—</text><subclause id="H07E4C756CEA541D397BBDDC7B76DAE14"><enum>(I)</enum><text>soundness of design;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5C869E28C4DC44509F9E5DCA0A489122"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the possibilities of securing productive results;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4C70FD80F72E41BEB0A736B3E59305E7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>minimization of duplication with other fisheries research and development projects;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF1BE1A6EFCA74D3FB6F8B2E117B8EFF9"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the organization and management of the project;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7DA7C184226C46468570181D2D5BD421"><enum>(V)</enum><text>methods proposed for monitoring and evaluating the success or failure of the project; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA70F24BCA4504E84AC29F5B5E79D89B2"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>such other criteria as the Secretary may require.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA61B53566A14A388E14220B5136AF26" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the Secretary fails to provide funds to a grant selected by the American Fisheries Advisory Committee, the Secretary shall provide a written document to the Committee justifying the decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HF8B6AA74DD84497E9854B23AACACB4DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Expansion of specified purposes of fisheries research and development projects grants program to include fisheries research and development projects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(c)(1) of the Act of August 11, 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/713c-3">15 U.S.C. 713c–3(c)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>fisheries science, recreational fishing,</quote> before <quote>harvesting,</quote>.</text></section><section id="H1E94D8D8E64A4B95A5CEBF785B0562C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Public availability of grants proposals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2(c) of the Act of August 11, 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/713c-3">15 U.S.C. 713c–3(c)</external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H039C360899A94320AAC47DABC91F67FE" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HD430738A60374967B9505096D6E543EF" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any person awarded a grant under this subsection shall make publicly available a title and abstract of the project to be carried out by the grant funds that serves as the public justification for funding the project that includes a statement describing how the project serves to enhance United States fisheries, including harvesting, processing, marketing, and associated infrastructures, if applicable.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

