<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H704562FB5CF149FFA14DF80BDCBA4121" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 884 EH: National Aviation Preparedness Plan Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>117th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 884</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a national aviation preparedness plan for communicable disease outbreaks, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5DE17C7793314826A7C80E4033B95C74" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3BA686A99DD54961A6C111CF939DF977" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Aviation Preparedness Plan Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HA2802D7A5EC44E7A8CD559EF065A489D"><enum>2.</enum><header>National aviation preparedness plan</header> <subsection id="H784E053EC7EB4A8FA1F05E6360845070"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, in coordination with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of Transportation considers appropriate, shall develop a national aviation preparedness plan for communicable disease outbreaks.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA101A9627A2944BD935D382ABD9C4D36"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan developed under subsection (a) shall, at a minimum—</text> <paragraph id="H7C2C8620DAFD4FCA95F0C9AEF238AF6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide airports and air carriers with an adaptable and scalable framework with which to align the individual plans, including the emergency response plans, of such airports and air carriers and provide guidance as to each individual plan;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H809B5285650D49C6AC00BC81A5DAAE52"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve coordination among airports, air carriers, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, other appropriate Federal entities, and State and local governments and health agencies with respect to preparing for and responding to communicable disease outbreaks;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H82D47D85F4DB4142A03A423757DE60DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent practicable, improve coordination among relevant international entities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75DA9F682C5D4E5B951A180D2272F36B" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a process to identify appropriate personal protective equipment, if any, for covered employees to reduce the likelihood of exposure to a covered communicable disease, and thereafter issue recommendations for the equipage of such employees;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEAB5E98AD5AE408B8BF73ABE21E2A63F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a process to identify appropriate techniques, strategies, and protective infrastructure, if any, for the cleaning, disinfecting, and sanitization of aircraft and enclosed facilities owned, operated, or used by an air carrier or airport, and thereafter issue recommendations pertaining to such techniques, strategies, and protective infrastructure;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91FF99F257D949628CFFB64DB8FB4E2A"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and assign Federal agency roles in the deployment of emerging and existing technologies and solutions to reduce covered communicable diseases in the aviation ecosystem;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H05203A3B82DE4D6ABC3EE39CB2344EE7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">clearly delineate the responsibilities of the sponsors and operators of airports, air carriers, and Federal agencies in responding to a covered communicable disease;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H92A5F01828B44DC2A60AB5CFAE1CD1C9" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate, as appropriate, the recommendations made by the Comptroller General of the United States to the Secretary of Transportation contained in the report titled <quote>Air Travel and Communicable Diseases: Comprehensive Federal Plan Needed for U.S. Aviation System's Preparedness</quote>, issued in December 2015 (GAO-16-127);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H94E6BD0D8ED044CF90E1F60754FD99D8"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the latest peer-reviewed scientific studies that address communicable disease with respect to air transportation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3CB4C547C3D643EFA63BA5062B1CA58A"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider funding constraints.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H076FA55E3EEE4D439F046008C6CC396C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When developing the plan under subsection (a), the Secretary of Transportation shall consult with aviation industry and labor stakeholders, including representatives of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF469D001142445C3ADB9C1398D1099C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">air carriers, which shall include domestic air carriers consisting of major air carriers, low-cost carriers, regional air carriers and cargo carriers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB6F4CBCB5DE4746B1A6FE7843113690"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">airport operators, including with respect to large hub, medium hub, small hub, and nonhub commercial service airports;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H89748B72E5F044B7907A2E70B6D550FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">labor organizations that represent airline pilots, flight attendants, air carrier airport customer service representatives, and air carrier maintenance, repair, and overhaul workers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF391424BDBBD44C1B7C331E4C041D48F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the labor organization certified under section 7111 of title 5, United States Code, as the exclusive bargaining representative of air traffic controllers of the Federal Aviation Administration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEAF19F2FA14B4AD7B07ED9CF1C2CF724"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the labor organization certified under such section as the exclusive bargaining representative of airway transportation systems specialists and aviation safety inspectors of the Federal Aviation Administration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA701B75565F044268D4389CFD9CD6DAA"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trade associations representing air carriers and airports;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H212ACA0AE9AC4A4DA577C41479FFCEEF"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">aircraft manufacturing companies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE2DBE25265C4DB7AD8306E107D1452D"><enum>(8)</enum><text>general aviation; and </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4002E22947846E9AF60DC977F47DC12"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other stakeholders as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3367C557B77409F9A14CC4785B922E8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the plan is developed under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that includes such plan.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A93383256704FA2B71EDDB241CF1BBB" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Review of plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which a report is submitted under subsection (d), and again not later than 5 years thereafter, the Secretary shall review the plan included in such report and, after consultation with aviation industry and labor stakeholders, make changes by rule as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HBC2914BA3C5C4FB4B5BD16D2B1A83B64"><enum>(f)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall conduct and submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a study assessing the national aviation preparedness plan developed under subsection (a), including—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC9AF9EFB53404FCAA9E6E70EFEBBE79F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether such plan—</text> <subparagraph id="H07FF5501954A492AAFBCF7DFE4AA9614"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is responsive to any previous recommendations relating to aviation preparedness with respect to an outbreak of a covered communicable disease or global health emergency made by the Comptroller General; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67E167BD238D4B0DB32FAFD9F9EB1C53"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets the obligations of the United States under international conventions and treaties; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00ADCB2663DA4CB39127A26976E37D83"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the United States aviation system is prepared to respond to an outbreak of a covered communicable disease.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8DFBC19292C4277B381A2D7B6065DD6"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H83209D3D7074466780377C6B0330E879"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered employee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered employee</quote> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA66A41836989490599EE7B2E569DC233"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an individual whose job duties require interaction with air carrier passengers on a regular and continuing basis and who is an employee of—</text> <clause id="HC04FDA46E888434BB1A09227EA58D5EF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an air carrier;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE6057AB8BF2408AB47CF449F88E7ABB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an air carrier contractor;</text></clause> <clause id="HDC5B1DA325214FD4A383431A54237AFE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an airport; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8890EAB5A4D74F4B941F9B5AF811E006"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Federal Government; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C5D71CA504F43B0801CF7268FD27760"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an air traffic controller or systems safety specialist of the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H506E547D8DDB42869C26E1C2E3ABF0B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered communicable disease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered communicable disease</quote> means a communicable disease that has the potential to cause a future epidemic or pandemic of infectious disease that would constitute a public health emergency of international concern as declared, after the date of enactment of this Act, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220913" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 14, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

