<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D36FC1B185F4CA397D283D4CC7CC5E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7613 IH: 21st Century Foundation for the Right to Express and Engage in Speech Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7613</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000596">Mrs. Greene of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 and ensure reasonable, non-discriminatory access to online communications platforms.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H451ECED8A872418FAF6A8586C1D4FDCB" style="OLC"><section id="HC68BD4E5EF8945D9A07398F490B7D336" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>21st Century Foundation for the Right to Express and Engage in Speech Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>21st Century FREE Speech Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4BAEE002E1C24D768D2143B5E0867948"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reasonable, non-discriminatory access to online communications platforms; blocking and screening of offensive material</header><subsection id="H124FD79B8F7B4058801A701D8B9ACE39"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part I of title II of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/201">47 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCA492C90303844CCA959B37E277C8EDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking section 230; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3A7D03589174646818AC6887A8A4C3C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H75D56A07AE584F659E5C3BCA3F6B5A49"><section id="HD9F3852B9C1648DA93D9CF92B27B58DC"><enum>232.</enum><header>Reasonable, non-discriminatory access to online communications platforms; blocking and screening of offensive material</header><subsection id="H8D5BE3F5B82843949ACD2201CD2C6D1A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD8C2B27C14FC4D22B032F0CFB8566871"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The rapidly developing array of internet and other interactive computer services available to individual Americans represent an extraordinary advance in the availability of educational and informational resources to our citizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A2EFED777C846F5B260C2D32B203CC5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These services often offer users a great degree of control over the information that they receive, as well as the potential for even greater control in the future as technology continues to develop.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2434A7235D5646129A5118A438460F43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The internet and other interactive computer services offer a forum for a true diversity of political discourse and viewpoints, unique opportunities for cultural development, and myriad avenues for intellectual activity, and regulation of the internet must be tailored to supporting those activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A066BE7A9BD44DF9E0713C411E104F9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The internet and other interactive computer services have flourished, to the benefit of all Americans, with a minimum of government regulation, and regulation should be limited to what is necessary to preserve the societal benefits provided by the internet.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9BCB9E86DAA4C319191C120935247B3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Increasingly Americans rely on internet platforms and websites for a variety of political, educational, cultural, and entertainment services and for communication with one another.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H088DD2BDB1CC48B891D8799BCBDBF3DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H10704F58A57F44C2BED5ADA8406DAB43"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to promote the continued development of the internet and other interactive computer services and other interactive media;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB0E1867BC854A568137AEBA8B3B855E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to preserve a vibrant and competitive free market for the internet and other interactive computer services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11B9827C24384AD4B183DE45B278258B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to encourage the development of technologies which maximize user control over what information is received by individuals, families, and schools who use the internet and other interactive computer services, rather than control and censorship driven by interactive computer services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47AEF2488F7C4C7BB1C17221E1A290F6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to facilitate the development and utilization of blocking and filtering technologies that empower parents to restrict their children's access to objectionable or inappropriate online material;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B54A1AE52504DF5B219741DCA380E6F"><enum>(5)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HA90799D1F9EF41EBB7FA9B96774A7968"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to ensure that the internet serves as an open forum for—</text><clause id="HBC9A13DF040A4F79B3581D44D4CD6BCD" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a true diversity of discourse and viewpoints, including political discourse and viewpoints;</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="H27890863ED6742E29DCB2127ED7421D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>unique opportunities for cultural development; and</text></clause><clause indent="up1" id="H1CACC0D123964192854AB84351DFA3A2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>myriad avenues for intellectual activity; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA5A0FD2BB954B1F99DD5FB03A8B2F6D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>given that the internet is the dominant platform for communication and public debate today, to ensure that major internet communications platforms, which function as common carriers in terms of their size, usage, and necessity, are available to all users on reasonable and non-discriminatory terms free from public or private censorship of religious and political speech;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE59C41FE959E4DA4B868AA721D7F97EA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to promote consumer protection and transparency regarding information and content management practices by major internet platforms to—</text><subparagraph id="H9F0A452EF7D5412ABCFE009D80E55BF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that consumers understand—</text><clause id="H8B991C487CBD494DA6081C152F0E08C0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the products they are using; and</text></clause><clause id="HF6B3539603EC482FB68C2739A50EDAE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>what information is being presented to them and why; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC538AFCE27B8424399C4C5A1D20FD4D4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent deceptive or undetectable actions that filter the information presented to consumers; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDEFB70A9A8849839459FD1CB8F0C00F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to ensure vigorous enforcement of Federal criminal laws to deter and punish trafficking in online obscenity, stalking, and harassment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF9701CB940E344C0916F193C6E9E5FE2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reasonable and nondiscriminatory access to common carrier technology companies</header><paragraph id="H361BDD9D280D4E14BF4EA1AA975D6D11"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A common carrier technology company, with respect to the interactive computer service provided by the company—</text><subparagraph id="H822D440A008A4F14BB657F97B79DD675"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall furnish the interactive computer service to all persons upon reasonable request;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90B6CA51616E456DAD93C2A911502773"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not unjustly or unreasonably discriminate in charges, practices, classifications, regulations, facilities, treatment, or services for or in connection with the furnishing of the interactive computer service, directly or indirectly, by any means or device;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE80DB4F933744D98E80E56FA34159E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may not make or give any undue or unreasonable preference or advantage to any particular person, class of persons, political or religious group or affiliation, or locality; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D58FBBF3BE044B18029597C5E92841E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may not subject any particular person, class of persons, political or religious group or affiliation, or locality to any undue or unreasonable prejudice or disadvantage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFF1D0D651AF4F6D88777DA9B627E795"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability to broadband</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the provision of broadband internet access service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H48028313CE354CC2B5F5006AD502C428"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consumer protection and transparency regarding common carrier technology companies</header><paragraph id="HC46E2B22035E4917AB608B42432C26D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A common carrier technology company shall disclose, through a publicly available, easily accessible website, accurate material regarding the content management, moderation, promotion, account termination and suspension, and curation mechanisms and practices of the company sufficient to enable—</text><subparagraph id="HFF667608ABC64C5C89AA152E1E0DB31E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consumers to make informed choices regarding use of the interactive computer service provided by the company; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80BB5650408D440E9A6934A54AA1501E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>persons to develop, market, and maintain consumer-driven content management mechanisms with respect to the interactive computer service provided by the company.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H624B9D6DEFF04F1A934FC9620989DD84"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Commission, after soliciting comments from the public, shall publish best practices for common carrier technology companies to disclose content management, moderation, promotion, account termination and suspension, and curation mechanisms and practices in accordance with paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF47A4DD41C7466EAA8F0D7550983248"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicability to broadband</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to the provision of broadband internet access service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59C5D79716404C0C88A6F3318988C074"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protection for <quote>Good Samaritan</quote> blocking and screening of offensive material</header><paragraph id="HDD0E4536C1C84C1AB00AA3C0769FD02D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Treatment of publisher or speaker</header><subparagraph id="H97707EBE949B4051819304EA5D50E7F0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No provider or user of an interactive computer service shall be treated as the publisher or speaker of any material provided by another information content provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2EF277C257884EB683BBC45EEF4568B8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to any affirmative act by a provider or user of an interactive computer service with respect to material posted on the interactive computer service, whether the act is carried out manually or through use of an algorithm or other automated or semi-automated process, including—</text><clause id="HD882877422F248EC968101F9A3BED77A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing its own material;</text></clause><clause id="HE2C1B6A0C58F4A85924615127C942221"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>commenting or editorializing on, promoting, recommending, or increasing or decreasing the dissemination or visibility to users of its own material or material provided by another information content provider;</text></clause><clause id="H1611AB7A988E4D438F17759BDC1F1D09"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>restricting access to or availability of material provided by another information content provider; or</text></clause><clause id="H2ADCD838A3424328B91DD8F8042C3F61"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>barring or limiting any information content provider from using the interactive computer service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H854D25197E2A47F6B3A2FAB5DF644AEE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil liability</header><subparagraph id="HEB104DCAF2814557BCEBC9EE20BEFF24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No provider or user of an interactive computer service shall be held liable, under subsection (c) or otherwise, on account of—</text><clause id="HA5A5DD59DEAB40A6B9FCFA5E302901C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any action voluntarily taken in good faith to restrict access to or availability of material that the provider or user considers to be obscene, lewd, lascivious, filthy, excessively violent, harassing, promoting self-harm, or unlawful, whether or not such material is constitutionally protected; or</text></clause><clause id="H75A491EBBFDF4334ABC04ED1AAD60B1F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any action taken to enable or make available to information content providers or others the technical means to restrict access to material described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F170F6E577E41A088EA1A3B5467848F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H3266387F91614EE5A21C16D2C1FEE1B0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>excessively violent</term>, with respect to material, means material that—</text><subclause id="H126241B9887245F7B68A8CF6856A8986"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is likely to be deemed violent and for mature audiences according to the V-chip regulations and TV Parental Guidelines of the Commission promulgated under sections 303(x) and 330(c)(4); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H6C415C8EFE55432D9EE2CD9506A67823"><enum>(II)</enum><text>constitutes or intends to advocate domestic terrorism or international terrorism, as defined in section 2331 of title 18, United States Code;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB15B6F6A10B843659AF1553717C05DB1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the term <term>harassing</term> means material that—</text><subclause id="H7F6D141095E84D4682ABB9AA32E1495D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is—</text><item id="HFC594D95C9A1406D931340D939D84816"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>provided by an information content provider with the intent to abuse, threaten, or harass any specific person; and</text></item><item id="H3C54C09E4D584B7C8372CA59E1AC64EF"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>lacking in any serious literary, artistic, political, or scientific value;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HBB6E763279EC40E59B1E60690103C06F" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>violates the CAN–SPAM Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/7701">15 U.S.C. 7701 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subclause><subclause id="H75DF4E3C70604980A541493A4E491640"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is malicious computer code intended (whether or not by the immediate disseminator) to damage or interfere with the operation of a computer;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1A40C5A316784BE6927179659549ED08"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the term <term>in good faith</term>, with respect to restricting access to or availability of specific material, means the provider or user—</text><subclause id="H371977D64FE84A4BA976EFE6DC58A177"><enum>(I)</enum><text>restricts access to or availability of material consistent with publicly available online terms of service or use that—</text><item id="H1D226C235FD14EC9ACC40BE62772A69D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>state plainly and with particularity the criteria that the provider or user of the interactive computer service employs in its content moderation practices, including by any partially or fully automated processes; and </text></item><item id="H48BC31A039EE4DA29499911680B81D63"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>are in effect on the date on which the material is first posted;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HD750B846068544319E6380159065555C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has an objectively reasonable belief that the material falls within one of the categories listed in subparagraph (A)(i);</text></subclause><subclause id="HAC02ABFED4704627B3157BF6CB5D11F8"><enum>(III)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF3A31470901945BBB7C4A1FA2CF401A1"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>does not restrict access to or availability of material on deceptive or pretextual grounds; and</text></item><item indent="up1" id="H5C8AAB826AFC4D60A76E5A35ED954BFA"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>does not apply its terms of service or use to restrict access to or availability of material that is similarly situated to material that the provider or user of the interactive computer service intentionally declines to restrict; and </text></item></subclause><subclause id="HBCEEB355852B4AEBB9B3ED34CA7AC32B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>supplies the information content provider of the material with timely notice describing with particularity the reasonable factual basis for the restriction of access and a meaningful opportunity to respond, unless the provider or user of the interactive computer service has an objectively reasonable belief that—</text><item id="H0A1BAA7266244B998739C9DF98C3BF3F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the material is related to terrorism or criminal activity; or</text></item><item id="H3046D69DC9534E358EA4A47B810469DE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>such notice would risk imminent physical harm to others; and</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H03B2AEA22B6743A3B2BE118BD624F114"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the terms <term>obscene</term>, <term>lewd</term>, <term>lascivious</term>, and <term>filthy</term>, with respect to material, mean material that—</text><subclause id="H374201FC3B0D4EF59217EB9532F1E648"><enum>(I)</enum><text>taken as a whole—</text><item id="H15EC8B465FFC44EC9754778AAA3858E3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>appeals to the prurient interest in sex or portrays sexual conduct in a patently offensive way; and</text></item><item id="HE36B0A7689B547178C324B4F53956E07"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>does not have serious literary, artistic, political, or scientific value;</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HADAA44F95E944F47B4A9005AFA48C6B2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>depicts or describes sexual or excretory organs or activities in terms patently offensive to the average person, applying contemporary community standards; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H926CA0604EEB450592D4297E938DFD0B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>signifies the form of immorality which has relation to sexual impurity, taking into account the standards at common law in prosecutions for obscene libel.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CDC2C96BE0B4982AED1E203F3080E77"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text>The Commission, after soliciting comments from the public, shall publish best practices for making publicly available online terms of service or use that state plainly and with particularity the criteria that the provider or user of an interactive computer service employs in its content moderation practices, including by any partially or fully automated processes, in accordance with subparagraph (B)(iii)(I).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D8F97EEBE8346B183E5AAD5A5B045E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Violations</header><paragraph id="H01D30B5838454DB48FD05AC4F8D0CA0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><subparagraph id="HD6B8C49C9BE64BC69C2B4DE7FC97F9C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person aggrieved by a violation of subsection (c) or (d) may bring a civil action against the provider or user of an interactive computer service that committed the violation for any relief permitted under subparagraph (B) of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C37ADE8383F4BC6900A3BB0F381657B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><clause id="HCC7F46B6A9B341DE97981BA568D001D4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The plaintiff may seek the following relief in a civil action brought under subparagraph (A):</text><subclause id="H878BDB19CE3D49E59E7367333BFC749D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An injunction.</text></subclause><subclause id="H339FF2FEC5D8495C91F2D6FBDB836B83"><enum>(II)</enum><text>An award that is the greater of—</text><item id="H5C2B8B6E3CC1438F804B9AAD1934C355"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>actual damages; or</text></item><item id="H7B7979FF98FB4688B66893C3C5C189AC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>damages in the amount of $500 for each violation.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H755E3139A1724E8BB0F08B4018E581BB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Willful or knowing violations</header><text>In a civil action brought under subparagraph (A), if the court finds that the defendant willfully or knowingly violated subsection (c) or (d), the court may, in its discretion, increase the amount of the award to not more than 3 times the amount available under clause (i)(II) of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H710CFEBE32DA400B9A69AE869DACFEF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Actions by States</header><subparagraph id="HC6FC02D1E7224B2DB6709745EF3C9E65"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Authority of States</header><clause id="HA348399D4E54463795B7FC2786C9BD07"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whenever the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, has reason to believe that any person has engaged or is engaging in a pattern or practice of violating subsection (c) or (d) that has threatened or adversely affected or is threatening or adversely affecting an interest of the residents of that State, the State may bring a civil action against the person on behalf of the residents of the State for any relief permitted under clause (ii) of this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause id="H508BEC4FC0904BBDBFC72FA70584763B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Relief</header><subclause id="H7CEE63C54821434D8E97C72F4B540725"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The plaintiff may seek the following relief in a civil action brought under clause (i):</text><item id="HA7D9C58DA2F949128A87390FCB5511D2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>An injunction.</text></item><item id="HF2B71299D6F3455A9250634CD7896277"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>An award that is the greater of—</text><subitem id="HEC58CF9848EE4C97A11B7F032394DDD9"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>actual damages; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H0166AF33688141129477667EE9454705"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>damages in the amount of $500 for each violation.</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause id="H16B64999F73743EA99C7073AA691F6FD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Willful or knowing violations</header><text>In a civil action brought under clause (i), if the court finds that the defendant willfully or knowingly violated subsection (c) or (d), the court may, in its discretion, increase the amount of the award to not more than 3 times the amount available under subclause (I)(bb) of this clause.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC865C44F1D744BAE94A10E8C377A8EBD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>For purposes of bringing a civil action under this paragraph, nothing in this section shall prevent the attorney general of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general or the official by the laws of the State to—</text><clause id="H1B083EFC9DB146CBAB5D7A1AFBF46558"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct investigations;</text></clause><clause id="HFC329959EDB44E11A0D4DE43C0D937F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>administer oaths or affirmations; or</text></clause><clause id="H3E93689427FC4EF284AEC36355E12C5E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA99335C593F496A8717255B04B5656E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect on State court proceedings</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to prohibit an authorized State official from proceeding in State court on the basis of an alleged violation of any general civil or criminal statute of the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEA096D763B34939BD497A3F158160C8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Attorney general defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>attorney general</term> means the chief legal officer of a State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC4D0C1DC9D84F508A37FD44D1A70D3E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header><subparagraph id="H20AEC241EEA846049BB1C19CF4D300F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>A civil action brought under this subsection may be brought in the location where—</text><clause id="H9795E242319E4D209966C274C89AF07D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the defendant—</text><subclause id="H142D5250F9A641C3A468A2AE68C4DC9E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is found;</text></subclause><subclause id="H341846D36C394CBB83024A060608E86F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H95899B731A7B4398821E59B7B0205FCD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>transacts business; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA73B3BED002143C48FC0CF7D7D32827F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the violation occurred or is occurring.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD47998BFBC6B4CB58D75D5E8D623B617"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>Process in a civil action brought under this subsection may be served where the defendant—</text><clause id="H2B9EFFF3F71C457E80EE2834D21FAF91"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text></clause><clause id="H74102CCA68264EB5912B3715BDF249AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be found.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF142BA31EEDD4E56A79C6FB4A25EA5AE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Obligations of interactive computer service</header><text>A provider of an interactive computer service shall, at the time of entering an agreement with a customer for the provision of interactive computer service and in a manner deemed appropriate by the provider, notify the customer that parental control protections (such as computer hardware, software, or filtering services) are commercially available that may assist the customer in limiting access to material that is harmful to minors. The notice shall identify, or provide the customer with access to material identifying, current providers of such protections.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE660CAA8465947719614C1357D41E64D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header><paragraph id="H4648A84F67EA49FA8DDEC4F042B615CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No effect on criminal law</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to impair the enforcement of section 223 or 231 of this Act, chapter 71 (relating to obscenity) or 110 (relating to sexual exploitation of children) of title 18, United States Code, or any other Federal criminal statute.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53F5C4A42E754061BFAD0BD8D3ACD3B4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on intellectual property law</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit or expand any law pertaining to intellectual property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76E2670CB29C46F39EF0631535A48AED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State law</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prevent any State from enforcing any State law that is consistent with this section. No cause of action may be brought and no liability may be imposed under any State or local law that is inconsistent with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H983776154FAB481A9CDB57A7EF5F6A16"><enum>(4)</enum><header>No effect on communications privacy law</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the application of the Electronic Communications Privacy Act of 1986 or any of the amendments made by such Act, or any similar State law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D1DACA5EE424D34A24575E8F0086B96"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No effect on sex trafficking law</header><text>Nothing in this section (other than subsection (e)(2)(A)(i)) shall be construed to impair or limit—</text><subparagraph id="HBC4E495BDFF942A18CFCF313CDE56100"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any claim in a civil action brought under section 1595 of title 18, United States Code, if the conduct underlying the claim constitutes a violation of section 1591 of that title;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BCE91DB7D5A4FFFA605C853E4A8F485"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any charge in a criminal prosecution brought under State law if the conduct underlying the charge would constitute a violation of section 1591 of title 18, United States Code; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8A65B9639CC46E396618A5DB2CC48CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any charge in a criminal prosecution brought under State law if the conduct underlying the charge would constitute a violation of section 2421A of title 18, United States Code, and promotion or facilitation of prostitution is illegal in the jurisdiction where the defendant's promotion or facilitation of prostitution was targeted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4B833D6A72741AB82426EB5C630EF81"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section:</text><paragraph id="H95A0111B903A4250A081320D8174DA67"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access software provider</header><text>The term <term>access software provider</term> means a provider of software (including client or server software), or enabling tools that do any one or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7A3FAE9C104D40FC889B4B8D8BAD9140"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Filter, screen, allow, or disallow material.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF4CE39FEE04281B8B6DECED9FC71D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Pick, choose, analyze, or digest material.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF6BB3A2E1454103913005616C884F80"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Transmit, receive, display, forward, cache, search, subset, organize, reorganize, or translate material.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E8FD3C521D149FD881C365689974642"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Broadband internet access service</header><text>The term <term>broadband internet access service</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0466BCD88A194CDEBD1439279A61E7CB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Common carrier technology company</header><text>The term <term>common carrier technology company</term> means a provider of an interactive computer service that—</text><subparagraph id="H68F8E0AB27D14EE8853BD29B6AB4630F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>offers its services to the public; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E376D8F2F6342AB8C2D63201FA39F41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has more than 100,000,000 worldwide active monthly users.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CA8A661304649309B39D3310BD1E407"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information content provider</header><subparagraph id="H05A01CF18CB4466EBE03C8080100630A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>information content provider</term> means any person or entity that is responsible, in whole or in part, for the creation or development of material provided through the internet or any other interactive computer service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE035F97A55946B2AF7FDE98185279CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibility defined</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <term>responsible, in whole or in part, for the creation or development of material</term> includes affirmatively and substantively contributing to, modifying, altering, presenting with a reasonably discernible viewpoint, commenting upon, or editorializing about material provided by another person or entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D8A2FF5285E4A45A3E6DA7E0A587707"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Interactive computer service</header><text>The term <term>interactive computer service</term> means any information service, system, or access software provider that provides or enables computer access by multiple users to a computer server, including specifically a service or system that provides access to the internet and such systems operated or services offered by libraries or educational institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC644FB1E0CAA473DA5197A597AB584C7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Internet</header><text>The term <term>internet</term> means the international computer network of both Federal and non-Federal interoperable packet switched data networks. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2D19C0593BC4AB8A97FD6DEF01A60A0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Material</header><text>The term <term>material</term> means any data, regardless of physical form or characteristic, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1B6AAD311348447EBD0011ED94EB502E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>written or printed matter, information, automated information systems storage media, maps, charts, paintings, drawings, films, photographs, images, videos, engravings, sketches, working notes, or papers, or reproductions of any such things by any means or process; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CCA1D53729944F1921F1C665A660F73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sound, voice, magnetic, or electronic recordings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6769FE8F83444131AEDEF0D2854355FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H70D8C876167349C79A2FC25AFE8EFB0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Communications Act of 1934</header><text>The Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/151">47 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HBCAB10880EB5442F977A683E19B708BD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 223(h)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/223">47 U.S.C. 223(h)(2)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 230(f)(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDCE60E7DE5446338EEC1EA5A0B5C1FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 231(b)(4) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/231">47 U.S.C. 231(b)(4)</external-xref>), by striking <quote>section 230</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40332CD8B2D2461C8EF8D92821EE3037"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Trademark Act of 1946</header><text>Section 45 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 5, 1946 (commonly known as the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1127">15 U.S.C. 1127</external-xref>), is amended by striking the definition relating to the term <quote>Internet</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3A5411D6B4134A598057CF172201724C"><subsection id="H11947B53AE9743858A9BDB0B746A3F34"><enum/><text>The term <term>internet</term> has the meaning given that term in section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H3701AC910D4B44EF90DE72596F2A6CA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Title 17, United States Code</header><text>Section 1401(g) of title 17, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H8939667AA884426FAAA66634B4FC0E33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H701BA72856584F169E49C4A27F988B87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (e)(2) of such section 230</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (h)(2) of such section 232</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40566B6F738B4B538AD78B6C36F58859"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Title 18, United States Code</header><text>Part I of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H5F1D7F5BAAA248F49C489B3C6A9E0EA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 2257(h)(2)(B)(v), by striking <quote>section 230(c) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(c)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232(e) of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF582225E62814FFC96557667106CC8BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 2421A—</text><clause id="HC8A6D5E8AF104E66A16CA15CA8B316FB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>(as such term is defined in defined in section 230(f) the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(f)</external-xref>))</quote> and inserting <quote>(as that term is defined in section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H9BA5C474E8B44F2984EDC23057DC4706"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>(as such term is defined in defined in section 230(f) the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(f)</external-xref>))</quote> and inserting <quote>(as that term is defined in section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H891DC4B077E44ABAB6E844C4372FB8AC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Controlled Substances Act</header><text>Section 401(h)(3)(A)(iii)(II) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841(h)(3)(A)(iii)(II)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 230(c) of the Communications Act of 1934</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232(e) of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C17AF8703FA404285FCB6A32627D099"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Webb-Kenyon Act</header><text>Section 3(b)(1) of the Act entitled <quote>An Act divesting intoxicating liquors of their interstate character in certain cases</quote>, approved March 1, 1913 (commonly known as the <quote>Webb-Kenyon Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/27/122b">27 U.S.C. 122b(b)(1)</external-xref>), is amended by striking <quote>(as defined in section 230(f) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(f)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>(as defined in section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A25C6781C5142D1B97A8D4BAAF09F79" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Title 28, United States Code</header><text>Section 4102 of title 28, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H3C0C725378A741BBB309490986B53E0D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><clause commented="no" id="HDD78231D291446E0B2FAF2BBEA6F11CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H6E0434C14AA445859D97B58A6813C383"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section 230 if</quote> and inserting <quote>that section if</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D8D8C4071C4B6A98159E7A6A573852" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2), by striking <quote>section 230 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDBF50C1B1214419D851C40DB477BF884"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Title 31, United States Code</header><text>Section 5362(6) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>section 230(f) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(f)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA55B1D68DC1549CFB4F321449DE293D7"><enum>(9)</enum><header>National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act</header><text>Section 157(e)(1) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/941">47 U.S.C. 941(e)(1)</external-xref>) is amended, in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>section 230(c) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/230">47 U.S.C. 230(c)</external-xref>)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 232(e) of the Communications Act of 1934</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H42EE6CA5E73C41918780E085AB69DBA5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Subsections (c) and (d) of section 232 of the Communications Act of 1934, as added by subsection (a), shall apply to a common carrier technology company on and after the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

