<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H440073CDD802405AAB925807C43E308A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 7403 IH: National Opportunity to Restore Uranium Supply Services In America Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7403</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220405">April 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000589">Mrs. Lesko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001109">Ms. Cheney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to carry out a program to operate a uranium reserve consisting of uranium produced and converted in the United States and a program to ensure the availability of uranium produced, converted, and enriched in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEE41BF51B2AA4C6A985CE653484747A8" style="OLC"><section id="H1B199A034E4F421A8B94958A5E416635" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Opportunity to Restore Uranium Supply Services In America Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NO RUSSIA Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H53D1CB9A4B474A55A194AFA25CE47533"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HF3ED227D5BA04635AABF5A4B04C4B83A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B0EA905CE6342DDB856ABFE78B57467"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Nuclear Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H866BD02BC0724A14B8E69C2E64A2CE0D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Uranium Reserve</header><text>The term <term>Uranium Reserve</term> means the national strategic uranium reserve operated pursuant to the program described in section 3(a). </text></paragraph></section><section id="H8A874DA121D4416386A03D0126C0F157"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Strategic Uranium Reserve</header><subsection id="H9CFE8109E7AB492C935AFDADC2A88CFD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text>On enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall immediately begin executing, with the amounts reallocated under subsection (f), a program to operate a national strategic uranium reserve to ensure the availability of uranium produced and converted in the United States in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H598C72A7828D459CA0B4E3C2AF5D45BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Uranium Reserve are—</text><paragraph id="H832D9A20F2A147B6A220CD5ACDFC2735"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure the availability of domestically produced and converted uranium in the event of a supply disruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE63EFE834F44E3B660C8E6AD01F60B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address domestic nuclear fuel supply chain gaps and deficiencies in uranium production and conversion; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BBD02F1F6744588BE3977C23B0EB6F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to support strategic nuclear fuel supply chain capabilities in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E198A9D8C264C9ABBEDDAC02D0181A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In operating the Uranium Reserve, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H98688BD8BDD74E9AB4D895065FC4024F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>operate the Uranium Reserve in a manner consistent with the recommendations in the document entitled <quote>Restoring America's Competitive Nuclear Energy Advantage: A Strategy to Assure U.S. National Security</quote>, released by the United States Nuclear Fuel Working Group in 2020;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B3C7BB563B448B8EBB64C566973877"><enum>(2)</enum><text>acquire uranium produced and converted in the United States that is sufficient to sustain the continued operation of nuclear reactors in the United States in the event of a supply disruption;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7D938BCE6BF48F6A3774E16EC3AD643"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make uranium available as needed, in a manner consistent with the cost recovery requirements described in subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FD047B099FB46D2B78FE373E6352579"><enum>(4)</enum><text>replenish, in a manner consistent with the requirements of this section, uranium made available by the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H789E49AC268C43B1BA021B354278DEE2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cost recovery</header><paragraph id="H82589492F0EC45CBB11AE66D1714AA65"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out activities under this section, the Secretary shall ensure that any uranium acquired, provided, or made available through the Uranium Reserve is subject to cost recovery based on the fair market value of the subject uranium.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F1B9C6DC17B4CA6A7416A2F6F3F617B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of certain funds</header><text>Notwithstanding section 3302 of title 31, United States Code, revenues received from the sale or transfer of uranium and other activities related to making uranium available pursuant to this section—</text><subparagraph id="H10F4FBEDF1E6499DB64257A71B6572E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be available to the Department for carrying out the purposes of this section, to reduce the need for further appropriations for those purposes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECD8B2A40DA7439493E490D4BE67F387"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5890B030360C46D2BE1E821C8C42AFBD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The Secretary shall exclude from the Uranium Reserve uranium from an entity that—</text><paragraph id="H8A8AC08636D24B27ADD7CB420BFABD94"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation or the Government of the People’s Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1898FEE36B324B14B8ECCBB4407FE955"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81733052A3644EB8A1A6868630A0EC89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding reallocation</header><paragraph id="H72F62DB454504256AEFAFD56C6A33714"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the amounts described in paragraph (2) shall be reallocated to the Office of Nuclear Energy of the Department for the purpose of executing the program described in subsection (a) by—</text><subparagraph id="H298105466537441A852451FA2BF5B2DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>continuing the activities initiated by the Department, including the National Nuclear Security Administration, using the amounts described in the proviso referred to in that paragraph;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE6D19822B3D3456FA6778DACDF3D4456"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carrying out other activities consistent with the purposes for which the amounts described in that proviso were originally made available; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF17FB1D6C35348F694ECDD3E0652E0A9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>carrying out activities in accordance with this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88B7A41C912F46EB808B2FCBD6946E25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amounts described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts referred to in paragraph (1) are the amounts that remain available as of the date of enactment of this Act from the $75,000,000 that shall be used for the Uranium Reserve Program described in the first proviso under the heading <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="appropriations-intermediate">weapons activities</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="appropriations-major">National Nuclear Security Administration</header-in-text></quote> under the heading <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="appropriations-major">atomic energy defense activities</header-in-text></quote> in title III of division D of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>; 134 Stat. 1369), that were made available to the Department by that Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E12FCD8F1EF45FBA4E2146AEBA60FA4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Paragraph (1) does not affect any amounts made available to the Department, including the National Nuclear Security Administration, that are not described in the proviso referred to in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0281906BF8D14919A19B0020A01EB543"><enum>4.</enum><header>Domestic uranium availability</header><subsection id="H129E9136248D41439CFB3E13B10D7958"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program (referred to in this section as the <quote>program</quote>) to ensure the availability of uranium produced, converted, and enriched in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE29DFF4A40CD485EB528EEB2F8A1E080"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the program shall be—</text><paragraph id="H11D54370069C4B9889CF6259538D63A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to eliminate reliance on Russian uranium;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F5975F44FB4CDA9F3C246195583FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to address domestic nuclear fuel supply chain gaps and deficiencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1374895678A4785939C7C2BEC850454"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to ensure the availability of domestically produced, converted, and enriched uranium to support the continued operation of nuclear reactors in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8D0CADAFA6824769A1A7A04D99A10B65"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the program, the Secretary shall consider, and, as appropriate, execute options—</text><paragraph id="H44829098C2094DF094EA122039E5D2FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to establish, through a competitive process, new and, as appropriate, diverse domestic uranium mining, conversion, and enrichment capacity that is needed to replace uranium imported from Russia;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FE7D8A3105C401AB31945C75DB17899"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to activate and expand the American Assured Fuel Supply to meet domestic and international nuclear fuel supply needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95491C4388F04350A99738A9E64D3FBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to restock the American Assured Fuel Supply, including by utilizing, or merging with, the Uranium Reserve;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADD62666A02144B3A73F077CB4EDC62A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that do not disrupt or replace market mechanisms; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DB67239D31B4F559C5376415FD521EC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>that ensure the use of domestic uranium utilized as a result of the program does not negatively impact the economic operation of nuclear reactors in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25844FA699794075A2990FFB183675DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The Secretary shall exclude from the program uranium from an entity that—</text><paragraph id="H2F50276304264454922632432FB07752"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation or the Government of the People’s Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF22DA13BD434AE7AF158FD2246B2A06"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

