<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1DBE1459E07645F1A2519736F9A1AFBC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9652 IH: Expanding Transparency for Hidden Independent Campaign Spending Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9652</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221221">December 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require all political committees to file separate reports for contributions of $1,000 or more which are received fewer than 20 days before the date of any election in which the committee makes a contribution, expenditure, independent expenditure or electioneering communication on behalf of a candidate or political party in the election, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H32F95B9F3C244D74ABECC79A420361B3" style="OLC"><section id="HE6B6DA02D34C4D25BA0C783FDC302AEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Expanding Transparency for Hidden Independent Campaign Spending Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Ethics Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFDF68258CEA04C0691E2215B1CECF4E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring all political committees to file separate reports for contributions received fewer than 20 days before election in which committee makes contributions or expenditures on behalf of a candidate or political party</header><subsection id="H3CD4B3C3236F46C7B5F899B7C490CD44"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 304(a)(6)(A) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104(a)(6)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>Each committee shall notify the Commission in writing of any contribution of $1,000 or more received by the committee after the 20th day, but more than 48 hours before, any election in which the committee makes a contribution to, or expenditure (including an independent expenditure) or electioneering communication (as defined in subsection (f)) on behalf of, a candidate or political committee of a political party in such election.</quote>. </text></subsection><subsection id="H1E5DEC300DD14F3CB953FB42530E2E60"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to elections occurring after the expiration of the 48-hour period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

