<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H253AF78FE3504D9DA94C2600D5B907CC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7961 IH: Safety From Violence for Healthcare Employees Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7961</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect hospital personnel from violence, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA392DF1078D54FD5B1EF9DDA5FE00224" style="OLC"><section id="HD0DA727CB1B84844A9890388F2AE638D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safety From Violence for Healthcare Employees Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SAVE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9ABCC6EF84F9468FAF818F314BB63BD6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prevention of violence against hospital personnel</header><subsection id="H245668311A70416B88F61804355BEE11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H28172B2FF6994B35A20ADD3F34D15C8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The incidence of assault and intimidation against hospital employees poses a serious national problem.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H166F0F86279B41F6AD85E8335AE3C3E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The problem of assault and intimidation against hospital and health care employees preceded the COVID–19 pandemic. According to an April 2020 Bureau of Labor Statistics report, the health care and social service industries experienced the highest rates of injuries caused by workplace violence and were 5 times as likely to suffer a workplace violence injury than workers overall in 2018. That report also found that the incidence rate for workplace violence against health care workers had steadily increased since 2011. The COVID–19 pandemic exacerbated this growing problem.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA12C07EB07F436CB66E2287406C3AF0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Workplace violence in hospitals inhibits hospital employees from performing their duties and thereby disrupts the delivery of health care services and leads to adverse patient outcomes. Violence towards hospital workers also has been associated with decreased productivity and quality of care, employee absenteeism, and increased employee turnover.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE168555C24A64082A5496C68C317C8E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>State and local authorities are now and will continue to be responsible for prosecuting the overwhelming majority of violent crimes in the United States, including assault and intimidation against hospital employees. These authorities can address the problem of assault and intimidation against hospital employees more effectively with greater Federal law enforcement involvement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A0C73B7E6964D15B528C1418F52E5A1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Existing Federal law is inadequate to address this problem.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68EE7C2075D74AF6AABB3544B31E6C25"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Assault and intimidation against hospital employees substantially affects interstate commerce in many ways, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD47027E18CD044A58A25AFF505320810"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Health care services are a significant part of the national economy. In 2020, expenditures on health care services accounted for 19.7 percent of the country’s gross domestic product (or $4,100,000,000,000). Within health care, hospitals and health systems are economic pillars that create jobs and support economic growth across State lines. In 2020, hospitals directly employed 6,300,000 individuals. More broadly, hospitals supported 17,600,000 jobs throughout the entire interstate economy—nearly 1 out of 8 jobs in the United States—and supported $3,600,000,000,000 in overall economic activity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62625FBC14F74CFEB73B153EC60279DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The health care market, and hospitals in particular, are heavily regulated by the Federal Government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D99A1D470C24684BBA8BD0E2F340E62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Hospital revenue comes from interstate or Federal sources, such as out-of-State insurers or Medicare.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H076B4093BA6241DFA7D99DCD1C7729C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Hospital employees who are victims of assault or intimidation are prevented from purchasing goods and services, obtaining or sustaining employment, or participating in other commercial activity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67840CDC7E054E6B8CDD3F2EA008EE57"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Facilities and instrumentalities of interstate commerce have been used in the commission of assault and intimidation against hospital employees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E2BFF84308D4F569A4FF75D776EA2CB"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Assault and intimidation against hospital employees has been committed using articles that have traveled in interstate commerce.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DB325385C42497899F46B25A18B4191"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In Summit Health, Ltd. v. Pinhas, 500 U.S. 322, 329–30 (1991), the Supreme Court of the United States held that it is <quote>clear</quote> that hospitals are <quote>regularly</quote> engaged in interstate commerce, performing services for out-of-State patients and generating revenues from out-of-State sources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE751E48D3645918C1E170DCDD2EF20"><enum>(8)</enum><text>In Taylor v. United States, 579 U.S. ___ (2016), the Supreme Court of the United States ruled that activities that affect commerce may be regulated so long as they substantially affect interstate commerce in the aggregate, even if their individual impact on interstate commerce is minimal. In addition, as the United States Court of Appeals for the Fourth Circuit recognized in United States v. Hill, 927 F.3d 188 (4th Cir. 2019), Taylor and other Supreme Court decisions establish that when Congress may regulate an economic or commercial activity—as it may with respect to hospitals—it also may regulate violent conduct that interferes with or affects that activity. Accordingly, if individuals are engaged in ongoing economic or commercial activity subject to congressional regulation—as hospital employees are—then Congress also may prohibit violent crime that interferes with or affects such individuals’ ongoing economic or commercial activity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC5DFF14CC374D3F9D7716C66226A7E3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Federal jurisdiction over certain violent crimes against hospital employees enables Federal, State, and local authorities to work together as partners in the investigation and prosecution of such crimes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DBA37575A8542AB99A1FF8FA1DB1D0C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The problem of assault and intimidation against hospital employees is serious, widespread, and interstate in nature as to warrant Federal assistance to hospitals to combat that activity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A60AA3AE0F245FEB53F658C365CDBB9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on interference with hospital personnel in the performance of duties</header><paragraph id="H25B419CFCF9C47DB94AE55A06C7E62D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/7">Chapter 7</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H458CE04E446542B99FF91A392C032B26" style="USC"><section id="H4BAAFA7492324DD49D07C28FB21A09C3"><enum>120.</enum><header>Interference with performance of duties of hospital personnel</header><subsection id="H96986E384FCC4DACBD56E967FBC422A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Whoever knowingly assaults or intimidates an individual employed by a hospital, or an entity contracting with a hospital or other medical facility, during the course of the performance of the duties of such individual, and, as a result, interferes with the performance of the duties of such individual or limits the ability of such individual to perform such duties, shall be fined under this title, imprisoned not more than 10 years, or both. </text></subsection><subsection id="H003ED5631DCE4C6A8FA537ABF5AE0534"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enhanced penalties</header><paragraph id="HA1CD6725C288464BBEA922839F268A4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acts involving dangerous weapons or acts that result in bodily injury</header><text>Whoever, in the commission of any act described in subsection (a), uses a deadly or dangerous weapon or inflicts bodily injury, shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB792C80AF141496A8C78D0E128B8C43D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acts committed during emergency declarations</header><text>Whoever commits any act described in subsection (a) during the period of a declaration of a public emergency for the area in which the act is committed shall be fined under this title or imprisoned not more than 20 years, or both.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE41C07201D2E4C90A45BFC344BF53F2C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Defense</header><text>It shall be a defense to a prosecution under this section that—</text><paragraph id="H15C8FB2FEEA146C2965D8D7798AABC2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the defendant is a person with a physical, mental, or intellectual disability; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5642866D8201447B9DC18510CCDEA079"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the conduct of the defendant was a clear and direct manifestation of such disability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H127A19E2F29B4C32B8C81226FE5B8F9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3A8A41AA015C41D89D3F5C786EA6EF57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hospital</header><text>The term <quote>hospital</quote> means any of the following medical facilities:</text><subparagraph id="HFCCBA63515364B0B91671FED6E8528F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A hospital (as defined in section 1861(e) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(e)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1B18937F1C84507907EA316EE0CB9E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A long-term care hospital (as defined in section 1861(ccc) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(ccc)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A1999941714B05BD701383E90D2340"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A rehabilitation facility (as defined in section 1886(j)(1)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(j)(1)(A)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F901E71381B496A8CCF6D955AA7548C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A cancer hospital (as described in section 1886(d)(1)(B)(iii) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(1)(B)(iii)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61B97CCCC96C44E7AD3F0327529E9C99"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A children’s hospital (as described in section 1886(d)(1)(B)(v) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(d)(1)(B)(v)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CCE6225D20F4171A177701E93A9D478"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A critical access hospital (as defined in section 1861(mm)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(mm)(1)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H568BF11A44F7445CB11EFD1E2C427DC9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A rural emergency hospital (as defined in section 1861(kkk)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(kkk)(2)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H49618BC89F2643AB875BBA19D432C672"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Declaration of a public emergency</header><text>The term <quote>declaration of a public emergency</quote> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H10CF9CB99C014454B9805ED6C58937F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A public health emergency declared by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E6B85F05F0346AAA6A51351F34265EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB56E2AC4F2E44BE89E4C071B84A0A99B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H360C7CB3AD5F48FFBDFF6C25BF91F040"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 18, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA26FF42025974D88885E823D5B19E05C" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">120. Interference with performance of duties of hospital personnel.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8C5D6DB3D744ABA943C48E99C204048"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grants for the protection of the hospital workforce against violence</header><text>Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after part OO the following:</text><quoted-block id="H8764B658ACDD4B3888816189165581F4" style="OLC"><part id="H3C65F5E2D06C41EDA17C24553BA18B33"><enum>PP</enum><header>GRANT PROGRAM FOR HOSPITAL WORKFORCE SAFETY AND SECURITY</header><section id="HD04EA4444A69410B853DA18EFED0A067"><enum>3061.</enum><header>Grant authorization</header><subsection id="H23514AA87AFF4286BCAC33EE377CD242"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General may make grants under this part to hospitals for the purpose of carrying out programs to reduce the incidence of violence at hospitals, including violence or intimidation against hospital personnel in the performance of their duties.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA232134E29334A2090E3941890F3FCF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this part shall be used to reduce the incidence of violence at hospitals through programs that may include one or more of the following:</text><paragraph id="HCEDDD68D01E4430FB296C228D311DAAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training hospital personnel to prevent violence or intimidation against others or themselves, including de-escalation training and specialized training in responding to mental health crises.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73E8D5C399F1455BB2DA491B806B9C55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coordination with State and local law enforcement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D26694004A74B9BB49587639F63B101"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Placement and use of hospital access control technologies, video surveillance, metal detection, panic buttons, status alert systems, restricted access capabilities, and safe patient and staff rooms, and other violence-prevention tools or measures.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EABB0FF5AA3433CB77BC67E0CCAEA62"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other measures that the Attorney General determines may provide a significant improvement in—</text><subparagraph id="HF7D0DA10DCE0469E8BFB83AF350DE3F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>training for violence prevention at hospitals; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC965D4599D9746D2B6DF53BD0A4C6BBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protection against violence and intimidation of hospital personnel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7732E3AD9BD34FF19E1E16BA8B99A233"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Preferential consideration in awarding grants</header><text>In awarding grants under this part, the Attorney General shall give preferential consideration, if feasible, to an application from a hospital that—</text><paragraph id="H309BD7E944184DD78ED2DDD8AD1B4DA4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>has a demonstrated need for improved security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38C5E694BB144D88B81E7A11EEDDD530"><enum>(2)</enum><text>has a demonstrated need for financial assistance; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF64556D9F07240F2A9562289CFC4C53F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has evidenced the ability to make the improvements for which the grant amounts are sought.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87A276612F64481A9E85C3A1EECE7600"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Equitable distribution of grant funds</header><text>In awarding grants under this part, the Attorney General shall ensure, to the extent practicable, an equitable geographic distribution among the regions of the United States and among urban, suburban, and rural areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7240CD3A1F3041A4B2ED62706A5CE727"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Not more than 2 percent of a grant made under this part may be used for costs incurred to administer such grant.</text></subsection></section><section id="H336E43DD8A1948C0BC619179F61682CC"><enum>3062.</enum><header>Applications</header><subsection id="HB02C175C2CE64049AAB4459E87B57DE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To request a grant under this part, the chief executive of a hospital shall submit an application to the Attorney General at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H765B1017E67E4FBCB492D96271CDC704"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each application under this section shall include—</text><paragraph id="H1CF0F41667594FD2960B5613270050D5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of—</text><subparagraph id="H3E0B971026DB4C6BA5F7FE3249E35A22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the intended uses of funds provided under the grant; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325C8F23BB724164854E6631301D0A4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the activities funded under the grant will satisfy the purpose of this part;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3F677029318462D91BB99CBD66EB97B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assurance that the applicant shall maintain and report such programmatic and financial data, records, and information as the Attorney General may reasonably require; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB20C4B7361824D268AC7603182DA861B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a certification, made in a form acceptable to the Attorney General, that—</text><subparagraph id="HD90DD0FEF8584EC18D974DD299AC68CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the programs to be funded by the grant meet all the requirements of this part;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H063B8743B71E425EA8C98348C496AB8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all the information contained in the application is correct; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24554DD4986F4E32985FEB8EDC8250D4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the applicant will comply with all provisions of this part and all other applicable Federal laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1BBCB2030340422FAB112A97DF94C945"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this part, the Attorney General shall promulgate guidelines to implement this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H79938E1C776D41BD9B57215EFF6845D6"><enum>3063.</enum><header>Annual report to congress; grant accountability</header><subsection id="H6FCE5D19AC61467B912E6CAAA838963A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the end of the fiscal year for which funding for grants under this part is made available, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report regarding the activities carried out under this part. Each such report shall include, for the preceding fiscal year, the number of grants funded under this part, the amount of funds provided under those grants, and the activities for which those grant funds were used.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD45ECD486AD44AEAB611D18BCB91B4D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant accountability</header><text>Section 3026 (relating to grant accountability) shall apply to grants awarded by Attorney General under this part. For purposes of the preceding sentence, any references in section 3026 to part LL shall be considered references to part PP.</text></subsection></section><section id="H13691B572BDB47DB87FA7C637A47ACB5"><enum>3064.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this part, the term <quote>hospital</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 120(d)(1) of title 18, United States Code.</text></section><section id="H8E266352A4D44E7989EEFC833A2A2F6B"><enum>3065.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2032 to carry out this part. Funds appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to the preceding sentence shall remain available until expended.</text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

