<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5DA406E3318C48A9BC82DE116DD06B87" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7937 IH: Revitalize, Enhance, and Nurture in Expanded Ways Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7937</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220603">June 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement, to establish a program to facilitate coal mine reclamation and award grants to certain States and Indian Tribes to carry out coal mine reclamation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H739C94555F5D49A0B61D128A28C8A8D8" style="OLC"><section id="H897EA793A33C45879963A9C7B00619DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Revitalize, Enhance, and Nurture in Expanded Ways Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RENEW Our Abandoned Mine Lands Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H096E7339EC874C7E932A104557F04756"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments to the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act</header><subsection id="H58FBDE703EBE43598621B9B2B4CDB063"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coal mine reclamation program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title V of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1251">30 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H07D3B5548A8F48E8B8CCC205A7C2DCE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HAC7DD730E3904176B267C955D164F496"><enum>530.</enum><header>OSMRE coal mine reclamation program</header><subsection id="H17F537373509425C94DC0D1DE75B69DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a program—</text><paragraph id="H1B0D487842CF42F4AAD4B845FB0A9009"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to help ensure the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement has sufficient funds to carry out covered reclamation projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7819D6063A4D477FB79F4A06E435A3EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to award grants to States and Indian tribes to carry out covered reclamation projects. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB9893E3FE971418FAC24BF8BB1770DC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header><paragraph id="H1DD159ABEECA41668F7C00C01AFD8E3E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may award grants under this section to States and Indian tribes to carry out covered reclamation projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6ECE48EF6C44EFAA71E0591FCC9BFB3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall allocate grant funds based on need. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB185976462264CC592D5674A32D3DD2D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this section—</text><subparagraph id="HE0A8670909DD4E2CBB11E3D3944EA544"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State or Indian tribe shall maintain State bonding requirements approved under section 503 that are not less stringent than the bonding requirements of such State on the date of enactment of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E89DE136A0B406B8B33009C27AA475A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the Secretary determines appropriate, a State or Indian tribe shall address deficiencies in its approved alternative bonding system on permitted coal mines;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H965D82516E3B41C7B499304D9ED65531"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an Indian tribe shall have an approved regulatory program pursuant to this title and section 710; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H451EEABEEDD34DA98310546B2012902E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State or Indian tribe shall demonstrate—</text><clause id="HD6608946D4174A2AA0E01902687E826D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the use of all available legal remedies to the extent practicable to recover reclamation costs from responsible persons liable under this Act, including corporate parents, owners, and executives;</text></clause><clause id="HC8743A245B454695A615C7ABBD0BCFF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the use of such grant funds, requirements for—</text><subclause id="HF3AB4F9FCC034011AF7B89AF0C46F9A8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>active coal mines within its jurisdiction to reclaim surface areas as contemporaneously as practicable with surface coal mining operations pursuant to the purposes of this Act;</text></subclause><subclause id="H921149CF1B374AC0850D00E72E7AC0B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coal mine reclamation within its jurisdiction to be carried out according to approved reclamation plans;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0A19E92FD32A4D6A87E61C12FDE6730D"><enum>(III)</enum><text>compliance with the Clean Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE5ADE783894F45C3B31D6D049232B937"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">payments of wages not less than those prevailing on similar projects in the locality, for all laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in the performance of construction, alteration, or repair work on a project assisted in whole or in part by funding made available under this section, as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as the “Davis-Bacon Act''); </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAB39233487C3462CAAEA9C63C4558393"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aggregation of reclamation projects when practicable to improve economies of scale; and</text></clause><clause id="H387A243BC838428AA2EB4C61DD8427FD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>active facilitation of community engagement in the design and oversight of reclamation projects; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H551D15426AB74794ACAC805E7A33FE59"><enum>(E)</enum><text>meet such additional requirements as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95E032BEC900471D9ED2DD96453BA382"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="HBE53BFC7A44A473498D6AE1C28523002"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall require, from each State or Indian tribe applying for grant funds under this section, an application for each fiscal year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2864008AFC434F1897697BCDE78FCD52"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Projected shortfall</header><text>Each application shall include the following information:</text><clause id="H247B84EDE5CC480EB725EDAEFE1D5CDD"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a State applicant, the projected annual shortfall in funding for reclamation with respect to all coal mines where the State forfeited a reclamation bond.</text></clause><clause id="H7B6C899E509740DD801BE6509BA55C03"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For an Indian tribe applicant, the projected annual shortfall in funding for reclamation with respect to all coal mines where the Indian tribe forfeited a reclamation bond. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4EA547F4B4740D88ADFF46416E3E10F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HE4F405A9677944CF8BAADC553E0AE314"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $385,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2032 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94513CEA46404332A324A2BD2139AFB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amounts made available under this section, the Secretary may use $1,000,000 each fiscal year for the costs of administering this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC3F4B109B9D4E97BB2D80FA05010FA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section: </text><paragraph id="H465AF48AADA444189AF9053BADF38E51"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered reclamation project</header><text>The term <term>covered reclamation project</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H4E13FA1C569D40DA830388613CF2C70A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a coal mine reclamation project on a site where a performance bond was forfeited and found to be insufficient; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE6B07C2CEFB4C62A7FD51E4FC07BEA9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes reclamation projects—</text><clause id="HA9849E59C81E4D9AA8112532937240D8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involving lands or waters mined for coal under a permit under this Act that were subject to permit revocation and bond forfeiture pursuant to section 800.50 of title 30, Code of Federal Regulations, (or its equivalent in an approved State or Tribal program); and</text></clause><clause id="H2AC5015F9A4A46C8A128C33E7C8BB9D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>where there is a shortfall between the actual cost of reclamation, including long-term water treatment, and the value of any forfeited bonding instrument. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BE8CBE46D5F44B4849845DEF76FA26C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62D381DE5F4E48688EE764881DDAD553"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The program established under subsection (a) shall terminate on September 30, 2032. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1DFA006CBE954C65ACD3100B732DE947"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants to the States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 705(a) of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1295">30 U.S.C. 1295(a)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3711F77F91DF4EB5B39F695B1401CBE5" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H30C56E3B8FBC41C5BC61B8D790EF4887"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to make annual grants to any State for the purpose of assisting such State in developing, administering, and enforcing State programs under this Act. Except as provided in subsection (c)—</text><paragraph id="HF939B77FD77D450B953E93C9617AE836"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">through fiscal year 2022, such grants shall not exceed 80 percent of the total costs incurred during the first year, 60 percent of total costs incurred during the second year, and 50 percent of the total costs incurred during each year thereafter;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87925D79DB6C4B229487D8C14668A45A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for fiscal year 2023 and 2024, such grants shall not exceed 75 percent of the total costs incurred during each year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87F6FF8C7F034B628021AD4EB4F91DD6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2025 and thereafter, such grants shall not exceed 100 percent of the total costs incurred during each year. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD4F14E13D67440D6A802C5BA320EF635"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents for the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1201">30 U.S.C. 1201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 529 the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H005D721C19A5407CB7964FA74070DFE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 530. OSMRE coal mine reclamation program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

