<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDAB5F0CB132F4CB3ACEC9C4F6A3403F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9163 IH: Advancing Justice for Servicemembers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221011">October 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to establish a time limit for the processing of harassment complaints made by members of the Armed Forces and to clarify the procedure for judicial review of such complaints, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6078373EB6C949909587515DBE145B19" style="OLC"><section id="HD4D9483ACA3C4CBCA9CA3DA4062F37E0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advancing Justice for Servicemembers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD1C9417AA6134BB2A910ACEC4A5954F7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Time limit for processing certain administrative complaints</header><subsection id="HBA3C6EE5F33A4F40927CE8BF432581C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/80">Chapter 80</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1561b">section 1561b</external-xref> the following new section: </text><quoted-block id="HF6638C2B07534BEFA91B0936BDEF7000" style="USC"><section id="HA8A9CABFB4824708B15456ED4B85D188"><enum>1561c.</enum><header>Processing a harassment or military equal opportunity complaint</header><subsection id="H70E6C6336F23493F8F1AECDE1FCC4272"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Time limit</header><text>An official authorized to take final action on a complaint from a member of the armed forces of harassment or prohibited discrimination shall ensure the procedures and requirements for the complaint are completed within 180 days after the date on which any supervisor or designated office received the complaint.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA50DE3A55A9C419F88323264192EA799"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><paragraph id="HA64ECC57060D4D30B4DEADD2CC5A1244"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Pursuant to section 706(1) of title 5, United States Code, a member of the armed forces may seek an order in a court of the United States directing the Secretary concerned to take final action or provide a written explanation no later than 30 days after the court enters its order, if an authorized official does not—</text><subparagraph id="H423E9B30F2B04187B281C97C10316067"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take final action on a complaint under subsection (a) within 180 days; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H04D02845ADED42D7A9C5E7C0D7285378"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the member a written explanation of the final action taken on a complaint under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EB157805A704E38BABC9F8713437902"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Pursuant to section 706(2) of title 5, United States Code, and no later than 30 days after a member of the armed forces receives a written explanation of the final action taken on a complaint under subsection (a), the member may seek review of the action in a court of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H114B5C0E0DC244009342B451B9D6C16D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than April 1 each year, the Secretary concerned shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report of the total number of court orders sought under subsection (b) and orders granted by such courts.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF569CDE554BA4EF497AC55C087F4B68F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1CA5C060824F4D0B95FFFA05E9201ED8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6E79475256664E14A946A62B7D18836A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H218493747394449D9B70B254CE7D4CF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2055530BA9A41D89B41486F69690128"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H705F552536474E2BB47C4CE588B797DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9638920BC624A6EBDFC5E52518CC9B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>complaint</quote> means an allegation or report of harassment or prohibited discrimination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93C0000E64E34C7F8B2C7E90B5F2333E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>designated office</quote> means a military equal opportunity office or an office of the inspector general or staff judge advocate, and any other departmental office authorized by the Secretary concerned to receive harassment and prohibited discrimination complaints.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2405DC6793F14B07A087E49F217FA3B5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <quote>harassment</quote> means behavior that is unwelcome or offensive to a reasonable person, whether oral, written, or physical, that creates an intimidating, hostile, or offensive environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE5A332D4C4843DDAEA4E81CBD236F4F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>prohibited discrimination</quote> means unlawful discrimination, including disparate treatment, of an individual or group on the basis of race, color, national origin, religion, sex (including pregnancy), gender identity, or sexual orientation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H758C1723C9D84607A5DAA335C8C539B9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <quote>member of the armed forces</quote> means a member of an armed force serving on active duty.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96E46C7C483D4AEA8DA01B8473F64CB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>supervisor</quote> means a member of the armed forces in charge or command of other members of the armed forces or a civilian employee (as defined in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code) authorized to direct and control service members. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB71AB8733FD04296A5DEB38E021F3F04"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 1561b the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HDB45DF4701E3410F9974805A23A341CF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HF6638C2B07534BEFA91B0936BDEF7000" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HA8A9CABFB4824708B15456ED4B85D188" level="section">1561c. Processing a harassment or military equal opportunity complaint.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

