<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6EEAC13D34DE4EEE8B58B5521131E8B8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7684 IH: No Tax Breaks for Radical Corporate Activism Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7684</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220506">May 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001311">Mr. Bishop of North Carolina</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to deny the trade or business expense deduction for the reimbursement of employee costs of child gender transition procedure or travel to obtain an abortion.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17C98D1067CC4F69BFD46CAE355FE38F" style="OLC"><section id="HA5811E4D385C49F0BAFC76902470D401" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Tax Breaks for Radical Corporate Activism Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H03D82B4D99554DC39DD28371B20FECE0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Denial of deduction</header><subsection id="H9B996891C6F74C838B1320581B1384DD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/162">Section 162</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (s) as subsection (t), and by inserting after subsection (r) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8975BE29BD6C4BEF9FED30C84E61E27D"><subsection id="H4AE86110C8D6454196A3619CA5C50667"><enum>(s)</enum><header>Disallowance of certain expenses relating to abortion or child gender transition</header><paragraph id="H7F25C13919ED4ECAA9BFF1F28AD224A0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No deduction shall be allowed under this chapter to an employer for any amount paid or incurred to reimburse an employee for, or to otherwise pay, expenses in connection with—</text><subparagraph id="H0AAD4EA0F0E048649C10522F7F4A0E20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>travel for the purpose of obtaining an abortion, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23558EBE683943CB933ED7B15814885F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any gender transition procedure for a minor child of the employee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E140B4F1DBF4579B821CE9AB73312EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H2B21A29F221F426081D089F358D4BA21"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Gender transition procedure</header><clause id="H6821A4FDFCD44528A89BBD3843814980"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>gender transition procedure</term> means any medical or surgical service which seeks to alter or remove physiological or anatomical characteristics or features which are typical for the individual's biological sex, or to instill or create physiological or anatomical characteristics which resemble a sex different from the individual's birth sex, for the purpose of gender transition, including—</text><subclause id="HA8500AE5A9D048EB8F648B9B03C145B0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>physician's services and inpatient and outpatient hospital services, including gender transition surgery, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H63AB8812CFAE4510BDCB5D8826C45A1F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>prescribed drugs related to gender transition, including puberty-blocking drugs, cross-sex hormones, or other mechanisms to promote the development of feminizing or masculinizing features (in the opposite sex).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD2C3F31954C4462A9CAD3D8335E18900"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Such term does not include—</text><subclause id="H88DE6BEB7FF74CD89E0559B71D0BEC97"><enum>(I)</enum><text>services for treatment of a medically-verifiable disorder of sex development, including—</text><item id="H3D569D76512E48C5B9BC74B3BC18DD0B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>external biological sex characteristics which are irresolvably ambiguous, such as presence of 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or both ovarian and testicular tissue, or </text></item><item id="HEAA12E0CABD843828A35F3405F36612A"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>other physician-diagnosed disorder of sexual development, with respect to which the physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action for a biological male or biological female, or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H8359D6F0AA9E4783AA7EE4D9449BCD02"><enum>(II)</enum><text>treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder caused or exacerbated by the performance of any gender transition procedure, whether or not the gender transition procedure was performed in accordance with State and Federal law or whether not a deduction for expenses in connection with the gender transition procedure is allowable under this chapter.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4B27531BDCC543ACAD48D0611F26C958"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Gender</header><text>The term <term>gender</term> means the psychological, behavioral, social, and cultural aspects of being male or female.</text></clause><clause id="HBD2E75D57C35405CB0800AD558EAFDC3"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Gender transition</header><text>The term <term>gender transition</term> means the process in which an individual goes from identifying with and living as a gender that corresponds to his or her biological sex to identifying with and living as a gender different from his or her biological sex, and may involve social, legal, or physical changes. </text></clause><clause id="H89AEE9A64A014C159B96039CC30BFDC2"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Gender transition surgery</header><subclause id="H6C23914EA32D4C7C87F4E98AF4CAEC0B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>gender transition surgery</term> means any surgical service, including genital or non-genital surgery, performed for the purpose of assisting an individual with a gender transition.</text></subclause><subclause id="HF611F32227BA4A5FAE57B9304784F9E2"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Such term does not include any service performed because the individual suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness which would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of major bodily function unless surgery is performed. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HB722FBC63CAE426C8D9EAEBB7D56849D"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Genital surgery</header><text>The term <term>genital surgery</term> includes surgical procedures such as—</text><subclause id="HAAE10C7F214E4892A0F0F83AEC89C205"><enum>(I)</enum><text>penectomy, orchiectomy, vaginoplasty, clitoroplasty, or vulvoplasty for biologically male patients, and </text></subclause><subclause id="HC5C1926A6BE44FCDAE303FC7CBC4F6BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>hysterectomy, ovariectomy, reconstruction of the fixed part of the urethra with or without a metoidioplasty or a phalloplasty, vaginectomy, scrotoplasty, or implantation of erection or testicular prostheses for biologically female patients.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H71B5598490F94868810C709DB3F5FEE5"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Non-genital surgery</header><text>The term <term>non-genital surgery</term> includes surgical procedures such as liposuction, lipofilling, voice surgery, and—</text><subclause id="HEA06B31E59F34D9C8DE535C5A354DCD6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>augmentation mammoplasty, facial feminization surgery, thyroid cartilage reduction, gluteal augmentation (whether implants or lipofilling), hair reconstruction, or various aesthetic procedures for biologically male patients, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE32B7F10BB1D448DA5CFFF38E48ECF31"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subcutaneous mastectomy, pectoral implants, or various aesthetic procedures for biologically female patients.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE4ACFFA593A9481BBF7A86668BAD26E4"><enum>(viii)</enum><header>Puberty-blocking drugs</header><text>The term <term>puberty-blocking drugs</term> means Gonadotropin-releasing hormone (GnRH) analogues or other synthetic drugs used in biological males to stop luteinizing hormone secretion and therefore testosterone secretion, and synthetic drugs used in biological females to stop the production of estrogen and progesterone, when used to delay or suppress pubertal development in children for the purpose of assisting an individual with a gender transition.</text></clause><clause id="HD5CBE8E6753E4C56A0B843378F1101AE"><enum>(ix)</enum><header>Cross-sex hormones</header><text>The term <term>cross-sex hormones</term> means testosterone or other androgens given to biological females at doses which are profoundly larger or more potent than would normally occur naturally in healthy biological females, and estrogen given to biological males at doses which are profoundly larger or more potent than would normally occur naturally in healthy biological males.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HADCA9B3DDDFB49B282F8621B72FD0BBC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Minor child</header><text>The term <term>minor child</term> means an individual who has not attained age 18.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC1FB4EAD34C047829DEA55B2821CD4C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

