<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBC5F550A0F3B472B8AA8A3514F6C30AD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7380 IH: Cartel Haven Sanction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7380</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220404">April 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the transmission of remittances from the United States to Mexico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H896633738AEA43A29EBDE7EFA0E63A7A" style="OLC"><section id="HE0CCD5A71DDB4A589587C661FF0E843A" commented="no" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cartel Haven Sanction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H796718292D584282A6C1235BFA0DD656"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority to prohibit the transmission of remittances from the United States to Mexico</header><subsection id="H547ACBEB6F3C4FF7BAC15532BADFF5E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall prohibit the transmission of remittances from the United States to Mexico.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD570FAB10614799826C3E72AC2316C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This section shall terminate on the date on which a physical wall on the international border between the United States and Mexico has been constructed and is fully operational.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE2F221662EB94B2ABFB05B87A7FFB29D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Authority to impose sanctions against Mexican drug cartel and human trafficking organizations and use the proceeds to provide assistance to United States citizens</header><subsection id="H40871CBB8E0E4CB98532D9936EA331B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President is authorized to take such actions as may be necessary to use the amounts described in subsection (b) to provide student loan forgiveness, job training, and addiction recovery treatment services to United States citizens.</text></subsection><subsection id="H104C3486BF2E448397F96224BD510DB2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts described in this subsection are amounts derived from the liquidation or sales of assets of individuals described in subsection (c) if such assets are subject to United States jurisdiction and control by reason of the imposition of sanctions under any provision of United States law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE1E46C178AA464DA2CC94F15641B4F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Individuals described</header><text>The individuals described in this subsection are individuals who are associated with illegal drug cartel or human trafficking organizations operating in Mexico. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

