<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6A265ECCA824C9C98E2E63A82E951B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7320 IH: Restorative Practices in Schools Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7320</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To help local educational agencies replace zero-tolerance disciplinary policies and punitive discipline in elementary and secondary schools with restorative practices.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H112424A6D64645F7B23A3462122F170A" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA4818A0501984F2FAD2E6F1896918A3B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Restorative Practices in Schools Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9E18D9FFE93949CFB034C4A92F30ACC3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to help local educational agencies replace zero-tolerance disciplinary policies and punitive discipline in elementary and secondary schools with restorative practices that—</text><paragraph id="H98063C47FC83467291DAEE9EEFCA1317"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide an intentional approach to school safety and student well-being that addresses the needs of the whole child;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE77FECC68E9D4984B6015629C44A2945"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recognize student behavior as a result of underlying need, and childhood emotional and behavioral development;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8044B8111674B27B645309A3BD8F174"><enum>(3)</enum><text>build community and repair relationships while developing students’ proactive skills for conflict resolution, communication, problem-solving, and empathy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CA8EB92DE2947A69C45C51509675049"><enum>(4)</enum><text>reduce undesirable behavior; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F36C241CE4F4460925DD54B59CCB198"><enum>(5)</enum><text>promote relationship-centered schools and safe, inclusive learning environments with positive school climates.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HCB23820DAE73437A914222AB60946223"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H112692F99A4640578483AC0F37AC762E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA Terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>evidence-based</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>parent</term>, <term>professional development</term>, <term>school leader</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, <term>Secretary</term>, <term>specialized instructional support personnel</term>, and <term>other staff</term> have the meaning given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1296D32421F946388234E2AF5BA6EF8A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program personnel</header><text>The term <term>program personnel</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HEA3351D5C07B4478BB80E3BC0F875FA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any agent of a local educational agency, including an individual who is employed by a local educational agency, or who performs services for a local educational agency on a contractual basis, including—</text><clause id="H980CFF87DFF147D2B74C57D266019335"><enum>(i)</enum><text>school leaders;</text></clause><clause id="HBAF752135E96469AA24880FB1FA4BC9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>educators;</text></clause><clause id="H48BA0FF351D44F8183B4D38D2F17058C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>specialized instructional support personnel;</text></clause><clause id="HD8A098A89821415CA9F679DB15A901C2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>paraprofessionals; or</text></clause><clause id="HA2C0C56E72E04F958138A5DF676400F1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other staff; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC7D96B8FDFD4DDE81301837A84F87BD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school-based law enforcement officer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB86A83A6A43B4DEAB5713798692652B0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Restorative practices</header><text>The term <term>restorative practices</term> means evidence-based practices that—</text><subparagraph id="H5995C28E9B61409BB6D93C96B0E047EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acknowledge and honor the dignity of students;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D587EE368C492088F61623D4FD1544"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are proactive approaches that teach and build community, empathy, and accountability school-wide to reduce and discourage undesirable student behavior;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE47F963A4CDB48F5B14D9DF1AC60AF4F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve school climate, elevate students' voices, and strengthen all relationships in a school community; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9B1BA74FFA144B8913C77354689A499"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may include—</text><clause id="HA38E8DFBA45E45168C0593BE34AB3A57"><enum>(i)</enum><text>strategies such as restorative dialogue, informal conferencing, proactive circles, and responsive circles;</text></clause><clause id="H162CCD0E9E554FB8B1BA1A584EB88901"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reactive strategies that address conflicts, individual incidents, and classroom-wide issues; and</text></clause><clause id="HDBADC1F03AFE4EFF8A18DBA22ED9FA4A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>formal conferences, reintegration circles, and circles of support and accountability to cultivate empathy and repair harm; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15AEC120D67F43ACAE1C136065F326FE" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>do not include mediation or school-based mediation to address bullying, harassment, or other forms of discrimination. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB01DCFEFD38444ACBC4B04B70FEBA2F0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>School-based law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>school-based law enforcement officer</term> means any person, sworn or unsworn, who—</text><subparagraph id="H543B9A8D77F34E3EB81CC00CBDA044AC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is assigned by the employing law enforcement agency to a local educational agency or school, who is contracting with a local educational agency or school, or who is employed by a local educational agency or school; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4762DF0E406542C2830BBA393B111431" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H71D1827FD717426091AD00A18CC1D88F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has the power to detain, arrest, issue a citation, perform a custodial investigation, or refer a person to criminal or juvenile court; or</text></clause><clause id="HB7BE3D0D2D194D888A84ABAE528E5A73" commented="no" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is considered under State law to meet the definition of law enforcement; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66D7285D30E34D799FED15C0B909A5BF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes an individual referred to as a <quote>school resource officer</quote>, <quote>school safety agent</quote>, or a <quote>school police officer</quote>, if that individual meets the definition in subparagraphs (A) and (B). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C1EB22BF53B4D6D9DCE6875013C331B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>School to prison pipeline</header><text>The term <term>school to prison pipeline</term> means the use of discipline practices such as zero-tolerance policies that funnel students out of school and toward the juvenile legal and criminal legal systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EA83D4A53B042DA8B1A287252537CD8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subgroup of students</header><text>The term subgroup of students has the meaning given that term in section 1111(c)(2) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(c)(2)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H49656CCE07044F4BAD96CC0AA764B155"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grant program</header><subsection id="HAA4042A6B1F842BAA7ADDA51091D994F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to local educational agencies to enable those local educational agencies to implement and sustain restorative practices for elementary and secondary schools and to replace existing punitive models, in accordance with subsection (d). </text></subsection><subsection id="HFD0AE7ED82EB4BEBABAB655351774E16"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><paragraph id="H92497FE979B8401BBBF08340B920EBB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Local educational agencies desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCC0EE5FE9D81440D85315000EB6A2894"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information about—</text><clause id="H81C0F4D6932C49CCB1DF7A39DBA935FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of students served by that local educational agency who are in contact with the juvenile legal system at the time the application is submitted;</text></clause><clause id="H4BB4F9146C2D4C029EF2D72BB570DF11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of residents living in the area served by the local educational agency who are in contact with the legal justice system at the time the application is submitted;</text></clause><clause id="H8C8E4596216D4EE18FCE3C66E5FCEC08"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the percentage and number of residents living in the area served by the local educational agency who are admitted to correctional facilities each year;</text></clause><clause id="HE9E114F48B504B1F857CF024C2E68CB1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the percentage and number of residents living in the area served by the local educational agency who are on probation, parole, or any other form of community-based supervision at the time of the application; and</text></clause><clause id="HBDB970B75E3D41E29F62FFA4CA7DEAA9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the percentage or number of students served by the local educational agency who—</text><subclause id="HC689AB21493548278A53851ADE9363BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>received one or more in-school suspensions;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6658A7F93CFA428196D7760448F0EC91"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received one or more out-of-school suspensions;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3A16B2635E8240E7835D5CC0D860E4D5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>were expelled because of zero-tolerance policies;</text></subclause><subclause id="H25863DDD18B04F9DBC892F43112D3C13"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>were referred to a law enforcement agency or official; </text></subclause><subclause id="H8120966607AC4596A83CE40916911D59"><enum>(V)</enum><text>were arrested for school-related activity; or </text></subclause><subclause id="H03BC9EA5957249C88DE08AE201B66F42"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>received corporal punishment; </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E53095F4E684393BA73BD13D3AB265E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demographic information that shows evidence that the community served by the local educational agency is disproportionally impacted by the legal justice system or that marginalized subgroups in that community are disproportionally impacted by the legal justice system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1AD83CDDB2D45259FE5D403243D0025"><enum>(C)</enum><text>documentation of meaningful community engagement and stakeholder interest in establishing or expanding restorative practices at the local educational agency or schools served by the local educational agency, including engagement and interest of teachers’ unions and organizations, school leadership parent-teacher associations, student councils, and not less than 1 advocacy organization for each subgroup of students, and which may include other relevant groups;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6584FCCE5FF4FF3919ABFF2E24081E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a plan to implement evidence-based, restorative, equitable, and non-discriminatory school discipline practices that improve the climate of the local educational agency and that meet the requirements of subsection (c); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C4A388F38EE4A19B89F7500AE33B28D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number and percentage of exclusionary discipline practices implemented by the local educational agency, including suspensions and expulsions, as a whole and disaggregated by student subgroup, students experiencing homelessness, and students who are children and youth in foster care; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H82DD5B9F6C6345D88E82BB196B08B735"><enum>(F)</enum><text>an assurance that the local educational agency will meet the requirements described in subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1EA4A475B7649CA94043388979288B3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a description of whether the local educational agency meets the criteria described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (3). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BB553D8554F4099B2A7BF2107239FCF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to local educational agencies that—</text><subparagraph id="HE8E857F8084D41F380641BDA5E15B77A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve communities that have been disproportionately impacted by the juvenile and criminal legal systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C40E99816E442F599C15AB664EE062F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have disproportionally high rates of grade retention, suspensions, and expulsions for certain subgroups of students;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C426B56FD384DDC8EA0600DC8CB74ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serve students in an area that has a high concentration of residents in poverty, including local educational agencies that are in the highest quartile of local educational agencies in a ranking of all qualified local educational agencies in the State ranked in descending order by the number or percentage of children in each agency counted under section 1124(c) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6333">20 U.S.C. 6333(c)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H597056981BF44E158007A698C69D5F13"><enum>(D)</enum><text>serve students in a rural community and need additional staff to support the implementation of restorative practices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H710904EB3CB4475886441DBF46E9A953"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant applicant pools</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall evaluate applicants according to the following two distinct applicant pools:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF92CEB4EB2C541C9A9F4F80431F7CC28"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicants seeking to implement restorative practices in one or more schools served by the local educational agency for the first time.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H38613A0BFF0845C995F872069A64F911"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Applicants seeking to expand and sustain existing restorative practice programs in one or more schools served by the local educational agency or improve data collection systems under subsection (d)(4), as the case may be. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8696CEC4C56846219BC48E1FEEB47A11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for grant recipients</header><text>In order to receive a grant under this section a local educational agency shall submit an assurance to the Secretary as part of the application described in subsection (b) that the local educational agency will agree to—</text><paragraph id="HE187931A8B0F4658A309B1A3CD782CEE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hire a full-time employee (who shall not have academic teaching or administrative duties distinct from the responsibilities described in this paragraph and shall not be a law enforcement officer or a retired law enforcement officer) whose primary responsibility is to provide training, professional development, coaching, and oversight for restorative practices implementation in the local educational agency or schools served by the local educational agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E71DB45B0F24104BB138500F1E4A731"><enum>(2)</enum><text>fund ongoing restorative practices training, professional development, and on-site coaching for all program personnel, students, and interested parents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC34E77C0486247AEBA248BCA0C1A5E5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>eliminate—</text><subparagraph id="HA8BE1DC566A7438D9D442D91E98C9523"><enum>(A)</enum><text>zero-tolerance disciplinary policies at the local educational agency or at all elementary and secondary schools served by the local educational agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2DAA004DFB642D182945A6EC437F063"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the application of these policies to undesirable behavior to the greatest extent possible under State law;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DC282909FEC4D889F2D35721C4D5580"><enum>(4)</enum><text>adopt safety and discipline policies or codes of conduct that—</text><subparagraph id="H2163D3B552C94959A00D335F8F366F09"><enum>(A)</enum><text>emphasize ways of maintaining safety that minimize the involvement of law enforcement (including school-based law enforcement officers and including U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement), to the greatest extent that is practicable and permitted under applicable Federal, State, and local laws; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFACE968B0B794A5B87EC708DD05D71AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eliminate the use of exclusionary discipline policies, including suspensions and expulsions for undesirable student behavior to the greatest extent permitted by Federal, State, and local laws;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF19CC1D7850645019B9646B65CF5EBA5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>implement implicit bias, cultural competence, and anti-racist training for program personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB364E6264354ABB9518A42DA736C137"><enum>(6)</enum><text>establish policies that limit when law enforcement can be called into schools, including by—</text><subparagraph id="HB090A393B5ED41DA91C09A3F53E318B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognizing the local educational agency as the primary authority responsible for school climate and safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC32E71AA501E4A74B21C7FAED0F54639"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requiring that school discipline issues be handled by program personnel who are not school-based law enforcement officers, police, security officers, or other law enforcement, unless there is a real, immediate, specific, and credible threat of serious physical injury to a student, teacher, or other member of the school community; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H75DAC0336B7C412EB391FC53A1F152B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing that school administrators shall have final responsibility and jurisdiction over the building, the grounds, and all members of the school community, to the greatest extent permitted by law;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AC78685CECD4341A7AE638628541AFB"><enum>(7)</enum><text>prohibit the issuance of tickets, summonses, and referrals of students to the juvenile or criminal legal systems for all school disciplinary matters and school status offenses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC98F009ABFC54249A5765DB7EE504749"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide proper notice and a right of action or appeals procedures for students, parents, and guardians involved in school discipline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B24EB3058054E9B9419102F87F57DBB"><enum>(9)</enum><text>prohibit the use of metal detectors, facial recognition software, and other surveillance technology and approaches; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85650564C8A04AFBBC241E54D8494D6E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>prohibit the sharing of student data (personal and academic) with Federal, State, or local law enforcement, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, or other law enforcement, except as required by law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4BB92AF5178D46A1966B63DE5A59D5B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Uses of grant funds</header><text>A local educational agency shall use grant funds received under this section to support the implementation of restorative practices in elementary and secondary schools served by the local educational agency. Funds may be used to carry out one or more of the following activities: </text><paragraph id="H8EE75B9B26E54457A3CFC24EE8339A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Hiring additional full-time and part-time employees (including students and parents) to lead evidence-based, restorative practices at the district or school level.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0A01DE8A3AB49A3BA0558C632D16873"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Providing anti-racist, culturally competent, and linguistically responsive curriculum and material development and training to program personnel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46EEC95616B649B7BAEAFCA18B634AE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Providing trauma-informed or healing-centered engagement practice training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1D9BA28B6844F57804DEEE05B62122F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>If not already in place, developing data collection systems to accurately document behavior incidents as well as school responses to those incidents, such as restorative circles to support implementation of restorative practices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAF28A69F6BE40AD810A92721DA63634"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Offering robust integrated student supports, such as wraparound services and social services necessary to address the underlying causes of undesirable student behavior, including hiring specialized instructional support personnel and related service providers such as psychologists, counselors, nurses, social workers, paraprofessionals, conflict resolution staff, and advisors, in a manner that is in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="H9EF20D38F8444FFFB7F91FFBD04442AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence-based student-educator ratios; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H934DE264F22149C2BBE282B7B4325B5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individual education plan requirements of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H251BB288188A45AEAB046ADAEBC0088E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Promoting partnerships and local liaisons in order to coordinate with existing social and community-based services and providers to connect youth with trusted and established resources.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45FAC510DDE14391B7E95F7902BC80CF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Developing and implementing diversion programs for young people in their communities, such as—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HCBEEAD0A65D44974905733DB3424D94D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>truancy diversion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7BD24ED8FD7B46C4B81FC1F61CD720E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>truancy boards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H16BF9A55EB444EADA7434CFA58567F0A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>peer mediation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E5DDA2407E640ACAE5FCACC2F939A51"><enum>(D)</enum><text>alternative dispute resolution to reduce referrals to a court-designated worker; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD7564795911D46BCB8CA47135DE2F4F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>relationship-centered schools that support strong family and community engagement.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF6C573906EFA4AD094010D6BAF757747"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Providing training and professional development for program personnel to identify, de-escalate, and otherwise appropriately respond to student trauma and harm. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B781899196E407782193BD9FFBF0FFA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H639E379A22F549738EE85842A95C751C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>local educational agency requirements</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving a grant under this section, and each year thereafter, each local educational agency that receives a grant under this section shall provide to the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H49FDEFA49A364AC283A76BF14C33AA7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a written assurance that—</text><clause id="H878563BFC42E45BDB7E98376B09F12DF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the local educational agency or schools served by the local educational agency have been notified of and are in compliance with the requirements described under subsection (c);</text></clause><clause id="HCDE2C17ED6274EDAA4ABDF6DD4A7D754"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all program personnel of the local educational agency have received training with respect to such requirements;</text></clause><clause id="HB08029ED35E3408BB3821258337F2C05"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>parents of students enrolled in the local educational agency or served by such local educational agency have been notified of those requirements with respect to the local educational agency based on receipt of the grant; and</text></clause><clause id="HB19B2904CAE648AAA07CD4F61A99407E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the notification required under clause (iii) is publicly available on the website of the local educational agency; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C503ADF2DFF4B47990B2F4F831A52C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a school climate report, which shall be publicly available in an easily accessible format on a school or district website, that includes a description of—</text><clause id="H5F95062EE7314441A77CC1A8A1EEB72D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the policies and procedures of the local educational agency with respect exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in the local educational agency or schools served by the local educational agency;</text></clause><clause id="H36383A07002D4C20947136FFC44CCBCF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how the local educational agency plans to implement, is implementing, or has implemented restorative practices and other models to address student behavior and reduce the use of exclusionary and aversive discipline practices or interventions in the local educational agency or schools served by the local educational agency; </text></clause><clause id="H7CCF07D70D8340179EC6EE85504AE5E6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>efforts of the local educational agency to ensure all program personnel receive the supports and training necessary to implement restorative practices;</text></clause><clause id="H984A164E32994F54B58C5A76133FCB82"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>efforts of the local educational agency to ensure program personnel are implementing practices of anti-racism, cultural competence, and anti-bias to ensure the school environment is free from racial and other forms of harassment;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H57CB5AF3BC1B431B915083893ADA8154"><enum>(v)</enum><text>how the local educational agency has taken steps to ensure its restorative practices have centered on the needs of those who have been harmed by zero-tolerance disciplinary policies and punitive disciplinary practices;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H495C8720181D464BA0D8F1AE64F4FDBA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of students that are served by the local educational agency who engaged in some form of restorative practice during the reporting period and the kinds of restorative practices that were used, disaggregated and cross-tabulated based on race, gender, and disability status, and by category described under subsection (b)(1)(A)(v);</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0BC74F9F45D64625A254056FC271DFAA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the number of students that are served by the local educational agency that were subject to exclusionary discipline during the reporting period, which shall be disaggregated and cross-tabulated based on race, gender, and disability status; </text></clause><clause id="H2181EC84553043A6BE19209E40EC3306"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>a demonstration of continued engagement among students, parents, and other stakeholders; and</text></clause><clause id="H64C4DBC915C24EB7BA9457EF5B5A9E15"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a plan that articulates how the local educational agency will sustain the use of restorative practices after the grant period is concluded.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF375893F1D99465391494AFE9E86B78B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall study data collected from the grant program under this section and other relevant programs and use such data to submit, not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and not less than once every 1 year thereafter, to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and make publicly available, a report—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBFD9D8EFE0584E95A3D7FAAC2F569919"><enum>(A)</enum><text>summarizing the information from grantees as described under paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5CA87D6D25054B568C197366BBF36811"><enum>(B)</enum><text>highlighting strong examples of restorative practices in schools; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H2F32E4362F854E4688DB50B69B4455D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>informing guidance on school discipline that can dramatically reduce the number of children who are funneled into the school to prison pipeline; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9B99E6F408B4FD985B9E35097011C10"><enum>(D)</enum><text>containing recommendations about how schools can strengthen compliance with Federal civil rights laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HDA91F3257C0041379F5D3FCA211829DB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Accountability</header><text>If the Secretary determines that an entity has misused funds or failed to comply with program requirements, the Secretary may withhold funds until an entity comes into compliance, in accordance with part D of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1234">20 U.S.C. 1234 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="HC3D5D5DA91E24DBDA6131B29C52D62E1"><enum>5.</enum><header>Study of restorative practices</header><subsection id="HA948BEABCB964A4CBEF87EE25557BDCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the school to prison pipeline for the purposes of—</text><paragraph id="H0876C7D14AD0436DB0C5A375DC54EF27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifying evidence-based interventions to improve student well-being and improve school climate, including restorative practices; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63F471190D864C138F93144BFD3C8F60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examining the role of State and local legal, and education systems in exacerbating disparities among students (based on race, sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity), socioeconomic status, and disability status), including the disproportionate involvement of certain students in the legal system.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15FBA122CED34D809EA4DA93EFD40CA2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall initiate the study under subsection (a), which may include—</text><paragraph id="HF50CCB725C3B46268491036F6AB50FF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examining school discipline policies that are alternatives to exclusionary discipline practices, that include—</text><subparagraph id="H91613156A8BC4ECCBC8337F8759C76F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the models for professional development and family engagement in local educational agencies or States that have adopted and effectively implemented such policies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC22F500BD5E4C14A5E67A5A9B7266EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a review of the research on the impact that such policies may have on student achievement, disproportionate discipline rates, and student well-being; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H299A81A3FBCB4DBFB4C289B9346F037A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the measurement tools used to collect, analyze, and respond to data related to student discipline, school climate, and student well-being after such polices have been implemented;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAD54970DBEC49F88A9C0F73E217B843"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examining the consequences that disparities in school discipline policies may have on affected students, including impacts on learning loss and school completion rates, families, and local communities, including increasing trauma and other risk factors associated with the school to prison pipeline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F98325222014717BD1357D6D60BF64B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifying harmful education and public safety policies that direct more students into the justice system and examples of efforts to disrupt such policies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H171F9B5840F247228501E17EF60D3BC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>elevating public health oriented approaches to improving student well-being and school climate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8861533660A642BD9D6403369D38CC32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon the conclusion of the study under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall prepare and submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives, and the Department of Education a report regarding the study and the conclusions and recommendations generated from the study.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

