<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H056E676497324EA8A2C86F9948371892" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7192 IH: Diagnostic Device Advisory Committee Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7192</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220321">March 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a panel on the real world impact of diagnostic medical devices, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H534E0858330043B5B0961C98BAEE6F40" style="OLC"><section id="H8FF1BEEC0F1940D3B70F9D75C294C465" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Diagnostic Device Advisory Committee Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H784DD979FE3D464EB0B8554D540C50E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Real World Impact of Medical Devices Panel</header><subsection id="HC47294C381CD4648A8A0E5F679B1CA84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, amend the charter of the Medical Devices Advisory Committee (or successor advisory committee) to establish a panel of experts on diagnostic medical device products for the purpose of providing advice to the Secretary in connection with the real world impact of the clearance, classification, approval, and authorization of devices, including diagnostic devices, under sections 510(k), 513(f), 515, and 564 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(k)</external-xref>, 360c(f), 360e, and 360bbb–3) to be known as the Real World Impact of Medical Devices Panel (referred to in this section as the <quote>Panel</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD49A0C841A354CF6A3D49165DB6354BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Advisory Committee Act shall apply to the Panel. </text></subsection><subsection id="HB5978552A95B4E9F976F5FB8B614929F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H2B87BCD75FEA487AB64F86634E2CF838"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Panel shall consist of 15 members, including the Chair. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF14CC153CBC4429F848626EF4D0436AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">11 members of the Panel shall be voting members. Of the remaining 4 members of the Panel—</text><subparagraph id="H99ECE0A35CB84F0585CEFD2098A85845"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 shall be a representative of consumer interests;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B781D1BBC04432AA73A8A8C0FB86018"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 shall be a representative of the interests of the device manufacturing industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DB716B85D8B4157A4A14E86ABC29231"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 shall be public health or population health-specific representatives. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C5F38805EC745238D6521C4C04954DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The members of the Panel specified in subparagraphs (A) through (C) of paragraph (2) shall be selected by the Secretary and shall be invited to serve for rotating terms of such duration as specified by the Secretary, except that any member appointed to fill a vacancy for an unexpired term shall be appointed for the remainder of that term. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H255FE6A34C204CBF8EFBBD5BF7E2DF4C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Panel shall provide to the Secretary—</text><paragraph id="HF4EC68BDDF024C18989952DAFD81C222"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advice and recommendations on the real world impact of the clearance, classification, approval, and authorization of devices, including diagnostic devices, under sections 510(k), 513(f), 515, and 564 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(k)</external-xref>, 360c(f), 360e, and 360bbb–3), including the impact of such devices on rural, underserved, or minority populations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DF025565596435D8BA430A786E35A34"><enum>(2)</enum><text>register comments about the negative and positive impacts of such devices on the United States population, the risk assessment posed by the use of such devices, and the need such devices would fill.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE9295F95453946CBA0F2BED713292D9F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consideration of recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, and any other applicable official shall, in making any final decisions, or amending existing decisions with respect to the clearance, classification, approval, and authorization of devices, including diagnostic devices, under sections 510(k), 513(f), 515, and 564 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/360">21 U.S.C. 360(k)</external-xref>, 360c(f), 360e, and 360bbb–3), take comments received from the Panel under advisement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2ABB95B8B29C474E84ADEE96E9B5A92C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="HF5DA79173D614B4EB83ED013F7B0C5D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Panel shall hold at least 1 meeting each year, at the call of the Chair.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBF7285D445E46709D711E4D11AC31DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recordings available</header><text>Recordings of the meetings of the Panel shall be available on the public website of the Food and Drug Administration. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

