<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H65C9B462CFB5484CB7DF97AC1BF360F3">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8200 IH: Capital Lending and Investment for Marijuana Businesses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8200</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220623">June 23, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend any applicable Federal law to permit access to community development, small business, minority development, and any other public or private financial capital sources for investment in and financing of cannabis-related legitimate businesses, and to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to create a safe harbor for national securities exchanges to list the securities of issuers that are cannabis-related legitimate businesses.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H9F5AD3AA3D684FAA8BECC576483468BF">
<section id="HDEBA5B8D511B41F6B529674838C01A4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Capital Lending and Investment for Marijuana Businesses Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLIMB Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAE4EFC13A15A4576A3A1D246326415AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Permitting access to community development, small business, minority development, and financial institution capital for investment in and financing of cannabis-related legitimate businesses and their service providers</header> <subsection id="HCFAE89C1559745A48F3A83F2DAED24D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proscription Against Federal Agency Action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No agency of the Federal Government shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HC76B8346AC9841F5A7AF1B6A8A78B2A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>initiate or otherwise support bringing civil, criminal, regulatory or administrative actions that would disqualify any business person or governmental authority from holding or obtaining any charter, license, registration, or official status, from maintaining, applying for or receiving funding, appropriations, grants, contracts, or other forms of monetary or non-monetary assistance from a governmental authority, or from marketing, offering, or selling any security, banking, or insurance or other financial services product, because such business or person—</text> <subparagraph id="H95BC405F346541D298F2132C6F315B02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides business assistance to a cannabis-related legitimate business or service provider; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD5279F427379464EAA103CB0F637E328"><enum>(B)</enum><text>receives cash or other compensation for providing business assistance to a cannabis-related legitimate business or service provider which cash or other compensation is generated from or is proceeds of the business operations of a cannabis-related legitimate business or service provider.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDB588C3070A34E6C9D319902FD448BFB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header> <paragraph id="H7A0E5F880AAE47688B8788FB435DE86D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>business assistance</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H42DFF911EF30484B8E653B15B4AAABC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provision of financial services including but not by way of limitation, commercial banking, deposit-taking, trust services, capital raising, lending, brokerage, prime brokerage, securities finance services, investment banking, custody services, credit card services, money transfer services, securities underwriting and investment advisory services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3289A09B81B4B6C9D5702FE4381B7A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sale of insurance or surety products;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44373E9C05914E7486A349A8B3D49B81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing debt or equity capital and the receipt of dividends, interest, or distributions of that capital;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EBA972B530B4770AED1FCC12645B598"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provision or accounting services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H53FA871CC8AA4A7EBCD40984D6BDDBB4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>sale, leasing, or renting of real estate;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3E213193F3944B58BAA1E0214AADD25"><enum>(F)</enum><text>provision of equipment, parts, substances or testing services needed to produce marijuana, hemp or extracts therefrom and to comply with the law, rules and regulations for testing in the applicable U.S. State, commonwealth, Washington, DC, Indian Tribe, or U.S. Territory;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H16E97BCE66754617A96BD58B5FAE321D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>provision of advertising or marketing services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3FB6F5601B7F468BBA337A6DF68E7490"><enum>(H)</enum><text>provision of management consulting services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF0AA5A2F64E142E18B798FB52042951D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provision of legal services or compliance services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7148D56057A145E091034625A156A39E"><enum>(J)</enum><text>provision of information technology, software and communications services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9D1B599D1102491E886787FC52B0E142"><enum>(K)</enum><text>provision of packaging, transportation, or other logistics services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBF3BC0691F844E0FB19351CEAFD95EAC"><enum>(L)</enum><text>underwriting, dealing, placement or public distribution of securities issued by a cannabis-related legitimate business, including the listing of any such securities on any exchange or trading venue, or any provision of services related to the foregoing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38E8CA81AD86407D8212F90A4BDD327A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Governmental authority</header><text>The term <term>governmental authority</term> means any Federal, State, municipal, national, local, tribal, or other governmental department, court, commission, board, bureau, agency, or instrumentality or political subdivision thereof, or any entity or officer exercising executive, legislative, or judicial, regulatory or adminis-trative functions of or pertaining to any government or any court, in each case, whether of the United States or a State, territory or possession thereof, a foreign sovereign entity or country or jurisdiction or the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H36D4FFECADBC4F24A6DC1C951B799B34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual, a partnership, a corporation, a limited liability company, a business trust, a joint stock company, a trust, an unincorporated association, a joint venture, a governmental authority, or any other entity of whatever nature.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H577D1BAA8EBF426F8B13376667A3FDF3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Safe harbor for national securities exchanges</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78f">15 U.S.C. 78f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE9C76A8C8F9843B2BF7B7B5740F3455E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H3F665AA08B1C46D5B9884C5E2FC8B013"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Safe harbor for cannabis-Related legitimate businesses and service providers</header> <paragraph id="HE2DE835F38724341B95164B696CCA534"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5BB7E67CA86C454598CA19AB0F44FA90"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Cannabis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cannabis</term> has the meaning given the term <term>marihuana</term> in section 102 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/802">21 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0DD6F3A660EE43A7A6E1C6DD02F39FCD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cannabis product</header><text>The term <term>cannabis product</term> means any article that contains cannabis, including an article that is a concentrate, an edible, a tincture, a cannabis-infused product, or a topical.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3A47D4D3152040C5A4B52B8FF3F40443"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Cannabis-related legitimate business</header><text>The term <term>cannabis-related legitimate business</term> means an issuer that—</text> <clause id="H4EA5BF04174B40A79CD9FF724E0E1B6F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>initiates, engages, or participates in any business or organized activity that involves cannabis or cannabis products, including cultivating, warehousing, producing, manufacturing, processing, selling, transporting, displaying, dispensing, distributing, or purchasing cannabis or cannabis products; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H27E73279899F4D96853B0F202D851412"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>engages in the activity described in clause (i) pursuant to a law established by a State or a political subdivision of a State, as determined by that State or political subdivision.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBEDDCA43C6BF468F9FB5D2EC51FD43EC"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Market participant</header><text>The term <term>market participant</term> means any broker dealer, underwriter, clearing agency or clearinghouse, securities depository, credit rating agency, alternative trading system, investment adviser, self-regulatory organization, or transfer agent.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA076B4CD7B9F45CF94631C9510B095C5"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Service provider</header><text>The term <term>service provider</term> means—</text> <clause id="H2A32CC0F34354807A9A85CF97BE33DD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an issuer that—</text>
<subclause id="H84D9A0BB714C4A788BE79C3C89850B0A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>sells or otherwise provides goods or services to a cannabis-related legitimate business; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3FF1BB72BB19404FA1C2B9E404927265"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provides any business service relating to cannabis or cannabis product, including without limitation—</text>
<item id="H86EEFD9AAF934481B736074F89A9B5D9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>legal, compliance, or accounting services;</text></item> <item id="H420ACD376062462A8BA0333FE3B5F721"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>sale, leasing, or renting of real estate or equipment;</text></item>
<item id="H9FEC668A0F5E45B99E138038F6F9010A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>provision of parts, substances, or testing services needed to produce marijuana, hemp, or extracts therefrom and to comply with the law, rules, and regulations for testing in the applicable U.S. State, commonwealth, Washington, DC, Indian Tribe, or U.S. Territory;</text></item> <item id="H1F542403FC7D4D0BA206634F6291A4C0"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>advertising or marketing services;</text></item>
<item id="HE8F2D9CE1B22402A94E578FC36A4B83C"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>management consulting services;</text></item> <item id="HE33B9B38F2534C8A95EA4B47353A893C"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>information technology, software, and communications services; and</text></item>
<item id="H57E0464228054C619C65AD30B86997CA"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>packaging, transportation, or other logistics services; and</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE9718C203F0445D8AA3EE0A8F9D95D44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is not a cannabis-related legitimate business.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H513F1A93A57B4282AA5E676A60EB196C"><enum>(F)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, and each of the territories and possessions of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03C64AB169B84356BDF2F137CA161952"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header><text>Notwithstanding section 32 of this Act, the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/801">21 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other Federal law, it shall not be unlawful for a national securities exchange registered pursuant to subsection (a) or any market participant to have listed, list, or intend to list, or permits the trading, or facilitates the offering, listing, or trading on a national securities exchange, of the securities of a cannabis-related legitimate business or a service provider.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H509384BAA74A467EAA2E5157A923EB64"><enum>4.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and the amendment made in section 2 shall take effect 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

