<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD03D334528044E9F8EB08DACAFA6261A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7422 IH: Medical Records Access Fairness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7422</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220406">April 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the HITECH Act to allow an individual to obtain a copy of such individual’s protected health information at no cost unless certain circumstances apply, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA2959D4C3E540CA98B21610CA5FD48A" style="OLC"><section id="HACF5D5F15A044B34BB4D786E2A3A6960" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Records Access Fairness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA2913EA4C41040A686D7791563AB06E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Access of individuals to protected health information at no cost unless certain circumstances apply</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 13405 of the HITECH Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17935">42 U.S.C. 17935</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAA618A7BAC2E4E98B36800F4C39FDEE4" style="OLC"><subsection id="HA97E9C36167D457DAF317C459F4E0C55"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Access of individuals to protected health information at no cost unless certain circumstances apply</header><paragraph id="H929A5C8EF1C948B59C9BC23919894EF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access of individuals to protected health information at no cost unless certain circumstances apply</header><subparagraph id="H048C5387CDAC42168C53B56D5A62ED4A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing an individual (and, if the individual expressly requests, a health care provider or a family caregiver) with access to a copy of such individual’s protected health information (or a summary or explanation of such information) in accordance with section 164.524 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations, a health care provider may only impose a fee on such individual if the individual is requesting—</text><clause id="HCF53262DDBC64A23B8F817C7887A3480"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a duplicate copy (or summary or explanation) of protected health information that was previously provided to such individual in the same calendar year of the request; or</text></clause><clause id="H8B5C4864EC694A08AA71D47F25218D2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a non-electronic copy (or summary or explanation) of protected health information that the health care provider has made accessible for the individual, at no cost, on an online portal of the health care provider.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H183C65E418FF43EE9DDEDD2CF16A549F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Copies transmitted to other health care providers</header><text>In the case of an individual who expressly requests a health care provider to transmit to another health care provider a copy of such individual’s protected health information (or a summary or explanation of such information), such transmitting provider may transmit such copy (or summary or explanation) in any form and format to the extent that such form and format is readily usable by such receiving provider.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H919D5F51A4504E7DAFD36CB059ADDD95"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed as requiring a health care provider to provide, at no cost, a copy of an individual’s protected health information (or a summary or explanation of such information) to any attorney of such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1CF98A39A2614C488F9B31660877574F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than six months after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall promulgate and amend regulations as necessary to implement the requirements described in this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H610C87C0664846E0BEB37493F3A21E90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This subsection shall apply with respect to requests for access to protected health information made on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

