<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC774AD8C88C44A49B83E34F3CAE4661A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>95 HR 6751 IH: Avi Kwa Ame National Monument Establishment Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6751</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Avi Kwa Ame National Monument in the State of Nevada, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0FEDA2912618429A8EDE28AD5AB57BF3" style="OLC"><section id="H9FB1C51A99D74449AD21024A42E50317" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Avi Kwa Ame National Monument Establishment Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H53840E525002462A95237BAECFECE591"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H4947322CFE78433A8793FF54E3DA6561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal public lands in southernmost Nevada comprise a nationally significant cultural and natural landscape.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC33F9889E9DC4B6292E58BD6155201CD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These lands are considered sacred by numerous Indian Tribes, and the lands are tied to the Indian Tribes’ creation, cosmology, and well-being, containing numerous cultural sites and objects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BF997E768C946AFB4A51B6805BF0CD8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Avi Kwa Ame, or Spirit Mountain, located on the eastern edge of the proposed monument, is designated a Traditional Cultural Property on the National Register of Historic Places in recognition of its religious and cultural importance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEDE6B46D6444CA7951C2D64C2A29867"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The lands showcase the progression of human history in the Eastern Mojave Desert, a literal crossroads of the American West. There are significant elements of Native American, Western-American, and Mining History, including the historic Mojave Trail/Road, originally used by Mojave and other Native Americans to transport goods from the southwest to trade with the Chumash and other coastal Tribes and later used in Western expansion, as well as the historic Walking Box Ranch which figures prominently in the history of movie making in America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C6BC746B47546439932293D3B7DE2F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The lands contain several prominent geological features, such as the volcanic Highland Range within the northern section of the Avi Kwa Ame landscape, which is about 10 miles long and remarkably rugged and ragged. The multicolored volcanic peaks, several thousand feet in elevation, tower above the surrounding valley and are remarkably scenic and are a designated Crucial Bighorn Sheep Habitat area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H704C587ABFD54CFA99F53664BD86C2F5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The lands are a rare biological hotspot that contain intact ecosystems, Joshua tree forests, outstanding wildlife habitat, and essential wildlife migration corridors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1A81ECF706F47D4AA09C9420AE6D02A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The remote nature of the area protects the ability to enjoy increasingly rare natural quiet and dark night sky and solitude.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3966A8E6E3FF44CB8BA48E171FA25300"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The lands provide important recreational opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A1B8D8238D74F609FC8327CD070A9C3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Establishing the Federal public lands within the Avi Kwa Ame landscape as a national monument will permanently protect these natural and cultural resources for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1E9AB8AC9AE44FA9AB70DBC5E5AA1DE4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H52A22169E9A9477E84D3D90531C5CFB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Council</term> means the Avi Kwa Ame National Monument Advisory Council established under section 5(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B46D7E87FF44F78BCA56CB886931768"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B9BC87196EB426B8FEB543E7C3EFB21"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the management plan prepared under section 4(d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD84DC6D9A1074BEF96F5A45E21C83FBA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Map</header><text>The term <term>Map</term> means the map entitled <quote>Avi Kwa Ame National Monument</quote> and dated February 1, 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ABD511BFE3F452CA52BB710E34C1B61"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Monument</header><text>The term <term>Monument</term> means the Avi Kwa Ame National Monument established by section 4(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9E2A20C3F094DDC85A7A203511F1163"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H447041B5F19848639483DE2826B159C0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Nevada.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF05A21E04DFA4421913E9D00B8C53382"><enum>4.</enum><header>Avi Kwa Ame National Monument</header><subsection id="H09E95C81EC424841BEBDE0C52F102806"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there is established the Avi Kwa Ame National Monument in the State, consisting of approximately 445,000 acres of Federal land administered by the Bureau of Land Management, as generally depicted on the Map.</text></subsection><subsection id="H73D5E7EF57CD4C0C8F70641EB02C6A2A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purpose of the Monument is to conserve, protect, and enhance for the benefit and enjoyment of present and future generations the cultural, ecological, scenic, wildlife, recreational, dark sky, historical, natural, educational, and scientific resources of the Monument.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6854CB095B674ADB8D7843CE4C91E6F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management</header><paragraph id="H1936E9777AE74CDD98DE7E00B2EFFA8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall manage the Monument—</text><subparagraph id="H72B61E2E3B144D3C8BEE08777A14BF28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a manner that conserves, protects, and enhances the resources of the Monument;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0372552019A4456FA5AB0958D75B4712"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text><clause id="HBC7F8914A04E41D1A0C4DC3CE504C8F5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H7936455D75244DD1984EDD969117F41E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H93FC8F3CA6A14930936BD82C8F7B0293"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE35ABD6DFE44F339D7FABCF6129639F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as a component of the National Landscape Conservation System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA620352DCB9C497CA51C62DB22146853"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header><text>The Secretary shall only allow uses of the Monument that the Secretary determines would further the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H128E5EA4FDCB4612A90843D87128D6A8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Native American access and use</header><subparagraph id="H29E1077C726846E282CD26DBC17545CE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Access</header><text>To the extent practicable, the Secretary shall ensure access to the Monument by members of an Indian Tribe for traditional cultural purposes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB3934A3F874B18869D01EDE2EC72D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use</header><clause id="H06C7052F3D984E4696E1059B19AC6FE0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In implementing this subsection, the Secretary, upon the request of an Indian Tribe, may temporarily close to the general public use of one or more specific portions of the Monument in order to protect the privacy of traditional cultural activities in such areas by members of the Indian Tribe.</text></clause><clause id="HD2BAB3B76EF14CBAA494DACD91191DE3"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Any such closure shall be made to affect the smallest area practicable for the minimum period necessary for such purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF007D4225374134A817636629984D26"><enum>(C)</enum><header>American Indian religious freedom</header><text>The access and use provided under this paragraph shall be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>), commonly referred to as the American Indian Religious Freedom Act, and, as applicable, the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5CB64A297CC49AF821F05AAFF671F8C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles</header><subparagraph id="H641FC094ACA14E63B2D31652686A8EFA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except in cases in which motorized vehicles are needed for administrative purposes, or to respond to an emergency, the use of motorized vehicles in the Monument shall be permitted only on roads designated by the management plan required by subsection (d) for the use of motorized vehicles.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D9068F0CBB643209C7CE04C977662D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Interim management</header><text>Until the completion of the management plan, the use of motorized vehicles in the Monument shall be permitted in accordance with the applicable land use plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6290E918C9D342F9A69ADC90A83D8E33"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>The grazing of livestock in the Monument, where established before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be permitted to continue—</text><subparagraph id="HD06E9834304A4E2E83001485D2AF6A69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to—</text><clause id="HA40A41B1C5BA457DA57D930A04B53092"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary considers necessary; and</text></clause><clause id="H45A8C3CB089D4CCA834166EC49A61C46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applicable law (including regulations); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C638ECE74D640C7A8551BB9A0C2DAE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44B98AD579144A31B9AC036BA7EDEED5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Wildlife water projects</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the State, may authorize wildlife water projects (including guzzlers) within the Monument.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2641A0C56174B029F4570CE448036D5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Hunting, fishing and trapping</header><subparagraph id="H893F61D225AE4C34A3689478F8495AA8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the Secretary shall allow hunting, fishing, and trapping on land and water within the Monument in accordance with applicable Federal and State law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0DF89BC4BE72479F8015BD1DE782D960"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Administrative exceptions</header><text>The Secretary may designate areas in which, and establish limited periods during which, no hunting, fishing, or trapping shall be allowed under subparagraph (A) for reasons of public safety, administration, or compliance with applicable law.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC3F1B00510D4189A7655EBE91647D8F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Agency agreement</header><text>Except in an emergency, regulations closing areas within the Monument to hunting, fishing, or trapping under this paragraph shall be made in consultation with the appropriate agency of the State having responsibility for fish and wildlife administration.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7C83496E36A4123B307E27C3D60E903"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects any jurisdiction or responsibility of the State with respect to fish and wildlife in the Monument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD526EE75B3E94289B77EF206FF42A36B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management plan</header><paragraph id="H30CFA28BB12C4C91AA61A0FF86D66A09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act and in accordance with paragraph (2), the Secretary shall develop a comprehensive plan for the long-term management of the Monument.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD50F5969999A4F91AE8B377CEE0E8625"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In developing the management plan, the Secretary shall consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H7BF4E0486F214765A3ADD680460981CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other Federal land management agencies in the area, including the National Park Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F6DBB6889A84D8798F354BCEA5748C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>appropriate State, Tribal, and local governmental entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0994F2C3AC94BDD9848686E02F906DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>members of the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE308DCC3A92D401F9F934625BBCA2FA1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incorporation of plans</header><text>In developing the management plan, to the extent consistent with this Act, the Secretary may incorporate any provision of an applicable land and resource management plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8E85DA285D144A88A54E672CC5BB31E9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired land and interests</header><text>Any land or interest in land within the boundary of the Monument that is acquired by the United States shall—</text><paragraph id="H41433DDBCF5F4C18ABD0C4EF4DF02690"><enum>(1)</enum><text>become part of the Monument;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DCCB23CC2164CA89AC595388C3BB458"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be withdrawn in accordance with subsection (f); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0F21CC0A33B457CA0EA30DCCA2A4661"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be managed in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="H9C00E760449242C9896CC87247B0FE5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94FB08472D664735B326C52291BD7D92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE76127FAD1F4E4F9A40229290289BA0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable law (including regulations).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCEAE3B9159C74468BBC3D77EF4D96B81"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all Federal land located in the Monument is withdrawn from—</text><paragraph id="H0D30309882F146818924C6D45E57C296"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C3D1D0F4738435E93A57999BFDDE76E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patenting under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67BFD8735A1A4FD4AEC93C1B348CBAAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H939187AF704445BDAF3949D7859DA264"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Easements and rights-of-Way</header><paragraph id="H91454BFD01D0493094CF295510834582"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No new easements or rights-of-way shall be conveyed on Federal lands within the Monument after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17BB79EB916B4548A12D7B94067CD069"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes the Secretary from renewing easements or rights-of-way in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act within the Monument in accordance with this Act and applicable law (including regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2449DFD354A4520B2660989102D1093"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Military, law enforcement, and emergency overflights</header><text>Nothing in this section precludes—</text><paragraph id="H3CA096180CAB41E9AB8CD96D71A5728E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>low-level overflights of military, law enforcement, or emergency medical services aircraft over the Monument;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F8CA2918D5344408BFEFC8D27205315"><enum>(2)</enum><text>flight testing and evaluation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C7318EC7BB14E09A248A80B47C58052"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the use or establishment of military, law enforcement, or emergency medical services flight training routes over the Monument.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H175E1837EBF74DF9BA0A60D6C1CBFB26"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Native American rights and uses</header><paragraph id="HB48BC40770C244C698D87FD65EDF8D07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section alters, modifies, enlarges, diminishes, or abrogates the treaty rights of any Indian Tribe, including off-reservation reserved rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A89A7E0C99146DFB8A045C7153A4FFE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall consult with interested Indian Tribes—</text><subparagraph id="H47A7CA4512574622BAD8A32B7D2E7C5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in developing and carrying out the management plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDE89E13C1CF4D089FE53B374DF1E2FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing access under subsection (c)(3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H516DDF53896C4F04B019703B5C1A90F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to determine whether to charter an advisory committee or otherwise formalize government-to-government collaboration on the management of the Monument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H15999558FD62455CB55559B4AB7C852C"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Map; legal description</header><paragraph id="HE136A8CF8BBF49B8BC60F80549393BB9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare a map and legal description of the Monument.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66852C57F1524D6C9DFDF5E1DE61AED3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corrections</header><text>The map and legal description submitted under paragraph (1) shall have the same force and effect as if included in this subtitle, except that the Secretary may correct any clerical or typographical errors in the legal description and the map.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D5223ABF1B64585B11FDB3976C65C7E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conflict between map and legal description</header><text>In the case of a conflict between the map and the legal description, the map shall control.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5F8BB51BFC649E5BC6D46FE5F2D2B98"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Availability of map and legal description</header><text>Copies of the map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H21325C01F0D043D5B426DFB61C1338AE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Avi Kwa Ame National Monument Advisory Council</header><subsection id="HC3691CDF9CF846CDA4D18A5062A54EEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish an advisory council to be known as the <quote>Avi Kwa Ame National Monument Advisory Council</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5EF66718D5D64B61879EDFCE979020C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7CD46CBDDFB24EEBA96C397BB6C05A2B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>The Advisory Council shall be subject to—</text><paragraph id="HC3DE89836C33416583213F099A3D2F70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73FE050311CF434882A861C2A100974D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20FDB8C74B9C4993A5BC6502F1CFF724"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Members</header><paragraph id="HE11AC6DE7B384D678A1869E6EEFD7F66"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Council shall include 11 members to be appointed by the Secretary, of whom, to the extent practicable—</text><subparagraph id="H47C191E6D9094F97901ABD41BE19F14B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 member shall be appointed after considering the recommendations of the Boulder City, Nevada, City Council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEA72F5F274E4F89A70B4D1CEBA98874"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 member shall be appointed after considering the recommendations of the Searchlight, Nevada, Town Advisory Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H753762DFFD884248A09434FC30DC8254"><enum>(C)</enum><text>1 member shall be appointed after considering the recommendations of the Laughlin, Nevada, Town Advisory Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE69A4108FD784DBAA8AD381A6127D4D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>6 members shall be appointed to represent Indian Tribes with a historical connection to the land within the Monument; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A957B533ADB468CBCF904CBB9D460FB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>2 at-large members from the County shall be appointed after considering the recommendations of the County Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D239DB55C9B449B96223BF92498024C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special appointment considerations</header><text>The at-large members appointed under paragraph (1)(E) shall have backgrounds that reflect—</text><subparagraph id="HBDB926E8F052407CB51B1F893323F65C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the purposes for which the Monument was established; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E241E4C2A95415586E3D7942F62DD1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the interests of persons affected by the planning and management of the Monument.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H987345C30EE84760BFB170BC8E5EA983"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that the membership of the Advisory Council is fairly balanced in terms of the points of view represented and the functions to be performed by the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D6A2F19F3AE4385A3A089C0D87596D8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Initial appointment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall appoint the initial members of the Advisory Council in accordance with paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C63E56FE5DE4E4DBF88BA978E31573F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties of the advisory council</header><text>The Advisory Council shall advise the Secretary with respect to the preparation and implementation of the management plan, including budgetary matters relating to the Monument.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDB29BA549DAA4CA3A931C5609E59A53A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>Members of the Advisory Council shall receive no compensation for serving on the Advisory Council.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFDEBC1966D141ACA0B7455498A255E7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><paragraph id="H8877BF89739044B7BFA28B60A68334ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Advisory Council shall elect a Chairperson from among the members of the Advisory Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H821020F6086A4DC68773B331FE1B49AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of the Chairperson shall be 3 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB75009C468D4DF3A86E9C0F1549EBA7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Term of members</header><paragraph id="HECC27A710E56402CA601D74598677C6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term of a member of the Advisory Council shall be 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD1D98B1998C43DD9093A196782BEB73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Successors</header><text>Notwithstanding the expiration of a 3-year term of a member of the Advisory Council, a member may continue to serve on the Advisory Council until a successor is appointed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC9C5554ABD974BE68CD0F991096F60E6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><paragraph id="HCB1BD50A2A334E2697842707750D5610"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vacancy on the Advisory Council shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B7083F642CA46B191B1A825E1504ADF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment for remainder of term</header><text>A member appointed to fill a vacancy on the Advisory Council shall serve for the remainder of the term for which the predecessor was appointed.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC2522A58F17648EDAA5A98553D1DAA9E"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Advisory Council shall terminate not later than 3 years after the date on which the final version of the management plan is published.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB64C06178DE14BBDA6D74F0196263DE4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Relationship to Clark County Multi-Species Habitat Conservation Plan</header><subsection id="H2392EDCA9D5546ED9B0114B1649B0126"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits, alters, modifies, or amends the Clark County Multi-Species Habitat Conservation Plan with respect to the Monument.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5EB40E5A4AE7453CA6A5A525B9F49D26"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conservation management areas</header><text>The Secretary may, in accordance with the Clark County Multi-Species Habitat Conservation Plan (including amendments to the plan) and applicable law, credit the acreage of Federal land within the Monument as Conservation Management Areas under the plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBDADEBC92B084E168DB5CB345894AE3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>In developing the management plan, to the extent consistent with this section, the Secretary may incorporate any provision of the Clark County Multi-Species Habitat Conservation Plan.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA3833D236F184EAFA8F70246E08D8872"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transfer of bureau of reclamation parcels</header><subsection id="H7D9FB57450EC4112A5118658C688109C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Transfer of parcels</header><text>The Secretary shall transfer administrative jurisdiction of any Bureau of Reclamation land within the Monument to the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD738DB2482D745BEBA227AF3AA02FFE6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Map and legal description</header><paragraph id="H37C00CB565CD47299681C4D290B8C0D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall finalize the legal description of the land being transferred to the Bureau of Land Management under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BAA71F9EF0B40A5B1BBB15E0160457C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minor errors</header><text>The Secretary may correct any minor error in—</text><subparagraph id="HD77A8F81BBCC4B588D24952DB15C0EAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Map; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01BB1EAD1FE14577BDC61A83FEF91573"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the legal description.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BA6AA1AFA6040CEBBE273A314D9B89D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Map and legal description shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the Bureau of Land Management and the Bureau of Reclamation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

