<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00762CED75D0442CBEF3448263F1E773" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9223 IH: Reviewing the Effects of Programs, Orders, and Rules with Thorough Study Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9223</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221021">October 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000687">Mr. Mfume</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require analyses of the impact of Government rules, programs, and policies on poverty and racial inequity, including the racial wealth gap, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1578BC14DCC4421B3E52D6FC8AB0477" style="OLC"><section id="HAE2390EFFBF94731B0E92E7A02F351DF" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reviewing the Effects of Programs, Orders, and Rules with Thorough Study Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REPORTS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H49EBC26D025F4EA18B88BD0C07E6AB78"><enum>2.</enum><header>Impact of Federal agency rules on individuals living at, near, or below the poverty line and racial inequity; GAO reports</header><subsection id="HAAF9294286A44065A919F2F20EE8DE8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Impact of regulations on poverty and racial inequity</header><text>Whenever an agency publishes notice of proposed rule making in the Federal Register for a major rule, the agency shall, with such notice, publish an analysis of the actual or potential impact of the major rule on—</text><paragraph id="H17898533A44347F4B07D89A90D8DB2B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals living at, near, or below the poverty line; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD7415552E74A789772A1ADA410FCCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">racial inequity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1728A0C008A44BC8063416AEABB8594"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report on impact of Federal Government programs or policies on poverty and racial inequity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During the calendar year in which the date that is one year after the date of enactment of this Act falls, and during each of the following nine calendar years, the Comptroller General shall publish an electronic report on between two and five Government programs or policies with a substantial economic impact (as determined by the Comptroller General) within the past 5 fiscal years. Any such report shall examine the actual or potential impact of such programs or policies on—</text><paragraph id="H037D29943424409B9C707529C1F0B315"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals living at, near, or below the poverty line; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H470604868E0D4E76AA3D07CE1496F7FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">racial inequity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6952F13512844CF49B26890B93D6FA7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Racial wealth gap</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis under subsection (a) or a report under subsection (b) may, at the discretion of the applicable agency head or the Comptroller General (as the case may be), include an analysis of the actual or potential impact of the major rule or Government program or policy (as the case may be) on the racial wealth gap.</text></subsection><subsection id="HABD9CB09B4C64A1A8405C01868980837"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H16196DDF39184DE9B58F07C54FD71CA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5373E528F244670BFD1B6C8CDF04F01" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>major rule</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 804 of such title 5; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44DC567420D845E2884B9A0A465DB027"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms <quote>poverty line</quote>, <quote>racial inequity</quote>, and <quote>racial wealth gap</quote>, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H9543C848E7464F839B866CDD358D6C15"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of an analysis under subsection (a), be defined as considered appropriate by the Director of the Office of Management and Budget; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3EAC9A69F3A48BCA21026EEFAC19A5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for purposes of a report under subsection (b), be defined as considered appropriate by the Comptroller General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

