<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60116499CB4B436C8AF9FEF8BE6ED28E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7810 IH: Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7810</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220518">May 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to prohibit the manufacture, processing, use, and distribution in commerce of commercial asbestos and mixtures and articles containing commercial asbestos, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94A7A13342F446B49714CEF10957D36E" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H2A3AD079BE4540B381EA44D42B6A764C"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC195FAA22F51447B96322DB72AB59A16"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commercial asbestos ban and reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2605">15 U.S.C. 2605</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1947BCB03FB349579318D2DD29E6837B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsection (j) as subsection (k); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4205AA2DA344FEFBDF879722F611017"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after subsection (i) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB968FE0EA9AA45D98F305D185289B066"><subsection id="H52F109D4156E41F0B12A745AC3F1F2F9"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Asbestos</header><paragraph id="H8F1CE589B9AE47F8B0A544F5C960FEF2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H1C5E1786959F47C481A82BAD65E711B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Commercial asbestos</header><clause id="H953D57B7BC5F42568EAC9455A50F0299"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>commercial asbestos</term> means asbestiform fibers that have been extracted and processed from any of the following minerals:</text><subclause id="HD5813250DCAE478D809291B3F1617562"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Chrysotile (serpentine).</text></subclause><subclause id="H4AE328B38D9849EC8581FCA1022F497B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Crocidolite (riebeckite).</text></subclause><subclause id="HCD446C1EED1149548577AEE68FC6281B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Amosite (cummingtonite-grunerite).</text></subclause><subclause id="H587B0683C1A8447CB53DA46FD45831BB"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Anthophyllite asbestos.</text></subclause><subclause id="HD7781D4B1FC946C49EEA2A52575D0774"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Tremolite asbestos.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC2AAED3021DC4ED18B80718DC81A1AD8"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Actinolite asbestos.</text></subclause><subclause id="H25B9993F41074C458BDA52D5C9771369"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Richterite.</text></subclause><subclause id="H7DFE618A13A54006B6372DACAAF1193F"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Winchite.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE3A14B1F26B14FA0AD0CEECEF062E46D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>commercial asbestos</term> does not include asbestos fibers that are not extracted or processed for the value of the asbestos fibers.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01E5BABC06F04B0EB6E07CDCA36165C5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Distribute in commerce</header><clause id="H4320A6BF1F744DC49EB7E5F47504FEB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), the terms <term>distribute in commerce</term> and <term>distribution in commerce</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 3.</text></clause><clause id="H294ABA7DC4C94A0BBE7A5CA7E6A25B57"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The terms <term>distribute in commerce</term> and <term>distribution in commerce</term> do not include, with respect to commercial asbestos—</text><subclause id="H637C29BE158848B19D4C5A96A9B87663"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">end-use of a mixture or article containing commercial asbestos and installed in a building or other structure before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title>; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H262881B489AC44E1B7D962C510917DE6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>distribution of a mixture or article containing commercial asbestos solely for the purpose of disposal of the mixture or article in compliance with applicable Federal, State, and local requirements.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4BA8B1A5753428C93E163615B8C2BF1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mixture or article containing commercial asbestos</header><text>The term <term>mixture or article containing commercial asbestos</term> does not include a mixture or article in which commercial asbestos is present solely as an impurity (as defined in section 720.3 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3582A7DADA464F719596FAACEBA1C5D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><subparagraph id="H160AD87F13F741948DFD5BBF0FFA9CB4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The prohibitions, requirements, and definition of the term <quote>commercial asbestos</quote> in this subsection shall—</text><clause id="H0FE2ABFF53B14AF6B3E2DFDF3A62DE08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>apply only—</text><subclause id="H4264211197334C899AF101DA5386B6C8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to chemical substances; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2F54B9B54AEC4BA3AEEC7C62FBDB7B93"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for purposes of regulating chemical substances under this Act; and </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8C0B92682A4D4B7A84E077C234D394BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have no effect on—</text><subclause id="H37798105114A475DBF86A07D1C64B394"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any other prohibition or definition of the term <quote>asbestos</quote>; or </text></subclause><subclause id="H1D0F119491AC468FAC7705E39B74CA77"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other requirement regulating asbestos, including for purposes of—</text><item id="H43A0B880DB4348CBA7C5DCDFF50A2CE4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>regulating cosmetics under the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>); and </text></item><item id="H516A1E6688404CB2AC839A6CBD52C1CD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>determining whether a cosmetic contains asbestos as an ingredient or as an impurity to an ingredient. </text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21F1B3E6A3A64D99847F37EF1F4D6636"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Impurities</header><text>Nothing in this subsection applies to any chemical substance, mixture, or article in which commercial asbestos is present solely as an impurity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1444A557B70246A79779513FEEED9600"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition of manufacture, processing, use, and distribution in commerce</header><text>Effective 1 year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title>, no person may manufacture, process, use, or distribute in commerce commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4863D4B9E5D4BEDB5BFAAFCA456817F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chlor-alkali industry</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (3), an owner, operator, or agent of an owner or operator of a chlor-alkali facility that is in operation on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title> may, until the date that is 2 years after that date of enactment—</text><subparagraph id="H6C65C4F0F5644C7A86AF8F34ADE9F1A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>import processed commercial asbestos fibers solely for the purpose of manufacturing diaphragms for use in the chlor-alkali process; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF88010706A194F679A13BF58098A30EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>use, hold, or process commercial asbestos fibers solely for the purpose of manufacturing diaphragms for use in the chlor-alkali process.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0393454A58954E9799129CC6A723129E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exemption for national security reasons</header><subparagraph id="HC33BB3296BDA4E80A969979330A7A6DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this subsection, the President may, on application, grant any person an exemption from the prohibition under paragraph (3) once for the manufacture, processing, use, or distribution in commerce of commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos only if the President determines that—</text><clause id="H722F5B6FCD604B6AAD8C61A271E07CCB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the manufacture, processing, use, or distribution in commerce of commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos by the person is necessary to protect the national security interests of the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H0B48091DE06F4D26A44C370F2C144356"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>no feasible alternative to the manufacture, processing, use, or distribution in commerce of commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos exists for the intended use.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00DF159323945DAB6427494DAE17396"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><clause id="H894ADC39ABAC4669A8A985FA0F113AC4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The period of an exemption granted under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 3 years.</text></clause><clause id="H0E128A9C28C7482FA2816BBB4BF5A206"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The President may, in accordance with subparagraph (A), extend an exemption granted under that subparagraph once, for a period not to exceed 3 years.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04B6474FEF1143F9BA2B2CA596A07566"><enum>(C)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An exemption granted under this paragraph (including any extension granted under subparagraph (B)(ii)) shall include such terms and conditions as are necessary to achieve the maximum extent practicable reduction in exposure to commercial asbestos.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20A4290C74DC4C49BCB7BFFC199534A5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Publication</header><clause id="HE74705F7A1344E6C8D0045B764BA5404"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after receipt of an application for an exemption under this paragraph (including an extension under subparagraph (B)(ii)), the President shall publish the application in the Federal Register.</text></clause><clause id="HE4711CC4F0BA4A61B4FC01BCB31BF36D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after granting an exemption under this paragraph (including an extension under subparagraph (B)(ii)), the President shall publish in the Federal Register—</text><subclause id="H31FEAB6EE7DC45468B42977E39EFC92B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a notice of the exemption; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H97CD0531AEBA4A899116E6245BE65419"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the terms and conditions included under subparagraph (C).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1CCA3EDE114549878698C30A5F2C4182"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The President, on a determination that publication under this subparagraph of information relating to an application or granting of a particular exemption would harm the national security interests of the United States—</text><subclause id="H91205691971F435AA5B2B05E30253237"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall not publish that information in the Federal Register; but </text></subclause><subclause id="H615399BF3691464F8B4AB02EF46BE54E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall provide that information to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3D68C89CD24444B923900B0193A5C07"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Application of waiver authority</header><text>Notwithstanding section 22, the Administrator may not issue a waiver under that section with respect to commercial asbestos.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB306B6B6676543CCB0783F7279717CE5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="H42389BA2708D465F86D988F339A65FD3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Timing and coverage</header><clause id="H3F3D520748FF4B7D90F60FAA1326B284"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Previous action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title>, any person who has manufactured, processed, used, or distributed in commerce commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos during the 3-year period preceding that date of enactment shall submit to the Administrator a report described in subparagraph (B).</text></clause><clause id="HAF9DA9304BAB43558B8575DC011E1394"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Later action</header><text>Any person manufacturing, processing, using, or distributing in commerce commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos during the period that begins on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title> and ends on the date on which the prohibition under paragraph (3) takes effect shall submit to the Administrator a report described in subparagraph (B) not later than 60 days after—</text><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4CCF67DB714B4A88835A8976E21746B1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title>, for any person who has manufactured, processed, used, or distributed in commerce commercial asbestos or any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos before that date of enactment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H127281EF6AE44046BBAEC5A6EFC7BDFC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the date on which the person initiates that manufacture, processing, use, or distribution in commerce, for any person initiating that manufacture, processing, use, or distribution in commerce on or after that date of enactment.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H597385619D844874BF93061E63F3B498"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Reports by chlor-alkali industry</header><text>An owner, operator, or agent of an owner or operator of a chlor-alkali facility importing, using, holding, or processing an article containing commercial asbestos pursuant to paragraph (4) in a calendar year shall submit to the Administrator a report described in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause id="H13B9919EF2B54765956A6F68EF1D8E9F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not later than March 1 of the following calendar year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA4A04BB99C15494B8ED479644459A777"><enum>(II)</enum><text>annually thereafter until the person has submitted such a report with respect to each calendar year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title> in which that person imported, used, held, or processed such an article. </text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0DC59EAFCCFA4D7ABA05F48A39BF996B"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Reports during exempted period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person granted an exemption under paragraph (5) shall submit to the Administrator a report described in subparagraph (B) not later than 27 months after—</text><subclause id="H9559B54D9F494C95800162238C857501"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the date on which the exemption is granted; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H423571A9994440E788AAA49AC015F146"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the exemption is extended, if applicable.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC6CAF1FA17408E972BE7E55BCA0321"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each report submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="HD5E8EEACD516407C90BD05FD0230FB59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the name and address of the person submitting the report;</text></clause><clause id="H7AAEA9375C5D41558848E50BFB143220"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name, title, and contact information of an authorized representative of the person submitting the report;</text></clause><clause id="H0EBD5D06EDCE4DEA87ADA6B9250C6946"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the location of the facility or facilities where the manufacture, processing, use, or distribution in commerce of commercial asbestos or mixtures or articles containing commercial asbestos has occurred, or will occur, during the reporting period;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H7C4B3E4005A04C89B368E5CC07457256"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a description of the manufacture, processing, use, or distribution activity during the reporting period of the person submitting the report and the intended and known uses of commercial asbestos and each mixture or article containing commercial asbestos by that person and all other persons to whom the commercial asbestos, mixture, or article is sold or otherwise distributed in commerce;</text></clause><clause id="H3F8964ABB79E444F852896FCE2CB7F9D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the quantity of commercial asbestos, and the quantity and concentration of commercial asbestos in any mixture or article containing commercial asbestos, that is manufactured, processed, used, or distributed in commerce, or expected to be manufactured, processed, used, or distributed in commerce, by the person during the reporting period;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC5E73ADACE7B4987A9D5C77678B98D0C"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable estimates of the quantity of commercial asbestos to be disposed of as a result of the reported manufacture, processing, use, or distribution activities, and the manner of the disposal; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA079F46E00A24479915B4E75EB7080EA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonably ascertainable estimates of—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H15224695454E4A43A70D6E9F730BDB4A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of individuals who, as a result of the reported manufacture, processing, use, and distribution activities—</text><item commented="no" id="HA0F20F0DE6604DE6B2CEFE428D8A9A17"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>have been exposed to commercial asbestos or mixtures or articles containing commercial asbestos; and</text></item><item commented="no" id="H1C6922FABCA048F8AD5171E4F87BA9A2"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>will be so exposed; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H360D44365E594FC39FBCD4EE33F59F7F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the nature, duration, frequency, and levels of any exposure described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35B6765441AC48098F21D71EB4F3FAC3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Reporting period</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (B), the reporting period for a report submitted under—</text><clause id="H8FDD2F5D3CD542EB875328F6314C42C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (A)(i) shall be the 3-year period preceding the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title>;</text></clause><clause id="H705B44A24FFD4F3C8CAC673F2605124C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (A)(ii) shall be the period that begins on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title> and ends on the date on which the prohibition under paragraph (3) takes effect;</text></clause><clause id="H81F604EAB7834F71A8DF39D487125F4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(iii) shall be the calendar year before the calendar year in which the report is submitted;</text></clause><clause id="H6F493D5DC53A4D2A9B067E1EC59AC1A8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(iv)(I) shall be the period that begins on the date on which an exemption is granted under paragraph (5) and ends on the date on which that exemption expires (not including any extension of that exemption); and</text></clause><clause id="HC4A98D8C0ABC446D9E57F73EC5929682"><enum>(v)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(iv)(II) shall be the period that begins on the date on which an exemption is extended under paragraph (5)(B)(ii) and ends on the date on which that extension expires.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21954D936D334CE6BCD76AFB862C55E9"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reporting forms and instructions</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Alan Reinstein Ban Asbestos Now Act of 2022</short-title>, the Administrator shall publish a notice in the Federal Register that provides instructions for reporting under this paragraph and a form or forms for use by persons submitting reports under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C6792821B7F4AE2B68212BEB55BD2EF"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which a report is submitted under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall, subject to section 14, make that report available to the public.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF25A0FA9E3E74D99857C2EBDC00D87A7"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Summary and analysis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date on which a report is submitted under subparagraph (A), the Administrator shall, subject to section 14, make available to the public a summary and analysis of the information that report contains.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H056475024CA349D084686455B732A7EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Public education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall—</text><paragraph id="HCE709A0E22564CD18515136EB27947DA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">publicize the prohibition under paragraph (3) of subsection (j) of section 6 of the Toxic Substances Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2605">15 U.S.C. 2605</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EBA2DD594A042078C0CC13BF9C0E2DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to persons who may be subject to that prohibition assistance in complying with that subsection. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

