<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3928675408474F2493A30299C58D46C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9468 IH: Improving Access to Higher Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9468</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221208">December 8, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to improve accessibility to, and completion of, postsecondary education for students, including students with disabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H601AA806A26C40EB9239DBFB00173B1E" style="OLC">
<section id="HA77CC9D27F214454A15EC1CCD22FE401" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="H0FEF7DFFAFA5421395E594AF6011B396"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Access to Higher Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB9C79DD2A0124FE9B687E657122174C5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration">
<toc-entry idref="HA77CC9D27F214454A15EC1CCD22FE401" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HFC8E0B1809034C79BF80F6D1BD155B87" level="title">Title I—Programs to provide students with disabilities with a quality higher education</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H748BBCA2C5EA4B5495DA776A030E0D78" level="section">Sec. 101. Supporting postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators in providing accessible education.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H7CCBA84246E746A7895697D2797E76DF" level="section">Sec. 102. Office of Accessibility.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3EC02B1AB8AC46B4BEF29309F59D85F4" level="section">Sec. 103. Accessible instructional materials and technology.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HA672048E89444E00BDB0275EFD590ED9" level="section">Sec. 104. Postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H2A76DB03E9004964A72E7B589E77E06E" level="section">Sec. 105. National Technical Assistance Center and National Coordinating Center for Inclusion of Students with Intellectual Disabilities.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8EF6E7B3D969473DAC9FCA13F90289EE" level="section">Sec. 106. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HB7AFA2D89FAB42FB8BAD9FC13A74B481" level="title">Title II—Miscellaneous provisions</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H147F16FDE80E49D9B779C261F9B94EE7" level="section">Sec. 201. Submission of data with respect to students with disabilities.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H2598997772FB4CAF98D81F7AF535B9E6" level="section">Sec. 202. Training for realtime writers to provide closed captioning and court reporting services.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8F41EC46D1D5429DAEBBA173FD5932AB" level="section">Sec. 203. Perfecting amendment.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<title id="HFC8E0B1809034C79BF80F6D1BD155B87"><enum>I</enum><header>Programs to provide students with disabilities with a quality higher education</header>
<section id="H748BBCA2C5EA4B5495DA776A030E0D78"><enum>101.</enum><header>Supporting postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators in providing accessible education</header>
<subsection id="H21800521DD2142C89A27AD0AA75F3978"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 762 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140b">20 U.S.C. 1140b</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0B13A1725B19428B8F52AA45E9DBE6D4" style="OLC"> <section id="H56C415DF46184FA28164609D1A402D4D"><enum>762.</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <subsection id="H037D17A8D9254FD49E174018B5297523"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Competitive grants authorized To support postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators in providing an accessible education</header> <paragraph id="HCDCA5120D4F240CBABA1D791E75272A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 765C, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education to enable the institutions to carry out the activities under subsection (b).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8CFEC09D0D274737916D0743065BEE89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Awards for professional development and technical assistance</header><text>Not less than 5 grants shall be awarded to institutions of higher education that provide professional development and technical assistance in order to improve access to, and completion of, postsecondary education for students, including students with disabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA8926795241F49DF94A1FAB5B3B4E45F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration; activities</header> <paragraph id="H66C45C682D9A4E3EBB6D0A5C28DD5460"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 5 years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H850FCFBB1FB640598262616599788B02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be used to carry out one or more of the following activities:</text> <subparagraph id="H5359EA4C1E8941C4B980C09BE213D434"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Teaching methods and strategies</header><text>The development and implementation of training to provide innovative, effective, and evidence-based teaching methods and strategies, consistent with the principles of universal design for learning, to provide postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators with the skills and supports necessary to teach and meet the academic and programmatic needs of students (including students with disabilities) in order to improve the retention of such students in, and the completion by such students of, postsecondary education. Such methods and strategies may include in-service training, professional development, customized and general technical assistance, workshops, summer institutes, distance learning, and training in the use of assistive and educational technology.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HF8B4A51BF13C4619A4C3BC3305AB9DCC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Implementing accommodations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and implementation of training to provide postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators methods and strategies of providing appropriate accommodations consistent with the principles of universal design (as defined in section 103) for learning for students with disabilities, including descriptions of legal obligations of the institution of higher education to provide such accommodations.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE253C2F35AC4728817F7AE9D08710E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effective transition practices</header><text>The development and implementation of innovative, effective, and evidence-based teaching methods and strategies to provide postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators with the skills and supports necessary to ensure the successful and smooth transition of students with disabilities from secondary school to postsecondary education. The teaching methods and strategies may include supporting students in the development of self-advocacy skills to improve transition to, and completion of, postsecondary education.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDB4E091F50154F22AE0AABFD455C4562"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Distance learning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and implementation of training to provide innovative, effective, and evidence-based teaching methods and strategies to enable postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators to provide accessible distance education programs or classes that would enhance the access of students (including students with disabilities) to postsecondary education, including the use of accessible curricula and electronic communication for instruction and advising that meet the requirements of section 508 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794d">29 U.S.C. 794d</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H347D067B134C48D98B25FF064A0B5FD3"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Career pathway guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The development and implementation of effective and evidence-based teaching methods and strategies to provide postsecondary faculty, staff, and administrators with the ability to advise students with disabilities with respect to their chosen career pathway, which shall include at least one of the following:</text>
<clause id="HD876B51F2F304A0089552BAB69B8A7A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Supporting internships, apprenticeships registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), or work-based learning opportunities.</text></clause> <clause id="H66BF1BA42E124D9D820725FF78DC9C15"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Counseling on coursework to meet the degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential appropriate for the field chosen.</text></clause>
<clause id="H4CEDCF5069F24040B5D750DB574654CE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Developing self-advocacy skills to advocate for appropriate accommodations once in the workplace.</text></clause> <clause id="HD9D279E3077E4433B45A2A8B9AE51B36"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Support with selecting a career pathway that leads to competitive, integrated employment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22E7F6B8D1B04E4D8781D19A7029B978"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Mandatory evaluation and dissemination</header><text>An institution of higher education awarded a grant under this section shall evaluate and disseminate to other institutions of higher education the information obtained through the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) of paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H10C81EF3A27E43F9BC0B7D0AF635BD71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Considerations in making awards</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HE838DCAA8A9D40FCAED4D2EFE5F37EE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>Providing an equitable geographic distribution of such awards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D380E852CD747038680C156F9D34161"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rural and urban areas</header><text>Distributing such awards to urban and rural areas.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5A03E84BB47D468CBE39E2F914C62577"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Range and type of institution</header><text>Ensuring that the activities to be assisted are developed for a range of types and sizes of institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H83CC2409605A42BD9B7A47ABD63057DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header> <paragraph id="H260D9B811F294E2F98A824861BAAC2EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public, a report on all projects awarded grants under this part, including a review of the activities and program performance of such projects based on existing information as of the date of the report.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0680370FD58348B2B38F253D18580A4F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent report</header><text>Not later than five years after the date of the first award of a grant under this section after the date of the Improving Access to Higher Education Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public, a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H439E6235034F436EAD1B44D59053996A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviews the activities and program performance of the projects authorized under subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5983B18F43C64A7EB1F77F6C21AB682A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides guidance and recommendations on how effective projects can be replicated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H94852A03BDB7474F9BFAA81B63FD170E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 763 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140c">20 U.S.C. 1140c</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6E1A7EFFAEDC45C29882ABD4784F2139" style="OLC">
<section id="H816DF7C02EA64D70B8F65EB295EF2F1C"><enum>763.</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each institution of higher education desiring to receive a grant under section 762 shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require. Each application shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HB4DEF4D841B741EFAE25481141BA85C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the activities authorized under section 762(b) that the institution proposes to carry out, and how such institution plans to conduct such activities in order to further the purposes of this subpart;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H20A60C612C0E47B69D5D3FB329061631"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of how the institution consulted with a broad range of people, including individuals with expertise in disability supports or special education, within the institution to develop activities for which assistance is sought;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB61EEEEDA8A34A9584A7EB8FDC567CCC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of how the institution will coordinate and collaborate with the office of accessibility; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE639F1DFF4924FE8B207C2757785FBD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the extent to which the institution will work to replicate the research-based and best practices of institutions of higher education with demonstrated effectiveness in serving students with disabilities.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H7CCBA84246E746A7895697D2797E76DF" commented="no"><enum>102.</enum><header>Office of Accessibility</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 1 of part D of title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140a">20 U.S.C. 1140a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H33AD53BB16574C16AA062D360C8A5081"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 765 as section 765C; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51370FB974AA4B629207553DF9FD821E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 764 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0865ABBF666245A280B77FB5BD1EE54A" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="H09040CE13AAA4DFF8B573B372CFEA6B9" commented="no"><enum>765A.</enum><header>Office of Accessibility</header>
<subsection id="H56AD3EED8CE1462ABEBFA87E645ED08A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Each institution of higher education shall establish an office of accessibility to develop and implement policies to support students who enter postsecondary education with disabilities and students who acquire a disability while enrolled in an institution of higher education.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD4B9778CF3834E469E76A3686B8020E6" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each office of accessibility shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HDFE067C2E7384215AA2E3F360ABA929C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>inform students, during student orientation, about services provided at the institution of higher education, and continually update such information through the accessibility office’s website and other communications to improve accessibility of such services;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0AE4F53D868401FA139B453886383AA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide information to students regarding accommodations and modifications provided by the institution of higher education with respect to internships, practicums, work-based learning, apprenticeships registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), or other work-related environments that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3F9EFEFDABFA4EB09840018CAC0C967D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the student may engage in through courses; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FC11873DD984AE3AB27AE3FE64B7085" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are necessary for completion of a degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential;</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5792CC3C38434234B6089865C699EE31" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide information to students regarding their legal rights under the Americans with Disabilities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) and section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A995AB8634244B6B490EB38EA35BEED" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in order to provide appropriate accommodations to students with disabilities, carry out the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HA52E43C1C4BD4AC89E8E50876EC9E28B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Adopt policies that, at a minimum, make any of the following documentation submitted by an individual sufficient to establish that such individual is an individual with a disability:</text> <clause id="H67C86BF871444AC0BA3EB445983107CD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Documentation that the individual has had an individualized education program (IEP) in accordance with section 614(d) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1414">20 U.S.C. 1414(d)</external-xref>), including an IEP that may not be current on the date of the determination that the individual has a disability. The office of accessibility may ask for additional documentation from an individual who had an IEP but who was subsequently evaluated and determined to be ineligible for services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>), including an individual determined to be ineligible during elementary school.</text></clause>
<clause id="H143BBCE12C6447B3A0152DD3AF9BE784" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Documentation describing services or accommodations provided to the individual pursuant to section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as a <quote>Section 504 plan</quote>).</text></clause> <clause id="HCAA31414D06143119FFC6A808DFD554A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A plan or record of service for the individual from a private school, a local educational agency, a State educational agency, or an institution of higher education provided in accordance with the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause>
<clause id="H5D944FEF9F684BBEB8B5E62530567941" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A record or evaluation from a relevant licensed professional finding that the individual has a disability.</text></clause> <clause id="H001AECD985784D6DAEC48E0E5FB62B04" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A plan or record of disability from another institution of higher education.</text></clause>
<clause id="H5EDE74BE238446C58BA5D8CA3175522C" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Documentation of a disability due to service in the uniformed services, as defined in section 484C(a).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H06EB7C7414744916BE8C53190A8E63BA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Adopt policies that are transparent and explicit regarding the process by which the institution determines eligibility for accommodations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H91BA364D0528484BBC753B8A87A3E350" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Disseminate the information described in subparagraph (B) to students, parents, and faculty—</text> <clause id="HBF008A97E45440BEAD7B2C8ACAF7BAEA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in an accessible format;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0BF594E0C9DB4EFB9CBCF5AEFFFF0A0A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during student orientation; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDCCABC5DB47B42BBAEF56D25C4FB4F31" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by making such information readily available on a public website of the institution.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1DAEBAEEA0F408D82F29828F173646F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Provide accommodations to students with mental health disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5B0EE324CCDF4B59AC932E36212FB25C" commented="no"><enum>765B.</enum><header>Competitive grant for innovation and accessibility</header> <subsection id="HEF03C523B755450B8DCDE57CF8527152" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header> <paragraph id="H2F3838E000D145B09A45CD2A3F290565" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From amounts appropriated under section 765C, the Secretary may award grants on a competitive basis to institutions of higher education to enable the institutions to carry out the activities described under subsection (c).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H197A624451E24395A0024F3144D40DD5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 5 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06C1B62584D84EDDBCF3F9997FBFD07F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration in making awards</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HC89B244781364C6BABA83DE1BA3475D1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Providing an equitable geographic distribution of such awards.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9D752546C654BC69E9E70B902E2A23B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Ensuring that the activities to be assisted are developed for a range of types and sizes of institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1765BCF79C04437F8DA0E57A424F87B8" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>Each institution of higher education desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require. Each application shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H13955432717D436DA179666DECEDF7A4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of how the institution will carry out the activities under subsection (c);</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEFECD8422B3143C2988E0B6569C5AF26" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the consultation the institution has had with a broad range of people within the institution, including individuals with expertise in disability supports or special education, in developing the information under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD145EBAC5BCB4D32ABBF6DB3C4E7029E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan for the sustainability of the program after the end of the grant period; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1637CA1D7B8B4D92B5B6745288330A48" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a written business plan for revenue and expenditures to be provided to the Department under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H163F80A3BE8749D9BAE0EE7E5B93844F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be used to—</text>
<paragraph id="HDD7CE62252D348AC941B03BED2C3C64D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop and implement across the institution of higher education, a universal design (as defined in section 103) for learning framework for course design and instructional materials to improve campus-wide accessibility to instruction, materials, and the learning environment; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC34053AC1CEF45EA8F9D59B42B8AA2B8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop or improve distance education courses consistent with the principles of universal design for learning to improve accessibility of instruction and materials.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDD82189A8CC8470491C01BC655197CEC" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="H8C43B41A264940C7AA5C5EAE6480520D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Grant recipient reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education awarded a grant under this section shall evaluate and disseminate to other institutions of higher education, the information obtained through the activities described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BEF41B093B341639F8D09150F4971F1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial report by Secretary</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public, a report on all projects awarded grants under this section, including a review of the activities and program performance of such projects based on existing information as of the date of the report.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F2FD2DA992643E6B33F4C6273FFF7F5" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Final report by Secretary</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date of the first award of a grant under this section, the Secretary shall prepare and submit to the authorizing committees, and make available to the public, a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H34E58F8F78AF457CB4A509D3937BF44E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reviews the activities and program performance of the projects authorized under this section; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H56781E62D013427E8DF109D581933418" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides guidance and recommendations on how effective projects can be replicated.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB4B67295E43549F891349B6A8F78F0DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending section 765C, as so redesignated, by striking <quote>2009</quote> and inserting <quote>2023</quote>.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H3EC02B1AB8AC46B4BEF29309F59D85F4"><enum>103.</enum><header>Accessible instructional materials and technology</header>
<subsection id="H0A641F62CDBD42F8A8324AB756E9E811"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of commission</header><text>The Speaker of the House of Representatives, the President pro tempore of the Senate, and the Secretary of Education shall establish an independent commission, comprised of key stakeholders, to develop guidelines for accessible postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies in order—</text> <paragraph id="H80C8FB601A094574A556C82AEF1D6CC8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to ensure students with disabilities are afforded the same educational benefits provided to students without disabilities through the use of electronic instructional materials and related technologies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H56F22557C0724A35BAEA0F68992CE2F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to improve the selection and use of such materials and technologies at institutions of higher education; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EC0C071397F437CBEB5E91648CA8AA3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to encourage entities that produce such materials and technologies to make accessible versions more readily available in the market.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDA5DA9F3274844519A0B652CB8BC1AC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), the commission shall—</text> <paragraph id="H463BD7F9ECAD44E79409BD64C811EE71"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review applicable information technology accessibility standards; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5D0CF33B8F84EA5BF302F102C6541B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compile and annotate such accessibility standards as an additional information resource for institutions of higher education and companies that service the higher education market.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H804C54572056463693622E7C9A8C11CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="H89395514271246B1BAB701318B6165E1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stakeholder groups</header><text>The commission shall be composed of representatives from the following categories:</text>
<subparagraph id="HFC010E17D5294181B9B68EFDDA3EEFFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Communities of persons with disabilities for whom the accessibility of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies is a significant factor in ensuring equal participation in higher education, and nonprofit organizations that provide accessible electronic materials to these communities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H243F05782EB44727B81CBF33BEB95440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Higher education leadership, including institution of higher education presidents, provosts, deans, vice presidents or deans of libraries, chief information officers, and other senior institutional executives.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0EB8BE6CAFDB4D1185D19CEBE904DD36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Developers of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and manufacturers of related technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC1BA2963EEFF46A193CBF16BA6478354"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointment of members</header><text>The commission members shall be appointed as follows:</text>
<subparagraph id="H35FA5B1621E445DFAD475A5EEB7E4413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>6 members, 2 from each category described in paragraph (1), shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives, 3 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the majority leader of the House of Representatives and 3 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the minority leader of the House of Representatives, with the Speaker ensuring that 1 developer of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and 1 manufacturer of related technologies are appointed. The Speaker shall also appoint 2 additional members, 1 student with a disability and 1 faculty member from an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1CD81F48F2194B57A882E6772131CDB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>6 members, 2 from each category described in paragraph (1), shall be appointed by the President pro tempore of the Senate, 3 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the majority leader of the Senate and 3 of whom shall be appointed on the recommendation of the minority leader of the Senate, with the President pro tempore ensuring that 1 developer of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and 1 manufacturer of related technologies are appointed. The President pro tempore shall also appoint 2 additional members, 1 student with a disability and 1 faculty member from an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2DB5AF3807FC40BCADD74B5F0BE438B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>3 members, each of whom must possess extensive, demonstrated technical expertise in the development and implementation of accessible postsecondary electronic instructional materials, shall be appointed by the Secretary of Education. 1 of these members shall represent postsecondary students with disabilities, 1 shall represent higher education leadership, and 1 shall represent developers of postsecondary electronic instructional materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H143A64FD3FA24086AC624274753B749C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility to serve as a member</header><text>Federal employees are ineligible for appointment to the commission. An appointee to a volunteer or advisory position with a Federal agency or related advisory body may be appointed to the commission so long as his or her primary employment is with a non-Federal entity and he or she is not otherwise engaged in financially compensated work on behalf of the Federal Government, exclusive of any standard expense reimbursement or grant-funded activities.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H29B67FC728FA41DEB2ED4E10FD67CE32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority and administration</header>
<paragraph id="HC7832913FDEB4B3EB7A225222730C3EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The commission’s execution of its duties shall be independent of the Secretary of Education, the Attorney General, and the head of any other agency or department of the Federal Government with regulatory or standard setting authority in the areas addressed by the commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H570705EFA8284BC3A7217E91FF724970"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header> <subparagraph id="HBE695C6AB15B4534B8ACB0A98781AD11"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Staffing</header><text>There shall be no permanent staffing for the commission.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA9620E43F7AA479D8CD8F53DF76C7A72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Leadership</header><text>Commission members shall elect a chairperson from among the appointees to the commission.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H83B2C1FF86BC4D18A078AAE982B51FED"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Administrative support</header><text>The Commission shall be provided administrative support, as needed, by the Secretary of Education through the Office of Postsecondary Education of the Department of Education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H4F85ACC1F2874FCCAC91E1F7F111E72F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header>
<paragraph id="H912403B6F601415AB7C866ACB0521734"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Guidelines</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, subject to a 6-month extension that it may exercise at its discretion, the commission shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HCCA7166E843E4210A53BEA328B5CE8F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop and issue guidelines for accessible postsecondary electronic instructional materials, and related technologies; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD873ACA1ECE41DB9A2E910746820685"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in developing the guidelines, the commission shall—</text> <clause id="HF03B1B68021C422AA981A89CCE26EA52"><enum>(i)</enum><text>establish a technical panel pursuant to paragraph (4) to support the commission in developing the guidelines;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H81F849C78FB149F095121D1AA5B99C92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>develop criteria for determining which materials and technologies constitute postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies;</text></clause> <clause id="H300DB69206A74C4ABAEE3C204A7D1CA3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>identify existing national and international accessibility standards that are relevant to student use of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies at institutions of higher education;</text></clause>
<clause id="H13E3CB7F0D18456D9BB7B73AA345D565"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>identify and address any unique pedagogical and accessibility requirements of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies that are not addressed, or not adequately addressed, by the identified, relevant existing accessibility standards;</text></clause> <clause id="HA397B6098A8845F1B2F5BADCA65E7C2B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>identify those aspects of accessibility, and types of postsecondary instructional materials and related technologies, for which the commission cannot produce guidelines or which cannot be addressed by existing accessibility standards due to—</text>
<subclause id="H33D4EE69ECCD4AD79007A35944F09B51"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inherent limitations of commercially available technologies; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="H73EDE934BE754E709320D2B01D6EC10A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the challenges posed by a specific category of disability that covers a wide spectrum of impairments and capabilities which makes it difficult to assess the benefits from particular guidelines on a categorical basis;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H998061C52EE943928197B41673C27A37"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>ensure that the guidelines are consistent with the requirements of section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) and titles II and III of the Americans with Disabilities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12181">42 U.S.C. 12181 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H16AC6C9B830B4E6A857A3A3FCF5333F8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>ensure that the guidelines are consistent, to the extent feasible and appropriate, with the technical and functional performance criteria included in the national and international accessibility standards identified by the commission as relevant to student use of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies;</text></clause>
<clause id="HD3137F1624884F3EA0CB28737C166982"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>allow for the use of an alternative design or technology that results in substantially equivalent or greater accessibility and usability by individuals with disabilities than would be provided by compliance with the guidelines; and</text></clause> <clause id="HEA5CD57DB363481B873616CB7DB6A293"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>provide that where electronic instructional materials, or related technologies, that comply fully with the guidelines are not commercially available, or where such compliance is not technically feasible, the institution may select the product that best meets the guidelines consistent with the institution’s business and pedagogical needs.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H41DD5E591B184A25B9DB5BCF74DC21AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annotated list of information technology standards</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, subject to a 6-month extension that it may exercise at its discretion, the commission established in section 2 shall, with the assistance of the technical panel established under paragraph (4), develop and issue an annotated list of information technology standards.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB426CB71A3924192B81592B6506C41FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>Issuance of the guidelines and annotated list of information technology standards shall require approval of at least 75 percent of the members of the commission.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB5C069DEF0384BC2A76BB33113337550"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical panel</header><text>Not later than 1 month after first meeting, the Commission shall appoint and convene a panel of 12 technical experts, each of whom shall have extensive, demonstrated technical experience in developing, researching, or implementing accessible postsecondary electronic instructional materials, or related technologies. The commission has discretion to determine a process for nominating, vetting, and confirming a panel of experts that fairly represents the stakeholder communities on the commission. The technical panel shall include a representative from the United States Access Board.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE338F9BDE0A84135B5571FD8680CDAA1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Review of guidelines</header><text>Not later than 5 years after issuance of the guidelines and annotated list of information technology standards described in subsections (a) and (b), and every 5 years thereafter, the Secretary of Education shall publish a notice in the Federal Register requesting public comment about whether there is a need to reconstitute the commission to update the guidelines and annotated list of information technology standards to reflect technological advances, changes in postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies, or updated national and international accessibility standards. The Secretary shall then submit a report and recommendation to Congress regarding whether the Commission should be reconstituted.</text></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0106C7F31E94D14ABA50E620C34F54D"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of application</header>
<paragraph id="H0B33089A71A146278558FA844C2C3D60"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Nonconforming Postsecondary Electronic Instructional Materials Or Related Technologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to require an institution of higher education to require, provide, or both recommend and provide, postsecondary electronic instructional materials or related technologies that conform to the guidelines. However, an institution that selects or uses nonconforming postsecondary electronic instructional materials or related technologies must otherwise comply with existing obligations under section 504 of the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/794">29 U.S.C. 794</external-xref>) and titles II and III of the Americans with Disabilities Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12181">42 U.S.C. 12181 et seq.</external-xref>) to provide access to the educational benefit afforded by such materials and technologies through provision of appropriate and reasonable modification, accommodation, and auxiliary aids or services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA55090DB9B4418DB87B46926B1F9E97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relationship To Existing Laws And Regulations</header><text>With respect to the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12101">42 U.S.C. 12101 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>), nothing in this Act may be construed—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFF9C0A08098041AAB1178DE702F872C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to authorize or require conduct prohibited under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973, including the regulations issued pursuant to those laws;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C255E59295145AE8F72E42C272F00F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to expand, limit, or alter the remedies or defenses under the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H44A5539E1019438D95932D43F9C5FB99"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to supersede, restrict, or limit the application of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H277553AF070C44748207B2F6DF8ECE17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to limit the authority of Federal agencies to issue regulations pursuant to the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEF29C8264C3D40649958B5571AF7395E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HD6C75E3FD32D4CCEB61DD8D9D8D8024E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annotated list of information technology standards</header><text>The term <term>annotated list of information technology standards</term> means a list of existing national and international accessibility standards relevant to student use of postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies, and to other types of information technology common to institutions of higher education, such as institutional websites or registration systems, annotated by the commission established pursuant to this section. The annotated list of information technology standards is intended to serve solely as a reference tool to inform any consideration of the relevance of such standards in higher education contexts.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A586D7AECAF4C24B1C952B8E82B049A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Postsecondary electronic instructional materials</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary electronic instructional materials</term> means digital curricular content that is required, provided, or both recommended and provided by an institution of higher education for use in a postsecondary instructional program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1102D10288B344DAA357F4B1E1D80CE1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Related technologies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>related technologies</term> refers to any software, applications, learning management or content management systems, and hardware that an institution of higher education requires, provides, or both recommends and provides for student access to and use of postsecondary electronic instructional materials in a postsecondary instructional program.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00A5E5D04A8C412BBC759B15A28A9D61"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Technical panel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>technical panel</term> means a group of experts with extensive, demonstrated technical experience in the development and implementation of accessibility features for postsecondary electronic instructional materials and related technologies, established by the Commission pursuant to subsection (e)(4), which will assist the commission in the development of the guidelines and annotated list of information technology standards authorized under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA672048E89444E00BDB0275EFD590ED9"><enum>104.</enum><header>Postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities</header> <subsection id="HDD2FCA0AEF0C467CA13271D7B55177CC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 766 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140f">20 U.S.C. 1140f</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H827B647B0C5E491DAF9077D2DAD0D10C" style="OLC">
<section id="HF55638896D734C50B73618D8F9F5B0DB"><enum>766.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the purpose of this subpart to support inclusive programs that promote the successful transition of students with intellectual disabilities into higher education and the earning of a degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential issued by the institution of higher education.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H46B54F9CC87C474F91702737A7866613"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Programs for students with intellectual disabilities</header><text>Section 767 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140g">20 U.S.C. 1140g</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFA7B3368F65543618371AF398AAE36FA" style="OLC">
<section id="H7CF0A86538C24EF9BC9601358E3EBC51"><enum>767.</enum><header>Inclusive higher education programs for students with intellectual disabilities</header>
<subsection id="HA908651809E746269C4053C9C5BAEBC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header>
<paragraph id="HA833A8117F9E46AAB37C8087520C2080"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under section 769(a), the Secretary shall annually award grants, on a competitive basis, to institutions of higher education (or consortia of three or more institutions of higher education), to enable such institutions or consortia to create or expand a comprehensive transition and postsecondary education program for students with intellectual disabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF510BF1C8F5149F4B8208AFF2B429378" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility and appropriations limits</header> <subparagraph id="HF6D4DB7FC4C74A3194DE9A185B94123B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Relation to other grants</header><text>An institution of higher education that received a grant under this section before the date of the enactment of the Improving Access to Higher Education Act may not receive an additional grant under this section unless—</text>
<clause id="HE8288479DFA44BA393BE7CA7B19414AF" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the institution receives a grant as part of a consortium of three or more institutions of higher education; or</text></clause> <clause id="H13A62A5264774B0D96417714208AACD9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the grant term of such preceding grant has ended.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H647BE90E421D492086D2F79C190DC155" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on amounts</header>
<clause id="HCFD0A009097B46818EA778243DEC8B3A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>A grant under this section made to an institution of higher education may not be in an amount greater than $300,000.</text></clause> <clause id="HAC3A13A682DE4D18B9BB7F4A1E67D176" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consortium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant under this section made to a consortia of institutions of higher education may not be in an amount greater than $500,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HABBE41EB96C5451695FDA6B9902AA0DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under this section shall be administered by the office in the Department that administers other postsecondary education programs in consultation with the Office of Postsecondary Education and the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services of the Department of Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H428AD58A8D164520B4C7477151A0EBC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration of grants</header><text>A grant under this section shall be awarded for a period of 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3E68D48235994EF398FB47250184ADAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An institution of higher education or a consortium desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEE22C2309A6D4DDF8D8B4AD747BE7F1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Award basis</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H277DE36C963E4704B0D1F7433E1FFB46"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for an equitable geographic distribution of such grants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7C9EE38DA8943DC84E0AB93D1C45B92" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to the extent possible, provide for an equitable distribution of such grants between 4-year institutions of higher education and 2-year institutions of higher education, including community colleges;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H61E1D15934BD47B8B5AC30374A7E366C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide grant funds for high-quality, inclusive higher education programs for students with intellectual disabilities, hereinafter referred to as inclusive higher education programs, that will serve areas that are underserved by programs of this type;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9D163065CF946A095D2518481DF178F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the case of an institution of higher education that provides institutionally owned or operated housing for students attending the institution, award grants only to such institutions that integrate students with intellectual disabilities into the housing offered to students without disabilities or to institutions that provide such integrated housing through providing supports to students directly or through partnerships with other organizations;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H784EC5E998604EA69DF3FDF653F55ADC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide grant funds to encourage involvement of students attending institutions of higher education in the fields of special education, general education, vocational rehabilitation, assistive technology, or related fields in the program;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E19D8EBE9754935AAAE981A7424D42E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>select applications that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HC8AE4B7C60BE4FABA2E6E327EC13F1E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrate an existing comprehensive transition and postsecondary education program for students with intellectual disabilities that is title IV eligible; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFBD5DB9B26C249CEA453C380CB14A261"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agree to establish such a program; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H349EDFC8B123408685E0F804FABF35C2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>give preference to applications submitted under subsection (b) that agree to incorporate into the inclusive higher education program for students with intellectual disabilities carried out under the grant one or more of the following elements:</text> <subparagraph id="H4E90FD5BF62E44C2AFE1BA7F36FCDBAB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The formation of a partnership with any relevant agency serving students with intellectual disabilities, such as a vocational rehabilitation agency.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD11E4AF1EEB2432088348AE70EE923AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Applications that represent geographically underserved States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA20980EA0B0F4EC7ADC249EFC109F424"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds; requirements</header><text>An institution of higher education or consortium receiving a grant under this section shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H42BB1B39678C4E9EBD6D99BABE2C0B76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use the grant funds to establish an inclusive higher education program for students with intellectual disabilities that—</text> <subparagraph id="H67255EA054A449EF9A83BA561D954241"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serves students with intellectual disabilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H07A8AAB89DE84D5389DD91AFCC88D804"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides individual supports and services for the academic and social inclusion of students with intellectual disabilities in academic courses, extracurricular activities, and other aspects of the regular postsecondary program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A4B2B0BEA814199ADC8B875889E8954"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to the students with intellectual disabilities participating in the program, provides a focus on—</text>
<clause id="HFFA377561BD1440099258B47B42FF9C9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>academic and career development;</text></clause> <clause id="HA8D58F0F8E9F4BF595F04A2597C89C90"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>socialization and inclusion with the general student population;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE7747399BA7C4DBEBC58046B2F375FE1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>independent living skills, including self-advocacy skills; and</text></clause> <clause id="H589703C40AE54EDA91F26048516165DC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>integrated work experiences and career skills that lead to competitive integrated employment;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5914A87A98C44ED7B33D83DFF001591E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>integrates person-centered planning in the development of the course of study for each student with an intellectual disability participating in the program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6A883ABAA71497D8C4E21C80B267F4D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>plans for the sustainability of the program after the end of the grant period, with a written business plan for revenue and expenditures to be provided to the Department by the end of year 3; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H06F224BE0B984D3C8D45BBC74139EC96"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">awards a degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential for students with intellectual disabilities upon the completion of the program;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CE62780FBA14E68A345B6446F718CDC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of an institution of higher education that provides institutionally owned or operated housing for students attending the institution or integrated housing through providing supports to students directly or through partnerships with other organizations, provide for the integration of students with intellectual disabilities into housing offered to students without disabilities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H94C78C24DCD3439D970CC0095FC711F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>participate with the coordinating center established under section 777(b) in the evaluation of the program, including by regularly submitting data on experiences and outcomes of individual students participating in the program; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA7AFFF67F7349C3A8BC80FC5F4D5255"><enum>(4)</enum><text>partner with one or more local educational agencies to support students with intellectual disabilities participating in the program who are eligible for special education and related services under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>), including the use of funds available under part B of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1411">20 U.S.C. 1411 et seq.</external-xref>) to support the participation of such students in the program.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA28E9658611342BA8407130CEA70E734"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>An institution of higher education (or consortium) that receives a grant under this section shall provide matching funds toward the cost of the inclusive higher education program for students with intellectual disabilities carried out under the grant. Such matching funds may be provided in cash or in-kind, and shall be in an amount of not less than 25 percent of the amount of such costs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HFEF899B07B944A9AAEBA8CE09F5D1CCA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Data Collection and Transmission</header> <paragraph id="HFD5F5AB1A7DB47BF99A1AF4C64A60850"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution or consortium receiving a grant under this section shall collect and transmit to the coordinating center established under section 777(b) on an annual basis for each student who is enrolled in the program, student-level information related to the experiences and outcomes of students who participate in the inclusive higher education program for students with intellectual disabilities.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1582980F876743D0882DC1871A100ACF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Longitudinal data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grantee shall collect longitudinal outcome data from each student participating in the program and transmit such data to the coordinating center established under section 777(b). Such longitudinal data shall be collected for every student each year for 5 years after the student graduates from, or otherwise exits, the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA910C03113B74D058B401B470C144AD8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Data to be collected</header><text>The program-level information and data and student-level information and data to be collected under this subsection shall include—</text>
<subparagraph id="HA440E2E095C4437CB22BAF14D7223385"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number and type of postsecondary education courses taken and completed by the student;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H55628F0C3F8B4829ACB35328445A8632" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>academic outcomes;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H031365FEDC254954AE8489B664CB4F89"><enum>(C)</enum><text>competitive, integrated employment outcomes;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H740694F4D19F4B99B999A5A9203F7358"><enum>(D)</enum><text>independent living outcomes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4FEA831943AD4D468530020C29371F3E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>social outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B7BD77919834980991FF23C8152AE24"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the first grant awarded under this section, the Secretary shall prepare and disseminate a report to the authorizing committees and to the public that—</text>
<paragraph id="H2310088AA4764C6C856CDC1CAAA16F6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviews the activities of the inclusive higher education programs for students with intellectual disabilities funded under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC110C70D3EDC4581B3FEC92BFFC0D62A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides guidance and recommendations on how effective programs can be replicated.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H93F6C75254924F15B020D351CF4BB7DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 769(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140i">20 U.S.C. 1140i</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2009</quote> and inserting <quote>2023</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H2A76DB03E9004964A72E7B589E77E06E"><enum>105.</enum><header>National Technical Assistance Center and National Coordinating Center for Inclusion of Students with Intellectual Disabilities</header> <subsection id="HC5A0AB3CF4304FCABAA266210328DC00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 777 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140q">20 U.S.C. 1140q</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0BEBF46A82564967AA82AF5C5050C297" style="OLC">
<section id="HDA28760BE71749EF8A614128206693E4"><enum>777.</enum><header>National Technical Assistance Center and Coordinating Center for Inclusion of Students with Intellectual Disabilities</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="H65DBD8D0C6244677B8C117DFBC2FC3EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National Technical Assistance Center</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H702AA75B13DE4B2EBD82838BC0B62C00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under paragraph (5), the Secretary shall award a grant to, or enter into a contract or cooperative agreement with, an eligible entity to provide for the establishment and support of a National Technical Assistance Center. The National Technical Assistance Center shall carry out the duties set forth in paragraph (4).</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H7888F49E936D4B0EAD96B9A5DA56AEE4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The program under this section shall be administered by the office in the Department that administers other postsecondary education programs in consultation with the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HA7455645CF054190A0D93CE31A7B1B4B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>In this subpart, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an institution of higher education, a nonprofit organization, or partnership of two or more such institutions or organizations, with demonstrated expertise in—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H72BDBACED248464A87F7DAF7B8993D75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>transitioning students with disabilities from secondary school to postsecondary education;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4481857B5D2478FAC76DAFA188D5AFE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>supporting students with disabilities in postsecondary education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3AA33820DD264E318ED0E8DDA2FA776C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technical knowledge necessary for the dissemination of information in accessible formats; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB51CCEB2D2BD49AC8961AB10A58AB1F9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>working with diverse types of institutions of higher education, including community colleges.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFD3880032309471195E3FA919BD187F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the National Technical Assistance Center shall include the following:</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H993D5B94D2CE49C284CCB2DBF9FD00AA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assistance to students and families</header><text>The National Technical Assistance Center shall provide information and technical assistance to students with disabilities and the families of students with disabilities to support students across the broad spectrum of disabilities, including—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H2F106C662CDF47238E9EC60D9184E8CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>information to assist individuals with disabilities who are prospective students of an institution of higher education in planning for postsecondary education while the students are in secondary school;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="HA01FE18A6C7C458E9974E117E5C6C160"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>information and technical assistance provided to individualized education program teams (as defined in section 614(d)(1) of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act) for secondary school students with disabilities, and to early outreach and student services programs, including programs authorized under subparts 2, 4, and 5 of part A of title IV, to support students across a broad spectrum of disabilities with the successful transition to postsecondary education;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HCB96C5EF3F44498484E30C36F24FF027"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>research-based supports, services, and accommodations which are available in postsecondary settings, including services provided by other agencies such as vocational rehabilitation;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H3D28DA0474694DF2A81B7B20DDD3A8A7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>information on student mentoring and networking opportunities for students with disabilities; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8E80F6A023FC41798B76614E24C6DE09"><enum>(v)</enum><text>effective recruitment and transition programs at postsecondary educational institutions.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9809AFD123A947D6979A94217E7380B5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assistance to institutions of higher education</header><text>The National Technical Assistance Center shall provide information and technical assistance to faculty, staff, and administrators of institutions of higher education to improve the services provided to, the accommodations for, the retention rates of, and the completion rates of, students with disabilities in higher education settings, which may include—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H61F7BF1D25544BEA81DC616B15422BC0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>collection and dissemination of best and promising practices and materials for accommodating and supporting students with disabilities, including practices and materials supported by the grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements authorized under subparts 1, 2, and 3;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H111A6D5186974D94A8E8279646375FAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>development and provision of training modules for higher education faculty on exemplary practices for accommodating and supporting postsecondary students with disabilities across a range of academic fields, which may include universal design for learning and practices supported by the grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements authorized under subparts 1, 2, and 3; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HDC5FA52779B74D46A537A6A0017E3A18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>development of technology-based tutorials for higher education faculty and staff, including new faculty and graduate students, on best and promising practices related to support and retention of students with disabilities in postsecondary education.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H2ABBBDDD9EB244F0A6EF8FD88B1AC18E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Information collection and dissemination</header><text>The National Technical Assistance Center shall be responsible for building, maintaining, and updating a database of disability support services information with respect to institutions of higher education, or for expanding and updating an existing database of disabilities support services information with respect to institutions of higher education. Such database shall be available to the general public through a website built to high technical standards of accessibility practicable for the broad spectrum of individuals with disabilities. Such database and website shall include available information on—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H7EB1F5DB7D1745C099D3A74EF508CB67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>disability documentation requirements;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H5AA107D3A8934596B42D1DBAB9653970"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support services available;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HE7FBA695C0904337AD946F4C91D478B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>links to financial aid;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H40BCF37250CA4CB4855CCD1BDE92D0A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>accommodations policies;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HD4E7A124A40246CF9B78AE6FAFF010E2"><enum>(v)</enum><text>accessible instructional materials;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H55C8290BE0784300978329A81F542688"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other topics relevant to students with disabilities; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H4DD060651E6C448785B7F1191126058C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the information in the report described in subparagraph (E).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9626B2678F2845BDBA52DDD6E84F4FE2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Disability support services</header><text>The National Technical Assistance Center shall work with organizations and individuals with proven expertise related to disability support services for postsecondary students with disabilities to evaluate, improve, and disseminate information related to the delivery of high quality disability support services at institutions of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H2E6B40C8892E40E388D74A1DB29C42A0"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Review and report</header><text>Not later than three years after the establishment of the National Technical Assistance Center, and every two years thereafter, the National Technical Assistance Center shall prepare and disseminate a report to the Secretary and the authorizing committees analyzing the condition of postsecondary success for students with disabilities. Such report shall include—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="H88559DD9D5EB49B49014199503D0C925"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a review of the activities and the effectiveness of the programs authorized under this part;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H3675F79079F449819BB8FA51ADF5DE98"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>annual enrollment and graduation rates of students with disabilities in institutions of higher education from publicly reported data;</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H7A003CC1893940818029CC97AD923F18"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>recommendations for effective postsecondary supports and services for students with disabilities, and how such supports and services may be widely implemented at institutions of higher education;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H89F62222CA654C98BFD469EDAB9C9D1E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>recommendations on reducing barriers to full participation for students with disabilities in higher education; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H3EE19254257A464780C7864B07FA4025"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a description of strategies with a demonstrated record of effectiveness in improving the success of such students in postsecondary education.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBC6FF52D840A44D58CFA3D7EA66BA962"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Staffing of the center</header><text>In hiring employees of the National Technical Assistance Center, the National Technical Assistance Center shall consider the expertise and experience of prospective employees in providing training and technical assistance to practitioners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE15E9E1B4A1C459C9859C22C8AD0A9B2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subsection $10,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5F41A77CF0CD47308241799A6B4CFECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>The National Coordinating Center for Inclusion of Students with Intellectual Disabilities</header> <paragraph id="H36E261A475084D57BE552C76E22175D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of eligible entity</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity, or a partnership of entities, that has demonstrated expertise in the fields of—</text>
<subparagraph id="H65816B88BEE84575B5575ED012041600"><enum>(A)</enum><text>higher education;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF6B3F15609924FA4ACE11D4008B4ED26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the education of students with intellectual disabilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2DA375CF4217489A9AFFC448058761C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the development of inclusive higher education programs for students with intellectual disabilities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB71B789800D49B29394778CB446B521"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evaluation and technical assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAAB1A0BA09F74026ADCF003C915444AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts appropriated under paragraph (7), the Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement, on a competitive basis, with an eligible entity for the purpose of establishing a coordinating center for institutions of higher education that offer inclusive higher education programs for students with intellectual disabilities, including institutions participating in grants authorized under subpart 2 to provide—</text> <subparagraph id="H9B287EA585FA4A9B861C6CD6D2348FB4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recommendations related to the development of standards for such programs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFB9D07F6587A4E44B16FF35799198425" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technical assistance for such programs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H67BB8CF3B1C644C68C898D248ED9A7AC" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluations for such programs, including systematic collection of data on the experiences and outcomes of individuals with intellectual disabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B51926794384B71A96735D88CB5BF77"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program under this subsection shall be administered by the Office of Postsecondary Education, in collaboration with the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H165BDA4530B745D8A438AF6F9E2F6C0C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into a cooperative agreement under this subsection for a period of five years.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H04C0293798304D21B43C140912151DA2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements of cooperative agreement</header><text>The eligible entity entering into a cooperative agreement under this subsection shall establish and maintain a coordinating center that shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H841FEE334A9E437B9AE405F394DEEED0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serve as the technical assistance entity for all inclusive higher education programs and comprehensive transition and postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA81A9FB23A084137AB862F4E3A716ABE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide technical assistance regarding the development, evaluation, and continuous improvement of such programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6406B57BC4241199C26E18E3B7E50D0"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate such programs using qualitative and quantitative methodologies for measuring program strengths in the areas of academic access, academic enrichment, socialization, competitive integrated employment, attainment of a degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential, and independent living;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8CF5CE8F361F4C40AD2D4376F7E889B5" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate participant progress by creating and maintaining a database of student-level information and data related to the experiences and outcomes of youth who participate in each inclusive higher education program that receives a grant under this subpart;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07C82B5441CF492796E4FF6E4A7A7B8E" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create and maintain a mechanism for continuing to collect outcome information from students who participated in inclusive higher education programs that were developed in previous grant award cycles;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9849DA4A5F4049D1866CFE91DD31B304" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist recipients of a grant under this subpart in efforts to award a meaningful credential and to seek institution of higher education approval for any newly developed credentials;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE0F887A1AE72407A8CB0C93255CB5606"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create and maintain a database of student and program level data reflecting implementation of the inclusive higher education program that receives a grant under this subpart;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3D2E65C3502A474085AEBE46DDEFE118"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create and maintain a mechanism to consolidate follow up data on student outcomes collected by inclusive higher education programs funded through previous grant cycles;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H49C89CC32D374A40ADF4D468CE2DDF88"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist recipients of grants under subpart 2 in efforts to award a degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential to students with intellectual disabilities upon the completion of such programs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4571881902E14106BD1420EAA2BF0C77"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify model memoranda of agreement for use between or among institutions of higher education and State and local agencies providing funding for such programs;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE45BB346E93842F78C2CF0D5A2133229"><enum>(K)</enum><text>develop recommendations for the necessary components of such programs, such as—</text>
<clause id="H53CECB42C4DF4C7083CF72EDAB756DD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>academic, career and technical, social, and independent living skills;</text></clause> <clause id="H33A2D9AA5D6B4A338C6E192F964D1ECF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evaluation of student progress;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA1D77443FD9341F3BB47DE15678E3A1B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>program administration and evaluation;</text></clause> <clause id="H81D8C932424B415AB1BBCBF25752507D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>student eligibility;</text></clause>
<clause id="H347455D40FEC4014B32FF9B23BB4A48F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>issues regarding the equivalency of a student’s participation in such programs to semester, trimester, quarter, credit, or clock hours at an institution of higher education, as the case may be; and</text></clause> <clause id="H8E39B1DFD3D54245BBE8B6E73FFF72E8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>access to student housing for students participating in the inclusive higher education programs, including accommodations and services that support independent living;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE8EBA9760664D34957E9AD31CA5937C"><enum>(L)</enum><text>review and analyze—</text> <clause id="H886992F367EA4C629CA50BAF2A84BAF8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of Federal and State legislation on inclusive higher education and inclusive higher education policy; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9BB06A97F2C74DFBA2D9CB82D5F1DD49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>funding streams for such programs;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2F7895E818A04460AE96EE085F07B289"><enum>(M)</enum><text>provide recommendations regarding the funding streams described in paragraph (H)(ii);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5D8D151CC86142F5B31214AEB8C89DC4"><enum>(N)</enum><text>develop mechanisms for regular communication, outreach and dissemination of information about inclusive higher education programs for students with intellectual disabilities under subpart 2 between or among such programs and to families and prospective students;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFFF3B2923D994BBA9588B06735492A8C"><enum>(O)</enum><text>host a meeting of all recipients of grants under subpart 2 not less often than once each year; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC529EC59160D40B8B80C6BDB7D86989D"><enum>(P)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">convene a work group to continue the development of and recommendations for model criteria, standards, and components of inclusive higher education programs and comprehensive transition and postsecondary programs for students with intellectual disabilities, that are appropriate for the development of accreditation standards—</text> <clause id="HF35A89E955394965ACC3CA7932F572F7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which work group shall include—</text>
<subclause id="HB5324F12543E4A5AA502FA7BAA02B7C8" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an expert in community college education;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8BAD4A4949664449968CECA2DEA231E1" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an expert in career technical education;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HDE69FADAEFB045B4A04D9FDF855074AC" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an expert in 4-year institutions of higher education;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4AD3AD7AD8FD47F8BA39F115034BE0AC"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>an expert in special education;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB3F38DA119514DE7B2D6B084B3C72B4B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a disability organization that represents students with intellectual disabilities;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H353F68A5E8A14E269F66379DC4B11139"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a representative from the National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H663002B8973445FD8F525D6B41FCA74B"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>a representative of a regional or national accreditation agency or association; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA9042811953547FB970AF06F67996F3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the work group will carry out the following activities—</text>
<subclause id="HDAC9DEEADDE74968A39156C537670B69"><enum>(I)</enum><text>conduct outreach to accrediting agencies;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H20CAEC946F25491CBC2ACA848331E83C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>develop a technical guidance document to support implementation of the model standards;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H22ED44A4026F4B1994DE641BA2274536"><enum>(III)</enum><text>develop and conduct a protocol for field testing and implementing the model standards; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HEC2D544543E34D9DAA785572C8B9FC0B"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>update recommendations for the model standards, criteria, and components of such programs, as applicable.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H085A1A71039441DCABB388E04B798EC1"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the establishment of the coordinating center under this subsection, the coordinating center shall report to the Secretary, the authorizing committees, and the National Advisory Committee on Institutional Quality and Integrity on the activities described in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB52434DCE19847EDB97F0411448D452E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this subpart such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2023 and each of the five succeeding fiscal years.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HC6E0B2E8488347FE92350B18D46C7953"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 778 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is repealed.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8EF6E7B3D969473DAC9FCA13F90289EE"><enum>106.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 760 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1140">20 U.S.C. 1140</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H51AEC8569FA44D758966CC730A3A8E42" style="OLC">
<section id="H27D2F64FBD0840FABC2AE3338DBFD2EC"><enum>760.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this part:</text> <paragraph id="HBF661DF01F5B4801B5C31F097DEACF46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Comprehensive transition and postsecondary program for students with intellectual disabilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>comprehensive transition and postsecondary program for students with intellectual disabilities</term> means a program that leads to a degree, certificate, or recognized postsecondary credential issued by an institution of higher education that meets each of the following requirements:</text>
<subparagraph id="H3F54890DB4784A3FA2ED6F28D0F9D3D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Is offered by an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H315174F6B32A4762B74A0F6D012F328B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Is designed to support students with intellectual disabilities who are seeking to continue academic, career and technical, and independent living instruction at an institution of higher education in order to prepare for competitive integrated employment.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35B1B2811A3C49388879D2A21D8947AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Includes student advising and a program of study.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E388CA67122463EB0C0A56622091143"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Requires students with intellectual disabilities to participate on not less than a half-time basis as determined by the institution, with such participation focusing on academic and career development components and occurring through one or more of the following activities:</text>
<clause id="H7CF24EE9E44C4D84B488723CFAFA9BE6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Regular enrollment in credit-bearing courses with students without disabilities that are offered by the institution.</text></clause> <clause id="H4377B78C9B8E4306B550AB753F15A974"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Auditing or participating in courses with students without disabilities that are offered by the institution and for which the student does not receive regular academic credit.</text></clause>
<clause id="H0623FACD649C4ED4A2C586D0A69DEC64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Enrollment in noncredit-bearing, nondegree courses with students without disabilities.</text></clause> <clause id="H4647B5CE4E214065AA8454FEA799FD2C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Participation in internships, apprenticeships, or work-based experiences in competitive integrated settings for a semester, or multiple semesters.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A902D034DF84022B763E534FE2EA225"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Requires students with intellectual disabilities to be socially and academically integrated with students without disabilities to the maximum extent practicable.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H09DF2C367022403EA1D5CA838B1DC187" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Does not require the work components (ii) to occur each semester.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H794F06D6BAD142FC87FC936ABD754601"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD12BB0D173304693B4CB1557629CDB9D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE35684229F345F4BA8AED262DC3A2D2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Office of accessibility</header><text>The term <term>Office of Accessibility</term> has the meaning given to the office of disability services of the institution or equivalent office.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF572A89F57CC4B67A55E1CD6F18A0383"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential</header><text>The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HADFAFDC3E1484C1C9959C1098F7E6DB3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Student with an intellectual disability</header><text>The term <term>student with an intellectual disability</term> means a student—</text> <subparagraph id="H22E3CE0019044D95B4296AE9F177FF65"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a cognitive impairment, characterized by significant limitations in—</text>
<clause id="H03A9816DA2944FC88DE9A2C66E6EDB6C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intellectual and cognitive functioning; and</text></clause> <clause id="H71C0D6A6CD5A447690168217B8B54826"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adaptive behavior as expressed in conceptual, social, and practical adaptive skills;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7BB0DD9A97EE4D5182A28CD990961A7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is currently, or was formerly, eligible for a free appropriate public education under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28773362FF78458A8713876ADF26F7AC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>or, in the case of a student who has not currently or formerly been found eligible for a free appropriate education under the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1400">20 U.S.C. 1400 et seq.</external-xref>), or a student who has not previously been found eligible as a student with an intellectual disability under such Act, documentation establishing that the student has an intellectual disability, such as—</text>
<clause id="H135FB6666EF649479D9F9C0D0BCF6CEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a documented comprehensive and individualized psycho-educational evaluation and diagnosis of an intellectual disability by a psychologist or other qualified professional; or</text></clause> <clause id="HB613B941A7534ECDA0CBA8675D2D47F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a record of the disability from a local or State educational agency, or government agency, such as the Social Security Administration or a vocational rehabilitation agency, that identifies the intellectual disability.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC8F00AB41F0040E7A5304EDFE89D2AF7"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Universal design for learning</header><text>The term <term>universal design for learning</term> means a scientifically valid framework for guiding educational practice that—</text> <subparagraph id="HBCAC8A52871044BA8BBE2637B4C9BEE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides flexibility in the ways information is presented, in the ways students respond or demonstrate knowledge and skills, and in the ways students are engaged; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9EBF140A621E47909915C748CDE95F0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>reduces barriers in instruction, provides appropriate accommodations, supports, and challenges and maintains high achievement expectations for all students, including students with disabilities and students who are limited English proficient.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></title> <title id="HB7AFA2D89FAB42FB8BAD9FC13A74B481"><enum>II</enum><header>Miscellaneous provisions</header> <section id="H147F16FDE80E49D9B779C261F9B94EE7"><enum>201.</enum><header>Submission of data with respect to students with disabilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1094">20 U.S.C. 1094(a)</external-xref>), is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45074B318E8D4F358A8D8B4D2C5B2F1E" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HBCE05122FDF44582948E6A3B125491E8"><enum>(30)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution will submit, for inclusion in the Integrated Postsecondary Education Data System of the Department or any other Federal postsecondary institution data collection effort, key data related to undergraduate and graduate students enrolled at the institution who are formally registered as students with disabilities with the institution’s office of accessibility, including the total number of students with disabilities enrolled, the number of students accessing or receiving accommodation, the percentage of students with disabilities of all undergraduate students, and the total number of undergraduate certificates or degrees awarded to students with disabilities. An institution shall not be required to submit the information described in the preceding sentence if the number of such students would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> <section commented="no" id="H2598997772FB4CAF98D81F7AF535B9E6"><enum>202.</enum><header>Training for realtime writers to provide closed captioning and court reporting services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 872(e) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161s">20 U.S.C. 1161s(e)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2009</quote> and inserting <quote>2023</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="H8F41EC46D1D5429DAEBBA173FD5932AB"><enum>203.</enum><header>Perfecting amendment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103(6) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003(6)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 3(2)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3</quote>.</text></section></title> </legis-body> </bill> 

