<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEC577CB8FC714616BA99ABEC2BD3699B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7979 IH: Securing Our Schools Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7979</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220608">June 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow certain funds provided in response to the public health emergency with respect to COVID–19 to be made available for school security measures, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50818DDEAB6D4130B35896A04B69862A" style="OLC"><section id="H54228A9120E54E8E923C25FEBBA5FF02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing Our Schools Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H6659BE27645248D28B3A538E3E99C807"><enum>2.</enum><header>Availability of funds for school security measures</header><subsection id="H366C7BD3841C4351B35895863458E455"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the unobligated balance of amounts made available under section 602 or 603 of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 802 and 803) to any State, territory, Tribal government, metropolitan city, or other units of local government (as such terms are defined for purposes of such sections) may be made available to carry out school security measures.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FEF0D0F8DC3482EBA77238A0EFBB8ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Nonrequirement of response to public health emergency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The use of amounts pursuant to the authority provided by subsection (a) shall not be required to be in response to, or in any way connected with, COVID–19 or the public health emergency with respect to COVID–19.</text></subsection><subsection id="H92EA3E29C44442E2B84BC5610A8F5939"><enum>(c)</enum><header>School security measure</header><text>For purposes of this Act, the term <term>school security measure</term> means any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H52587EF828C74BD6A9C5AA4040D4B204"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An evidence-based strategy or program to prevent violence, which may include the use of appropriate technologies, including the placement and use of metal detectors and other deterrent measures and emergency notification and response technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0694A9C0D1A94071BBDBB7E284F38313"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Training to prevent student violence against others and self, including training for local law enforcement officers, school personnel, and students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB28BEE9C75F4238AA01A7AD43BA1A79"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The development and operation of an anonymous reporting system for threats of school violence, including a mobile telephone application, hotline, or internet website.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79E213F3C6194735B42CDCC476775A57"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The development and operation of—</text><subparagraph id="H3F9735154EFC48D2A741E852135275FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a school threat assessment and intervention team that may include coordination with law enforcement agencies and school personnel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5655F1113B7E44E79086E2854CBCD0C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specialized training for school officials in responding to mental health crises.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H184AEA05416049FEBACE2CFC3FBD6824"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Coordination with local law enforcement agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC0DA6AD6C53434590A747D74820C1C6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A security assessment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF736B0E1C5BB4FA99CE089C55D8C7311"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Security training of personnel and students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2D9549A8974DC4A9D220DBB247D093"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Acquisition and installation of technology for expedited notification of local law enforcement during an emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74289F9E61594997BE938B2BAFA3547C"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Reinforcing or replacing classroom doors, locks, or window panels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53E6F662B2B34E5196CAD2B26C8DFB40"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Constructing fencing, bollards, planters, curbs, walls, or any other entry control measure to create a single point of entry to the campus.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80F49AF56A494C038DB378BFB94E3012"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Clearing exterior spaces of foliage or structures to eliminate spaces that could conceal illicit activity, provide access to the building above the first floor, or otherwise aid an intruder.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC678068010EE45A68E4224FB6DB0168C"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Installing a system to monitor hallways, stairwells, and utility rooms, such as physical inspection or surveillance cameras.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39652355E632438CA3A28CC18E22DA4F"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Hiring and paying the salaries of qualified individuals, such as retired law enforcement officers or military veterans, to serve as armed school resource officers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

