<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H27EB083D7D224461B4A9CF1609BA1729" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8375 IH: To establish the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park in the State of Illinois, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8375</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220714">July 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park in the State of Illinois, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8BCB3BF4840C448F97180686E0B27899" style="OLC"><section id="HA242CAA0EF504D1181486F53EA52EFA3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings; purposes</header><subsection id="H9A06725C7F624A8CBA985585A06DCD61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following: </text><paragraph id="H8BB73B6E783844C58337199A1261720E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Prairie du Rocher and the French Colonial Historic District are the finest historical and architectural examples of French Colonial Heritage in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H458B608E255443D1972DF9E4AE1C1757"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Kaskaskia, Fort de Chartres and Prairie du Rocher once served as the western boundary of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72A76A13861543FD905FBD2841A683AF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 1763, Pierre Laclede Liguest quartered in the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial District in the Winter of and founded St. Louis in February of 1764.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD49900645CC74475805D6FE306E0149F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On July 4, 1778, General George Rogers Clark, with the assistance of Father Pierre Gibault, captured Prairie du Rocher and the Village of Kaskaskia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27EDDA6092E4C0C8C4D1FB7CCF6316C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On November 28, 1803, Meriwether Lewis and William Clark visited the Village of Kaskaskia, seeking Engages and troops to accompany them on the Lewis and Clark Expedition.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H257D3DE3BF9E4769A5CE4B7BAA5885FF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1818, Kaskaskia served as the first State Capital of Illinois.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E6BB571259645188301EC1CE657E564"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 1825, General Marie-Joseph-Paul-Yves-Roch-Gilbert du Montier de Lafayette visited the Village of Kaskaskia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13C3F0CB063F47B4A15EF2C0A69330BB"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1960, Fort de Chartres, the French seat of government and primary military station on the upper Mississippi River, erected in 1720, was declared a National Historic Landmark.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46295D32063142E4BF666D1017F13776"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In 1966, Fort de Chartres and the Modoc Rock Shelter were declared National Historic Landmarks.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF0EE265402411B9D647B9DF11FD0F4"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1973, the Creole House in Prairie du Rocher was added to the National Registry of Historic Places.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4450A3975F1A423683B53DBD070948C3"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 1974, Prairie du Rocher and the French Colonial Historic District, an area of 22 square miles, was created and added to the National Registry of Historic Places, along with the ancient Kolmer Indian site.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H115E24653F794F6398F44AFA71793D09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are to—</text><paragraph id="H9FA4A19B959644FD9B96F0B4C2D5D261"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recognize the importance of Prairie du Rocher and the French Colonial Historic District as a nationally significant architectural village of the cultural heritage of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C20BB9358EB4494B809617A3BB91F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park to serve as the focus of interpretive and educational programs on the history of the French Colonial Historic District, and to assist in the preservation of historic sites within the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial Historic District.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFB783CC84E00495581EFA76EFC3F58C0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park</header><subsection id="HDAAB3CCCCB314E15B0EAE341471DAED0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to assist in the preservation and interpretation of, and education concerning, of Prairie du Rocher and the French Colonial Historic District, and to provide technical assistance to a broad range of public and private landowners and preservation organizations, there is hereby established the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park in the State of Illinois.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36B5BDC57CCD4C0F818ACC067222B00C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Area included</header><text>The historical park shall consist of lands and interests therein as follows:</text><paragraph id="HB2D59346F61E4E87930134D0EB0C6ABF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Lands and structures associated with—</text><subparagraph id="H73BD86751559459AB4C8AE730FA8F5D9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Creole House (1800), a French creole vernacular post in ground (poteaux-sur-sol) construction—one of only five remaining in the United States; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5C954FE376441CB72570910167BF06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Pierre Menard Home (1803) Menard was the first Lieutenant Governor of Illinois; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E5F26F41574A01AD950A86F8DF8857"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Doiron Bienvenue House, post in ground (poteaux-sur-sol) construction (1860).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19E2FE535641423497A973D3CBEF0001"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A portion of the Fort Kaskaskia State Historic Site, a 200-acre park, which celebrates the vanished frontier Village of Kaskaskia, is home to the earthen remains of Fort Kaskaskia, and preserves Garrison Hill Cemetery, where Pierre Menard and dozens of veterans are interred.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB66697D192644EE28F8EE0DCDB1464D6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any Federal land acquired under section 5 and used as in interpretive visitor center complex for the historical park. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H181378C57C674C8B9E5358B78C745FA0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Administration; management</header><subsection id="H2967AE90DFA74EE8AA5F75A238526896"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the historical park in accordance with this title and with provisions of law generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text><paragraph id="HED32A1F4AE4A46FB826CB57F4B506DD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">section 100502 of title 54, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDC00349C7EE45008B4D2EBC0C28E895"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3AA3E847E9FE41C7BB3E7EBED02261B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Management</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall manage the historical park in such a manner as will preserve resources and cultural landscapes relating to the history of the historic district and to enhance public understanding of the important cultural heritage of the historic district.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0F034330CD2D4811A2E1B8760B10B160"><enum>4.</enum><header>Interpretive visitor center complex</header><subsection id="H374BE495B36C40DCB74B53E00EA29190"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HA99B9C035C8A4A93914DE4580D115B10"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Construction; lease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to construct on Federal land or lease space to operate and to maintain an interpretive visitor center complex to provide for the general information and orientation needs of the historical park and the historic district and serve the needs of the historical park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B58AABA9764490FBD2B6BC9AABEA5DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When the planning and development of the interpretive visitor center complex, the Secretary shall consult with—</text><subparagraph id="H5970B85E894945A2860E03563A67E64D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the State of Illinois;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35F8A9D5777B40CD9D1EF0408C8C0E83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Randolph County;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2ED7E444AAE349F58864B500EAF21EC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Village of Prairie du Rocher; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF0EEEF19DBE4690B590772CC8A503C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Illinois Department of Natural Resources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD5B0865A8CB4471B120C2B2DA28D82D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to enter into cooperative agreements for the development of the interpretive visitor center complex, educational programs, and other materials to facilitate public use of the historical park and historic district with—</text><paragraph id="H54B7F2B378E04F8CB25A8BBEF1AB08C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State of Illinois;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9334DED52443F9AE5DC9C6680BD5B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Randolph County;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEACAF7C88CC147889A5C24DF3AEACF57"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Village of Prairie du Rocher; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB850B94A52B4BAE9D086A69402D7EF4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Illinois Department of Natural Resources.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H42C451C4A741444596800B9A04560C93"><enum>5.</enum><header>Acquisition of property</header><subsection id="H50A0FA3B043A4D089720578E7EC46EFF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authority</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, the Secretary is authorized to acquire lands and interests therein within the boundaries of the historical park by donation, purchase with donated or appropriated funds, and exchange.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEF2C64116845458CA0DE92EA19029474"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State and local properties</header><text>Lands and interests therein that are owned by the State of Illinois, or any political subdivision thereof, may be acquired only by donation or exchange.</text></subsection></section><section id="H13F40A0310DC46BAA4BD2A548258610A"><enum>6.</enum><header>Donations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary may accept and retain donations of funds, property, or services from individuals, foundations, or other public or private entities for the purposes of providing programs, services, facilities, or technical assistance that further the purposes of this Act. Any funds donated to the Secretary pursuant to this section may be expended without further appropriation.</text></section><section id="HDBF8A400C45B485BB91959B4378DD9E0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Grant Assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary is authorized to make grants to park partners for projects not requiring Federal involvement other than providing financial assistance, subject to the availability of appropriations in advance identifying the specific grantee and the specific project. Projects funded through grants under this section shall—</text><paragraph id="HF5D345EF114A42B093CE1D74FA1F7A7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be used only for construction and development on non-Federal property within the boundaries of the historic district;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98F209ED21D94F04BFFBC65661F1D006"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the purposes of the historical park; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB025ABA54F194EDD8D3689CCBA32C5E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enhance public use and enjoyment of the historical park.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H98EF5D38F6C44BFA8FA8D1CB0E6AFFDC"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7B2BD6DBCF434F33A6839BD0DAA42FE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Historic district</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>historic district</term> means the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial Historic District listed on the National Registry of Historic Places. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84817D2E76EA46D28F49FB921C47E764"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historical park</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>historical park</term> means the Prairie du Rocher French Colonial National Historical Park established by section 2(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFC90766FC3B4DFB930112062765052A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

