<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H62BE5CD7E7BC42C998D4D7F7EF9D7AB1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7804 IH: Law Enforcement Officer Safety and Security Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7804</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220517">May 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001194">Mr. Moolenaar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow qualified current or former law enforcement officers to purchase their service weapons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26D929BBDFAD41A683F2500275ABC179" style="OLC"><section id="H5BB183F03FD9439EB62C65B6AEDAE5FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Law Enforcement Officer Safety and Security Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HA62A0AC8266F4E9C8F1F055855129969"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purchase of service weapons by qualified current or former law enforcement officers</header><subsection id="H8E38CE4EE13E407C85478A20554AF721"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subsection (b), an agency shall offer for sale at fair market value a single, functional firearm, which would otherwise be destroyed, to an individual—</text><paragraph id="HE9E3AE0EF9CA4F9392C156E9FB88D4D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>who is—</text><subparagraph id="HE31CE2144ADD45FBA5ACD251B39DC496"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a law enforcement officer employed by and in good standing with such agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AA00A87A81A4E7B862187974751C2BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a former law enforcement officer separated from the employ of such agency for reasons other than misconduct, neglect of duty, or malfeasance; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFBB611E1046490688BE1A287B6A3CAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to whom such agency most recently issued such firearm.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAABCD3BEFFE44AF5A2C99223A3782029"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Background check required</header><paragraph id="H9D9931C74C1B4308A98397A5A432D438"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency may not sell a firearm to an individual under subsection (a) of this section until the national instant criminal background check system established under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>) has notified the agency that receipt of a firearm by the individual would not violate subsection (g) or (n) of section 922 of title 18, United States Code, or State law, unless paragraph (1) of section 922(t) of title 18, United States Code, would not apply to the transfer by reason of paragraph (3) of such section 922(t) if the agency were a licensee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CBDF09DF397491EBEF62ED7905D964F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communication between a Federal agency and NICS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purpose of the sale of a firearm under subsection (a) of this section, an agency may contact the national instant criminal background check system in the same manner as a licensee is authorized to contact the system under section 103 of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901</external-xref>), for information on whether receipt of a firearm by a prospective buyer would violate section 922 of title 18, United States Code, or State law, and the system may respond to such contact as if the agency were a licensee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3E95D4CD4FF42BEB79B54CB0D19BAD8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HFED0E48695D245BA9D6C900033FB99D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A47DB30120B4203ABE5D38EB6B1277A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>firearm</term> means a pistol or revolver.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9DAB636940A484EA1F1B5A6E4084A17"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Good standing</header><text>The term <term>good standing</term> means, with respect to an individual who is a law enforcement officer, that the individual—</text><subparagraph id="HEC6D84615B3D4DF38B09E78A263DF75D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not currently the subject of any disciplinary action by the employing agency of such individual, which could result in permanent loss of police powers and removal from such agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98067F0DAFE64B9F8D6D5BA5E95B8B4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is not prohibited by Federal law from receiving a firearm.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H669B5389BB8C411089E28C9C5CEAC561"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given such term under section 8401 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73E31626B4664C53B3C7A0CAF009075C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Licensee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>licensee</term> has the meaning given such term in section 103(j)(1) of the Brady Handgun Violence Prevention Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40901">34 U.S.C. 40901(j)(1)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

