<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0110CAC26FAC468E82F0C40E5217A333" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6562 IH: Carbon Limiting Emissions At Refineries Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6562</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220202">February 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Energy Policy Act of 2005 to require the Secretary of Energy to create a plan for research, development, and commercialization projects capable of making significant reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions or carbon intensity of qualified fuel production facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H44B4879BCFBD48558CC450B3CAB367ED" style="OLC"><section id="HE33E7F4F205742AFB5AB13F83094C6A3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Carbon Limiting Emissions At Refineries Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLEAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H77FB93F367D64662B491A2885E2F5BBB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Carbon emissions and intensity reduction technologies for qualified fuel production facilities</header><subsection id="H78DF2CDF8BF743B3B5A7A65A0EF58A95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Carbon reduction program</header><text>Section 962 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16292">42 U.S.C. 16292</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H46AC373EA91245B2A3D16243DAC3BB24" style="OLC"><section id="HC4A49855D26C4E0CB2EB664D9F1636F2"><enum>962.</enum><header>Carbon emissions and intensity reduction for qualified fuel production facilities</header><subsection id="H282973510D8F402DA978947F260382D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Energy shall transmit to the Congress a plan outlining opportunities for research, development and commercialization projects capable of making significant reductions in global greenhouse gas emissions and/or carbon intensity of qualified fuel production facilities, including a road map for advancing the readiness level of such technologies from laboratory scale to industrial use for the 5-year period beginning on the date of the submission of the plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H32C85997581B45648DF68095DE56822C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the Secretary submits the plan under subsection (a) to Congress, the Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of carbon emissions and intensity reduction technologies based on such plan to facilitate the development of—</text><paragraph id="H3548D9BE2E7F44E7B9353D3D3557CB57"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promising research projects including but not limited to energy usage reductions, use of advanced catalysts, electrification of heat and steam generation, hydrogen firing, low grade waste heat recovery, membrane separations, and other process improvements that, with appropriate support, could produce commercially-feasible technologies capable of meaningfully lowering the global greenhouse gas emissions or carbon intensity of qualified fuel production facilities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E9A8559BD614B359CE69B4B5AE583A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>carbon capture and sequestration technologies for qualified fuel production facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD3ECAB5798F34D58A5325254A36BB5D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Demonstration projects</header><paragraph id="H6466B0C737204E4D97CF2FC92C59C0F8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (b), the Secretary may award funds for commercial-scale demonstration projects for qualified fuel production facilities that test the scale of technology necessary for commercial operation, in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B95F0C7286044ECA21E19F322FB5525"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Engineering and design studies</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (b), the Secretary may award funds for front-end engineering and design studies in addition to, or in advance of, issuing an award for a demonstration project under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE5543D086B04A4EA2C1E1D2470D78C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An entity seeking an award to conduct a demonstration project under this subsection shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BF259F83B68427DA3C661EDEBC50D1A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The Secretary shall only provide an award under this subsection after reviewing each applicant and application for—</text><subparagraph id="H010DFD4D80514991AE07EB75D5E9080E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>financial strength;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB34452F87F4C47CDA38153E5A7D0FE47"><enum>(B)</enum><text>construction schedule;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77643E92D94E461085A7DD11D582AD19"><enum>(C)</enum><text>market risk; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09BD10E57AE84ED4B938CA203A180630"><enum>(D)</enum><text>contractor history.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70AA80A3EAD643FD98ED364CBE18E87A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An awardee under this subsection shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE93E51A5AB1542189C8A2D2D870E2283"><enum>(A)</enum><text>utilize technologies that have completed pilot-scale testing or the equivalent, as determined by the Secretary;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45E54B2EC57F46F980AC12A8A740D7BB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>secure and maintain agreements for technologies designed to reduce carbon intensity of or otherwise lower net greenhouse gas emissions at, qualified fuel production facilities or for the utilization or sequestration of captured carbon dioxide; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7996E38EDCB34811B5940ACA11B87F1F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>upon completion, demonstrate greenhouse gas emissions and/or intensity reduction or carbon capture technologies utilized by a qualified fuel production facility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D45709D1A3F4DDDA31C3627E647BBD5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cost sharing</header><text>The Secretary shall require cost sharing under this subsection in accordance with section 988.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB5B5EAC089442319682F96D17BE8FA3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>No technology, or level of emission reduction, shall be treated as adequately demonstrated for purpose of section 111 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7411">42 U.S.C. 7411</external-xref>), achievable for purposes of section 169 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7479">42 U.S.C. 7479</external-xref>), or achievable in practice for purposes of section 171 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7501">42 U.S.C. 7501</external-xref>) solely by reason of the identification of such technology in reports or programs established under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB8C197046684767B6B42055BEF5B384"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualified fuel production facilities defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>qualified fuel production facilities</quote> means petroleum refineries or facilities that manufacture commercial amounts of drop-in fuel as defined in section 2922h(c)(1) of title 10, United States Code. </text></subsection><subsection id="H4A1AE4D65FD04850B8E06F9D8ACC29A5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>For activities under this section, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $200,000,000 annually to carry out its purpose.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

