<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B52817AA55E4BA0B55300814C5E239D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6735 IH: Supporting Access to Nurse Exams Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6735</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004 to increase access to Sexual Assault Nurse Examiners, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H10E7CBE83BB8454EA2A822E5BCC2810B" style="OLC"><section id="HD025E69D0A204089BE57A7D6B77CC3BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Access to Nurse Exams Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SANE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H04721EC649E247DB93970A2051A312E1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40723">34 U.S.C. 40723</external-xref>) is amended by striking subsections (a), (b), and (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H50239292E26A4422876AD42231D57962"><subsection id="HF830D2EDCC554294AC44244C71FB8106"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8FF0A2E62CE846BCBD5BB2B9E156A99D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Culturally competent</header><text>The term <term>culturally competent</term>, used with respect to services, supports, or other assistance, means services, supports, or other assistance that is conducted or provided in a manner that—</text><subparagraph id="H6B301D11D93D41BC9EED1AABDB90EAD0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is responsive to the beliefs, interpersonal styles, attitudes, languages, and behaviors of individuals receiving the services, supports, or other assistance; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43C0044DFEE74A918B14C4B802D322DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the greatest likelihood of ensuring the maximum participation of individuals receiving the services, supports, or other assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98D04DF3C27B47559C9916B84FDDFD5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H9BAD90F65FA34F1285F8AD20D7E2AC41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a Tribal government or hospital;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H704785F0502F4508BBC72D0824B4CCA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a sexual assault examination program, including—</text><clause id="HA37FB73745EF426782DB025FDC1DA853"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a SANE program;</text></clause><clause id="H8B5FFBC432D34434999CB56446A87A7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a SAFE program;</text></clause><clause id="HE0E3B43F94A04FEF852D5D5FEEEF8FF7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a SART program;</text></clause><clause id="H1D73657DA7FD409C80C40414E1883BF4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>medical personnel, including a doctor or nurse, involved in treating victims of sexual assault; and</text></clause><clause id="H055182AFD6F849C5B0F4FD5B8D57408C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a victim service provider involved in treating victims of sexual assault;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB68F9F242C2A4D319FCECDC2711D7D3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a State sexual assault coalition; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H726D309FC2C948239CECFA8E49B9445B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a health care facility, including a hospital that provides sexual assault forensic examinations by a qualified or certified SANE or SAFE; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H09A21CC34D1D442A89F5B6F895093D2C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a sexual assault examination program that provides SANE or SAFE training; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA8E32977A634E6C8B56554ED72965CD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a community-based program that provides sexual assault forensic examinations, including pediatric forensic exams in a multidisciplinary setting, by a qualified or certified SANE or SAFE outside of a traditional health care setting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4958BAF05DE4BFF917A654F1EA996F5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Health care facility</header><text>The term <term>health care facility</term> means any State, local, Tribal, community, free, nonprofit, academic, or private medical facility, including a hospital, that provides emergency medical care to patients.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF0FE90216EB400CAD9BE5A87B7133C1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Medical forensic examination; MFE</header><text>The term <term>medical forensic examination</term> or <quote>MFE</quote> means an examination of a sexual assault patient by a health care provider, who has specialized education and clinical experience in the collection of forensic evidence and treatment of these patients, which includes—</text><subparagraph id="H5F2E01CC3C0F4AB78362408E79AB3BC2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gathering information from the patient for the medical forensic history;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H048000F5E937404AAA74CED93EBBB27E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an examination; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H136EB36FD8BA4AE4B8EB765EB4F1218D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinating treatment of injuries, documentation of biological and physical findings, and collection of evidence from the patient; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86DBED4F7541495F8F853F5EB79E8CF2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>documentation of findings; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8474074F23048F699F313B29C3C3553"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing information, treatment, and referrals for sexually transmitted infections, pregnancy, suicidal ideation, alcohol and substance abuse, and other non-acute medical concerns; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4531BA58589C4FFC9CB973BE0AC9DF47"><enum>(F)</enum><text>providing follow-up as needed to provide additional healing, treatment, or collection of evidence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF358F1385004D5885276C43D0D3B68A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Pediatric SANE and SAFE</header><text>The term <term>pediatric SANE and SAFE</term> means a SANE or SAFE who is trained to conduct sexual assault forensic examinations on children and youth between the ages of 0 and 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAC75846FEA14026BA95D69B891F25BD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Qualified personnel</header><text>The term <term>qualified personnel</term> includes a registered or advanced practice nurse, physician, doctor of osteopathy, or physician assistant who has specialized training conducting medical forensic examinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB22D0911B5E464192546BDE47DFC6F6"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified SANE and SAFE training program</header><text>The term <term>qualified SANE and SAFE training program</term> means a program that—</text><subparagraph id="HC99F83AD25854A768FAD241CAEC10806"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is qualified to prepare current and future sexual assault nurse examiners to be profession-ready and meet the applicable State and National certification and licensure requirements, through didactic, clinical, preceptor, or capstone programs that include longer-term training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77BC944668F24BB4B88818E0699CC013"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides that preparation under a health care model that uses trauma-informed techniques; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D4406BB6DE64588974C9961EE5C6E7A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is approved as meeting the most recent National Training Standards for Sexual Assault Medical Forensic Examiners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EF870B6D53E4DEA8A66612B29A5DEF6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Rural area</header><text>The term <term>rural area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE215907676C04D079462D09050472714"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5F83503A5FE4F5698C613375DF8E6BA"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault</term> means any nonconsensual sexual act or sexual contact proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the individual lacks capacity to consent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E1B3670F10347A281554FB551F80AC7"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Sexual assault forensic examiner; SAFE</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault forensic examiner</term> or <quote>SAFE</quote> means an individual who has specialized forensic training in treating sexual assault survivors and conducting medical forensic examinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA11B7EA6E804029A14F4C63CDDD7E0A"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Sexual assault forensic examination</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault forensic examination</term> means an examination of a sexual assault patient by a health care provider, who has specialized education and clinical experience in the collection of forensic evidence and treatment of these patients, which includes—</text><subparagraph id="H4401489667DE4A8B90BCF1EE08A69694"><enum>(A)</enum><text>gathering information from the patient for the medical forensic history;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC93198BF5EDD4D54A2C43458E1643038"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an examination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4309275F222A48DA869C607F9C70A56B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>coordinating treatment of injuries, documentation of biological and physical findings, and collection of evidence from the patient;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF92303448D674B979C774D7B8C37E8AF"><enum>(D)</enum><text>documentation of findings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B2DF053755497AB913ABEF005FE5AB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>providing information, treatment, and referrals for sexually transmitted infections, pregnancy, suicidal ideation, alcohol and substance abuse, and other non-acute medical concerns; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33F33BD03CE543D8A5DF4B8237680F9E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>providing follow-up as needed to provide additional healing, treatment, or collection of evidence. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0057B83F6870422C96F5D064CAA80B3E"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Sexual assault nurse examiner; SANE</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault nurse examiner</term> or <quote>SANE</quote> means a registered or advanced practice nurse who has specialized training conducting medical forensic examinations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7247A366D1204A3186E6FAB796D34FD9"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Sexual assault response team; SART</header><text>The term <term>sexual assault response team</term> or <quote>SART</quote> means a multidisciplinary team that— </text><subparagraph id="H726CFEBE27854660A45C9958552BF2DD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provides a specialized and immediate response to survivors of sexual assault; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE01D69CB99E848B08B01C36D8F94C242"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include health care personnel, law enforcement representatives, community-based survivor advocates, prosecutors, and forensic scientists. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92AD1908D0354E6FBD63D4998661C549"><enum>(15)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, and any territory or possession of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ECF2EA171B0433BB1C93B30D23FE437"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Trauma-informed</header><text>The term <term>trauma-informed</term> means, with respect to services or training, services or training that—</text><subparagraph id="HD7A95CDC3DAE49138199446FF491C843"><enum>(A)</enum><text>uses a patient-centered approach to providing services or care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1362A04CD3743C2987780D77FB8F061"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promotes the dignity, strength, and empowerment of patients who have experienced trauma; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF817425C6EAB41DCB1CEE482A0B7874C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incorporates evidence-based practices based on knowledge about the impact of trauma on patients’ lives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48EAC64D7820436B8CC0EB548A2BD642"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Underserved populations</header><text>The term <term>underserved populations</term> has the meaning given the term in section 40002 of the Violence Against Women Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/12291">34 U.S.C. 12291</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H18BB3C980A5E4B7F888B3B757544D8E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sexual assault nursing examiner grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40723">34 U.S.C. 40723</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after subsection (a), as amended by section 2, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF6C646DB191F409BBFF9E03F7853E86F"><subsection id="H47110732BC8A4EAA9DB70FDDBE6EB57F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sexual assault nurse examiner training program grants</header><paragraph id="HED24F339539F47F09DC81482114E2326"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization for grants</header><text>The Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall make grants to eligible entities for the following purposes:</text><subparagraph id="H9B82C14816B44F099267EB9384C1FAC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To establish qualified regional SANE training programs—</text><clause id="H4F026EE0E54743E6A44B13AF5FDFA2D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to provide clinical education for SANE students;</text></clause><clause id="HDA2CD9B010F148EABAF232113134555D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to provide salaries for full- and part-time SANE instructors, including those specializing in pediatrics and working in a multidisciplinary team setting, to help with the clinical training of SANEs; and</text></clause><clause id="HD0A50591B618410F85D7E184D857BCA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to provide access to simulation laboratories and other resources necessary for clinical education.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H823EB730A78C4065A017CD3DF3899010"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To provide full- and part-time salaries for SANEs and SAFEs, including pediatric SANEs and SAFEs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6CBDE0CEA70F422791F95622C7F3741B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To increase access to SANEs and SAFEs by otherwise providing training, education, or technical assistance relating to the collection, preservation, analysis, and use of DNA samples and DNA evidence by SANEs, SAFEs, and other qualified personnel. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6F96064D03845D78A1DED8F3B9B5778"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Preference for grants</header><text>In reviewing applications for grants under this section, the Attorney General shall give preference to any eligible entity that certifies in the grant application that the entity will coordinate with a rape crisis center or the State sexual assault coalition to facilitate sexual assault advocacy to support sexual assault survivors and use the grant funds to—</text><subparagraph id="H43CBDD9AD4C04A80B4325878BC2B3FF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>establish qualified SANE training programs in localities with a high volume of forensic trauma cases, including adult and child sexual assault, domestic violence, elder abuse, sex trafficking, and strangulation cases;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20BFC82F700D441480017EC976791D23"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increase the local and regional availability of full- and part-time sexual assault nurse examiners in a rural area, Tribal area, an area with a health professional shortage, or for an underserved population, including efforts to provide culturally competent services; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD694F83222A4F8386B342B5338100CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish or sustain sexual assault mobile teams or units or otherwise enhance SANE and SAFE access through telehealth.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H74989FFBABF14A3D966F5CB7E7505EBA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Directive</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 304 of the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40723">34 U.S.C. 40723</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCC4BCD40D0004CEE8FEF528CC2C4B8A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8920C65FFEE9468182C64B19B1489064"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b), as added by section 3, the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD307C11CDE4B499D9C4335508E7E645F"><subsection id="H0E66B0EAC67243E78713B0F6CFA8FDF3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Directive to the Attorney General</header><paragraph id="HF1D7C3C2FB0548EEA862F8666372E7C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the beginning of fiscal year 2022, the Attorney General shall coordinate with the Secretary to inform health care facilities, including Federally qualified health centers and hospitals, colleges and universities, and other appropriate health-related entities about—</text><subparagraph id="HE463D71A24384A7590AE4DC76E6F894B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the availability of grant funding under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA11F7373C58C4CF18AA121E4DFD7D28B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the role of sexual assault nurse examiners, both adult and pediatric, and available resources of the Department of Justice and the Department of Health and Human Services to train or employ sexual assault nurse examiners to address the needs of communities dealing with sexual assault, domestic violence, sex trafficking, elder abuse, strangulation, and, in particular, the need for pediatric SANEs, including such nurse examiners working in the multidisciplinary setting, in responding to abuse of both children and adolescents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD421D558AA5249029350935459C9349E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall collaborate with nongovernmental organizations representing SANEs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H55AADBD470D1464CAC2A7A132803983D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public information on access to sexual assault forensic examinations</header><paragraph id="HED4D9D3AC0A74DF59338E6ECC4962602"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Supporting Access to Nurse Exams Act</short-title>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall establish, and update annually, a public website on the access to forensic nurse examiners.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2AA36C73EBE4C5CAB72DD0A42B4BD6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The website required under paragraph (1) shall with specificity describe, by State—</text><subparagraph id="HBC2780289D5C411E96CF42D1DF5DA8D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>funding opportunities for SANE training and continuing education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E75E75E6ABB4EB4A88E19D5411DB700"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the availability of sexual assault advocates at locations providing sexual assault forensic exams.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE42EACB2AED453BA18B702EEAAE4E90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Supporting Access to Nurse Exams Act</short-title>, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary, shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on—</text><subparagraph id="H784122D80A9D4876B40846C338EE86B6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the availability of, and patient access to, trained SANEs and other providers who perform MFEs or sexual assault forensic examinations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEB6576AF3B04E6EB5807177B25775B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the health care facilities, including hospitals or clinics, that offer SANEs and sexual assault forensic examinations and whether each health care facility, including a hospital or clinic, has full-time, part-time, or on-call coverage;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD547BA63FF3647818BAC68BC4F5D896A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>regional, provider, or other barriers to access for SANE care and services, including MFEs and sexual assault forensic examinations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H920F401FBD334D0A8E0728B0C4CBCAE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>State requirements, minimum standards, and protocols for training SANEs, including trauma-informed and culturally competent training standards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78B826258F3A4479BC8C869276735F9B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>State requirements, minimum standards, and protocols for training emergency services personnel involved in MFEs and sexual assault forensic examinations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49913A497B1B474B9DC397C44F2AF5A0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the availability of sexual assault nurse examiner training, frequency of when training is convened, the providers of such training, the State’s role in such training, and what process or procedures are in place for continuing education of such examiners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40C1F48315364E29B42C528D7CE550BC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the dedicated Federal and State funding to support SANE training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H55B818AAE237475CA74DEABF2113A21D"><enum>(H)</enum><text>funding opportunities for SANE training and continuing education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF14DADE58CA4D4CBFFC37F3C9DA0748"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the availability of sexual assault advocates at locations providing MFEs and sexual assault forensic exams; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FCADFE7D45E41B5858B63AACEEBE561"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the total annual cost of conducting sexual assault forensic exams described in section 2010(b) of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10449">34 U.S.C. 10449(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HFF922B08BB2345318116E0386DEBB9BA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (e) of section 304 of the DNA Sexual Assault Justice Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40723">34 U.S.C. 40723</external-xref>), as redesignated by section 4 of this Act, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB639733DC9064BD8AD8D852B0C426CB9"><subsection id="H5C5B4302135349CEAA8616EC97BD9C58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028 to carry out this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

