<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFDF8C87E06F4EAFA34B554AF3D570AE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8171 IH: Protect Minors from Medical Malpractice Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8171</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect children from medical malpractice in the form of gender transition procedures.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H560D13D319B341DE896F575D7F27FAB4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H034542E391164C66B984478CF003DF06" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Minors from Medical Malpractice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0A50B205AB7A4E3ABB362C5587B10A43"><enum>2.</enum><header>Private right of action for a gender-transition procedure performed on a minor</header> <subsection id="H47F76285A1CB43C19D2A5C2B94EE8E78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A medical practitioner, in any circumstance described in subsection (c), who performs a gender-transition procedure on an individual who is less than 18 years of age shall, as described in subsection (b), be liable to the individual if injured (including any physical, psychological, emotional, or physiological harms) by such procedure, related treatment, or the aftereffects of the procedure or treatment.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4BC7FDCF0BFF4E7BB3483D88082C7731"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text>An individual covered by subsection (a) who receives a gender-transition procedure from a medical practitioner (or a representative, including a legal guardian, on behalf of such individual) may, not later than the day that is 30 years after the date on which the individual turns 18 years of age, bring a civil action against such medical practitioner in a court of competent jurisdiction for—</text> <paragraph id="HFC234B88A74140618229E66DDB9DE5D6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>declaratory or injunctive relief;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7DE6D94AA31448C283DFA14A7AFB6653"><enum>(2)</enum><text>compensatory damages;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB553EC2D3DB4AFDA790C1FD0F4CC025"><enum>(3)</enum><text>punitive damages; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H343118493C2440B89EE37897E26953DE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>attorney’s fees and costs.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE3DBDE3F343445DE8EA8E38D9736385C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Circumstances</header><text>For the purposes of subsection (a), the circumstances described in this subsection are that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2155A65EB5B34D47B1D71AC0A82DF772"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the medical practitioner or the individual receiving the gender-transition procedure traveled in interstate or foreign commerce, or traveled using a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F8DC4C5CFCB41AE8C5C1D63A23008EB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the medical practitioner used a means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H412901F217AC4000A0B69A6BD0585DD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any payment of any kind was made, directly or indirectly, in furtherance of or in connection with the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68A65A05EC7D4046A835FF6228E9675D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the medical practitioner transmitted in interstate or foreign commerce any communication relating to or in furtherance of the conduct described in subsection (a) using any means, channel, facility, or instrumentality of interstate or foreign commerce or in or affecting interstate or foreign commerce by any means or in any manner, including by computer, mail, wire, or electromagnetic transmission;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEDBEB70B44B4BC6A659C6500DD8C1CA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any instrument, item, substance, or other object that has traveled in interstate or foreign commerce was used to perform the conduct described in subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43729A709D224F91A0B4D8BCFEFB1C21"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) occurred within the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, or any territory or possession of the United States; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF56E59F978F34512BDDE3E86450CAFE5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the conduct described in subsection (a) otherwise occurred in or affected interstate or foreign commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H968401B5895646AEACAFAF4376F5D7A9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preserving freedom of conscience and medical judgement for medical providers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no provision of Federal law shall require, or be construed to require, a medical practitioner to perform a gender-transition procedure.</text></section> 
<section id="HB0DC5E401B91471EBFE9022C5DC33037"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibition on funding for certain states</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any State that requires medical practitioners to perform any gender-transition procedure on an individual in the State shall be ineligible to receive any Federal funding from the Department of Health and Human Services.</text></section> <section id="HB31565433CC9436B9535307E28F3E3B3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H628963087016454B89301DA09D956BB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biological sex</header><text>The term <quote>biological sex</quote> means the genetic classification of an individual as male or female, as reflected in the organization of the body of such individual for a reproductive role or capacity, such as through sex chromosomes, naturally occurring sex hormones, and internal and external genitalia present at birth, without regard to the subjective sense of identity of the individual.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B514F38868948A3A73F5F9091D9900E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gender-transition procedure</header> <subparagraph id="H8B1102AC63C64AED82B500CB75672392"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <quote>gender-transition procedure</quote> means—</text> 
<clause id="H464DC6721800473BA8406893194C96F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the prescription or administration of puberty-blocking drugs for the purpose of changing the body of an individual so that it conforms to the subjective sense of identity of the individual, in the case such identity is at odds with the individual’s biological sex;</text></clause> <clause id="HBDE9E104F2EE4664BD43F564C3B030B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the prescription or administration of cross-sex hormones for the purpose of changing the body of an individual so that it conforms to the subjective sense of identity of the individual, in the case such identity is at odds with the individual’s biological sex; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7909E96FF5C6443F9E258FB6A792134B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a surgery to change the body of an individual so that it conforms to the subjective sense of identity of the individual, in the case such identity is at odds with the individual’s biological sex.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD99E6440DFF24942AD06801719C88938"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <quote>gender-transition procedure</quote> does not include—</text> 
<clause id="H2D0DED6384744A18BF30F353D2965282"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an intervention described in subparagraph (A) that is performed on—</text> <subclause id="H6528D734F70A460984DEA22C5C79B4A2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an individual with biological sex characteristics that are inherently ambiguous, such as those born with 46 XX chromosomes with virilization, 46 XY chromosomes with undervirilization, or having both ovarian and testicular tissue; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF1D975027D6D4565977A90F346E552FE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an individual with respect to whom a physician has determined through genetic or biochemical testing that the individual does not have normal sex chromosome structure, sex steroid hormone production, or sex steroid hormone action, for a biological male or biological female;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HD537AF24B5CB466DBDFFE24D18719004"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the treatment of any infection, injury, disease, or disorder that has been caused or exacerbated by the performance of an intervention described in subparagraph (A) without regard to whether the intervention was performed in accordance with State or Federal law or whether the intervention is covered by the private right of action under section 2; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H526C3C8BDB90400EBDA6B0B8CD930C52"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any procedure undertaken because the individual suffers from a physical disorder, physical injury, or physical illness that would, as certified by a physician, place the individual in imminent danger of death or impairment of major bodily function unless the procedure is performed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H756AB2C6C30C43F58808D28F45ECFF43"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical practitioner</header><text>The term <quote>medical practitioner</quote> means a person who is licensed, certified, or otherwise authorized by the laws of a State to administer health care in the ordinary course of the practice of the person’s profession.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HF1E21A5805314334B98F89C08922268B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

