<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3A371DE0E964D8B818A085E6B1F75ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9259 IH: Cybersecurity Skills Integration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221031">October 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to establish a pilot program to award competitive grants for the integration of cybersecurity education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H86AE10F83DFA4D409C7BCAAAEAC1FE9F" style="OLC"><section id="H4913799505D24490A8E31DF590790DBC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cybersecurity Skills Integration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1CB0D7FCA12544BB9A2C79EB8B418EE6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to improve the cybersecurity competencies of the critical infrastructure workforce, particularly operators of critical infrastructure technology, by developing postsecondary career and technical education programs that integrate cybersecurity education.</text></section><section id="H2DF3EC3B16F543F8929EFD623E301C37"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cybersecurity education grants</header><subsection id="HB6DCAA3C980E4A75AAC8E6022128151E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts made available to carry out this Act, the Secretary of Education shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, establish a pilot program under which the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible partnerships for—</text><paragraph id="H54FD3FDD64A44D15A75B79CE060CC800"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development and implementation of postsecondary career and technical education programs that incorporate cybersecurity education and prepare individuals to meet workforce needs in critical infrastructure sectors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FE244AF66744B4B9A0E0B15CBBFA4A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the integration of cybersecurity education into existing postsecondary career and technical education programs that prepare individuals to meet workforce needs in critical infrastructure sectors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB09F9D6C271A402496AD772E0EE12E97"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under this Act, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Labor, the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, and the Secretary of Homeland Security, to determine the greatest workforce needs in critical infrastructure sectors.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87AEFA2CFA774DDC96FCC5ED1C4D9AAC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of any grant made under this Act shall not exceed $500,000 in any fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87B4FC183B684CAC833BDE6BA03508F3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this Act, an eligible partnership shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, containing such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, and including a description of—</text><paragraph id="HE26E56C4D32E45B6BD6804E7BCF5106B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the roles and responsibilities of each partner in the eligible partnership, and each partner’s capacity to support the postsecondary career and technical education program to be developed and implemented with funds awarded under this Act, or the postsecondary career and technical education program into which cybersecurity education will be integrated with funds awarded under this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7707F532371B48AF8E73DA2531CF25F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the critical infrastructure sector or sectors that such postsecondary career and technical education program prepares individuals to enter;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36969A2C1C9A40A298F1A69E8F9EEA08"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the in-demand occupation within such sector or sectors that such postsecondary career and technical education program prepares individuals to enter;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC6DB3E506A4D3EA997B15ADB58989A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the workforce needs of such critical infrastructure sector or sectors, including cybersecurity workforce needs, and how the postsecondary career and technical education program will meet such workforce needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64A3C982A8D3493AAA453ABB924CC628"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how the eligible partnership will incorporate cybersecurity education aligned to the National Initiative for Cybersecurity Education (NICE) Cybersecurity Workforce Framework developed by the National Institute of Standards and Technology of the Department of Commerce, or successor framework, into such postsecondary career and technical education program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20966AA6B8324A0A83965170F1EE4965"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the assessment, capstone project, or other means of demonstrating knowledge and cybersecurity skills specific to the critical infrastructure sector or sectors that such postsecondary career and technical education program prepares individuals to enter, and an assurance that such assessment, project, or other demonstration of knowledge and skills will be a requirement for program completion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F65A936AE404A13BFE861D2E9EAF297"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the work-based learning opportunities the eligible partnership will offer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E3D7B26E58E42AC830B679A71EE759D"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such postsecondary career and technical education program will lead to a recognized postsecondary credential and employment in the critical infrastructure sector or sectors targeted by the postsecondary career and technical education program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F3CA3088AE9451F85F6BF67C673778C"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the process through which the cybersecurity education curriculum and educational materials developed or integrated using such grant will be updated annually to include the most recent information on cybersecurity threats specific to such critical infrastructure sector or sectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEA7F22CA2BBF44C893456C56A5023CC5"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such postsecondary career and technical education program will be sustained following the grant period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26661A49BC35425CB164BEF6D0021101"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how such postsecondary career and technical education program will promote diversity within the cybersecurity workforce in critical infrastructure sectors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB30185DE1524EB29CB1F732B49E16CF"><enum>(12)</enum><text>any other purpose for which the eligible partnership intends to use funds awarded under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H04BDF46363B24B0C85B5D8822B4BEFD4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regional diversity</header><text>When awarding grants under this Act, the Secretary shall ensure that grants are awarded to eligible partnerships in different regions.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF7701F6984564B6A88C48219AFD54342"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting Requirements</header><text>An eligible partnership that receives a grant under this Act shall annually submit a report to the Secretary that includes—</text><paragraph id="HCE63D223645A44F8938A7B913E6F29F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of how any funds awarded to the eligible partnership under this Act have been used during the period covered by the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C09F1BA35984B329692F1760465D7EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of students who have received a recognized postsecondary credential during such period from the postsecondary career and technical education program into which cybersecurity education was incorporated using such funds, disaggregated by the subgroups of students described in section 1111(c)(2)(B) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(c)(2)(B)</external-xref>) and by each special population; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H011BC890DC494FF4BA32AD36DDDB6A4A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any updates made during the preceding year to the cybersecurity education curriculum and educational materials of such postsecondary career and technical education program in accordance with the requirements of subsection (d)(9); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02419871516442EA8AD3B9E5DDFC3103"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of participants in unsubsidized employment in an in-demand occupation in a critical infrastructure sector targeted by the postsecondary career and technical education program after exiting the postsecondary career and technical education program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H576EFDB9294D4848BE08B40A87B009E3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act $10,000,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="H85F93E349CE644A3A67D8F8594589CD6"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0EED72E64D344EC89096F0F802FE3EEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical Infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1016(e) of the USA PATRIOT Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA80F0338D442DA8A5F8FF0FD783D2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cybersecurity education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cybersecurity education</term> shall mean education on critical infrastructure cyber defense, including—</text><subparagraph id="HBF96A771AE74405BBA6262B869A094FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring the confidentiality, integrity, and availability of information systems used in critical infrastructure, including control systems and operational technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H804A847DFF564E33A51AED64CC7CF380"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing engineering skills applicable to industrial control systems and operational technologies used in critical infrastructure systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEAC74B5E59C4341A2FEA94D4E023AFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training to ensure the continuous physical and environmental safety of the operations of critical infrastructure systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H11F710DBD0F44074ACDCEDF645E777A9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><subparagraph id="H92084698C84E4E91956E20663EF7C73D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required partners</header><text>The term <term>eligible partnership</term> means a partnership that includes—</text><clause id="H4B04B763E4B94BD29242CD56EE47D399"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a postsecondary educational institution; and</text></clause><clause id="HF72A80A26EC749CF991BA0B3A700F287"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">2 or more public or private employers, in a critical infrastructure sector, with demonstrated cybersecurity workforce needs, that is located in the region where the postsecondary career and technical education program will be developed and implemented with a grant awarded under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F80E8854F544A4FB40C0CD16C55868E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Optional partners</header><text>The partnership may also include one or more—</text><clause id="HFDC8746DC27B4F3C975D0D6A1D788F9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>community stakeholders (such as local governments, nonprofit institutions, economic development organizations, planning agencies, labor organizations, or industry associations);</text></clause><clause id="H09DC382BB0944DD898AD8EC605C65D17"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">local educational agencies (as the term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>)); and</text></clause><clause id="HF86BDA89E47049DD90C1E56723078BE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">eligible agencies that are located in the region where the postsecondary career and technical education program will be developed and implemented with funds awarded under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C9E2B8775244C11870B7EDCCBE3CCEF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible agency</term> means a State board designated or created consistent with State law as the sole State agency responsible for the administration of career and technical education in the State or for the supervision of the administration of career and technical education in the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5229D5466E44ED9AAE0E09545D06CF1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>In-demand industry sector or occupation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04F892BF16124586A6CADC10CD745AA2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Postsecondary educational institution</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary educational institution</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H0558C59FD4974A78986C2B1ABA837675"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an institution of higher education (defined in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>)) that provides not less than a 2-year program of instruction that is acceptable for credit toward an associate’s or bachelor's degree;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F1B989AF66F4D2981CAAFFF768C0CED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a tribally controlled college or university (defined in section 2(a)(4) of the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1801">25 U.S.C. 1801(a)(4)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H559053E3EB4E45EEAAC4191125E02295"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit educational institution offering certificate or other skilled training programs at the postsecondary level.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H744486C96BDD4F178159153F971B7163"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Postsecondary career and technical education program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>postsecondary career and technical education program</term> means a coordinated, nonduplicative sequence of academic and technical content at the postsecondary level that—</text><subparagraph id="H7ADFD21A667E43F6A1A80F1DC296DD55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>addresses both academic and technical knowledge and skills, including employability skills;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64ADDD1A590B45E6B67A749F8A6DECAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is aligned with the needs of industries in the economy of the State, region, Tribal community, or local area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1FB8F914C3D84FEDA643A97EA2F7988E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>progresses in specificity (beginning with all aspects of an industry or career cluster and leading to more occupation-specific instruction);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H736A9DC0CF684C9FBB3D335F1C8DB6E3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>has multiple entry and exit points that incorporate credentialing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6548AB2C076A4FF7A794EC3B4858DBA5"><enum>(E)</enum><text>culminates in the attainment of a recognized postsecondary credential.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H118FF869261A448C8CB648FF31319F01"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73EAA3A207614688B39F2F8EDF743954"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Work based learning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>work based learning</term> means sustained interactions with industry or community professionals in real workplace settings, to the extent practicable, or simulated environments at an educational institution that foster in-depth, firsthand engagement with the tasks required in a given career field, that are aligned to curriculum and instruction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFA2C94A293F4FEDB6CAA9AB870E2B9F"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Recognized Postsecondary Credential</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9084E06063C74803A06727C327B1B149"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Special Populations</header><text>The term <term>special populations</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1F954E9997B94D47A692E2E5722B8464"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">individuals with disabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AE4382064A14BEFA8641A3DEF6D4B33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>individuals from economically disadvantaged families, including low-income youth and adults;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0983A788FF9B4337888A0A72FC743B97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>individuals preparing for non-traditional fields;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H516D8B5810C24714800CEFBC069C654B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>single parents, including single pregnant women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E408E9673784E11AC6FF9E3A8561F0C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>out-of-workforce individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE0D0D0E86BC429AA68EC881F3567F7E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>English learners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7CE04ACC9184581B1232AE9BE644009"><enum>(G)</enum><text>homeless individuals described in section 11434a of title 42, United States Code;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA851D96034514771B3FC9169AAD6BCB8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>youth who are in, or have aged out of, the foster care system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE1E5FD1B1354D839B65C9AA5C65B2AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>youth with a parent who—</text><clause id="H77A347D02DD1493C9AD53842B41F08E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a member of the Armed Forces (as such term is defined in section 101(a)(4) of title 10, United States Code); and</text></clause><clause id="H972AC83E56D8411C910717983A5BE32D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is on active duty (as such term is defined in section 101(d)(1) of such title).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

