<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD5110F8954CF4FDEA3175AABF87869DD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5616 RH: DHS Basic Training Accreditation Improvement Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 174</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5616</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–244, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20211019">October 19, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220208">February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220208">February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220208">February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reporting regarding accreditation of basic training programs of the Department of Homeland Security, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HA832D9C627B8431B93A5F7619C848F32" style="OLC"><section id="H87E7E46B283241FCB9D6E350C7CE7E4E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Basic Training Accreditation Improvement Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF93952D9187A49B788216016ED993E5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reporting on basic training programs of the Department of Homeland Security</header><subsection id="H92E2403C8DD64467848AF63AFF600E70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header><paragraph id="HA1A543E81E9748728F899EFC2E39CE81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall report to the relevant congressional committees on the accreditation status for each basic training program within the Department of Homeland Security, including information relating to the following:</text><subparagraph id="HEAD75B9B54CD4CBDA372AD8B03E84C18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The date on which each such program achieved initial accreditation, or in the case of a program that is not currently accredited, the reasons for not obtaining or maintaining accreditation, the activities, if any, taken to achieve accreditation, and an anticipated timeline for accreditation of such program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A5CD7BC83194416AC7A46ECABA9421B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The date each such program most recently received accreditation or reaccreditation, if applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C205ED3038847C79BEF7E82389A07AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Each such program’s anticipated accreditation or next reaccreditation date.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A9C99685CE04030A74A5A75A3675462"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The name of the accreditation manager for each such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0121DF05037D4067A73DDCC5A80901EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of reporting requirement</header><text>Annual reports under paragraph (1) shall terminate when all basic training programs of the Department of Homeland Security are accredited.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3618DAB5D8F94499A0D6F9E418CE4B9F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Lapse in accreditation</header><paragraph id="H582515AB6E424A3DBE248AED3BF80C88"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a basic training program of the Department of Homeland Security loses accreditation, the head of the relevant component of the Department shall notify the Secretary of Homeland Security not later than 30 days after such loss.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H704F4BC73A8342D996DEB7DD92B5E5D6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice to congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a notification pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the relevant congressional committees of the lapse in accreditation at issue, the reason for such lapse, and the activities underway and planned to regain accreditation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB5B417F55DB45EEB4128FCF044B00DD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCE11F4AAB13C4A9C8E9558D24E814BE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Accreditation</header><text>The term <quote>accreditation</quote> means the recognition by a board that a basic training program is administered, developed, and delivered according to an applicable set of standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E2B0B13D8324F55BEE2980A96431216"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accreditation manager</header><text>The term <quote>accreditation manager</quote> means the individual assigned by the component of the Department of Homeland Security to manage accreditation activities for a basic training program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C866643FF904897837F0F957ED5ED07"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Basic training program</header><text>The term <quote>basic training program</quote> means an entry level program of the Department of Homeland Security that is transitional to law enforcement service, provides training on critical competencies and responsibilities, and is typically a requirement for appointment to a law enforcement service job or job series.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93AB762CEE4C4A3EAB7FA13E3DAE5A2B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reaccreditation</header><text>The term <quote>reaccreditation</quote> means the assessment of a basic training program after initial accreditation to ensure the continued compliance with an applicable set of standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D324D3B22E347B199B82A0A2D432855"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>relevant congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD0E4F28AB2B84CD49210066832FAC924" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security shall carry out research and development of systems and technologies to enhance access to training offered by the Federal Law Enforcement Training Centers to State, local, Tribal, and territorial law enforcement, with particular attention to law enforcement in rural and remote communities, for the purpose of enhancing domestic preparedness for and collective response to terrorism and other homeland security threats.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc><action-date>February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

