<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB5920FDCCC084AFC9DA3D98D28CEB5B0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9600 IH: The Range of Light National Monument Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9600</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To designate the Range of Light National Monument in the State of California, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H741C425BA4DE42099B1F2811F63C51F4" style="OLC">
<section id="H3B51D71571E24F70A477A3E18B6A489A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H9BF50F0CDB304112807716494BC637FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Range of Light National Monument Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H622649D7B1654DAEB6197A3E4C337FAC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H3B51D71571E24F70A477A3E18B6A489A" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HB47A6FB7304345BF9481FFCF324C4B0E" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H0B617DC67A6546288BA03F137837D203" level="section">Sec. 3. Findings.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H5D822756DB194BC5B1946215E83BF44C" level="section">Sec. 4. Establishment of the Range of Light National Monument, California.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HE15B1C4367EB4BABBAB3E25D13680830" level="section">Sec. 5. Management of Federal lands within the monument.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H709A51A241024F43B03EF29064806444" level="section">Sec. 6. Development of management plan.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HCBA796F092CE43D7AEDE737815C897CF" level="section">Sec. 7. Existing and historical uses of Federal lands included in the monument.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD7A92C6BC8D9422884061BFF38AF3E4B" level="section">Sec. 8. Acquisition of land.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H90FC2063410B4AD1A26806361E9B9CC1" level="section">Sec. 9. Watershed management.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H3B97149FFA9D46268515DBE5639E0057" level="section">Sec. 10. Withdrawal of Federal land from mining laws.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H8A35FFC5DFE14418B6BFE121B079CD27" level="section">Sec. 11. Visitor services plan.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H9D3A16A14A7F47B7B3B24092337038A1" level="section">Sec. 12. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="HB47A6FB7304345BF9481FFCF324C4B0E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H526F9032136A4103BDCBCEE4E4D68891"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the plan developed consistent with section 6.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4E8C8B0E1EFE47D2948BE7CA39100BD4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National monument</header><text>The term <term>national monument</term> means the Range of Light National Monument.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9F8C1E30F6D64268A239DA1D0BE94AFA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4D973C378CB9482B9CB020D5D684CB97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to those Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of the Interior; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73F853F752224159896666F1D2F85063"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to those Federal lands under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA1EBCFD1CDA14FB4861DD66F6096434C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretaries</header><text>The term <term>Secretaries</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior acting jointly.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB81A21EC6BD042E3928F4F619D2FFBAC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Trails</header><text>Trails mean non-motorized trails available only to non-motorized users, including non-motorized bicyclists, except in Wilderness areas where existing regulations for trails remain the same. Electronic bicycles are considered a form of <quote>motorized</quote> bicycling.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE24F3A833D9B49B189B2392729576F0A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Roads</header><text>Roads are defined as roads available only to street legal vehicles.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H0B617DC67A6546288BA03F137837D203"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="HD04EC3B17EDF47688A71F3E72DF3F75B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H0BA38A1D3E7D4DC5AD478C234ED99B6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Sierra Nevada ecosystem is a diverse mountain range that is geologically, ecologically, hydrologically, recreationally and historically significant to the American people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98DADFC0106E47C0A73A270B5CB3BAFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Range of Light National Monument sits between two National Parks, Yosemite and Kings Canyon, in the center of longest interconnected wilderness in the contiguous United States and its establishment will create an interconnected wildlife corridor to facilitate the migration and survival of native species and provide habitat for rare, threatened, and endangered species.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8974A1D8A22749F2A997704B16329057"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Sierra Nevada ecosystem contains one of the most diverse coniferous forests in the world. Ponderosa pine, incense-cedar, white-fir, douglas-fir, sugar pine and scattered groves of giant sequoia intermix and coexist. These trees fight climate change, store carbon, and support a vast array of California’s wildlife.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF451411A4904FB38865943A574CC421"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Sierra Nevada ecosystem and watershed is vital to the people of California. The rivers, springs, alpine lakes and groundwater within the watershed contribute to the Kings, the Merced, and the San Joaquin Rivers, which support wildlife, enhance recreation, and provide drinking water for millions of Californians.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22C880DCB2BC489191E03A427A53FEF5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The interactions between the climate, topography and biota in the Sierra Nevada have created some of the most productive soils for conifers in the world, which has improved vegetation, erosion, wildlife distribution, and water quality throughout the range. These soils harbor the microorganisms and nutrients that provide the basis for the forest’s health and support hundreds of plant species, many of which are endemic to the region and are found nowhere else on earth.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A824BB5499B465DAFB0C22E7684F9F9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Range of Light ecosystems, forests, and watersheds provide a wild and rugged landscape enjoyed by hikers, bicyclists, birders, picnickers, sight seers, fishermen, campers, rock climbers, boaters, equestrians, and other recreationists.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H19043CBBDDEB4D18BCFE5B8EC11546CE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Sierra Nevada tribes have been stewards of the land for more than 10,000 years. Native Americans of the Sierra Nevada have hunted, fished, gathered, and made their homes throughout the region. Many sites along rivers and elsewhere in the national monument are part of tribal history and are considered sacred. Preserving these sites is vital to maintaining tribal identity, as well as enabling the continuation and renewal of annual cultural traditions and ecological land management practices.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H5D822756DB194BC5B1946215E83BF44C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of the Range of Light National Monument, California</header> <subsection id="H973BCA837F584A88AE8B0D92AE559D3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and boundaries</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, there is established the Range of Light National Monument as a unit of the National Park System in the State of California, which consists of approximately 1,427,750 acres of Federal land and interests in Federal land in California, as generally depicted in the map entitled <quote>Range of Light National Monument Map</quote> and dated November 2022. The Range of Light National Monument is composed of the Sierra National Forest in its entirety and the San Joaquin Gorge managed by the Bureau of Land Management.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H42CDABB7023848819605904E2F56D6FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the national monument are—</text> <paragraph id="HAEB7C854E29F4331BDFF08903CB67A96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preserve, protect, and restore nationally significant biological, ecological, cultural, historical, recreational, geological, hydrological, scenic, and scientific resources in the Sierra Nevada’s ecosystems, forests, and soils;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD27001391D974C4E99FB2168004BCA9B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to preserve, protect, and restore watersheds, including meadows, above ground tributaries, springs and groundwater, and surface waters that contribute to the San Joaquin, Kings, and Merced Rivers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0198D5A244AD4FF7B1D97C4A674BC7A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to provide wildlife connectivity and a migratory area for native species and to provide habitat for rare, threatened, and endangered species through protection and restoration;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4438C01312154920A5325553042F9A45"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to secure now and for future generations the opportunity to experience and enjoy a diverse and natural forest landscape, wildlife, free-flowing water, an unfettered rugged environment, and recreation on public land;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75202110214B461087219A43B994DFE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to provide environmentally responsible, well-managed recreational opportunities and spaces for people to connect with nature within the national monument;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD8D099778DBB49B4A8DBE76DA0871A1D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to provide educational, recreational, visitor, and interpretive services that will increase public understanding of and appreciation for the natural and cultural resources of the Sierra Nevada and the national monument area; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EEFB032FC2B481AB1FA54EAE7C64593"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to protect Native American sacred cultural sites and traditional practices and to involve Native Americans in the planning and the care of native plants and cultural sites in the monument area.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7A356E6E2DD04512A189C60AFD04FDCC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer and administration of lands</header><text>Upon enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall transfer the Federal lands and Federal buildings under the jurisdiction of the National Forest Service, managed specifically as the Sierra National Forest, without consideration, to the administrative jurisdiction of the National Park Service for administration as a national monument that is part of the National Park System. Upon enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Interior shall transfer the Federal lands and Federal buildings under the jurisdiction of the Bureau of Land Management and Bureau of Reclamation, managed specifically as the San Joaquin Gorge, without consideration, to the administrative jurisdiction of the National Park Service for administration as a national monument that is part of the National Park System.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H01FEF6C10F6F47C7B9314A07D7DFB622"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Legal descriptions; corrections of errors</header> <paragraph id="HB252AFFF9BFE4A9DA55D1F7D51999B68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preparation</header><text>As soon as practical after the date of the enactment of this Act, but not later than 1 year after such date, the Secretary shall prepare final maps and legal descriptions of the national monument, which shall have the same force and effect as if included in this Act, except that the Secretary of the Interior may correct clerical and typographical errors in the existing maps and legal descriptions.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9E85FED78AA344C79B70D988A1B9603B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>As soon as practicable after the preparation of the maps and legal descriptions under paragraph (1), the Secretary of the Interior shall submit the maps and legal descriptions to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6825CE87362A4286B6D0FF94D428F748"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The maps and legal descriptions prepared pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be on file and available for public inspection at appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H3DAF3079967C4527BD4FEAF72C1B9939"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Administration and jurisdiction</header>
<paragraph id="H75024DD082144306BD2C03052843D5C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Public lands</header><text>The public lands included in the national monument area shall be administered by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the National Park Service.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BFA6B9A0CEB4413801F0EAC4F9DF64C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State and local jurisdiction</header><text>Nothing in this Act alters, modifies, or diminishes any right, responsibility, power, authority, jurisdiction, or entitlement of the State, any political subdivision of the State, or any State or local agency under existing Federal, State, and local law (including regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HE15B1C4367EB4BABBAB3E25D13680830"><enum>5.</enum><header>Management of Federal lands within the monument</header>
<subsection id="HBEAAB6769B744F2D93518035B8293EE4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National park system</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary of the Interior shall manage the public lands included in the national monument area in a manner that protects, and enhances the natural resources and values of the lands, in accordance with—</text> <paragraph id="HA29305DE67EB4FE996CD9D171FC21078"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F4014F819374E37A8DDC11F2AD782B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8D70C76A0EBA4352A8F6F1615A4D7BDB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>) in existing wilderness areas; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE2D8A0823A9348B692CE2332482ECC2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other applicable law (including Federal, State, or local law, and regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H215F1F8B4B5B45E48109615473ECCA1B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of non-Federal lands and related provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text>
<paragraph id="HD7EDA27C4BB64417974F67FA2947E53E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>authorizes the Secretary to take any action that would affect the use of any land not owned by the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5007CA2AE5CC4E679366C0308EE9E01C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects the use of any non-Federal land within the national monument area;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6E7FD30B1FBC4585BBAB837428936DEF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies any provision of Federal, State, or local law with respect to public access to or use of non-Federal land;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02DD4C203229487580E9A6D1CBF61700"><enum>(4)</enum><text>requires any owner of non-Federal land to allow public access (including Federal, State, or local government access) to private property or any other non-Federal land; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2AAEC5F86BA74DA9ACBB8D5597F03592"><enum>(5)</enum><text>creates any liability, or affects any liability under any other law, of any private property owner or other owner of non-Federal land with respect to any person injured on private property or other non-Federal land.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1D5C82ADE9F457985AD32E7CF9BD2F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Resolution of conflicts</header><text>If there is a conflict between a provision of this Act and a provision of another law specified in subsection (a), the more restrictive provision shall control.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H90F4EA617C794C4DA6ED6D0778094172"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorized uses</header><text>The Secretary shall allow only such uses of the national monument as the Secretary determines would further the purposes specified in section 4 of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H709A51A241024F43B03EF29064806444"><enum>6.</enum><header>Development of management plan</header> <subsection id="H62B62C1EF4754520A73810D89D9F943B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall create a comprehensive management plan for the national monument that fulfills the purposes described in section 4.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA44736CA66ED4C77908CAFAC434640A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Incorporation of visitor services plan</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall incorporate the visitor services plan into the management plan as described in section 11.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HCBA796F092CE43D7AEDE737815C897CF"><enum>7.</enum><header>Existing and historical uses of Federal lands included in the monument</header> <subsection id="HFE31D02C8C424A13A17A01283E277EE2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the jurisdiction of the State of California with respect to the management of fish and wildlife located on public land in the State, except that the Secretary of the Interior, after consultation with the California Department of Fish and Wildlife, may designate zones in the national monument where, and periods when, hunting shall not be allowed to accommodate traditional tribal uses, public safety, wildlife health, administration, or public use and enjoyment.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H42282880CC3145ADAF0BF3F50A68444F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Motorized and mechanized vehicles</header><text>The use of motorized and mechanized vehicles on lands within the national monument shall be permitted only on roads designated for their use. In the Sierra National Forest, all roads currently classified as Forest Service Maintenance Level 1 roads will be closed, and Maintenance Level 2 roads will be converted to Maintenance Level 1 roads indefinitely unless they lead to campgrounds, picnic areas, private inholdings, non-motorized trailheads, selected viewpoints or are needed for administrative purposes or to respond to an emergency. When managed by the National Park Service, these roads shall be classified as paved, maintained dirt roads, and unmaintained dirt roads. Selected roads shall remain open, partially or fully, paved or dirt, in accordance with the Range of Light National Monument map, and shall remain open only to street-legal vehicles. Closed roads may be remediated or converted to non-motorized trails and may remain available to non-motorized recreational use at the discretion of the park service and in accordance with the visitor services plan, as detailed in subsection (a). The existing roads and trails in the San Joaquin Gorge shall remain and shall be managed as is, at the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D01E7A3EF9749A2A0C0CB767BEDFEC0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Grazing</header><text>Livestock grazing permits within the national monument, where established or planned before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall be allowed to continue until the end of their permit period, a maximum of 10 years from the issued permit date, subject to all applicable laws and regulations. Grazing permits shall not be re-issued once expired and shall be retired.</text>
<paragraph id="H328932EEBBD747E39EF4DCE61517CEA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Donation of grazing permits and leases</header>
<subparagraph id="H71981C080F5A4379BD29DE915B4708E1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept the donation of any valid existing leases or permits authorizing grazing on public land or National Forest System land, all or a portion of which are within the area depicted as the <quote>Range of Light National Monument</quote> on the maps entitled <quote>Range of Light National Monument</quote>.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5121BBAF6E4044D6AAA95F52D31DDAA9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Partial donation</header><text>A person holding a valid grazing permit or lease for a grazing allotment partially within the area described in subparagraph (A) may elect to donate only the portion of the grazing permit or lease that is within the area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H96A2199C442149F4BA8DD4F53A67A208"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>With respect to each permit or lease donated under paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HBBDFD0670F79488193B0ED2DCF0D2CF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>terminate the grazing permit or lease or portion of the permit or lease; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE3FDEB3944504F9DAE3C8281F0D0F87E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure a permanent end to grazing on the land covered by the permit or lease or portion of the permit or lease.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3A36539AC94B471CB8DD12B36F20826F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commercial recreation activities</header><text>The Secretary shall allow commercial recreation activities within the national monument in accordance with—</text>
<paragraph id="H5652C5AAA3994532B39ABBCB2FC4AAAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB15D9C4E12F44F4CA5A9648A9B625EF7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D7868C6D7614AC6B1F94B2241944DB6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1133">16 U.S.C. 1133 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD67A2CF3C6584347BA78A5078D0DD4A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>other applicable law (including Federal, State, or local law, and regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0F92314D03DB4D72A8D799AF7D2B1F73"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fishing and gathering</header><text>The Secretary shall allow fishing and gathering within the national monument in accordance with applicable laws and regulations of the United States and the State of California.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC603CFE52484412FA92E4448BF997D87"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Forestry</header><text>The Secretary shall prohibit the cutting, sale, harvest or removal of timber and other vegetative material within the national monument for commercial purposes, commercial logging, or for biomass energy production. No part of the monument shall be considered suitable for timber production or calculation or provision for sustained yield of timber. The Secretary may permit the cutting of timber in the national monument only in cases where the cutting of such timber is required to preserve and protect wildlife, or the natural, scientific, scenic or historical objects in the area. The Secretary may permit the removal of tree materials for personal use fuel wood, in cases where the removal does not harm the forest, wildlife or the natural, scientific or historical objects in the area.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H5BA3F1882D424053B304D01A86E1CD30" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Buyouts, donations and termination of existing timber contracts</header>
<paragraph id="HBCDD2AACFCC14CBF92FA906AD1B03142" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Secretary shall accept the donation of any valid existing contract authorizing logging on public land in National Forest System land, which is within the area depicted as the <quote>Range of Light National Monument</quote> on the maps entitled <quote>Range of Light National Monument</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BE97CC17CF94565BAD2EBF3634115AB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Buyouts</header><text>With respect to purchased timber contracts, the Secretary may buy back the contracts for the sale of timber within the boundaries of the Monument at the time of enactment of this Act, for the price sold, in accordance with applicable Federal law.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE93C3F132BAB42F199AC00E4647DBD4F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>All timber sales and contracts will be terminated at date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5406CA91788E47619F7BEBCDC1676F1B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Use of chemicals</header><text>The application of any toxic chemicals (other than fire retardants), including pesticides and herbicides, shall be prohibited within the national monument area.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE3FF3A2F43254066A00867C138B3891C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Trails</header><text>A non-motorized trail system will be constructed and maintained using existing non-motorized trails and roads decommissioned from motorized use.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF73F7A15A37F405B89217DB14462A0C0"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Existing cabin leases</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall preclude the renewal or continuation of valid leases for cabins, homesites or similar structures on federally owned lands in the national monument in effect on date this law is enacted.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H57BBB54ADE644363BE6C5421C079B383"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Specific protections</header><text>The use of street-legal motorized vehicles in the national monument shall be permitted only on existing roads designated for use by vehicles. In recognition that certain conditions are deemed desirable for maintaining the rugged character of the national monument, Congress declares its intention to retain selected dirt roads. Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal lands may be used for the construction of any new road or to pave any existing dirt road or to pave any partially paved dirt road in the national monument. Roads that are deemed destructive to the natural landscape or harm wildlife and the values of the national monument shall be closed at the discretion of the park service.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9F934AF26D624E7798002659C46FE41B"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Private property access</header><text>In instances where roads have been closed to the public and those roads lead to private property, the private property owners shall retain the right to access their lands via the closed road.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H44EAB9BECD794027BE7923DEEAEFBB88"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Native american cultural and religious uses</header><text>Nothing in this Act diminishes—</text> <paragraph id="H46F5AE45A3AF43E5AA2AF7583E8574B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the rights of any Indian tribe; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD0F6460AE63440579B5829AE7C6EEA55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any tribal rights regarding access to Federal land for tribal activities, including spiritual, cultural, and traditional food-gathering activities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD7A92C6BC8D9422884061BFF38AF3E4B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Acquisition of land</header> <subsection id="H44C7382F3E2648A78FC513AFEA2E38F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acquisition authorized; methods</header><text>Non-Federal held land or interests in land within the boundaries of the national monument may be acquired for management as part of the national monument only by—</text>
<paragraph id="H3F5A589C7AE8401DB67C4B9C0E2C864B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>donation; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2754AF452F247A6BBE26B926FD7760B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>purchase from a willing seller.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7161D20881C3498C92FBDBD0979ED7EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Valuation of private property</header><text>The United States shall offer the fair market value for any interests or partial interests in land acquired under this section unless donated.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D8C953765F24EA78B018AFDC75F9F37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incorporation of acquired lands and interests</header><text>Any land or interest in land within the boundaries of the national monument that is acquired by the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act shall be added to and administered as part of the national monument.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H90FC2063410B4AD1A26806361E9B9CC1"><enum>9.</enum><header>Watershed management</header>
<subsection id="H4CFE89D7268D45669CFA7A05C372E0DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Water rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> <paragraph id="HDF68BF0EBBDB48AF9B45DB89D0EE1C55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>affects the use or allocation, in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, of any water, water right, or interest in water;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4A039675EF44423CBF25CD77EB42E540"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects any vested absolute or decreed conditional water right in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act, including any water right held by the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB7739A04AFF74AED8EFECED7CAD54EBE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>affects any interstate water compact in existence on the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00F7F1562C82458CB014542CC4348991"><enum>(4)</enum><text>relinquishes or reduces any water rights reserved or appropriated by the United States in the State of California on or before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H425FA85B3282489ABF3CAE86B684AC35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Power generation</header><text>All lands in the recreation area which have been withdrawn or acquired by the United States for reclamation purposes shall remain subject to the primary use thereof for reclamation and power purposes so long as they are needed for such purposes.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H45388CAF68E5475CA7D9C971C1593708"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tributaries of the kings river, the merced river, the san joaquin</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, no Federal lands may be used for the construction of any new dam or diversion, or expansion of any existing dam or diversion, on any tributary of the Merced, Kings and San Joaquin Rivers and the south, middle and north forks of the Merced, Kings and San Joaquin Rivers within the boundaries of the national monument.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H734A735A814A437BB2EBF53C233A27A8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Water for the national monument</header><text>There is hereby reserved, as of the date of this Act and subject to valid existing rights, a quantity of water sufficient to fulfill the purposes for which this national monument is established. Nothing in this reservation shall be construed as a relinquishment or reduction of any water use or rights reserved or appropriated by the United States on or before the date of this proclamation.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H3B97149FFA9D46268515DBE5639E0057"><enum>10.</enum><header>Withdrawal of Federal land from mining laws</header>
<subsection id="HDD35B130E92349D8B2108A563C18D477"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights as provided in section 4, the Federal lands and interests in lands included within the national monument are hereby withdrawn from—</text> <paragraph id="H2953F23A474042A0B4374542B5190BBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H89E88A5CA6424B38A8CD42F7D26A3357"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H500F4A59B4924AFDBD19CD45E771E8DE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing and geothermal leasing laws and mineral materials laws.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFB64674D9D734B16A4832D0C4FFDC232"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of existing rights</header><text>The withdrawal under subsection (a) is subject to valid, existing rights. If such rights are relinquished or otherwise acquired by the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act, the land that was subject to the rights shall be immediately withdrawn in accordance with subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8A35FFC5DFE14418B6BFE121B079CD27"><enum>11.</enum><header>Visitor services plan</header> <subsection id="H287926AF5C3E4CAF9144710E72F40F8C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Visitor services</header> <paragraph id="H80A6AB0572F24611A6078DB981507F80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this subsection is to facilitate the development of an integrated visitor services plan that will provide enhanced visitor experiences and resource protection in the national monument through expanded recreational opportunities, public safety, fire management, interpretation, education, and law enforcement.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBA05193CE5948FF93258B9E0F0C7CAB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall develop and apply an integrated visitor services plan for the national monument.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD08151A150604BD7A1B7B00C67C4F38B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The visitor services plan shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0F257CE7FE304955B13A1832C7B782C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include a regular and adequate ranger patrol and staffing plan, which covers the remaining open roads and provides for people management and resource protection to prevent human-caused wildfires; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC233A48DA5754CAAA5F6E2E614101533"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide and plan for adequate disposal of trash and recycling and management of garbage removal throughout the national monument and where appropriate and needed to prevent garbage accumulation and vandalism; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF7DA0967551141ACB4D46AFD54B11A96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>manage dispersed camping to protect natural resources and wildlife, enhance recreation, and prevent human-caused wildfires;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H65A6E9774A3C4908BB02F95996133DF7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>maintain and manage all existing picnic areas and campgrounds to ensure that visitors have adequate developed sites for recreation;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA55222182A4D4E5397A2B8F58A534F07"><enum>(E)</enum><text>develop a non-motorized trail network and prepare a maintenance and management plan for front-country and back-country trails and create and maintain trail maps, trails, and trail signs, with a particular emphasis placed on trail interconnectivity;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H41781A3A806E4526A576A82EE6FEF54B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>ensure adequate closure of roads and provide visitor signs indicating closures, and create a program for restoring the natural environment on closed roads and for developing trails on closed roads designated as non-motorized trails;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H52570FBF1D5142368A55330C5C4431B4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>assess the current level of interpretive and educational services and facilities; include recommendations to better manage recreation area resources and improve the experience of recreation area visitors through expanded interpretive and educational services and facilities, and improved enforcement; and manage recreation area resources to reduce negative impacts on the environment, the forest, and the watershed in the area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC1F480AC48E484E91DF7A03D73F8CB9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>assess opportunities to provide recreational non-motorized trails that connect with adjacent National Forest, Bureau of Land Management, and Park Service lands; and to develop and carry this out in accordance with applicable Federal, State, and local laws and ordinances;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H89B96A3D434D4AB6BCEA96F5FE6653BE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in developing the visitor services plan, the Secretary shall consult with the State and local agencies, nongovernmental organizations, tribes, and the public; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD9E8FB6CA3754F8D858DD629F0270F88"><enum>(J)</enum><text>in hiring personnel, the secretary shall prioritize hiring applicants formerly employed in jobs associated with commercial logging activities on public lands and biomass production and low income applicants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H85943715C1A54ACFA0288E801DD6BB65"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Visitor facilities</header><text>As needed, the Secretary may construct visitor use facilities in the national monument area or improve upon existing Federal buildings under the jurisdiction of the park service. Such facilities shall be developed in conformance with all existing Federal, State, and local laws (including regulations) and applicable Federal, State, and local plans.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC0D6E439AFDD4B8CAE5841F6EA27F73F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Donations</header> <paragraph id="HB9E6B53209D745BEBB559D0E31E2D348"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may accept and use donated funds, property, in-kind contributions, and services to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB43663EB3F4E4BE9AF1930F69D9B4739"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The Secretary may not use the authority provided in this Act to accept non-Federal land that has been acquired, after the date of the enactment of this Act, through use of eminent domain.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCC4CFB240734DE3A3BDF7E1EF53363E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><text>In carrying out this Act, the Secretary may make grants to, or enter into cooperative agreements with State, tribal, local governmental entities, non-profit entities and private entities to conduct research, develop scientific analyses, and carry out any other initiatives relating to the management of and visitation to the national monument.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H9D3A16A14A7F47B7B3B24092337038A1"><enum>12.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is hereby authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this Act.</text></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

