<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDE76A4E35D548DC85F8BC6097BF4401" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7388 IH: Offshore Wind American Manufacturing Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7388</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220404">April 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000185">Mr. Scott of Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a manufacturing investment tax credit and a production tax credit for manufacturing facilities that produce offshore wind turbine components.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H63F566B7D1A247969E9DF2FCF85A2054" style="OLC"><section id="H6BBAA01B834549E0AD6DE862675BC624" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Offshore Wind American Manufacturing Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC750A86F4C4740B1BAA9A53648D657A0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Offshore wind manufacturing credit</header><subsection id="HFBE48E491E7D42239737845E7A4C0783"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 36B the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7354FB23B7714C88A30C4C465E45F408"><section id="H022810CE92234C3E884104EBBF14DE03"><enum>36C.</enum><header>Offshore wind manufacturing credit</header><subsection id="HCF52B9DE198E438D94D4EE662D03501D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allowance of credit</header><text>There shall be allowed as a credit against the tax imposed by this subtitle for any taxable year an amount equal to the sum of—</text><paragraph id="H0F655436369943509913289E1153CEC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the offshore wind manufacturing investment credit, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82102FAD3D2D479D9F25D27D49B894E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the offshore wind manufacturing production credit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4667D9086A97463A8D3D40D46DE75EE8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit amounts</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H3BD0FF88BB6847AEB34F4545CE258E1B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufacturing investment credit</header><subparagraph id="H62619ACF44504E1D9A04A30579C03534"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The offshore wind manufacturing investment credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 30 percent of the qualified investment for such taxable year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA271E4496E34EDE8973C815E57B8A4E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified investment</header><clause id="H2FF4866AD7ED4199B8D1EF6626151AD7"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The qualified investment for any taxable year is the basis of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property placed in service in the United States by the taxpayer during such taxable year.</text></clause><clause id="H11E1C5EF49694A3E971DFA2C3D2FD02F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In the case of property which is leased by the taxpayer as described in subparagraph (C)(iii)(II), the qualified investment shall not exceed the payments made by the taxpayer under the lease, except to the extent the taxpayer incurs expenses with respect to such property which are not covered by the lease.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4097017B03954224BDAEA68A943BC8C3"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Advanced offshore wind manufacturing property</header><text>The term <term>advanced offshore wind manufacturing property</term> means property—</text><clause id="HAEC9DFCF691D40A0AC578ABC64FC61C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is used predominantly to manufacture, meaningfully assemble, or process any qualified offshore wind component,</text></clause><clause id="HFD4EEDF8C75248C79C82A2DF3721500D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to which depreciation (or amortization in lieu of depreciation) is allowable, and</text></clause><clause id="H993CD9FF887D435CBE33E1F8E8487012"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which—</text><subclause id="HDC213E728BA34BF1809DF83FB7DD69D3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is constructed, reconstructed, or erected by the taxpayer, or</text></subclause><subclause id="H7A0186225D9B40BF83964ECE3FC76957"><enum>(II)</enum><text>which is leased or acquired by the taxpayer, if the original use of such property commences with the taxpayer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ED77847AE5441B9A95C3691E0724551"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manufacturing production credit</header><subparagraph id="HAFBF36B3E57B410F9EFF83C468770ACB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The offshore wind manufacturing production credit is an amount equal to the applicable rate with respect to any qualified offshore wind component, related vessel, qualified cable, or qualified steel which—</text><clause id="H84467B9C6A074358A780B818C8A6AA78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is produced by the taxpayer at a qualified manufacturing facility, and</text></clause><clause id="H3917DC2A1C984F30AF64A27E975C1C92"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during the taxable year—</text><subclause id="HE8E3D37DFE3E4542BE0D6303173CE609"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is sold by the taxpayer to—</text><item id="H6A7AD7C87B0C433EBFCDA92CBA365DCD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an unrelated person, or</text></item><item id="H07BC6DEF5898480BA66EEE14F8C6488C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a related person for the use of such person in their trade or business (with the exception of any trade or business related to resale of such offshore wind component without any subsequent modification, assembly, or integration into a project), or</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H4E079AA604484AE58E9A8E0FFEF4AC21"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if not sold, is placed in service or operation by the taxpayer or any other person.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AAEC716EA0B45B8B87F3544BE821C3F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicable rate</header><text>The applicable rate is—</text><clause id="HE3DD87DAD0CE4AADB6D680DC73D64491"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to any qualified offshore wind component other than a substation, the total rated capacity (expressed on a per watt basis) of the completed offshore wind turbine for which the component is designed, multiplied by—</text><subclause id="H979D434FD3B942909275808C8AAC7F70"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of any blade or drive train, 2 cents,</text></subclause><subclause id="H7E846951BC1544A8AC94C2700157D39F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of any tower, 3 cents,</text></subclause><subclause id="H34761AD934584970939CDB69E933AE93"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in the case of any foundation, 4 cents, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC61E47920D824361A7A942716F170688"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>in the case of any nacelle, 5 cents,</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H8F941F7C5E1F406980051D8245F2BCA9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>with respect to any substation, 2 cents per watt of total rated capacity,</text></clause><clause id="HE3F2A1B485124E81B631FA4FBB972591"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to any related vessel, an amount equal to 10 percent of the sale price of such vessel,</text></clause><clause id="H8DE5BB0DC9944471A2A087B52EED46FE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>with respect to any qualified cable, an amount equal to the product of—</text><subclause id="HDB22AB1956AE471B913F82A925808300"><enum>(I)</enum><text>30 cents multiplied by the total rated capacity (expressed on a per kilowatt basis) of such cable, multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="HD9CFB1D6CB0540C4864E4068944C31B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the number of kilometers of such cable placed in service, and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF837494B54714C65BE7A221F3BC5C03C"><enum>(v)</enum><text>with respect to any qualified steel, an amount equal to 10 percent of the sale price of such steel.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF39318F3F4A94DBE9C8C4899C6407A61"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified manufacturing facility</header><text>The term <term>qualified manufacturing facility</term> means any new or existing facility—</text><clause id="HCC4AD4F36ABA491DB0365642664EC92F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>which is located in the United States, and</text></clause><clause id="H26918740F86C407A95E5B7D346232811"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which manufactures or meaningfully assembles qualified offshore wind components, related vessels, qualified cables, or qualified steel.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A748855C35B4CE1B3EE8FDD0D05BCAC" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Production and sale must be in trade or business</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any qualified offshore wind component, related vessel, qualified cable, or qualified steel, produced and sold by the taxpayer shall be taken into account under subparagraph (A)(ii)(I) only if the production and sale described in subparagraph (A) is in a trade or business of the taxpayer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA2BF0314EAB4969B853D15FA20A03CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE25C50EB40844AD87277BB9257F9059"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Qualified offshore wind component</header><subparagraph id="H15AD53F9601A48529C530D1F31E6B822"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>qualified offshore wind component</term> means any blade, tower, nacelle, drive train, foundation, or substation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD65494E8372C40C286764A075B19F129"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Definitions</header><clause id="H21C3BD6BB2644C0BA7B5E4B396021A40"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Blade</header><text>The term <term>blade</term> means an airfoil-shaped blade which is responsible for converting offshore wind energy to low speed rotational energy.</text></clause><clause id="HBAA769FAE5E340BDA97108B4CB24EC01"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Tower</header><text>The term <term>tower</term> means a tubular steel, concrete, or steel lattice which supports the structure of an offshore wind turbine, and the transition piece which connects the tower to the foundation.</text></clause><clause id="H2083894F35994785B4EE534336AE32FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Nacelle</header><text>The term <term>nacelle</term> means the assembly of the drive train and other tower-top components of an offshore wind turbine (other than the blade) within their cover housing. </text></clause><clause id="HDE34958291244B8C97C9E05697733222"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Drive train</header><text>The term <term>drive train</term> means the component which is housed in the nacelle and converts the low-speed, high-torque rotation of the rotor to electrical energy.</text></clause><clause id="H9D4FC63D0D1449EE83410CD463C4AD10"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>foundation</term> means the component which secures an offshore wind tower and above-water turbine components to the sea floor, including—</text><subclause id="H1326888BD0AF4748A35943D8B4985C28"><enum>(I)</enum><text>fixed-bottom foundations such as monopiles, jackets, or gravity-based foundations, or</text></subclause><subclause id="HF8B93A7761894EABB10D444802409D47"><enum>(II)</enum><text>floating platforms and associated mooring systems.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9A9BEF0100A94BC891026CE1112C1EB0"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Substation</header><text>The term <term>substation</term> means a structure which is dedicated to the transmission of energy generated by offshore wind.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H05C9003ECD9B43F9B3BD2BD1D0829EE3" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Related vessel</header><text>The term <term>related vessel</term> means any vessel which is purpose-built or retrofitted for purposes of the development, transport, installation, operation, or maintenance of offshore wind components and offshore wind turbines.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H8B59D58C85EC4E5FB44E3DA6120FEC9B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Qualified cable</header><text>The term <term>qualified cable</term> means—</text><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HAEECE7A6FB6A4EEC8F1E16A873CD0BF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any export cable with a total rated capacity of not less than 132 kilovolts, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HAF7D3F144D664742A20D3803C3DA6418"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any interarray cable with a total rated capacity of not less than 66 kilovolts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="HA43D7C2950FC4285A44A738E97DBF8E9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified steel</header><text>The term <term>qualified steel</term> means steel which is used in the tower or foundation with respect to an offshore wind turbine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7F0896F0723945C9AE61C0EDE3BA2F72"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H5033A9C5B08E41F692DA755E2385417B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>Any reference to the Secretary means the Secretary in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, except that the Secretary shall have the authority to implement regulations and other guidance under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF8553071D4445F9CEDEDDD1ABED870"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain rules made applicable for investment credit</header><text>For purposes of the offshore wind manufacturing investment credit determined under subsection (b)(1), rules similar to the rules of subsections (a) and (c) of section 50 shall apply.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A74926598244CBCB257E80E620D4ED7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with general investment credit</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under section 48C with respect to any facility taken into account for purposes of the credit under subsection (b)(2), or any facility with respect to which any qualified investment is taken into account for purposes of the credit under subsection (b)(1). The credit under this section shall be allowed without regard to whether any qualified investment (as defined in section 48C(b)) with respect to a facility has been taken into account for purposes of section 48C in any preceding taxable year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A694F56E745453EB03BE86411244134"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Labor conditions with respect to offshore wind manufacturing investment credit</header><subparagraph id="H5DC0A01DE37046FF9CD9525EFD37D790"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property which does not satisfy the requirements of subparagraphs (B) and (C), as determined by the Secretary, the amount of the credit determined under subsection (b)(1) shall be 6 percent of such amount (as determined without regard to this subparagraph).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21EF53C07CE44EB696D8556635C63561"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prevailing wage requirements</header><clause id="H0FEF96D486FA4FBBAD0E7E3614648067"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The taxpayer shall ensure that any laborers and mechanics employed by contractors or subcontractors in— </text><subclause id="H120D40C97BDE49248340DC5C20D3F883"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the construction, reconstruction, or erection of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property, and</text></subclause><subclause id="H095DFDF19C434ECAB2CD3AA84CD2407A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for the 10-year period beginning on the date such property is originally placed in service, any alteration or repair of such property,</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on work of a character similar in the locality as determined by the Secretary of Labor in accordance with subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code. </continuation-text></clause><clause id="HFA399FA5D65F4D34B56705BB825A5B13"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Correction and penalty related to failure to satisfy wage requirements</header><text>In the case of any taxpayer which fails to satisfy the requirements of clause (i), such taxpayer shall be deemed to have satisfied such requirement for any year if, with respect to any laborer or mechanic who was paid wages at a rate below the rate described in such clause for any period during such year, such taxpayer— </text><subclause id="HED171999362B4F8CAB8AA58D83A4A8CD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>makes payment to such laborer or mechanic in an amount equal to the sum of— </text><item id="HF13EEBFB2D474FEC9D2DEC07A1A02A21"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an amount equal to the difference between the amount of wages paid to such laborer or mechanic during such period and the amount of wages required to be paid to such laborer or mechanic pursuant to such clause during such period, multiplied by 3, and</text></item><item id="HF5FF207140AA4421B4C1D0B5A353C268"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>interest on the amount determined under item (aa) at the underpayment rate established under section 6621 for the period described in such item, and </text></item></subclause><subclause id="H2637AC21246C421CA8B9D0417D328845"><enum>(II)</enum><text>makes payment to the Secretary of a penalty in an amount equal to the product of— </text><item id="HAE380CB3E78A4B1EBDADB91CCD18D679"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>$5,000, multiplied by</text></item><item id="H8E9F02E20F4546A6AC6427AE53940047"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the total number of laborers and mechanics who were paid wages at a rate below the rate described in clause (i) for any period during such year.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H563D7521D7EE40EA911682A105EE228B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Apprenticeship requirements</header><clause id="HDE9878DCDC9E4541A6FF1D35E1073D8E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Apprentice labor hours</header><subclause id="H899414321BC245FE8475ECF80013A915"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Percentage of total labor hours</header><text>Each contractor and subcontractor engaged in the performance of construction, reconstruction, or erection of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property, shall, subject to subclause (III), ensure that not less than the applicable percentage of the total labor hours of such work be performed by qualified apprentices. </text></subclause><subclause id="H3E4F980F7DC34F1DB54CD061C5B00D96"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of subclause (I), the applicable percentage shall be determined separately with respect to each contractor and subcontractor in accordance with the following table:</text><table table-type="" table-template-name="Generic: 1 text, 1 num" align-to-level="section" frame="topbot" colsep="1" rowsep="0" blank-lines-before="1" line-rules="hor-ver" rule-weights="4.4.4.0.0.0"><tgroup cols="2" grid-typeface="1.1" rowsep="0" thead-tbody-ldg-size="10.10.12"><colspec coldef="txt" colname="column1" min-data-value="200" rowsep="0" colwidth="269pts"></colspec><colspec coldef="fig" colname="column2" min-data-value="10" rowsep="0" colwidth="56pts"></colspec><thead><row><entry align="center" morerows="0" namest="column1" rowsep="1" colname="column1">In the case of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property the construction, reconstruction, or erection of which, begins:</entry><entry align="center" morerows="0" namest="column2" rowsep="1" colname="column2">The applicable percentage is:</entry></row></thead><tbody><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">Before January 1, 2023</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">10%</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">After December 31, 2022, and before January 1, 2024</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">12%</entry></row><row><entry align="left" rowsep="0" stub-definition="txt-ldr" stub-hierarchy="1" colname="column1">After December 31, 2023</entry><entry align="right" rowsep="0" colname="column2">15%.</entry></row></tbody></tgroup></table></subclause><subclause id="H803FBB3FF4DF4128B13C78A7FBFE59E2"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Apprentice to journeyworker ratio</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of subclause (I) shall be subject to any applicable requirements for apprentice-to-journeyworker ratios of the Department of Labor or the applicable State apprenticeship agency recognized by the Office of Apprenticeship, pursuant to the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the National Apprenticeship Act) (50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFA3CC11ABAEB4FCF932227C16D313DC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Apprentice diversity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contractor and subcontractor engaged in the performance of construction, reconstruction, or erection of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property shall have a plan to hire, retain, and increase participation of apprentices from underrepresented groups to the greatest extent possible.</text></clause><clause id="HFC6DFCE4FB4B4238A7D4546A6598010A"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply in the case of a taxpayer who demonstrates—</text><subclause id="H8AE0D2A4054C4020A6217CC1AA33796B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a lack of availability of qualified apprentices in the geographic area of the construction, alteration, or repair work, and </text></subclause><subclause id="H73E09B0E53EE4284868B85AF611D2A86"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a good faith effort to comply with the requirements of such clause.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7B460AD8F5074283AA7615808FAF987D"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>In the case of any failure to satisfy the requirements of clause (i) (except as provided in clause (iii)) with respect to any construction, reconstruction, or erection of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property, the taxpayer shall make payment to the Secretary of an amount equal to—</text><subclause id="HD7EED76FC7B34DC58D8548BAB5FA77E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>$500, multiplied by</text></subclause><subclause id="HD3CE4335A2414EABA4CF224CDD46C7B6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the total labor hours for which such requirements were not satisfied by any contractor of subcontractor.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HA2D1597C22E84D3C8B3A6750C5619177"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subparagraph—</text><subclause id="H6A70871900D54F56B2E543D9B3CFE3A7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Good faith effort</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>good faith effort</term> means that the taxpayer has requested qualified apprentices from a registered apprenticeship program, as defined in section 3131(e)(3)(B), and such request has been denied. The preceding sentence shall not apply if such denial is the result of a refusal by the contractors or subcontractors engaged in the performance of construction, reconstruction, or erection of any advanced offshore wind manufacturing property to comply with the established standards and requirements of such apprenticeship program.</text></subclause><subclause id="HA774F61640654E40B8C17D8D00A953FB"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Labor hours</header><text>The term <term>labor hours</term> means the total number of hours devoted to the performance of construction, reconstruction, or erection work by employees of the contractor or subcontractor. Such term does not include any hours worked by—</text><item id="HE2491580FB884347B94FF1FA3FCC82AB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>foremen,</text></item><item id="H61E98BBF974346CF8D41239AB106C80C"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>superintendents,</text></item><item id="HC05D16CFF3BA43F9821A5973EE6DDF7F"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>owners, or</text></item><item id="HA9C21431648E4FE786908C85AF71C84B"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>persons employed in a bona fide executive, administrative, or professional capacity (within the meaning of such terms as used in part 541 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HADA0FD380FE14FC286324AD895DDFC58"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Qualified apprentice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>qualified apprentice</term> means an employee participating in an apprenticeship program registered with the Office of Apprenticeship of the Employment Training Administration of the Department of Labor or a State apprenticeship agency recognized by the Office of Apprenticeship pursuant to the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the National Apprenticeship Act) (50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3D76DEB12E24AA1A753A6249E373CF4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Labor standard with respect to offshore wind manufacturing production credit</header><subparagraph id="H418AEC9E288641E3BCEE73C5ACBF2823"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any qualified manufacturing facility which satisfies the requirements of subparagraph (B), as determined by the Secretary, the amount of the credit determined under subsection (b)(2) shall be increased by 10 percent of the amount of such credit determined without regard to this subparagraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA728EB2498146AA92A156BC96526CE2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Labor requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualified manufacturing facility satisfies the requirements of this subparagraph if all employees providing production or maintenance services at such facility are represented for the purposes of collective bargaining under section 9 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB6CA61A3EBF845838742C63466F86DF4"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Registration</header><paragraph id="HC639629D1A734DD88FB630494BB5A3EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under this section unless the taxpayer registers with the Secretary, at such time, in such form and manner, and subject to such terms and conditions, as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe. Such regulations shall include a provision that each taxpayer must submit a declaration made under the penalties of perjury certifying compliance with the requirements under paragraphs (4) and (5) of subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA8EBDE5B71B4C37BA9EFFBDF841EEA0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Registration in event of change in ownership</header><text>Under regulations prescribed by the Secretary, the taxpayer (other than a corporation the stock of which is regularly traded on an established securities market) shall be required to re-register under this subsection if after a transaction (or series of related transactions) more than 50 percent of ownership interests in, or assets of, the taxpayer are held by persons other than persons (or persons related thereto) who held more than 50 percent of such interests or assets before the transaction (or series of related transactions).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F001BD750064A0AA1329F1777B27703"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Denial, revocation, or suspension of registration</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of section 4222(c) shall apply to registration under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD350964F3F6349D597A1F9FE30C5BD2E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information reporting</header><text>The Secretary may require—</text><subparagraph id="H1DD1F647FE6F4B43BC6C6DC8DF489473"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information reporting by any person registered under this subsection, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7DD422544BA4C6DB4D3446B50304AA4" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information reporting by such other persons as the Secretary deems necessary to carry out this section. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C28C5D34E7544FDA0A648235C28593A" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="H9F5E1919FBB0488C951A1F6D46A14F1B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Offshore wind manufacturing investment tax credit</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HAD6D8037BF8947518CB5DB454A63E0DC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), in the case of any qualified investment with respect to advanced offshore wind manufacturing property which is placed in service after December 31, 2028, the amount of the credit determined under subsection (b)(1) (without regard to this subsection) shall be reduced by—</text><clause commented="no" id="HBA5D22DFBFCD4C39AB8525B28685E3E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of property placed in service in calendar year 2029, 30 percent,</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H39DF1F27BE734845AF6EA06B29970CF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of property placed in service in calendar year 2030, 65 percent, and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H334C00F3BFDC47629E5D85D7FC410B93"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of property placed in service after December 31, 2030, 100 percent.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA981180A850145299CDA80237A297997"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Certain progress expenditure rules made applicable</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of subsections (c)(4) and (d) of section 46 (as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of the Revenue Reconciliation Act of 1990) shall apply for purposes of subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA423483E36B04EFCB71F5F2459C6E79A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Offshore wind manufacturing production tax credit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed under subsection (b)(2) in the case of any qualified offshore wind component, related vessel, qualified cable, or qualified steel, first sold or placed in service after December 31, 2030.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD78ADFA4F9B04C96BF035A32A9D813BC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart C of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 36B the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9444F628AA624C9D9AD2F6DF56590B12"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H022810CE92234C3E884104EBBF14DE03">Sec. 36C. Offshore wind manufacturing credit.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4E75B0A464DC4D8C85A0CCCEA80922F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 1324(b) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, 36C</quote> after <quote>36B</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA36CFCF743E94827A1131B3767FB5518"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to—</text><paragraph id="H23C2712F480B4B669B7A378BFB16C7CD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any qualified investment (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/36C">section 36C(b)(1)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as added by this section) with respect to property placed in service beginning after August 1, 2021, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEED1EAF2F694A2284F08CAB40CFDB1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">qualified offshore wind components, related vessels, qualified cables, or qualified steel (within the meaning of section 36C of such Code, as so added) first sold or placed in service after August 1, 2021.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

