<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB37B81A4E0AF462A80D7528E7BCD9379" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7716 IH: Coordinating Substance Use and Homelessness Care Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7716</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220511">May 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To help persons in the United States experiencing homelessness and significant behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, by authorizing a grant program within the Department of Housing and Urban Development to assist State and local governments, Continuums of Care, community-based organizations that administer both health and homelessness services, and providers of services to people experiencing homelessness, better coordinate health care and homelessness services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2E1C256E01A246E3B325F2C57F88E657" style="OLC"><section id="H59557086F6284F14AA0D102516875671" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Coordinating Substance Use and Homelessness Care Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0265797E87044A8EBDFA1BD74A5461C9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6BBA7F48197241B7A4C55897CEFB926C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States has a homelessness crisis, with more than 580,000 people experiencing homelessness on a single night according to the Department of Housing and Urban Development’s 2020 Annual Homeless Assessment Report to Congress. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H749CB60AD6FE4CAA837AA637C18B219E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While the lack of affordable housing is the primary driver of homelessness, behavioral health conditions, including substance use disorders, can exacerbate homelessness and can also be a consequence of homelessness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44C1C18A61C34CA893C36552E760DACC"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research shows that people experiencing homelessness have higher rates of substance use disorder than people with housing stability. Some people who experience homelessness use substances to cope with the trauma and deprivations of their circumstances, but substance use disorders frequently make it more difficult for people experiencing homelessness to secure permanent housing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42EE6886928C4ED0A0226DBDD87D7B5F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Many individuals with substance use disorder who experience homelessness have co-occurring illnesses. The combined effect of physical illness, mental illness, and lack of housing results in higher mortality rates for individuals experiencing homelessness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA78B5C20757A4160A92842DA5DE6D75E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Safely and securely housing individuals who are experiencing both homelessness and behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, often requires supportive services and close coordination between housing and social service providers, in addition to low-barrier, affordable housing. Subsidized housing is critical, but not enough—access to additional voluntary person-centered supportive services is needed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FF18EAB923947839E7FB96197D8DE2E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nevertheless, it is imperative that when people experiencing homelessness, including those with a behavioral health condition such as substance use disorder, choose to seek help that housing as well as health care and person-centered supportive services be coordinated, particularly given their acute needs and the significant costs incurred by communities for law enforcement, correctional, and emergency department care for failing to do so.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B5663563C354C928C89EDBD739D2A1F"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing access to health care and voluntary person-centered supportive services can be beneficial in securing and successfully maintaining stable housing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8636BD7F270C4F198D0227122A7346A3"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Integration of health and homelessness services to achieve optimal outcomes for people experiencing homelessness, significant behavioral health conditions such as substance use disorder, and other health conditions can be challenging for State and local governments, continuums of care, and community-based organizations that administer both health and homelessness services and providers of homelessness services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9F967A3C48D4846BFE7ECA63AA40603"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Capacity-building is needed to create systems-level linkages between the two sets of services to allow for smoother pathways and simpler navigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5A973ECDDC1465F9CE0234D9F3101E4"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Black, Hispanic, and Indigenous people are disproportionately underserved by person-centered supportive services. In order to address critical services deficits and affirmatively serve protected classes of people with significant behavioral health conditions, including substance use disorders, who are experiencing homelessness, the grant program established under this Act can be used to build the capacities of homelessness services providers that have demonstrated cultural competencies in service provision and a record of serving Black, Hispanic, and Indigenous people and other underserved populations experiencing homelessness that also suffer from substance use disorders.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H954046EAE885440CB6E8275A2525DF2F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of grant program</header><subsection id="H801E911B6D3E494E964F23AF3F4DB104"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the working group established pursuant to subsection (b), shall establish a grant program to award competitive grants to eligible entities to build or increase their capacities for the better coordination of health care and homelessness services for people who are experiencing homelessness and significant behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, and are voluntarily seeking assistance.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8439099FCB6A4585BB66109AF9F932E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Working group</header><paragraph id="H8F6C74CDE55D41BABA61568F5CD0610B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an interagency working group to provide advice to the Secretary in carrying out the program under subsection (a). The working group shall include representatives from the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the United States Interagency Council on Homelessness, Department of Health and Human Services, Department of Agriculture, and Bureau of Indian Affairs, to be appointed by the heads of such agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8AC6741AFAF4B48BCAB0B9EB29E2FB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of assistance tools</header><text>The working group shall, not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, develop training, tools, and other technical assistance materials that simplify homelessness services for providers of health care and simplify health care services for providers of homelessness services by identifying the basic elements the health and homelessness sectors need to understand about the other, and shall circulate such materials to interested entities, particularly those who apply for grants awarded pursuant to this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2E24733851F4DF58C1B01D9B545A285"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Capacity-Building grants</header><paragraph id="HD395499983724F35824373DDAFC04F4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award 5-year grants to eligible entities, which shall be used only to build or increase their capacities to coordinate health care and homelessness services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H505FD2D1A8F845C193497351CAB0FEDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the proceeds from the grants awarded pursuant to this Act may be used to pay for health care, with the exception of efforts to increase the availability of Naloxone and provide training for its administration, or rent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD44A2A50B0B6471F814C5B1F4147425E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount awarded to an entity under a grant under this subsection shall not exceed $500,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC23295F97CA946A0B4EB696731D1589F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection an entity shall—</text><subparagraph id="H492646C586B7449399D6FF8926ED0EAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be—</text><clause id="HF8A37A9B33AA4B1FBF14294ACE8D51BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a governmental entity (at the county, city, regional, or locality level);</text></clause><clause id="H403383F47333432480D7AB4F68F80D8E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an Indian tribe, a Tribally designated housing entity, or a Tribal organization;</text></clause><clause id="H9C179DF58DC24994A290634A33F7DE32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public housing agency administering housing choice vouchers; or</text></clause><clause id="HB692E40DC75F4C58BC1AE8B152267F3C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a continuum of care or nonprofit organization designated by the continuum of care; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB0CBA94C6214D4BA2C4EC7A75AE7581"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be responsible for homelessness services; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89F95A624A9A42B18B2834AA4C721C0E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide such assurances as the Secretary shall require that, in carrying out activities with amounts from the grant, the entity will ensure that services are culturally competent, meet the needs of the people being served, and follow trauma-informed best practices to address those needs using a harm reduction approach; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13543FB545E0435D9B10FC28F55C1BED"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate how its capacity to coordinate health care and homelessness services to better serve people experiencing homelessness and significant behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, can be increased through—</text><clause id="H6CD7AFE9C676433BA9392A8BDDF51CE3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the designation of a governmental official as a coordinator for making connections between health and homelessness services and developing a strategy for using those services in a holistic way to help people experiencing homelessness and behavioral health conditions such as substance use disorders, including those with cooccurring conditions;</text></clause><clause id="H1346ED5E68F644EDADD06E919581236A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements in infrastructure at the systems level;</text></clause><clause id="H2A55FE591C9E427EB6E94DC8954524D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements in technology for voluntary remote monitoring capabilities, including internet and video, which can allow for more home- and community-based behavioral health care services and ensure such improvements maintain effective communication requirements for persons with disabilities and program access for persons with limited English proficiency;</text></clause><clause id="HBE06F3233C0F49E0AC6E570686229ECB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improvements in connections to health care services delivered by providers experienced in behavioral health care and people experiencing homelessness;</text></clause><clause id="H107463FCB4214B85828FDC8945EB4E2B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>efforts to increase the availability of Naloxone and provide training for its administration; and</text></clause><clause id="H71ED17A0CD31446EBD766B796A631EFA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional activities identified by the Secretary that will advance the coordination of homelessness assistance, housing, and substance use services and other health care services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79FA82FCE4AC45F1BC83D62703C843D1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible grantee receiving a grant under this subsection may use the grant to cover costs related to—</text><subparagraph id="HA399AACC6A6A4BA58ED422F42FBBED0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hiring system coordinators; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84402279919C4AD68D83E7584A6D1D66"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">administrative costs, including staffing costs, technology costs, and other such costs identified by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92E419219F28420593D3CB75989662B9"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Distribution of funds</header><text>An eligible grantee receiving a grant under this subsection may distribute all or a portion of the grant amounts to private nonprofit organizations, other government entities, public housing agencies, tribally designated housing entities, or other entities as determined by the Secretary to carry out programs and activities in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61255F569FDF44F69066BB08E3F56977"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Oversight requirements</header><subparagraph id="H4AA1A58F19AF4017B86115C314C16E9C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 6 years after the date on which grant amounts are first received by an eligible entity, such entity shall submit to the Secretary a report on the activities carried out under the grant. Such report shall include, with respect to activities carried out with grant amounts in the community served—</text><clause id="HD4AA1BACF62D432799CA403C9D51A671"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">measures of outcomes relating to whether people experiencing homelessness and significant behavioral health issues, including substance use disorders, who sought help from an entity that received a grant—</text><subclause id="H65C8C328643E41AD9D85350550A88FD6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>were housed and did not experience intermittent periods of homelessness;</text></subclause><subclause id="H635521DA93614BD6814C11FBA7AF2DFE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>were voluntarily enrolled in treatment and recovery programs;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD420E2C51D554C6B9E4CEBE82B4694FF"><enum>(III)</enum><text>experienced improvements in their health;</text></subclause><subclause id="H31340B10EBD74D85A4FC5975800C86ED"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>obtained access to specific primary care providers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HC18CEE1C337F47978926813DB0F274B6"><enum>(V)</enum><text>have health care plans that meet their individual needs, including access to mental health and substance use disorder treatment and recovery services;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDB7EE21CD06E45C39A3D5DBFCA4A808E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>how grant funds were used; and</text></clause><clause id="H401DF184359D4A42B423BAA674BA1265"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other matters determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24FCEA73F9834A889B9180F4E30F26E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to condition the receipt of future housing and other services by individuals assisted with activities and services provided with grant amounts on the outcomes detailed in the reports submitted under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4C7606DEC048C6A6CA023BDD91A1FF"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H58495DA466E6441BBEB36CC5E0D2B4DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Indian Tribe; Tribal organization</header><text>The terms <term>Indian Tribe</term> and <term>Tribal organization</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>) and shall include tribally designated housing entities (as such term is defined in section 4 of the Native American Housing Assistance and Self-Determination Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/4103">25 U.S.C. 4103</external-xref>)) and entities that serve Native Hawaiians (as such term is defined in section 338K(c) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/254s">42 U.S.C. 254s(c)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H069B78758C614D67B10DFB33021CA8D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Person experiencing homelessness</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>person experiencing homelessness</term> has the same meaning as the terms <term>homeless</term>, <term>homeless individual</term>, and <term>homeless person</term> as those terms are defined in the McKinney-Vento Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11302">42 U.S.C. 11302</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41FA996D9680470BA31D61B4BA51FCB9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Substance use disorder</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>substance use disorder</term> means the disorder that occurs when the recurrent use of alcohol or drugs, or both, causes clinically significant impairment, including health problems, disability, and failure to meet major responsibilities at work, school, or home.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C8CBAFE1B3B49C1A50042FD6F7E831A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section, $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027, of which not less than 5 percent of such funds shall be awarded to Indian tribes and tribal organizations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

