<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H83220F6DD35E4A069BEFBB3C29D002F6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6507 IH: Child Health Savings Account Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6507</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220125">January 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow for the establishment of child health savings accounts, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9B4EE95AFAE94E0B82917EDAACA536BB" style="OLC"><section id="HBABF93274FDF42C1934C314189F42BFD" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Child Health Savings Account Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5C701C00417A41C29321D1EC6398DE0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Health savings accounts</header><subsection id="HFE5475E2F8DC41988D77BC23210B4553"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Child health savings account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/223">Section 223</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8150566B5FAA441DBCB1379FA58929FE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HBD8BF82EEDA34DB8BDCB089BD760C8DA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Child health savings account</header><paragraph id="HD0685401718946D18B2F6C2636E34182"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any deduction allowed under subsection (a) for any taxable year, there shall be allowed as a deduction under this section an amount equal to the aggregate amount paid in cash by an individual during the taxable year to a child savings account of a child of the individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF4285B53CBF4312A47A4FA0973FF0AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The amount taken into account under paragraph (1) with respect to each child of an individual during the taxable year shall not exceed an amount equal to $3,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1D8FEADFC2C40B8815B93B9AAA9685F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Child health savings account</header><text>For the purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>child health savings account</quote> means a health savings account designated as a child health savings account and established for the benefit of a child of an individual, but only if under the written governing instrument creating the trust, no contribution will be accepted to the extent such contribution, when added to previous contributions to the trust for the calendar year, exceeds the dollar amount in effect under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CF1153D16A54EEBAA5D60FC114FD4A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of account before age of 18</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, except as otherwise provided in this subsection, a child health savings account shall be treated as a health savings account of the parents of the child until the child attained the age of 18, after which such account shall be treated as a health savings account of the child.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB41180E2DA145979A5F0E746BEF50D3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Distributions</header><subparagraph id="HD7E98C6AAD694A3094C6AE89398BFAA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section—</text><clause id="H29429E373A3543FBAA7AB99B6A4ACAAC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Before age of 18</header><text>Any amount paid or distributed out of a child health savings account before the child with respect to whom the account was established has attained the age of 18, shall be included in the gross income of the parents of the child, and subsection (f)(A) shall apply (relating to additional tax on distributions not used for qualified medical expenses).</text></clause><clause id="H62578127636D4027B09462A54A42EE45"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Age 18 and older</header><text>Any amount paid or distributed out of such account after the child has attained the age of 18 may only be treated as used to pay qualified medical expenses to the extent such child is not covered as a dependent under insurance (other than permitted insurance) of a parent.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H818FE5C454B7454B9CA4425C790BA4FB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions for disability or death of a child</header><text>If the child becomes disabled within the meaning of section 72(m)(7) or dies—</text><clause id="H21D60BFB977C41D6BB7AEA36C79AA409"><enum>(i)</enum><text>paragraph (1) shall not apply to any subsequent payment or distribution, and</text></clause><clause id="H72ECCAFE9DF048FF9CC4D3EE70F32917"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a parent may rollover the amount in such account to an individual retirement plan of the parent, to any health savings account of the parent, or to any child health savings account of any other child of the parent.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H528F593208B949D28911EAD12B8BCD66"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4BA33DF1AA284546B1C89874E2940504"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

