<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA30EB20DF94D48EBB069A3D75161F749" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7948 IH: To require any entity established to develop congressional redistricting plans for a State to hold public hearings at which individuals who are members of communities of interest have a meaningful opportunity to express their views on proposed redistricting plans, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7948</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220603">June 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require any entity established to develop congressional redistricting plans for a State to hold public hearings at which individuals who are members of communities of interest have a meaningful opportunity to express their views on proposed redistricting plans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAF04A0AEEF5B427DBB539377A3E9AAAE" style="OLC"><section id="HED17F968644D496398A6F99DAE47613B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requiring entities established to develop congressional redistricting plans to hold public hearings</header><subsection id="HA4188110A0F246F29E464D8408384783"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity other than the legislature of a State, including an independent redistricting commission, a special master appointed by a Federal or State court, or a Federal or State court, which develops a congressional redistricting plan for a State shall—</text><paragraph id="HED3560B9019B485DB76A854357D44D97"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hold multiple public hearings prior to the development of a final plan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5220E4DCD4414D0AA18A82BAB831ADA8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that individuals may attend such hearings virtually;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D29EF131E7C446EB7E6E58DC5E83648"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hold such hearings in locations which are within a reasonable distance of the locations of communities of interest; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30BC5A6B0A2B41A9B81B3F1DCDCCD22F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>ensure that members of communities of interest have meaningful opportunities to express their views on any of the entity’s plans. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29AAF04179814E0FB4D42597D3B063B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of political subdivisions as communities of interest</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>communities of interest</term> may, in certain circumstances, include political subdivisions such as counties, municipalities, tribal lands and reservations, or school districts, but shall not include common relationships with political parties or political candidates.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67B3DC1DF51F4878AD770E8564B01B76"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="HE74477A01B1548F397527BCA5379A66D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Action by Attorney General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court for such declaratory or injunctive relief as is necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA695A040D2074B63AD99B6F21C82C1CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who is aggrieved by a violation of this Act may bring a civil action in an appropriate district court for such declaratory or injunctive relief as may be appropriate with respect to the violation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAA4A7FA29F0A437984619840FE823339"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall apply with respect to redistricting carried out pursuant to the decennial census conducted during 2030 or any succeeding decennial census.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

