<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HA96FDF9095294DB4899CDBF19A2BAEB4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 5522 RH: Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 495</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5522</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–678]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20211008">October 8, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Interior to develop and maintain a cadastre of Federal real property.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H3ED9C669A7F341FBB1B1E4B3856843FE" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA61527E3F62144FA9421A0F41B89655B"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Land Asset Inventory Reform Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H784393EB9DE844C5B63AABA1ECCDC162"><enum>2.</enum><header>Cadastre of Federal real property</header><subsection id="H7004A42D259640D3849C44C22CAD6090"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCB8F6703A88D4274B283B680D5DB080D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cadastre</header><subparagraph id="H5E5D8F9F5A7E4D3A85E81F8580319266"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>cadastre</term> means an inventory of real property developed through collecting, storing, retrieving, or disseminating graphical or digital data depicting natural or man-made physical features, phenomena, or boundaries of the earth, and any information related to the data, including—</text><clause id="H8D162C49871C4C07BAF614A0719FD4C1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>surveys;</text></clause><clause id="H5558A72842C2435DBAF54163E0BE98FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maps;</text></clause><clause id="H64B84E2ED211454785DE962E1A368F03"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>charts;</text></clause><clause id="H16CAA3F6921349EA9ABF620CB903E665"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>satellite and airborne remote sensing data;</text></clause><clause id="H4A915B4948CA43978176DE233333FEEE"><enum>(v)</enum><text>images; and</text></clause><clause id="HD7A4589F193F4369BE005E6680F33A9B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>services of an architectural or engineering nature performed by 1 or more professionals, as authorized to perform the services under State law, if applicable, such as—</text><subclause id="H9BD98D5706A843E7B0F9A7C255387FFB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a surveyor;</text></subclause><subclause id="H35054CC64EAF470980E563C08663819A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a photogrammetrist;</text></subclause><subclause id="H802097EE006649D493FBFFE49482AC79"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a hydrographer;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA8D065AE90684203A9573B456AF13B25"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a geodesist; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB04BC972530C4405994D87D2DA955E3B"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a cartographer.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68E50C2F0366462390B145CE5594E4D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>cadastre</term> includes—</text><clause id="HF19F83051AF9475A9B76FBE68A339939"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a reference frame consisting of a current geodetic network that is consistent with, and not duplicative of, the National Geodic Survey of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration;</text></clause><clause id="H14D4DDBB4408454D9C9870D29122FB37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a series of current and accurate large-scale maps;</text></clause><clause id="HB87654C8A20140948549338E6BF132E2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>an existing cadastral boundary overlay delineating all cadastral parcels;</text></clause><clause id="HD06226CB5F2E416F9F4CB9A3DCC862A5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a system for indexing and identifying each cadastral parcel; and</text></clause><clause id="HB9D23661BCC0456590EF48203FF56F69"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a series of land data files, each including the parcel identifier, which can be used to retrieve information and cross-reference between and among other existing data files that may contain information about the use, assets, and infrastructure of each parcel.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA90DBBCEDD6487AB65D1B307F4BF5E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H619B1570BF5846B5BB751C7F5033B9DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal real property</header><text>The term <term>Federal real property</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H3FDA6B89FD2142F89650A9EE7D00F285"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any real property owned, leased, or otherwise managed by the Federal Government; but</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAA5FF69CD0247A3B26B9CD901D0FEE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">does not include real property held in trust by the Federal Government for the benefit of one or more Indian Tribes or individual Indians or restricted lands owned by an Indian Tribe or individual Indians.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H39DFB234164243E68C8E5AD1932687D1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Landholding agency</header><text>The term <term>landholding agency</term> means a Federal department or agency with statutory authority to control real property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50E4191F6B104DF586F610AEC3205C45"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Real property</header><text>The term <term>real property</term> means real estate consisting of—</text><subparagraph id="H5F613170713440F2BB0DF8EAE623FD1C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31170E549BAB4E0997DB14E9B6B16DBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>buildings, crops, forests, or other resources still attached to or within the land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H105710EE1D864D9B8131BC156AB67DBD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improvements or fixtures permanently attached to the land;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D195AAF0622469ABE7FF75696FC5C81"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any structure on the land; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA654A8280714B9794E2EF3746F01F60"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any interest, benefit, right, or privilege in the property described in subparagraphs (A) through (D).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H750A846EAB9647F592ED57E4E5D94B55"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2722AD394D4746C3A22F68966AE9ECEE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Cadastre of Federal real property</header><paragraph id="H6FDD4B893E06437DBE9DE7CDCC831B2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interagency data standardization</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of landholding agencies, shall jointly develop and adopt interagency standards to ensure compatibility and interoperability among applicable Federal databases with respect to the collection and dissemination of data relating to Federal real property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01AE9E2437F144919B8CED31366EE803"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Development of cadastre</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the heads of landholding agencies, shall develop (and thereafter maintain) a current and accurate multipurpose cadastre of Federal real property and any real property included under paragraph (3)(A) to support Federal land management activities on Federal real property, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3BDD987CDAE745669ADC30902EBB39DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>resource development and conservation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8B30D75A3D047169F2A0A368F87D4E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>agricultural use;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2A44E37D44441FDB9734FFD37829F53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>active forest management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCA2589F34ED4B2E8816A0888823FE31"><enum>(D)</enum><text>environmental protection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H207E2358D33C41F093F46120A21B95CB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other use of the real property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H337315F3106744A9971F7EB440EF0FDD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing</header><subparagraph id="H60276F301B28413EB8079D019BB818B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cost-sharing agreements with States to include any non-Federal land in a State in the cadastre under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AAE143876D14A21AE2D358259B49A5F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text>The Federal share of any cost-sharing agreement described in subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 50 percent of the total cost to a State for the development of the cadastre of non-Federal land in the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB18CCF30D22E4846BB31B41253BEC731"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consolidation and report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives a report describing—</text><subparagraph id="HFAD2E70C65814FD0A0B910AD7BBB863F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre of Federal real property currently authorized by law or maintained by the Department, including—</text><clause id="H74AFE580CC4F4A28BEF43AE5E392A4DB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the statutory authorization for each existing real property inventory or component of a cadastre; and</text></clause><clause id="H768BB9D518464885991520FC1ED4DE43"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount expended by the Federal Government for each existing real property inventory or component of a cadastre in fiscal year 2020;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA66A54EF18B94278A7E75E5F2A9A6868"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre of Federal real property currently authorized by law or maintained by the Department that will be eliminated or consolidated into the multipurpose cadastre under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C5381477214E20BF5018F3FE6E00CB"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCB423C142C0F46E8B08A35F2443D03F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre of Federal real property currently authorized by law or maintained by the Department that will not be eliminated or consolidated into the multipurpose cadastre under paragraph (2); and</text></clause><clause id="H49EC25BE46F0437C8C34FEBAB912A8C7" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a justification for not eliminating or consolidating an existing real property inventory or component of a cadastre described in clause (i) into the multipurpose cadastre under paragraph (2);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F05A097FBC84F30B345549E9D3E7A64"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the use of existing real property inventories or any components of any cadastre currently maintained by any unit of State or local government that can be used to identify Federal real property within that unit of government;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CE85EF44C6A41B6BEC0EA0E21A598C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the cost savings that will be achieved by eliminating or consolidating duplicative or unneeded real property inventories or any components of any cadastre of Federal real property currently authorized by law or maintained by the Department that will become part of the multipurpose cadastre under paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5B0C3C9548C4B6291A659FB852840AA"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan for the implementation of this section, including a cost estimate and an assessment of the feasibility of using revenue from any transactional activity authorized by law to offset any costs of implementing this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78B7393DE107442A98E9556A069ED3BC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an assessment described in subparagraphs (A) through (E) with regard to each cadastre and inventory of Federal real property authorized, operated, or maintained by each other Federal agency, which shall be conducted in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, the Administrator of the General Services Administration, and the Comptroller General of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C6A2DA55D474914A474B42282025F9E"><enum>(H)</enum><text>recommendations for any legislation necessary to increase the cost savings and enhance the effectiveness and efficiency of replacing, eliminating, or consolidating Federal real property inventories or any components of any cadastre of Federal real property currently authorized by law or maintained by the Department.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H064760C876094BD29C74E6E9C1601F0A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination</header><subparagraph id="H59E51120C4ED4C849D289637E043C349"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H583A259CBEA74C98974641699BC72CFD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>participate (in accordance with section 216 of the E-Government Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/44/3501">44 U.S.C. 3501</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/347">Public Law 107–347</external-xref>) and section 757 of the Geospatial Data Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2806">43 U.S.C. 2806</external-xref>)) in the establishment of such standards and common protocols as are necessary to ensure the interoperability of geospatial information pertaining to the cadastre under paragraph (2) for all users of the information;</text></clause><clause id="H411118FE43E64C5F870801B065AD46EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>coordinate with, seek assistance and cooperation of, and provide liaison to the Federal Geographic Data Committee established by section 753(a) of the Geospatial Data Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2802">43 U.S.C. 2802(a)</external-xref>) for the implementation of and compliance with such standards and requirements of that Act as may be applicable to—</text><subclause id="H57514D9245784E85BA07BB88EF5FD6FA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the cadastre under paragraph (2); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H926896F080004C5A9967EED04809E9BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any aspect of the development of the cadastre under paragraph (2);</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC372B71E35254D78B909BF5ECC8458CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>integrate, or make the cadastre interoperable with, the Federal Real Property Profile or other inventories established pursuant to Executive Order 13327 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/121">40 U.S.C. 121</external-xref> note; relating to Federal real property asset management), the Federal Assets Sale and Transfer Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/1303">40 U.S.C. 1303</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/287">Public Law 114–287</external-xref>), or the Federal Property Management Reform Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/318">Public Law 114–318</external-xref>; 130 Stat. 1608); and</text></clause><clause id="HF418B81D2E974EEAACBABF328CC1D7FF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, integrate with and leverage current cadastre activities of units of State and local government.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB6D867A40D2449D82B22C3B70364E16"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contracts considered surveying and mapping</header><clause id="H8491E1B71C044568B9D40EDA707070BA"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A contract between the Secretary and a member of the private sector to provide products and services for the development of the cadastre shall be considered to be a contract for services of surveying and mapping (within the meaning of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code).</text></clause><clause id="H94A59ACEF14647B7AC5628C289750BC9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Selection procedures</header><text>A contract described in clause (i) shall be entered into in accordance with the selection procedures in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/11">chapter 11</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85E0C4BD712E46F897D299B5195F26C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transparency and public access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H79CD0D583E824F90ACEA2D73CF471489"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in accordance with any requirements applicable to the Department under section 759 of the Geospatial Data Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2808">43 U.S.C. 2808</external-xref>), make the cadastre under subsection (b)(2) publicly available on the internet—</text><subparagraph id="HC7F74BFE803E4B9199467DD5A435B813"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a graphically geo-enabled and searchable format; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA86D7A49E0E3418185FFE2D587CC30D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a manner that is consistent with, and meets any requirements for integration with, the GeoPlatform established under section 758(a) of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2807">43 U.S.C. 2807(a)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3264A8664A854089A6E81329ED150FA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure that the inventory referred to in subsection (b) includes the identification of all land suitable for disposal in accordance with the <act-name parsable-cite="FLPMA">Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE4CFE0DA0F443168C7CB88627425A88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in consultation with the Secretary of Defense and the Secretary of Homeland Security, prevent the disclosure of any parcel or parcels of land, any buildings or facilities on the land, or any information related to the land, buildings, or facilities if that disclosure would impair or jeopardize the national security or homeland defense of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79722735ACEB4E019ACD7C0D052AE91F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicable law</header><text>Any data that is part of the cadastre developed under subsection (b)(2) shall be—</text><paragraph id="HC59F1218D524457BA02349A15F8ECED1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>considered to be geospatial data for purposes of the Geospatial Data Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/2801">43 U.S.C. 2801 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68563804DFE943F8A1B90BA2E8D93AF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>subject to the requirements of that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B056B8408244D0BA2049BCBEEC51251"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effect</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section—</text><paragraph id="H42CD3C49EDCF434E801E07A8B7C8A59B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">creates any substantive or procedural right or benefit; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE43A68F4CEC2462CB0E9B95088DDE24B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requires or authorizes—</text><subparagraph id="H6D10BFEE87764B5CB3719F01D72D38E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any new surveying or mapping of Federal real property;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB52ADA3BC763439C998618D30F7CE18C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the evaluation of any parcel of land or other real property for potential management by a non-Federal entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA532C116210B4EBEA75F98032C0918B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the disposal of any Federal real property; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23E0466598A447A68765BDFDBD60DD13"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any new appraisal or assessment of—</text><clause id="HD1A05200D09C4F16B9D2E83DF4CEFEA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the value of any parcel of Federal land or other real property; or</text></clause><clause id="H3AF141943EB841568A2F670380684C09"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the cultural and archaeological resources on any parcel of Federal land or other real property.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

