<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2696F3A9C63D4244886F8449CECB9CED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9425 IH: Responsibility and Integrity in Security Clearance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9425</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221205">December 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 to require congressional notification if relatives or financial associates of the President are granted security clearances contrary to the advice or recommendation of a background investigation or determination of an adjudicating agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9AFA5BAE934142DE82DB6C74088F9576" style="OLC"><section id="HCB764EEBED9542E6ADDC1F93A1659D40" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Responsibility and Integrity in Security Clearance Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RISC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9BCDF358A3954C01B552B6CA2B0B5F5B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Notification to Congress for certain security clearance determinations for relatives or financial associates of the President</header><subsection id="H51EE6FD96DD5410D809C5277D50E0677"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3001 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3341">50 U.S.C. 3341</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H82174A79E13B4943B75B9693DE0C1DA0" style="OLC"><subsection id="HEF0DCBED2CAC4D17BB538E04A0656E80"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Relatives and financial associates of the President</header><paragraph id="HF25F05F6F63340BCB9605822DEC94B7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chief of Staff of the White House shall notify (in writing) the Members of Congress specified in section 503(c)(2) of the National Security Act of 1947 if the President or any other individual grants a security clearance or access determination with respect to a covered individual contrary to—</text><subparagraph id="H945B1DEF9F7E4202AD49A3BBCF84FA5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recommendations of the Federal Bureau of Investigation with respect to any background investigation for a covered individual who is an employee of the White House or the Executive Office of the President; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DE86A6B570745F3BB013E946FDBD864"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the determination of any agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA11CD3C3413246BB8F47A33ED442BB42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The notification under paragraph (1) shall occur not later than 5 days after the President or other such individual makes the contrary determination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H818CA20417BC4EAEBE74E62F8F335A4D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of covered individual</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>covered individual</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1947C2CC4F864038BFC274AB7C7CD5FB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any relative (as that term is defined in section 3110(a)(3) of title 5, United States Code) of the President; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92C16253C11647AEB01DA7F5C6DBCA46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any individual who has entered into a contract, or is currently in contract negotiations with, the President or an entity in which the President has a financial interest.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4C8799DB16564764A0EED360F2C10B03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="HABA2E7B2080B43499BC14A3D8AE803E8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply to any contrary determination described in paragraph (1) of subsection (k) of section 3001 of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3341">50 U.S.C. 3341</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a), made before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C2AD978155E4132A0E2CA48C13766BB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Retroactive determination</header><text>With respect to any contrary determination under such paragraph (1) made before the date of enactment of this Act, the notification required under such paragraph shall be made not later than 5 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18BFBB79FC9D4B0CA08CE4DCE8F9156B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Readjudication</header><subparagraph id="H2503E7CFEA0D4369BEEB2F200D873C4D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The security clearance or access determination of any covered individual (as that term is defined in subsection (k) of the Intelligence Reform and Terrorism Prevention Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3341">50 U.S.C. 3341</external-xref>), as added by subsection (a)) subject to notification under paragraph (2) shall be revoked.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8737C1D738324F0FA1CCD8943CD100BE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Readjudication</header><text>A subsequent background investigation and agency adjudication is required before a security clearance or access determination may be granted to such covered individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

