<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H19B2C3D6D1CA4AA5B339C4F12E596D2A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7459 IH: DHS Rural and Remote Hiring and Retention Strategy Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7459</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to issue a strategy to improve hiring and retention of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel in rural or remote areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H26D643CF376F4B628D3E97766FCE2BE4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB7C5C871AE78492EB84584F41D6FEF59" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DHS Rural and Remote Hiring and Retention Strategy Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H3346EA58FC964487B6333DABE24D8787"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy</header> <subsection id="H985F1B71E7624BCFB2549CA0473DB561"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Chief Human Capital Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and the Director of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, shall issue a strategy and implementation plan, including benchmarks, to improve the hiring and retention of individuals by U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement in rural or remote areas relating to employment in such areas.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD15612114F794AB48CFE75E484722695"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall take into consideration the following:</text> <paragraph id="H5E924FFE262142A9AD65036E7EEB4502"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Feedback from individuals who are U.S. Customs and Border Protection or U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement candidates or new hires at locations in rural or remote areas, including feedback on the quality of life in such areas for new hires and their families.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3079EAF740604E65839AEDA49028C19F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Feedback from U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel, other than new hires, who are stationed at locations in rural or remote areas, including feedback on the quality of life in such areas for such personnel and their families.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H939574B2D9304ADC9299895BAC49C20A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Feedback from U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement personnel who have decided to separate from U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement, as the case may be.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A8075DDA87A4DADA04C59E4DAB76D05"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of existing Federal programs, including financial incentives and other compensation-based flexibilities, regarding how to most effectively aid spouses and families of individuals who are candidates or new hires in a rural or remote area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD80062F8BFB443B1A6656AC14C753BFE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An assessment of Department of Homeland Security internship programs and the usefulness of such programs in improving hiring by the Secretary of Homeland Security in rural or remote areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5929A442548D44D5A5427267899C8236"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>The implementation plan required under subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H2B3DFF2C38204477AF723A9A57B96F31"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a pilot or other program, as appropriate, to address hiring and retention challenges faced by U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement in rural or remote areas; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H699ED5F9E2A7416ABF137FDDF36126F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enhance strategic recruiting efforts of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement through relationships with institutions of higher education (as such term is defined in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>)), veterans transition and employment centers, and job placement programs in regions that could assist in filling positions in rural or remote areas.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H71B6ED2F4315449588213851E477B379"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress and GAO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date that is one year after the date of issuance of the strategy and implementation plan required under subsection (a) and for four years thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall report to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, and the Comptroller General of the United States on the extent to which such strategy and implementation plan has improved the hiring and retention by U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement of employees in rural or remote areas.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H35A8CAC217A7489DA5869E7D775EEECA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>GAO assessment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after receiving each report required under subsection (d), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the committees referred to in such subsection an assessment of the effectiveness of U.S. Customs and Border Protection and U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement actions described in each such report, including recommendations for improvements as the Comptroller General determines appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H61B7075999D0430BBC503DEC85738B80"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Rural or remote areas defined</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>rural or remote areas</quote> means areas within the United States that are not within an area defined and designated as urbanized areas by the Bureau of the Census in the most recently completed decennial census, and includes areas along the northern and southern borders.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

