<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="HC7C0CD079A194BD3A30B29F1C3C2AC11" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7158 : Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 7158</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221205">December 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to enter into contracts and agreements for the payment of care in non-Department of Veterans Affairs medical foster homes for certain veterans who are unable to live independently, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HB58C4BC463AB444EBE3F856F2CA02505" style="OLC"><section id="HD4149818D80540EC8446CBF082F1A333" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2D5465EB270B45E296304F8F22151C56"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secretary of Veterans Affairs contract authority for payment of care for veterans in non-Department of Veterans Affairs medical foster homes</header><subsection id="H5445170AB6D94DA5852B62C833D6FA27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><paragraph id="H6569B399824E4BCF9997A980A164BBC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1720 of title 38, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HE9F7B7EFEF174A36B99136665EDD8AB5" style="OLC"><subsection id="H92043549C6B446E58F1B72A0523211FD"><enum>(h)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7518F3706760455FA5FDBBEC8369A106"><enum>(1)</enum><text>During the five-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of the Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act, and subject to paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H6B93ED030A3D459B8AEA205AE69D5FE1" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at the request of a veteran for whom the Secretary is required to provide nursing home care under section 1710A of this title, the Secretary may place the veteran in a medical foster home that meets Department standards, at the expense of the United States, pursuant to a contract, agreement, or other arrangement entered into between the Secretary and the medical foster home for such purpose; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8ADA8DFD0DB41D7976787E500895E7E" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary may pay for care of a veteran placed in a medical foster home before such date of enactment, if the home meets Department standards, pursuant to a contract, agreement, or other arrangement entered into between the Secretary and the medical foster home for such purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE94590C060534C259E2485E03230E612" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A veteran on whose behalf the Secretary pays for care in a medical foster home under paragraph (1) shall agree, as a condition of such payment, to accept home health services furnished by the Secretary under section 1717 of this title.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E18FA01DD24EB9B13DEA2720071A08" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In any year, not more than a daily average of 900 veterans receiving care in a medical foster home, whether placed before, on, or after the date of the enactment of the Long-Term Care Veterans Choice Act, may have their care covered at the expense of the United States under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A09153DB807451BA754C81A5DB315F2" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The prohibition under section 1730(b)(3) of this title shall not apply to a veteran whose care is covered at the expense of the United States under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79BEB7873C424CDD906113B2E3744692" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>medical foster home</quote> means a home designed to provide non-institutional, long-term, supportive care for veterans who are unable to live independently and prefer a family setting.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BC76E9931644911872A41C02C1962BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (h) of section 1720 of title 38, United States Code, as added by paragraph (1), shall take effect 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E3E31849AD54878B80674E32515D95A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ongoing Monitoring of Medical Foster Home Program</header><paragraph id="H0E46426A2BAB46EFB2F2EC409E2011FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall create a system to monitor and assess the workload for the Department of Veterans Affairs in carrying out the authority under section 1720(h) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), including by tracking—</text><subparagraph id="H0969E5F4FDCD4E71B74352AF69B3F01A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requests by veterans to be placed in a medical foster home under such section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DEFF9344ED74BC2802115ED6A0332AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>denials of such requests, including the reasons for such denials;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA052954F7C874AE2AC24F33AB8C4408E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of medical foster homes applying to participate under such section, disaggregated by those approved and those denied approval by the Department to participate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE501F2F1DD714506AF68F2F9745962EC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>veterans receiving care at a medical foster home at the expense of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H727BC2C8BFEC4519A954C4358FCBABEB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>veterans receiving care at a medical foster home at their own expense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48572E9A48D04141B2E314DBA512C233"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Based on the monitoring and assessments conducted under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall identify and submit to Congress a report on such modifications to implementing section 1720(h) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1), as the Secretary considers necessary to ensure the authority under such section is functioning as intended and care is provided to veterans under such section as intended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21D7B94CCD51426598177176F764F198"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Medical foster home defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>medical foster home</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 1720(h) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05730872C0FA4B6EA7F85D3C7B5FA756"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comptroller General Report</header><text>Not later than each of three years and six years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report—</text><paragraph id="HF7D3915839D846B086A00256E72B56DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assessing the implementation of this section and the amendments made by this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA3E9A133F27483A892A8879C07987F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assessing the impact of the monitoring and modifications under subsection (b) on care provided under section 1720(h) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2210CDF11FF94828A3584F9244CAB898"><enum>(3)</enum><text>setting forth recommendations for improvements to the implementation of such section, as the Comptroller General considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD0E18D99BAB94E7696709B8908C9D715" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Modification of certain housing loan fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The loan fee table in section 3729(b)(2) of title 38, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>January 14, 2031</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>February 15, 2031</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9323E36128C54AC2A505383D428BE802" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20221201" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives December 1, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

