<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H153763D31AB544ABB070A3F086417FBE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7602 IH: Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7602</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220427">April 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prevent organizational conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7113BB3A0AAD457F998D03817C7691B9" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H455DB63697EA40C7B4B0D68A9A793950" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Organizational Conflicts of Interest in Federal Acquisition Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEED09CBEB87E4ED3B48DA37EF6DF076F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H4086B5C3152C42518F4EFD79EE3140AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal Government’s reliance on contractors for mission support services can create the potential for conflicts of interest related to impaired objectivity or undue influence due to contractor business relationships with regulated or other entities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EA611CAC64A4589A2BAE2939275E886"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Comptroller General bid protest decisions in recent years have shown failures in proper identification and mitigation of organizational conflicts of interest. These decisions focus on the issue of <quote>impaired objectivity</quote> in contract support, or a situation in which a contractor is unable to provide impartial recommendations and advice to the Government due to competing interests of the contractor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24654AAAD9FD41B58E0C7BE0AA34A59A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prior efforts by the Administrator for Federal Procurement Policy and the Director of the Office of Government Ethics, undertaken pursuant to the Duncan Hunter National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/417">Public Law 110–417</external-xref>), have determined that changes are needed to the Federal Acquisition Regulation to prevent and mitigate conflicts of interest in Federal contracting.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB1D554C6EE234BC2BB5BBF7C91D926FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Protecting against conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition is vital to the integrity of Government operations. </text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE13987179CC646DF8F550F9DB41C38F6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Preventing organizational conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition</header> 
<subsection id="H154E5F1F2A63491C89BA74CFDE9F131B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Acquisition Regulatory Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H603E539FBD0B453F9965D83B641B091F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify contracting methods, types, and services that raise heightened concerns for potential organizational conflicts of interest beyond those currently addressed in the Federal Acquisition Regulation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD02D9AD48B14916BA050BFC92A20C8C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>revise the Federal Acquisition Regulation to—</text> <subparagraph id="H81D13B95AE224A8E8574F7248DFE3D18"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address organizational conflicts of interest with sufficiently rigorous, comprehensive, and consistent governmentwide policy and guidance to prevent or effectively mitigate such conflicts of interest in Federal acquisition;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA098F7CB894042B6BCF457E0BE176FD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide and update definitions related to organizational conflicts of interest, to include contractor relationships with public, private, domestic, and foreign entities that may cause contract support to be subject to potential conflicts of interest, including undue influence;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29CE4EF1B17349F7BF05409191DBD668"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide executive agencies with solicitation provisions and contract clauses that require contractors to disclose information relevant to potential organizational conflicts of interest and limit future contracting with respect to potential conflicts of interest with the work to be performed under the awarded contract, for agency use as needed;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H60BFEF85304A413AA2D48E128620EE09"><enum>(D)</enum><text>require executive agencies to tailor the solicitation and contract clauses described in subparagraph (C) as necessary to provide specifics on information required to be disclosed and limitations on future contracting based on the potential for conflict with the work to be performed under the awarded contract; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H18024304337F40A98BF5ABD66B8B620F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>require executive agencies to establish or update agency conflict of interest procedures to implement the Federal Acquisition Regulation revisions made under this section, and periodically assess and update these agency procedures as needed to address agency-specific conflict of interest issues.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC732986C59E45ED95D1406D240AB183"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Executive agency defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 133 of title 41, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

