<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="HF39E7EBF00E7471D8FE5FF11115F451C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 6899 ENR: Russia and Belarus SDR Exchange Prohibition Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6899</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To prohibit the Secretary of the Treasury from engaging in transactions involving the exchange of Special Drawing Rights issued by the International Monetary Fund that are held by the Russian Federation or Belarus.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HA0A9EBA60F964129ABB310F104D97AB8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H93E898FC37AF4E9CB182A8F6B5FB404A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Russia and Belarus SDR Exchange Prohibition Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7CB7FAB6BBA94A21BBA6BCEE592D1C3D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Special Drawing Rights exchange prohibition</header> <subsection id="HBF89AB8BFF4943E0BE9DF7E74AFFEB22"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury may not engage in any transaction involving the exchange of Special Drawing Rights issued by the International Monetary Fund that are held by the Russian Federation or Belarus.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3739FE3122B74B21965058D964B63E43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advocacy</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text> <paragraph id="H11AA5EA9892A4CEFB241CDB718811127"><enum>(1)</enum><text>vigorously advocate that the governments of the member countries of the International Monetary Fund, to the extent that the member countries issue freely usable currencies, prohibit transactions involving the exchange of Special Drawing Rights held by the Russian Federation or Belarus and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B33DF0A160841A68D3E42A26593F157"><enum>(2)</enum><text>direct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act) to use the voice and vote of the United States to oppose the provision of financial assistance to the Russian Federation and Belarus, except to address basic human needs of the civilian population.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD8AA5A29DD2C49428430B80EA83055E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The preceding provisions of this section shall have no force or effect on the earlier of—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8DD03B2FD86545B78C2A88B452DE7D72"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD02D4EFC6F0743D8A46B7315B2525203"><enum>(2)</enum><text>30 days after the date that the President reports to the Congress that the governments of the Russian Federation and Belarus have ceased destabilizing activities with respect to the sovereignty and territorial integrity of Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72437F35F8DC430088893D30AE072DB4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of this section if the President reports to the Congress that the waiver is in the national interest of the United States and includes an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation> </bill> 

