<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDB7EEC65F40B4BF49F3356FBDF56D9BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7414 IH: Recruiting in Underserved Rural Areas and Localities for Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7414</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220406">April 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, to direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to establish a rural recruitment office within the Department of Veterans Affairs to recruit health care professionals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8597ED5BCF040168B917258BB5F07FF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HA9201ABCAD1D48BCBCCDEF26B3684C76" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recruiting in Underserved Rural Areas and Localities for Veterans Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RURAL Veterans Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H46CC5F08FDA448E5A5B8E43677372537"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of the Office of Rural Recruitment</header> <subsection id="H6C29636420E54EA198205EAD93109584"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/38/73">Chapter 73</external-xref> of title 38, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/38/7308">section 7308</external-xref> the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F06EA4F54ED4F8B9D7A53B7114C56E2" style="USC">
<section id="H6BB2CAEB775F471187EE7DE13589B2D4"><enum>7308A.</enum><header>Office of Rural Recruitment</header>
<subsection id="H1E5145F794EF4F57975D78433A029A2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an office within the Office of the Under Secretary for Health to be known as the <quote>Office of Rural Recruitment</quote> (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>). The purpose of the Office is to improve the recruitment of health care professionals for rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8B1583488DA04FB29CA8678062AF82E8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Under Secretary of Health shall appoint the head of the Office who shall be called the Director of the Office of Rural Recruitment (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>).</text></subsection>
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20E3A6E7019D4F039C2736955FC78813"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H79B8FCE1D012404AB6AF9CAE85077406"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Annually, the Director, in collaboration with the directors of each community-based outpatient clinic and medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall, to determine the hiring needs of such clinics and centers, do the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H27F277F32CA647749CB0EDBE39C0C296" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assess the efficacy of hiring incentives to recruit health care professionals to practice in rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H61E7A07785964EEE8F5047372CB517E0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assess resources and funding necessary for rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs, which may include data from the most current determination published in the Federal Register pursuant to section 7412(a) of this title.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39D8C9B19B86436A8B7AE381888BFFE7" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identify hiring incentive programs offered for retaining health care professionals (including the Education Debt Reduction Program, the Employee Incentive Scholarship Program, and other programs under chapter 76 of this title) that provide scholarships, tuition reimbursement, and education debt reduction for health care professionals.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEFF4BCE24E0C47D5B72FBBB583C69416" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determine the number of health care professionals who accepted positions in rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs during the previous fiscal year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA07A31CF71542D9B80A9BED9986F253" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Determine the number of health care professionals that left positions described in subparagraph (D) during the previous fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1C7621E5CDF841B8BCC6EB74B401C9F1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director, in collaboration with the directors of each community-based outpatient clinic and medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs, shall develop and implement a national plan using information gathered under paragraph (1) and the strategies under subsection (d) to—</text> <subparagraph id="H66B3A12631BF49D885562D5588F70718"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruit health care professionals for rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H117CF44CAD06499DB77C6CCB11F66451"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determine which such clinics or centers are high-need;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5EE3F758F0C047078FB64A238E71D377"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop best practices and techniques for recruiting health care professionals in rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB78D921D585249C692688DC74664BF7A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than twice each fiscal year, train rural recruitment employees in the best practices and techniques developed under subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6816E6640B8948D085315C06C7AAEB60"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide recruitment resources to the Veterans Integrated Service Networks, rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics, and rural and highly rural medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs, such as pamphlets and marketing material.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H85C14D99F65B488894A6FC2BB3D63821" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall coordinate an annual meeting for rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs to communicate rural recruitment needs among such clinics and centers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H80A651EBBB1E4A7880F63FC5D22DAA06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Veterans Integrated Service Networks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The director of each Veterans Integrated Service Network that includes at least one rural or highly rural community-based outpatient clinic shall annually develop and maintain a strategy to recruit health care professionals. Such strategy shall include the designation of at least one rural recruitment employee from the human resources department of such Veterans Integrated Service Network, or if no such department exists, any department within such Veterans Integrated Service Network.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1BCBEA7672364B36B448384E2A832DAA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HCC61D372E40F4506957FFC92F820CE3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The director of each rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinic and medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs shall submit to the director of the respective Veterans Integrated Service Network of such clinic an annual report on hiring needs with respect to recruiting health care professionals within such clinic.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41626DC034514F3FA8FC26B4A59CCBB1" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The director of each Veterans Integrated Service Network described in subsection (d) shall submit to the Director an annual report containing—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0F3B2D8B3F004687B64F197B595D3B38"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the strategy under such subsection; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H62641D72252A4500BBBC776CFCFDA65D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of hiring needs with respect to recruiting health care professionals in rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HED12B7EDC342458488DF77737D7278C2" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director, shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives and Senate an annual report containing the information gathered pursuant to subsection (c)(1) and the national plan under paragraph (2) of such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6348999DDE9242029A8D915084B3DD2A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H87F0A51D78DC469CA68F1F19479F5063"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rural recruitment employee</term> means an employee of a Veterans Integrated Service Network designated under subsection (d) who is responsible for recruiting health care professionals for rural and highly rural community-based outpatient clinics and medical centers of the Department of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD91559E0D38C4FD4A17B2A1477C3D1DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>rural</term> and <term>highly rural</term> have the meanings given such terms under the rural-urban commuting codes developed by the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H28CCCC37618C4375ADEB5EC57BCDECF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of rural recruitment employee</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2026, the director of each Veterans Integrated Service Network that has at least one rural or highly rural community-based outpatient clinic shall designate a rural recruitment employee as required by the strategy described under section 7308A(d) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4DBB18FF8BF043C3959977398793E32B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting timeline</header><text>The first reports under paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) of section 7308A(e) of title 38, United States Code, as added by subsection (a), shall be submitted not later than 12 months, 18 months, and 24 months, respectively, after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF4773D29E02B47E8B8F6AB71202FEE75"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections at the beginning of such chapter is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 7308 the following new item:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E1E022F2C3C4A92A23921120B4024D5" style="USC"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">7308A. Office of Rural Recruitment.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="HDD8DC5AFBA474C40A43F36B4BBF4A1C6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on a scholarship program and establishment of a fellowship program for health care professionals</header> <subsection id="H3C0DA72F61A243D5B23FF27943DCF24C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study on the feasibility of a rural recruitment scholarship program</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H793CE1FC38414BD7B628E1EC7152E341"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Feasibility study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Rural Recruitment established under section 7308A(a) of title 38, United States Code, as added by section 1(a), shall conduct a study on the feasibility of a scholarship program for health care professionals to attend the Uniformed Services University of the Health Sciences in exchange for service as full-time employees at a rural or highly rural community-based outpatient clinic or medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs for a period determined by the Director.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F8DFCC8E47B40B6B0828F671FB960FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report and recommendation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than September 30, 2025, the Secretary, acting through the Director, shall submit to Congress a report—</text> <subparagraph id="H89B16B7071E344BDB37EF6E6BBBEA337"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the study conducted pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC1F635BD5BFA494CA766F7B4927B270B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>containing a recommendation with respect to the operation of and funding for the program described under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBCF9DB302E114A8FA2E2DE99B5EE0119"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of the Rural Health Quality and Access Fellowship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out section 7302 of title 38, United States Code, the Secretary shall establish the Rural Health Quality and Access Fellowship program to provide fellowships to health care professionals at the graduate or post-graduate level who—</text>
<paragraph id="HB2A1F56142DF4B39ABA8F6C47227CDA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve on a short-term basis as full-time employees at a rural or highly rural community-based outpatient clinic or medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H80F2000F35274D3E91B911F460E5C3EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct research on—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD7B199330E68455AB1A714D14B8E950E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improving the quality of rural health care, including best practices for remote health care;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD893C97CD4A4499BA9C7341471A64291"><enum>(B)</enum><text>access to health care in rural areas; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA61EEAD5B2D548F6BCCF102B0DEF5951"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recruitment and retention of health care professionals in rural areas.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD835B3873EA1485CA72A06BE4F275524"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Health care professional defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>health care professional</term> means an individual who qualifies as an appointee under section 7402 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

