<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB2EFB20C231244F9BD058FC618B06340" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7102 IH: American Energy for American Consumers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7102</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220316">March 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the export of crude oil and finished motor gasoline produced in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE1B804054F2545BD8E225F06C1422935" style="OLC"><section id="H36FA098208B24908AF92AA1B2E4E63B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Energy for American Consumers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9EED0B7B101940F7AC2C2C878BAC2C65"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on the export of crude oil and finished motor gasoline</header><subsection id="H50EC7E69379A480DAF8F72D9D4FA6564"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall promulgate a rule prohibiting, during the period described in subsection (d), the export of crude oil and finished motor gasoline (as defined by the Energy Information Administration) produced in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H113573EF0D6C47B3A790F30F0401C995"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><text>In promulgating the rule under subsection (a), the President may exempt from the prohibition described in such subsection exports of crude oil or finished motor gasoline—</text><paragraph id="H2DC23889269644D693877621C32DCEDC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as the President determines to be consistent with the national interest, taking into account the national interest as related to the need to leave uninterrupted or unimpaired—</text><subparagraph id="HB5AFB5B8FC754EDA841B2A2E86AC7ABD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exchanges in similar quantity for convenience or increased efficiency of transportation with persons or the government of a foreign country;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4589127634BF45C593AB3F0D1730FE2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>temporary exports for convenience or increased efficiency of transportation across parts of an adjacent foreign country which exports reenter the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56810D5F0CDE4E75B11B351270F5E4E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the historical trading relations of the United States with Canada and Mexico; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB19C182AADE34A628FBD3EAB3D8B6B36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>as the President determines appropriate for national security purposes, such as to a country that is a party to a mutual defense treaty with the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82FB53E40C89454FBC859F27EB4FAA25"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver of notice and comment</header><paragraph id="H87315B934A734658BC6F47F9560D2A72"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The provisions of subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall apply with respect to the promulgation of any rule pursuant to this section, except that the President may waive the requirement pertaining to the notice of proposed rulemaking or period for comment only if the President finds that compliance with such requirements may seriously impair the ability of the President to impose effective and timely prohibitions on exports.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ADB996A871841D1A8EAE1FC7E05CBD6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Opportunity to comment thereafter</header><text>In the event such notice and comment period are waived with respect to a rule promulgated under this section, the President shall afford interested persons an opportunity to comment on any such rule at the earliest practicable date thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H653D2F84D5814576A538E68CF8054E68"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The period described in this subsection is the period that begins on the effective date of the rule promulgated under subsection (a) and ends on the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="H5335E4BC20D34AB0A8C6AEE8A67F7874"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that the President determines the national average price for unleaded gasoline has been, for a period of at least 30 days, at or below the national average price for unleaded gasoline on January 1, 2022; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE66809A9AC5469B955D11A4E40E18E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that the President determines is the formal end to the conflict between Russia and Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

