<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HEF8B432490EC4BEAAA01CEAED12C4452" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7081 RH: Ukraine Comprehensive Debt Payment Relief Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 237</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7081</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–317]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220315">March 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 15, 2022</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To seek immediate bilateral, multilateral, and commercial debt service payment relief for Ukraine.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H3EA578484C0A4A079CB190BD37805BEB"><section id="HAE4D9D86EBBF4DF3AB63DE2A58CA23D7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ukraine Comprehensive Debt Payment Relief Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3F0564C6C7AE4327947EA5823B2CC8E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Suspension of multilateral debt payments of Ukraine</header><subsection id="H40DE584A7F90462F850E7393D6350367"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United States position in the international financial institutions</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall instruct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act) to use the voice, vote, and influence of the United States to advocate that the respective institution immediately suspend all debt service payments owed to the institution by Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC214CAD76862453AA02FCD3F93D41014"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Official bilateral and commercial debt service payment relief</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, working in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall commence immediate efforts with other governments and commercial creditor groups, through the Paris Club of Official Creditors and other bilateral and multilateral frameworks, both formal and informal, to pursue comprehensive debt payment relief for Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB115229DC5E34DDE919B01391B51E483"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Multilateral financial support for Ukraine</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall direct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act) to use the voice and vote of the United States to support, to the maximum extent practicable, the provision of concessional financial assistance for Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H925C5C955C7C452DBEA4CAA3DC4FC0DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Multilateral financial support for refugees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall direct the United States Executive Director at each international financial institution (as defined in section 1701(c)(2) of the International Financial Institutions Act) to use the voice and vote of the United States to seek to provide economic support for refugees from Ukraine, including refugees of African descent, and for countries receiving refugees from Ukraine.</text></subsection></section><section id="H451EDF9139A542579D6560067C9446AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report to the congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than December 31 of each year, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="HA15348612E6C47518D8D570E75DC47EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the Committees on Financial Services, on Appropriations, and on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Foreign Relations and on Appropriations of the Senate, a report on the activities undertaken under this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H390A2F528DFA4A8DA193248B712857EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make public a copy of the report.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H07AAFA3D85294CCF9F5F91F4E5B99764"><enum>4.</enum><header>Waiver and termination</header><subsection id="H91C566B5C7EB4D1DAA842F8DEAC315F0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may waive the provisions of this Act if the President determines that a waiver is in the national interest of the United States and reports to the Congress an explanation of the reasons therefor.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0FF4374F93E452AA39D8884AA02C789"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The preceding provisions of this Act shall have no force or effect on or after the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

