<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H22A4346396D2424DA791787B9A8A6A20" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8140 IH: HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8140</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220617">June 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enable high research activity status historically Black colleges or universities to increase capacity toward achieving very high research activity status, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC44A02D440AF4E6A9E363E49DBBC23F6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB5A90309DF014874A04A9588B0D39222" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>HBCU Research, Innovation, Security, and Excellence Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="HF4CE225D742F4CF4A4FE44FB141A100C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6DDB4B9CF0DB414BBDE0077776122F7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Historically Black colleges and universities hold a unique position in the efforts of the United States to diversify the science, technology, engineering, and mathematics academic and workforce communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88487557C8A544639A38895E9D630B88"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Although our Nation’s historically Black colleges and universities make up just 3 percent of the colleges and universities in the United States, historically Black colleges and universities graduate 25 percent of African-American students with baccalaureate degrees in the fields of science, technology, engineering, and mathematics.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFC2E275E2CF4F8EAB78C835AD75DCE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Historically Black colleges and universities are the institution of origin for almost 30 percent of Black graduates of science and engineering doctorate programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FCA20A18608491FA58F602681C74025"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The health of the Department of Defense and the United States research ecosystem relies on high quality researchers from a diverse talent pool.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDFEEA6DFE0F04F9AB75C73C84779E978"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Historically Black colleges and universities have a history of conducting high quality research in unique areas, both providing impactful research outcomes and developing the next generation of the research ecosystem, including by—</text> <subparagraph id="H4F213162A38C4C0EAC24BFCF7EA4C54A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conducting high quality research in unique areas that has enriched the Department of Defense research enterprise and the United States research ecosystem, including—</text> 
<clause id="HDDD7A4BA13284C088639B89313591216"><enum>(i)</enum><text>providing science and engineering faculty research opportunities at U.S. Navy Laboratories; </text></clause> <clause id="HCCA09FCC7F0C4A9A99126D8814EFE40F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a <quote>Young Investigators Program</quote> at the Air Force Research Laboratory supporting basic and applied research on aerospace systems (RQ), materials and manufacturing (RX), and information (RI); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H62B9175BCB2F44A385B0763588E5A232"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Centers of Excellence in biotechnology and materials science; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0420B087AC324165AF36E573F2A0CE10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strengthening and diversifying the United States research ecosystem by increasing the number of students who are students of diverse backgrounds from historically Black colleges and universities with undergraduate or graduate degrees in science, technology, engineering, or mathematics; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF4C93CCEAC546CCA325458F40BEFD96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>fueling domestic and international collaborations that led to trailblazing discoveries and innovative technologies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCACD3A328B0406697651F97B03887B6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2019, historically Black colleges and universities received $371,000,000, or about 0.8 percent of the $44,500,000,000 in Federal funding to institutions of higher education for research and development. The amount of funding for 2019 is a marked decrease from fiscal year 2018, when historically Black colleges and universities received $400,000,000 in Federal research and development funding (0.9 percent of the Federal funding to institutions of higher education for such purposes).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF4C94F939EA46829B33810C572046FA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>There are no historically Black colleges and universities designated as very high research activity status, as classified by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H51E16C4DD91745CEA44CAD4B99548269"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Meaningfully investing in the research capacity of historically Black colleges and universities is an investment in our Nation’s future and will help meet accelerating science, technology, engineering, and mathematics workforce demands and safeguard the national security interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H85B39D1D3E1F459F886E151DB0109398"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of the program established under this Act is to provide additional pathways needed for further increasing capacity at historically Black colleges and universities to achieve and maintain very high research activity status.</text></section> <section id="H332450FED7E1481B8D8BF7B5664D4465"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="HF303ED0193124B12B3B555CF9C01AED1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible institution</term> means a historically Black college or university that is classified as a high research activity status institution at the time of application for a grant under section 5.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC76CA0F94C7468E8E73FFE58597983B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High research activity status</header><text>The term <term>high research activity status</term> means R2 status, as classified by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A040F8F0C7D452FB43AA9EA69DC0565"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Historically Black college or university</header><text>The term <term>historically Black college or university</term> has the meaning given the term <term>part B institution</term> under section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A61C6F89B3A47EBA669C111AE90D88F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47058F17843143208DA512E6BD35213A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Very high research activity status</header><text>The term <term>very high research activity status</term> means R1 status, as classified by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0A30E979A5A4ABDB4385E77313B053F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Very high research activity status indicators</header><text>The term <term>very high research activity status indicators</term> means the categories used by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education to delineate which institutions have very high activity status, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H603D263ADB224EA4AE1B29A2023B1ABD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>annual expenditures in science and engineering;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6BD4F35E90C46A6AD370E2CD65B1BD7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>per-capita (faculty member) expenditures in science and engineering;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5911EE845A314B548BCAB11441B8A765"><enum>(C)</enum><text>annual expenditures in non-science and engineering fields;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFEB750DC6DF44EE09D906DD7B35A8033"><enum>(D)</enum><text>per-capita (faculty member) expenditures in non-science and engineering fields;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6A61FB1364DF4AB8863D1357463054DC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>doctorates awarded in science, technology, engineering, and mathematics fields;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF08C23C5CE3C4AA3B5AFA45A48C063D6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>doctorates awarded in social science fields;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD0F85FB71114B1EBAA408B8F336CFBC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>doctorates awarded in the humanities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAC3339ECE254503AA9798AF526B3440"><enum>(H)</enum><text>doctorates awarded in other fields with a research emphasis;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H444061A8C65F49059F802E04B5035405"><enum>(I)</enum><text>total number of research staff including postdoctoral researchers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H487CAF98731E4E3C8EC87E700EE1C465"><enum>(J)</enum><text>other doctorate-holding non-faculty researchers in science and engineering and per-capita (faculty) number of doctorate-level research staff including post-doctoral researchers; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE9A9CE78C5247338834932CCAE130F5"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other categories utilized to determine classification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H9FFFAF14E4EC42EE8A0A306EB11CCC5B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Program to increase capacity toward achieving very high research activity status at historically black colleges or universities</header> <subsection id="HDDB4ECEDEB9448868FA54EE11AF966AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header> <paragraph id="H3D674E9D640E42D18020CB4979F24DBA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish and carry out, using funds made available for research activities, a pilot program to increase capacity at high research activity status historically Black colleges and universities toward achieving very high research activity status during the grant period.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCE702415A7042698407E5EB97C24511"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>In establishing such program, the Secretary may consider the recommendations pursuant to section 262 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/2362">10 U.S.C. 2362</external-xref> note) and section 220 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBB9294B7DFBC4130814209563E7CAC8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants authorized</header><text>The Secretary shall award, on a competitive basis, grants to eligible institutions to carry out the activities under subsection (d)(1).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A3E5696D7F743A1812266D607B27717"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible institution seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information and assurances as the Secretary may require, including a description of—</text> <paragraph id="HB53F6668326D423AA8484BE7A8566815" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nascent research capabilities with respect to research areas of interest to the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCACD5EB2F0C7414D9BFA01309CAEEBBE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a plan for increasing the level of research activity toward achieving very high research activity status classification during the grant period, including measurable milestones such as growth in very high research activity status indicators and other relevant factors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98484EB9DCAB4E9F8AD552231374B91B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such institution will sustain the increased level of research activity after the conclusion of the grant period; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H309A6CF5512F45ADB2B19393D433A14B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>how the institution will evaluate and assess progress with respect to the implementation of the plan under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H791C749FF1A6431EA651E3E9EA9180CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program components</header> <paragraph id="HC54C86EDB6964BD5ABD10714308554C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible institution that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to support research activities with respect to research areas for STEM and critical technologies, as determined by the Secretary under paragraph (2), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H889F67DBFC874531A06D107789A8F553"><enum>(A)</enum><text>faculty professional development;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF595A9475462405F8F0D6FAAC8A5F779"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stipends for undergraduate and graduate students and post-doctoral scholars;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBDCFF279A47248ED94294F7F68A4B8B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>laboratory equipment and instrumentation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72318AE4FD9D41AB8842D53D7F1BCDF4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recruitment and retention of faculty and graduate students;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBBD8A797F41546DAB34E40104B744D5A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>communication and dissemination of products produced during the grant period;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H04517D53D9984DB698D132819CBF0557"><enum>(F)</enum><text>construction, modernization, rehabilitation, or retrofitting of facilities for research purposes; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5C9A700BA5164C3ABA8065B7F72ACB0B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>other activities necessary to build capacity in achieving very high research activity status indicators.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA581C0F4E5444E0EA2BE769BB10E96CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Strategic areas of scientific research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Defense Science Board, shall establish and update, on an annual basis, a list of research areas for STEM and critical technologies.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A34C26F1E5A490C84581C3BD124E868"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Research progress reporting</header> 
<subparagraph id="H361C9C55AD02432BBAA0AEE904E7EC82"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after receiving a grant under this section, and every 3 years thereafter, an eligible institution shall submit to the Secretary—</text> <clause id="H2F24C8F83A86485A941D467940896721"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a report that includes an assessment by the institution, using the criteria established in subparagraph (B), of the progress made by such institution with respect to achieving very high research activity indicators; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1E8C5175B895441EA83F49EAD6160AC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an updated plan described in subsection (c)(2).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7EDE69FDC9D34CE9830E96278A369295"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Research assessment</header><text>The Secretary, in partnership with the eligible institution, shall establish criteria for the report required under subparagraph (A)(i).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD409153C30C4412A4E3CB0C1B33C61F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant awarded under this section shall be for a period of not more than 10 years, to be determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE15D1D18B2A34476AC272AE19BB448CD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expansion of eligibility</header><text>The Secretary may award grants under this section to historically Black colleges and universities that are not eligible institutions if the Secretary determines that the program can support such colleges and universities while achieving the purpose of the program described in section 3.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2658005DEF3F42E1BF3ED122EDB558AB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall prepare and submit a report to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives providing an update on the pilot program, including—</text> <paragraph id="HE6B69FB3B93E48339D9ECD0DD7A28DE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>activities carried out under the pilot program;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95CAF3E5433643F4A2963C82AD92267D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the growth in very high research activity status indicators of eligible institutions that received a grant under this section; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A4DD7B52F524B9A969F53329E80C030"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emerging research areas of interest to the Department of Defense conducted by eligible institutions that received a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0C3B82A32534F93B72897CB5E41EAE3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The authority of the Secretary to award grants under the pilot program established by this section shall terminate 10 years after the date on which the Secretary establishes such program.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD1B391F59946477EB606D425A8CD9C17"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the termination of the pilot program under subsection (f), the Secretary shall prepare and submit a report to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives on the pilot program that includes the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HAAAA1B764D8D4525BFDCE876BCAADF05"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the growth in very high research activity status indicators of eligible institutions that received a grant under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A5D11F9B8E44395A87FB56491158A0A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation on the effectiveness of the program in increasing the research capacity of eligible institutions that received a grant under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE0827C86D9D45B58521D7F47996F28B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An description of how institutions that have achieved very high research activity status plan to sustain that status beyond the duration of the program.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H525DEFBCCE8C48E2B95DC6E5122DE6DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An evaluation of the maintenance of very high research status by eligible institutions that received a grant under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6449554F32C4433195B71C01823E6EA3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>An evaluation of the effectiveness of the program in increasing the diversity of students conducting high quality research in unique areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD082B9F01B0646C4854011DFC45808C7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Recommendations with respect to further activities and investments necessary to elevate the research status of historically Black colleges and universities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEB21C1033FA463D98012A8B658A3B87"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Recommendations on whether the program established under this section should be renewed or expanded.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

