<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA49A5EC891FD4B7F86F2D33F7A330067" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9094 IH: Strategies To Address Antimicrobial Resistance Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9094</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to enhance efforts to address antimicrobial resistance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H20BDD2E74E2D42BC81A4D34B225604FB" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H80A6FFC682ED4ED19576AC01BFA2D5E7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strategies To Address Antimicrobial Resistance Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>STAAR Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H788F6794CB374E849A07CF843B1A8A85"><enum>2.</enum><header>Combating antimicrobial resistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 319E of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d-5">42 U.S.C. 247d–5</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H89DD1ADBAFBD473C839C7C65442AC02D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H1509AE57F0834F2EA9D6950E4F00067F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>and coordinate Federal programs relating to antimicrobial resistance</quote> and inserting <quote>relating to antimicrobial resistance, coordinate Federal programs relating to antimicrobial resistance, and pursue the goals of the National Strategy for Combating Antibiotic-Resistant Bacteria (referred to in this section as the <quote>National Strategy</quote>)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CBE0D6C49CB4F229DD7D139CC2C9CBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (2) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01ECBFEDA80D4CABAE04587F7C301BB5"><paragraph id="HD53D7E28BEBF477FA60695EE06E996BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members of task force</header><text>The task force described in paragraph (1) shall be co-chaired by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Defense, and shall be composed of representatives of relevant Federal agencies and such executive departments, agencies, or offices as the co-chairs may designate.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H178FA501CE82456B8D66761108CF1EC5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (4) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H436214CC9EDD4C4B8969F3F905846AF8"><paragraph id="HB9EF2535110542EB97FF0B220DF25ABA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>At least twice a year, the task force described in paragraph (1) shall have a public meeting to assess progress and obstacles to implementing the objectives of the National Strategy. The task force may discuss and review based on need or concern the following (among other issues):</text><subparagraph id="H035681E66F964ED089DD466B8592560E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal activities to slow the emergence of antimicrobial-resistant pathogens and prevent the spread of resistant infections. Such activities may include optimal use of vaccines and other infection control measures to prevent infections, implementation of health care policies and antimicrobial stewardship programs that improve patient outcomes, regional efforts to control transmission across community and health care settings, and public awareness campaigns.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AB2AD82372945D8AB23AAD05FADFE74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal activities to strengthen national One-Health surveillance efforts, which are efforts addressing the interactions between human, animal, and environmental health, to combat antimicrobial resistance. One-Health surveillance efforts to combat antimicrobial resistance may include enhanced data sharing and coordination of surveillance and laboratory systems across human and animal settings, and enhanced monitoring of sales, usage, resistance, and management practices of antimicrobial drugs along the food-production chain. Such surveillance and laboratory systems may include the National Healthcare Safety Network, the Emerging Infections Program, the National Antimicrobial Resistance Monitoring System, the National Animal Health Monitoring System, the National Animal Health Laboratory Network, the Veterinary Laboratory Investigation and Response Network, and the antimicrobial resistance Laboratory Network.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66500F5205C34BA785FBD1D35BE48082"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Federal efforts to advance the development and use of rapid and innovative diagnostic tests for identification and characterization of antimicrobial-resistant pathogens. Such efforts may include development of new diagnostic tests and expansion of their availability and use to improve treatment, infection control, and outbreak response.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA849C1AEC2B247F8957AC8D9C65B049B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal efforts to accelerate basic and applied research and development for new antimicrobial drugs, other therapeutics, prevention efforts, and vaccines. Such efforts may include support for basic and applied research, provision of scientific services and guidance to researchers, and fostering of public-private partnerships.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H449D12A7152440088D31C20339409340"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federal efforts to improve international collaboration and capacities for antimicrobial-resistance prevention, surveillance, and control and antimicrobial research and development. Such efforts may include collaborations with foreign ministries of health and agriculture, the World Health Organization, the Food and Agriculture Organization, the World Organization for Animal Health, the United Nations Environment Programme, and other multinational organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H027A7717B48C47BBB99D34374CA6246E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF938FAEC5F9A43F7A795B152A9B938E2"><paragraph id="H483E2594F27F454599935193673F00B1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Availability of information</header><text>The task force described in paragraph (1), to the extent permitted by law, shall—</text><subparagraph id="HAD91F5035FF94DFA934B07435F0C496D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide the Presidential Advisory Council on Combating Antibiotic-Resistant Bacteria described in section 505 of the Pandemic and All-Hazards Preparedness and Advancing Innovation Act of 2019 with such information as may be required for carrying out the functions of such Advisory Council, including information on progress in advancing the National Strategy, meeting minutes, and other key information of the task force; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94B8CCCDBC6E4BD184F10D2CED7AED74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that all information described in subparagraph (A) is made available on the websites of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52FBF070FE1A4EF790491FBDFF59FFAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h)—</text><subparagraph id="H2B2344DCAE6E43538E4F0A03189BF501"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Information related to</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24C855F2FA234DABB095D355FF960F88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0DB2033751E4654912BA56C6A9F032B"><paragraph id="HC272F70B323D49BF96B13267A921BD94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text>The Secretary</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32E1505C5C9141B88F32E087A67AA45F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB23E3D1D108D4AF7B06C282F056E8D2B"><paragraph id="HA63DB990C73445CB8A4BC5254F00FB38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Encouraging antimicrobial stewardship programs</header><text>The Secretary shall encourage health care facilities to establish antimicrobial stewardship programs that are consistent with documents issued by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention relating to the core elements of antimicrobial stewardship programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16F60E0008884B7CB6099D4C3339588B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definition of antimicrobial stewardship</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>antimicrobial stewardship</term> means coordinated interventions designed to improve and evaluate the appropriate use of antimicrobial agents, including promoting the use of antimicrobial drugs only when clinically indicated, and, when antimicrobial drugs are clinically indicated, promoting the selection of the optimal antimicrobial drug regimen, including through factors such as dosage, duration of therapy, and route of administration.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63710D8EC4DF493089D89439FCFFB401"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (m), by striking <quote>$40,000,000</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2029.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2643C31FF5E04DB288BAFF41DC779F2D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD83D93823F654CC7A0CA73A32E9451B7"><subsection id="H352998045185459883A2D4F1268FC7EB"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Annual report on implementing the National Strategy objectives</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Strategies To Address Antimicrobial Resistance Act</short-title>, and annually thereafter, the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Defense, and the task force described in subsection (a), shall submit to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives, and make available on the websites of the Department of Health and Human Services, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Defense, a report on the progress made in implementing the objectives of the National Strategy.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HFDB55503DC124C07A344D7F8356F536D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional strategies for combating antimicrobial resistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/243">42 U.S.C. 243 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 319E the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE36F906C1C6E42AE8C152BCCA56A1BF6"><section id="H1C6F3375F9884715A8F5136D85F3B477"><enum>319E–1.</enum><header>Surveillance and reporting of antimicrobial use and resistance</header><subsection id="H95D8BEC9ED5A4B99A11BF8638FC318BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall use the National Healthcare Safety Network and other appropriate surveillance systems to assess—</text><paragraph id="HB4C9E2B3681847C89B0219F2B121E0BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appropriate conditions, outcomes, and measures causally related to antimicrobial resistance, including types of infections, the causes for infections, and whether infections are acquired in a community or hospital setting, increased lengths of hospital stay, increased costs, and rates of mortality; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82490B0F830245D1963EDBD6E17B2CCC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>changes in microbial resistance to drugs in relation to patient outcomes, including changes in percent resistance, prevalence of antimicrobial-resistant infections, and other such changes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE368705CD6704F6F9D85BBB31CB9201D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Antimicrobial use data</header><text>The Secretary shall work with Federal agencies (including the Department of Veterans Affairs, the Department of Defense, and the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services), private vendors, health care organizations, pharmacy benefit managers, and other entities as appropriate to obtain reliable and comparable human antimicrobial drug consumption data (including, as available and appropriate, volume antimicrobial distribution data and antimicrobial use data, including prescription data) by State or metropolitan areas.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA14A4F77688547A98BB4EB9FF1BFBBF8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Antimicrobial resistance trend data</header><text>The Secretary shall intensify and expand efforts to collect antimicrobial resistance data and encourage adoption of the antimicrobial resistance and use module within the National Healthcare Safety Network among all health care facilities across the continuum of care, including, as appropriate, acute care hospitals, dialysis facilities, nursing homes, ambulatory surgical centers, and other ambulatory health care settings in which antimicrobial medications are routinely prescribed. The Secretary shall seek to collect such data from electronic medication administration reports and laboratory systems to produce the reports described in subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H119AEE35D86E44ED9706357D7855EF2E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public availability of data</header><text>The Secretary shall, for the purposes of improving the monitoring of important trends in patient outcomes in relation to antimicrobial resistance—</text><paragraph id="HE7A938B4DA5F43AD8AE97D671636FF4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make the data derived from surveillance under this section publicly available through reports issued on a regular basis that is not less than annually; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61EB75D18A6444C3981847DE1EB038A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine opportunities to make such data available in near real time.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3035E9F8FE05414EB3795F63FF0DA106"><enum>319E–2.</enum><header>Detecting network of antimicrobial resistance regional laboratories</header><subsection id="H07951061295A41B694C1E3BABA991030"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish not less than 7 Antimicrobial Resistance Surveillance and Laboratory Network sites, building upon the intramural and extramural programs and laboratories of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, to intensify, strengthen, and expand the national capacity to—</text><paragraph id="H63BBF87233F94EDF9735B044CE757D3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>monitor the emergence and changes in the patterns of antimicrobial-resistant pathogens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA50A808C0794D16B4911261ADAC0791"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe, confirm, and, as necessary, facilitate a response to, local or regional outbreaks of resistant pathogens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H471BEA2C60274B82BCEC034568C29756"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess and describe antimicrobial resistance patterns to inform public health and improve prevention practices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H415ABA471F954416B5660797D1626DAD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>obtain isolates of pathogens, and in particular, pathogens that show new or atypical patterns of resistance adversely affecting public health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAB4064FCD314B59A4B9BF88928F254F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assist in studying the epidemiology of infections from such pathogens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F97116242D84C5A97023B5E11B29989"><enum>(6)</enum><text>evaluate commonly used antimicrobial susceptibility testing methods to improve the accuracy of resistance testing and reporting;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H651F561A920645BCA7E821E56ACA20E7"><enum>(7)</enum><text>as necessary, develop or evaluate novel diagnostic tests capable of detecting new or emerging resistance in pathogens;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E66A74FDFD644A5AB0EA1210A0F1A8C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>link data generated by regional laboratory networks under existing public health surveillance networks and relevant government agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC785BC01203C47E8B83C85A0B70BBD9B"><enum>(9)</enum><text>provide laboratory assistance and reference testing of antimicrobial-resistant pathogens to enhance infection control and facilitate outbreak detection and response in health care and community settings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCB8E4597655543C6BAF3CB53A7F7F552"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Geographic distribution</header><text>The sites established under subsection (a) shall be geographically distributed across the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE083F9DED3EA480A9522F495ABFD617C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nonduplication of current national capacity</header><text>The sites established under subsection (a) may be based in academic centers, health departments, and existing surveillance and laboratory sites.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0D224DEC8C6E40FF8ADBDFC161AC86A1"><enum>319E–3.</enum><header>Clinical trials network on antimicrobial resistance</header><subsection id="H692A36DAD86347CAB2C6A3DA6D6339B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The Secretary shall maintain a Clinical Trials Network on Antimicrobial Resistance to enhance, strengthen, and expand research on clinical science, antimicrobial and diagnostic development, and optimal usage strategies with respect to addressing antimicrobial resistance. Such Network shall, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="HB2A0059AB0AA4C4C9A2C013C5DE56C2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>facilitate research to better understand resistance mechanisms and how to prevent, control, and treat resistant organisms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44096EF3A95A425E90FD6156383E6843"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advance clinical trial efforts to develop antimicrobial diagnostics, and evaluate and optimize the usage of such antimicrobial diagnostics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94539DB0D6A74D5CB695749BAB077A51"><enum>(3)</enum><text>conduct clinical research to develop natural histories of resistant infectious diseases;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H351E8C8B81EE4F03A498F9B8B6AA7567"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examine patient outcomes with currently available antimicrobial therapy and validate and improve upon biomarkers and other surrogate end­points; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4093A408373A481CA6C0C7E4A1D49C2F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>study shorter treatment duration and early cessation of antimicrobial therapy for treatment efficacy and the effect on development of resistance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB411A5291AD0498DB4FF9CD080978B51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2029.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8EFD7C61A9D544CB8894860A83B21212"><enum>319E–4.</enum><header>Regional prevention collaborative efforts</header><subsection id="H262F8AC2E8A64EE2BD24AEFA65DD48C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall work with State and local health departments to support the expansion of collaborative efforts by groups of health care facilities that focus on preventing the spread of antimicrobial-resistant pathogens that pose a serious threat to public health, and that are designed to interrupt and prevent the transmission of significant antimicrobial-resistant pathogens being transmitted across health care settings in a geographic region. Such collaborative efforts shall—</text><paragraph id="H64A8F2F5B4F74325BD8E5A625318C529"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify significant drug resistant pathogens being transmitted across health care settings locally;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67EBB9B927D345AEACE0EB03139BC4F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>implement evidence-based interventions to interrupt the transmission of antimicrobial-resistant strains of pathogens and prevent the infections caused by such pathogens, including evidence-based transmission prevention guidelines, rigorous hand-hygiene protocols, and infection control and prevention measures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H844DE3E24BBF4453A9BAC5CF5AA28035"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess compliance and identify barriers to adherence to such measures;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71D5644DDBD342458B46B6938736EA43"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evaluate the impact of such measures, to the extent possible, on hospital readmissions in health care facilities across the continuum of care, rates of health care associated infections, or any other relevant measures that characterize the health or economic impact of the collaborative efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A3C2211C72E4BD5A8A763B45C5416AD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>provide recommendations for improved outcomes and compliance with such measures.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4ED5086FA4B41B7A4F0821EF740F4AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prevention epicenters</header><paragraph id="H7A85BAE8791E402095F054511ECD3DCB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expansion</header><text>The Secretary may intensify and expand academic public health partnerships through the Prevention Epicenters Program to provide the regional prevention collaboration efforts described in subsection (a) with tools, strategies, and evidence-based interventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA96DC31965C4700BBCA77036B90F225"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evaluations and research</header><text>The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention and the epicenters participating in the Prevention Epicenters Program shall work with entities, including the entities participating in the regional prevention collaborative efforts, to—</text><subparagraph id="H1890BB93E02640AE99A9817EB3A57024"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate new and existing interventions to prevent or limit infection rates in health care facilities across the continuum of care and in community settings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5C513FB5E3142E58248A3014E5383AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate public health research on the prevention and control of resistant organisms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H412E584ECCD74D05A08F6D8AF548BFDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assess the feasibility, cost-effectiveness, and appropriateness of surveillance and prevention programs in differing health care and institutional settings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HCFC1379C39CF40BCADBC647B889445D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Educational materials</header><text>The Secretary shall use the evaluations, research, and assessments described in subsection (b), along with other scientific evidence, to create and disseminate educational materials focused on infection prevention and control for use in health care facilities across the continuum of care and in community settings.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H3C322B06B15348A2A28BB43F27D05805"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of confidential and national security information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act, and the amendments made by this Act, shall not be construed to permit the disclosure of any trade secret, confidential commercial information, or material inconsistent with national security, that is otherwise prohibited by law.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

