<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE9147D3FB4E546F5AAEBFA89018B9D7E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>112 HR 8697 IH: Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8697</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act to address satellite offices of the United States Patent and Trademark Office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H95EAB2BE036B42F1ADB02228D4F26F03" style="OLC"><section id="H6701E29683654469AF931D7DC0A7B27C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Unleashing American Innovators Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAA6434DCB55D4C9FB3E143E89439CC87"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H368B30DF5BF94DDEB18697906C446BDC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Intellectual Property and Director of the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1A30EF3535140A9B390142F7C318CB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the United States Patent and Trademark Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41F2CD6D1F15487383009B3BEB65D1DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Patent pro bono programs</header><text>The term <term>patent pro bono programs</term> means the programs established pursuant to section 32 of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/35/2">35 U.S.C. 2</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC70AB2666B2940D3A0D1ACD4A4F5689B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Southeast region of the United States</header><text>The term <term>southeast region of the United States</term> means the area of the United States that is comprised of the States of Virginia, North Carolina, South Carolina, Georgia, Florida, Tennessee, Alabama, Mississippi, Louisiana, and Arkansas.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF3545131957F4210B92DF54112F95EDE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Satellite offices</header><subsection id="HD5135362BE124070BFFE08412DD813D8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments to purpose and required considerations</header><text>Section 23 of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/29">Public Law 112–29</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/35/1">35 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3F37E5888FC146A49F6E975847198A7E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H8369BB06F7DB444E83A1D000BBCCB8DE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)— </text><clause id="H9914B723246B42B9BDC4662B11FBA232"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>increase outreach activities to</quote>; and </text></clause><clause id="H2CA4518B9CBF492D9EB5AEB5675C143F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>Office</quote> the following: <quote>, including by increasing outreach activities, including to women, people of color, veterans, individual inventors, or members of any other demographic, geographic, rural population, or economic group that the Director may determine to be underrepresented in patent filings</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7241577826534163AA4F7AFF818B4C43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9A4E7DD229494F6CB496F636FE2C18AF"><paragraph id="H94CDC184A1754ECBB2DD22A4AC87A5EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance patent examiner and administrative patent judge retention, including patent examiners and administrative patent judges from economically, geographically, and demographically diverse backgrounds;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E1BD87D32A34892A2C7AD7B86980BD8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HC462769090014D7692347A514DC5957A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H92991AB7572743489C089C508757032D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76273BB980BE47A98DE67D766AF0601D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7BC959F6A6A44128B745F29875616A50"><subparagraph id="H7946B8AC32344968A2AB3D645DD0B91A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each office established after July 1, 2022, shall consider the proximity of the office to anchor institutions (such as hospitals primarily serving veterans and institutions of higher education) and to women, people of color, veterans, individual inventors, or members of any other demographic, geographic, rural population, or economic group that the Director may determine to be underrepresented in patent filings.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE898C3DA8B44D4E8AAECA772D2446DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Southeast regional office</header><paragraph id="H71F3A4C925F849EC872C3420C9536E56" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to the satellite offices required to be established under section 23 of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (35 U.S.C. note), not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish a satellite office of the Office in the southeast region of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A9A801AE704BA8ACC8EFACB74899E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>When selecting a site for the office required under paragraph (1), the Director shall consider the following: </text><subparagraph id="HD4EA29D0988C4301A55649F2EA3FA8E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of patent-intensive industries located near the selection site.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H365E7CB6541945138A7611DB6582092D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The number of research-intensive institutions, including institutions of higher education, located near the selection site.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H878C3069718E4FAA8A3F9DC825609750"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any legal or business frameworks of the relevant State or local government that support intellectual property-intensive industries located near the selection site.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80D15B4260864C56ABC8D477CF937387"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Study on additional satellite offices</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall complete a study to determine whether additional satellite offices of the Office are necessary to— </text><paragraph id="H2A921D3B75364784A4987B11C819C517"><enum>(1)</enum><text>achieve the purposes described in section 23(b) of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/35/1">35 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> note), as amended by this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19F5266742654B8AACE145C80BFBC0AE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase participation in the patent system by women, people of color, veterans, individual inventors, or members of any other demographic, geographic, rural population, or economic group that the Director may determine to be underrepresented in patent filings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB33E724366E84650A8F28EB81AB7F587"><enum>4.</enum><header>Community outreach offices</header><subsection id="HD3A2163AE2564AFA84C3EDB844CD1B8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="H17C5FA82853B49F3A3943C72740D3920"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish not fewer than 4 community outreach offices throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A527400EF5499CB0E4BE66905835ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Restriction</header><text>No community outreach office established under paragraph (1) may be located in the same State as— </text><subparagraph id="H0F2D78B8FFC240A096952CB64DC9C750"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the principal office of the Office; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3680BB8186274070A39F5448B4A5FBF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any satellite office of the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H017D2D46E82E41ABB888860C7D52315D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirement for Northern New England region</header><subparagraph id="HCB01A8D77B7B4FF59CACC4EB9F5A9F91"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall establish not less than 1 community outreach office under this subsection in the northern New England region, which shall serve the States of Vermont, New Hampshire, and Maine. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4324AE2661E740E3BE8B4E48ACF1B431"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the location for the office required to be established under subparagraph (A), the Director shall give preference to a location in which—</text><clause id="HC9B462C76C524030829A475C5BBC90BA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as of the date of enactment of this Act— </text><subclause id="HB5DE9362D92444C4B5241C17AD9B0910"><enum>(I)</enum><text>there is located not less than 1 public institution of higher education and not less than 1 private institution of higher education; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H519FD604A16F42B0BA0C014545E9B4DB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>there are located not more than 15 registered patent attorneys, according to data from the Office of Enrollment and Discipline of the Office; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2BED20244AD542458FBDA0056B41359A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>according to data from the 2012 Survey of Business Owners conducted by the Bureau of the Census, less than 45 percent of the firms (as that term is defined for the purposes of the Survey) are owned by women, minorities, or veterans.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8DFCC96BF4B24030BA9F7FD6B647C86B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the community outreach offices established under subsection (a) are to—</text><paragraph id="H5F80E6B88C0F405D9FE6B4E1C09B74F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>further achieve the purpose described in section 23(b)(1) of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/35/1">35 U.S.C. 1</external-xref> note), as amended by this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50724ABD9C09454CB5DEACB85A20D09C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>partner with local community organizations, institutions of higher education, research institutions, and businesses to create community-based programs that— </text><subparagraph id="H783910FC5CFF4F9AA8C04820984EFFF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide education regarding the patent system; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDB6DCC1C1EC4949B7BA9BE2D00D3C71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>promote the career benefits of innovation and entrepreneurship; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H454F66D34FA047A3BFE1B5319EBDEF65"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">educate prospective inventors, including women, people of color, veterans, individual inventors, or members of any other demographic, geographic, rural population, or economic group that the Director may determine to be underrepresented in patent filings about all public and private resources available to potential patent applicants, including the patent pro bono programs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2AF06E7BBD15402EB7442B2229C66105"><enum>5.</enum><header>Updates to the patent pro bono program</header><subsection id="HD2F1AC74796F4A7AABEF86350BE48A61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study and updates</header><paragraph id="H1C3605FE3D9E421BB24BFB9FF1379221"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall— </text><subparagraph id="HB590A6EDE2A346B7AA8CF3236EC0491C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>complete a study of the patent pro bono programs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA781734F55F849848081080B329E4765"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit the results of the study required under subparagraph (A) to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE10A909CF3F48D88E591E32075B9327"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope of the study</header><text>The study required under paragraph (1)(A) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H0669C1546FBC472DAB554A6346ED6A3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assess—</text><clause id="HB31E2DF51C7F4F3AAD0AEADC391FE14D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the patent pro bono programs, as in effect on the date on which the study is commenced, are sufficiently serving women, people of color, veterans, individual inventors, or members of any other demographic, geographic, rural population, or economic group that the Director may determine to be underrepresented in patent filings;</text></clause><clause id="H7C4ADD1F35394761B52554F91D80E71A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the patent pro bono programs are sufficiently funded to serve prospective participants;</text></clause><clause id="HF2786639303F443AA0B6A0DC1411BF44"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether any participation requirements of the patent pro bono programs, including any requirement to demonstrate knowledge of the patent system, serve as a deterrent for prospective participants; </text></clause><clause id="H4EBBE03D90CF48FE82C7ED7FDC730836"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the degree to which prospective inventors are aware of the patent pro bono programs;</text></clause><clause id="H41920C6F2C4249F8A99D9493108E6391"><enum>(v)</enum><text>what factors, if any, deter attorneys from participating in the patent pro bono program;</text></clause><clause id="HA7672F517D2748EC8D4D08CCE0E8B19D"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>whether the program would be improved by expanding the patent pro bono program to include non-attorney advocates; and</text></clause><clause id="H7F8346B1C3704E1AA45AE2B402AF63E1"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other issue the Director determines appropriate; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A1E9A1B7E9A48388299D70AE50C8D1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make recommendations for such administrative and legislative action as may be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77A5E56644E14664BD925026CEE5AC1A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of results</header><text>Upon completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Director shall work with the Patent Pro Bono Advisory Council, operators of patent pro bono programs, and intellectual property law associations across the United States to update the patent pro bono programs in response to the findings of the study.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB147D88135C743EE86472FC0E368A0B1" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expansion of income eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall work with and support, including by providing financial support, to intellectual property law associations across the United States that have established patent pro bono programs to expand eligibility for such programs to individuals living in a household, the gross household income of which is not more than 400 percent of the Federal poverty line. Patent pro bono programs may elect to set a higher eligibility level.</text></subsection></section><section id="H26B9307E31ED426AA8BA72593AEE6689"><enum>6.</enum><header>Pre-prosecution patentability assessment pilot program</header><subsection id="HEBFC40B7EFEF4710AF7B1E51DC3EF3ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pilot program</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall establish a pilot program to assist first-time prospective patent applicants in assessing the likelihood of issuance of a potential patent submitted by such a prospective applicant.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC147632D95924BD087673820E157E545"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the pilot program required under subsection (a), the Director shall establish—</text><paragraph id="HAC88745596EF4986809A6E85101E26A2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a notification process to notify a prospective patent applicant seeking an assessment described in that subsection that any assessment so provided may not be considered an official ruling of patentability from the Office;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09888272450541C583471F0404DA6D4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conditions to determine eligibility for the pilot program, taking into consideration available resources;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF53FE2D5CAD2467CB9C6DC08C86AA076"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reasonable limitations on the amount of time to be spent providing assistance to each individual first-time prospective patent applicant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BF703B273F64D1AA25293721ED7FF07"><enum>(4)</enum><text>procedures for referring prospective patent applicants to legal counsel, including through the patent pro bono programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H287DA34D93C442798C42B453F2B8DA5B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures to protect the confidentiality of the information disclosed by prospective patent applicants.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H560EA2B80D274F6B954E9D789B46C51E"><enum>7.</enum><header>Fee reduction for small and micro entities</header><subsection id="HED32F75FA89B4E85822FE0E6020AF080"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Title 35</header><text>Section 41(h) of title 35, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H15459769D353495FA4C6925A6F7DCAC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>50 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>60 percent or more, at the discretion of the Director,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0272F101670849019C4AE5C4EA8410B8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>75 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>80 percent or more, at the discretion of the Director,</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CE58B012F484C93BC64AD427BC6C017" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title 35</header><text>Section 123 of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3918E47F904C4D85AECCC77E0381B1BB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEAD546517BA34238843E55C3EEF2E568" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Penalties for fraudulent certifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other penalty available under law, an applicant that is found to have made a certification described under this section on a fraudulent basis shall be subject to the following penalties:</text><paragraph id="H46B24C9CAB7F43A0BD570BB1C9B92D8F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Abandonment of the patent application concerned, if such application is pending.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A0712FEC243465C9CC2D12BEFFD66AE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Revocation of the patent concerned, if the patent has been issued. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H375B502043A044FAB55DE33E8632AD5D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Title 35</header><text>Section 41(h) of title 35, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA2012A87A6314E2F8E9AE12233AF075E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1C1EB0BFD4544BFA9D4CA6DC672766EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Penalties for fraudulent certifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to any other penalty available under law, an entity that is found to have made a certification on a fraudulent basis that a fee reduction required by this subsection applies, such entity shall be subject to the following penalties:</text><subparagraph id="H0BC7A3EDE06948A6ADD3956EDC3AEF83" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Abandonment of the patent application concerned, if such application is pending.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95841D3BC41C4C988E0B86512C405E38"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Revocation of the patent concerned, if the patent has been issued. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8E85D803139943B9A2C9DDFCD0D6D0F6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Leahy-Smith america invents act</header><text>Section 10(b) of the Leahy-Smith America Invents Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/29">Public Law 112–29</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/35/41">35 U.S.C. 41</external-xref> note) is amended by striking <quote>50 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>60 percent, or by a higher percentage at the discretion of the Director,</quote> and by striking <quote>75 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>80 percent, or by a higher percentage at the discretion of the Director,</quote>. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

