<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="HC3EF42531D91474EB35FD5530834E8CB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6538 EH: Active Shooter Alert Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">IB</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6538</legis-num>
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To create an Active Shooter Alert Communications Network, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" style="OLC" id="HA716B3FE124C4C349AA8D48D2479D52B">
<section id="H300D91EF3E204742A586A477BF4D8113" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Active Shooter Alert Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H82783AD3E3B94A898F0CC4B1F7816BBC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H1062F23B5FA843D293E379D6970C348C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active shooter</header><text>The term <quote>active shooter</quote> means an individual who is engaged in killing or attempting to kill persons with a firearm in a populated area and who is determined to pose an active, imminent threat to people in that populated area.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE6B189E0B5DD4EBDABA2E1486276B31D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator of FEMA</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator of FEMA</quote> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H35577B5124724E2E9B0F8D97D782F2E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairman of the FCC</header><text>The term <quote>Chairman of the FCC</quote> means the Chairman of the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7BD5BDEF20D4DEBB182325D9A4F7EC6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordinator</header><text>The term <quote>Coordinator</quote> means the Active Shooter Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice designated under section 3(a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H53A58F87C22549FA816E06867B93EC3C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Network</header><text>The term <quote>Network</quote> means the Active Shooter Alert Communications Network, an interconnected system of Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments that is organized to provide information to the public, within geographically relevant areas, on active shooter situations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73E1EDBD35554266B86609C2101EC304"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Populated area</header><text>The term <quote>populated area</quote> means a location where one or more persons other than the active shooter are present.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF27006737D5D4FED89B2B150679B400C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means any of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, American Samoa, Guam, Puerto Rico, the Northern Mariana Islands, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H5F73E2B1CEE24D3FB0D5D9DD0B54F7FB"><enum>3.</enum><header>National coordination of active shooter alert communications network</header> <subsection id="H96DE998B6C0C4321B3D34344C96A2346"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordination within Department of Justice</header><text>The Attorney General shall assign an officer of the Department of Justice to act as the national coordinator of the Active Shooter Alert Communications Network regarding an emergency involving an active shooter. The officer so designated shall be known as the Active Shooter Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H678913BC6D3343A9B914373E695535BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Coordinator shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA3B605BD1D104B9FB94052300268E6E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage Federal, State, Tribal, and local government agencies to establish procedures to respond to an active shooter, including active shooter procedures relating to interstate or interjurisdictional travel (including airports and border crossing areas and checkpoints), and focus on governments that have not yet established such procedures; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1CFC56E5F19540CFBCC3BDA47BC8E7ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>work with State, Tribal, and local governments to encourage appropriate regional and interjurisdictional coordination of various elements of the Network.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9494C710F88C4781BE997470E5F3C168"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The Coordinator shall encourage the adoption of best practices established under section 4(a) in State, Tribal, and local governments for—</text>
<paragraph id="H82235B19E9D54862834D4D870423632F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the development of policies and procedures to guide the use of mass alert systems, changeable message signs, or other information systems to notify local residents, motorists, travelers, and individuals in the vicinity of an active shooter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C2AF5DD07414A58A2BC25518A25E8BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the development of guidance or policies on the content and format of alert messages to be conveyed on mass alert systems, changeable message signs, or other information systems relating to an active shooter;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5C819C94A00244388E6DA4AE52180B9F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the coordination of State, Tribal, and local Active Shooter Alert communications plans within a region for the use of mass alert systems relating to an active shooter;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D1D7BC0A2CF41E69C03AE144BAB6761"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the planning and designing of mass alert systems for multilingual communication with local residents, motorists, travelers, and individuals in the vicinity of an active shooter, which system may include the capability for issuing wide area alerts to local residents, motorists, travelers, and individuals in the vicinity of an active shooter;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDBFE2633F7C04FA6BD185E48DE84FCDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the planning of systems and protocols to facilitate the efficient issuance of active shooter alerts and other key information to local residents, motorists, travelers, and individuals in the vicinity of an active shooter during times of day outside of normal business hours;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8456C40C70D44ABD8E9CC633EB99A62C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the provision of training and guidance to transportation authorities to facilitate the appropriate use of mass alert systems and other information systems for the notification of local residents, motorists, travelers, and individuals in the vicinity of an active shooter; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H149DD5B277AF4ABEB45BC1036D1BB039"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the development of appropriate mass alert systems to ensure that alerts sent to individuals in the immediate vicinity of an active shooter do not alert the active shooter to the location of individuals sheltering in place near the active shooter.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD0ABA4FC556C48A19094089AB43E522B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Integrated Public Alert and Warning System</header><text>In carrying out duties under subsection (b), the Coordinator shall notify and coordinate with the Administrator of FEMA, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Chairman of the FCC on using the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System to issue alerts for the Network.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H40531747365F43CEAC70D3D1EE56B2FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter until such time as each of the State, Tribal, and local governments have adopted an active shooter alert protocol, the Coordinator, in consultation with the Administrator of FEMA, Secretary of Transportation, and the Chairman of the FCC, shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the Coordinator and the effectiveness and status of the Active Shooter Alert communications plan of each State, Tribal, and local government within each region that has implemented such a plan.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H8E98C562B4B148C68BA6E8BB58FDF74A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Standards for issuance and dissemination of alerts through active shooter alert communications network</header> <subsection id="H8BB1F0EA57044B86A1A08715E0510E3A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of best practices</header> <paragraph id="H7EA506A9AE7D4A7FB64A57E7AD891D8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (c), the Coordinator, using the recommendations of the Advisory Panel established under subsection (b) and in coordination with the Administrator of FEMA, the Secretary of Transportation, the Chairman of the FCC, local broadcasters, and Federal, State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies, shall establish best practices for—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD28545FBB8EE4855833C2488E0E19132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the issuance of alerts through the Network;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F7369F6786B41D5A3C62A118F4346A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the extent of the dissemination of alerts issued through the Network; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H899B65F2DB75407FBE26393E654E7DED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the achievement of the goals described in section 3(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBEEF6E87A4B44548ABF12A405E57E0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updating best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Coordinator shall review the best practices established under paragraph (1) no less frequently than every 5 years to ensure the best practices are consistent with updated data and recommendations on active shooter situations and technological advancements in the Integrated Public Alert and Warning System or other technologies. The Coordinator shall convene the Advisory Panel as necessary to provide updated recommendations if the best practices are to be updated.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB7CCC5968458440686BA084A58774CA8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory Panel</header>
<paragraph id="H8574561EA9EB406DA377D98EE805569F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Coordinator shall establish an Advisory Panel to make recommendations with respect to the establishment of best practices under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53742BB1CB3D48C8BF8E018C8BC30E0F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Panel shall be comprised of at least 9 members, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H82343C9788F743208E861AAE0D8BECDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 5 law enforcement officers, including at least one nonsupervisory law enforcement officer, who have responded to active shooter incidents and who represent rural, suburban, and urban communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2BE37C82C2347BABED222622EFB2143"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at least 1 public safety expert who is not a law enforcement officer and who has responded to an active shooter incident;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE45F4E8C87944713AF53776BE7DE5E64"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 emergency response official who is not a law enforcement officer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H85CAAFFBB56B4738BD112935F4AB350D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 city planning expert; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2649A2C9157D41C8B0F68558A978748F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 1 mental and behavioral health expert.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5FC52D33E5B940B2B27F8CF3310F2CCD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Advisory Panel shall submit to Coordinator recommendations with respect to the establishment of best practices under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H40548F13882E4676AD175834AD67443C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header>
<paragraph id="HEA3590AF68AA44D0BA7505AE2A3D354B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The best practices established under subsection (a) shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HB43022C9D70341939AA87B6081FB2D97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be adoptable on a voluntary basis only; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H679F036BB54C4035B77D994EECB664E2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable (as determined by the Coordinator, in consultation with State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies), provide that—</text> <clause id="HBC40CDDA95AC46ECAF53F8762A5CBD6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>appropriate information relating to an active shooter response is disseminated to the appropriate law enforcement, public health, communications, and other public officials; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA8825F6D6AC54A848F184A9433058DAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the dissemination of an alert through the Network be limited to the geographic areas most likely to be affected by, or able to respond to, an active shooter situation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31674BFD9D3C48FAB3FA4EDBBCAD4C55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No interference</header><text>In establishing best practices under subsection (a), the Coordinator may not interfere with systems of voluntary coordination between local broadcasters and State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies for improving and implementing the Network.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H269BC4B1DC6C4F1ABD31580151FE580C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Comptroller General study on State responses to active shooter situations requiring the issuance of public alerts and warnings</header>
<subsection id="H8A1F91F942FC4F778FF1B649F4B0F0EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on State and local responses to active shooters and situations requiring the issuance of a public alert or warning. Such study shall address each of the following:</text> <paragraph id="H2D630C00E347415183FEC01FB7356602"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Differences between the definitions of the term <quote>active shooter</quote> used by different States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6ED3070BC80643A89A0BBE40E14FEA0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount of time it takes and the process in each State to receive approval from the State alerting officials after a local law enforcement agency requests the issuance of a public alert or warning, such as an AMBER Alert, a Blue Alert, or an Ashanti alert.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DDC92B4DE484F3E852342FECEBAF4B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A comparison of the timing and effectiveness of the issuance of public alerts and warnings by State, Tribal, and local alerting officials.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H477713C1CBDE43B383F9064648FC1750"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report containing the findings of the study conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE43F0B4D92C84618A1DC79F78AF6EDE9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> <subsection id="HA846C86414BB451FA955F472E0015AA9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out this Act $2,000,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HBCCAC3427C374EE88427E98BFC6DB462"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HA4D64E6AB9FA4381BDD5F099A82A5783"><enum>7.</enum><header>Limitation on liability</header> <subsection id="HA7A6D3059C634C14BC346340B19446F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed to provide that a participating agency, or an officer, employee, or agent thereof, shall be liable for any act or omission pertaining to the Network.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H80773FA22C264FF782B6F491EE682B50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State or other Federal law</header><text> Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the application of any State or other Federal law providing for liability for any act or omission pertaining to the Network.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220713" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives July 13, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

