<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6766E291D3914A50A7C19A366985DD40" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9490 IH: Neutralizing Emerging Threats from Wireless OEMs Receiving direction from Kleptocracies and Surveillance states Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9490</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221212">December 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to foreign telecommunications companies engaged in economic or industrial espionage against United States persons, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD34F77FC50214518B63DBB49AC84F1A2" style="OLC"><section id="H3BA5A4DA0DF842DA972A4DB8981DBB0A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Neutralizing Emerging Threats from Wireless OEMs Receiving direction from Kleptocracies and Surveillance states Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NETWORKS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEBE13B2F929D44F89476E412504A3E86"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to economic or industrial espionage by foreign telecommunications companies</header><subsection id="H3C109CA53448444BBB445398B25AD4E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On and after the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all significant transactions in property and interests in property of a foreign person described in subsection (b) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subsection><subsection id="H76F53398A4A34F90BC090F609475E55D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foreign persons described</header><text>A foreign person is described in this subsection if the President determines that the person, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="HDB1353DBB43F440B96DAFD3A6CD9DA51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>produces fifth or future generation telecommunications technology; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CF8E08FDB894A3A865FEF87F23BFCE6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engages in—</text><subparagraph id="HAD098911DECD4610BC4F9E1E56E002C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>economic or industrial espionage with respect to trade secrets or proprietary information owned by United States persons; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63E25393136A4CFBBC251A72CF1EA55A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other related illicit activities, including violations of sanctions imposed by the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A15084ACCB24CBB8C8918B9A1395758"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="HC8C1A27039284E01A903C143A9AF0B13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any activity subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC12021FC81774961B5E85F728DB96714"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subparagraph id="H0CAC8B7B5AFB4ECFB544432BD8A38698"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions authorized under this section shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E3A34DCD17D4B59866FBF15154907CA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5044C34156C24CFEBC367655CA61DBFA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person for renewable periods of not more than 90 days each if the President determines and reports to Congress that such a waiver is vital to the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4CF5835E1A2448C08420C95B8BC857AF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header><paragraph id="H712D2A64402A4E8F8321C9B8C7506A9F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise the authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to the extent necessary to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11A1B22FEDDC43CA8B063C3921656170"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (a) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out that subsection shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12A0974E0A7C48F4ADB604CE52E79607"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="HD1CFC2937AD04CE29AEBC8516748CC2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section:</text><subparagraph id="H9B3926E950FE4066BA83A1E62541C87D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Economic or industrial espionage</header><text>The term <term>economic or industrial espionage</term> means—</text><clause id="H6DE3DAF649F148D1B8CBEEB557631D78"><enum>(i)</enum><text>stealing a trade secret or proprietary information or appropriating, taking, carrying away, or concealing, or by fraud, artifice, or deception obtaining, a trade secret or proprietary information without the authorization of the owner of the trade secret or proprietary information;</text></clause><clause id="H6EB48549EB784DFC852B4EDA0634B332"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>copying, duplicating, downloading, uploading, destroying, transmitting, delivering, sending, communicating, or conveying a trade secret or proprietary information without the authorization of the owner of the trade secret or proprietary information; or</text></clause><clause id="H0A1F1C939E0C407BB5166B0129EAE883"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>knowingly receiving, buying, or possessing a trade secret or proprietary information that has been stolen or appropriated, obtained, or converted without the authorization of the owner of the trade secret or proprietary information.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59507E8A11834A3186E84FC320ADBA16"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fifth or future generation telecommunications technology</header><text>The term <term>fifth or future generation telecommunications technology</term> means telecommunications technology that conforms to the technical standards followed by the telecommunications industry for telecommunications technology that is commonly known in the industry as fifth generation or future generation technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D3C3754A24141B8A6BCFCE1716FF1FE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means any person that is not a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F80F9072F6D48E6B3BD22AFE524CC03"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term>, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E6F0B91E2AA4084A439D10239158404"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term <term>person</term> means an individual or entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1248C56E5955421FB64B9915AAD82E20"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Proprietary information</header><text>The term <term>proprietary information</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1637(d) of the Carl Levin and Howard P. <quote>Buck</quote> McKeon National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1708">50 U.S.C. 1708(d)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F77F09CE16146CD8C284B498C89C501"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Third and fourth generation telecommunications networks</header><text>The term <term>third and fourth generation telecommunications networks</term> means telecommunications networks that conform to the technical standards followed by the telecommunications industry for telecommunications networks that are commonly known in the industry as third or fourth generation networks. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE93B72BF1EBA4F0B8C6D623C3AD1D5DF"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Trade secret</header><text>The term <term>trade secret</term> has the meaning given that term in section 1839 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF659D05B2D6C4501BDD26751B2802907"><enum>(I)</enum><header>United States person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><clause id="H8CEC3EA211114F418109987A8A1C5E05"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></clause><clause id="HE29494EF03C14A5DBD9015997C1B8A28"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63041531D12D4D56B75621B4EC414BA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of significance</header><text>For the purposes of this section, in determining if transactions are significant, the President may consider the totality of the facts and circumstances, including factors similar to the factors set forth in section 561.404 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations (or any corresponding similar regulation or ruling).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C86710142DA490CA0F7771FAC591700"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>For purposes of this section, a transaction shall not be construed to include—</text><subparagraph id="HC262ADADC72D421EB4F657C775288D17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participation in an international standards-setting body or the activities of such a body; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F64FE79821040ECB36C9D5260C7EED2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a transaction involving existing third or fourth generation telecommunications networks. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

