<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5E69C9C40A594A4986A08F1E757A5311" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7391 IH: Accountability for Cryptocurrency in El Salvador Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7391</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220404">April 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reports on the adoption of a cryptocurrency as legal tender in El Salvador, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE28A37BDCF09441B8231D37DF3FC12D7" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC02908377D1641DD8C76AB67FBF2DA67"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accountability for Cryptocurrency in El Salvador Act</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>ACES Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9EC23DCA53104FAF8605FD90FA5CAC17"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on adoption of cryptocurrency as legal tender in El Salvador</header><subsection id="H4D644367C37545B9881D93D9A7AFAA63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the adoption by the Government of El Salvador of a cryptocurrency as legal tender.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD6CD3086AC4745FC90E03131D69E2C13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HBF6856584DD7431788EB6FE869287717"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the process followed by the Government of El Salvador to develop and enact the Bitcoin Law (Legislative Decree No. 57, Official Record No. 110, Volume 431, enacted June 9, 2021), which provides the cryptocurrency, Bitcoin, with legal tender status in El Salvador.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CB9F102EC234F1BBE2F4EFC29EAF555"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="H6AAA0A8BC9EF440B8BAF0F789292B5F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the regulatory framework in El Salvador with respect to the adoption of a cryptocurrency as legal tender and the technical capacity of El Salvador to effectively mitigate the financial integrity and cyber security risks associated with virtual-asset transactions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC382A63582F4D65B920768E0531C02B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the regulatory framework in El Salvador meets the requirements of the Financial Action Task Force with respect to virtual-asset transactions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEAD4C0AC30D4D22B40B5E2B7959B58F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impact on individuals and businesses of requiring tender of Bitcoin; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEDB1FAAFEE864E83BB5E63C5A5E92D24"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the impact of such adoption of a cryptocurrency on—</text><clause id="H81A2D9F4F08942988BCB58430CB4ED20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the macroeconomic stability and public finances of El Salvador, including taxation; </text></clause><clause id="H329B750A63BD43B5B3118B40DD09E0EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the rule of law and democratic governance in El Salvador; </text></clause><clause id="HCA2D5F69AE644DB8892A0C043999C8D7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the unbanked population in El Salvador;</text></clause><clause id="HB37FA47C51C14EE2A017379F23A1BE0B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the flow of remittances from the United States to El Salvador;</text></clause><clause id="HB153ED7F809A41C5A89E0F5F84B2DFC5"><enum>(v)</enum><text>El Salvador's relations with multilateral financial institutions, such as the International Monetary Fund and the Word Bank;</text></clause><clause id="HF0A4B9CBB74D48BA92BDF5053344650E"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>bilateral and international efforts to combat transnational illicit activities; </text></clause><clause id="HFFD5B75986DD473D82D41B71614BBB82"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>El Salvador's bilateral economic and commercial relationship with the United States and the potential for reduced use by El Salvador of the United States dollar; and</text></clause><clause id="HF5246D7B7A404C4C9A8505580001535C"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>existing United States sanctions frameworks and the potential for the use of cryptocurrency to circumvent such sanctions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAD4327EADC540A8838963B9F878DE36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the internet infrastructure of El Salvador and an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="HC50453A146F54633B67D602BE7C1CB9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the degree to which cryptocurrency is used in El Salvador; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2BA861D138645A3A8B95A1C2F52CD62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>matters relating to chain of custody and the potential for hacking and cybertheft of cryptocurrency; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9A1B943605E4FB4AA25F5A49DDA140F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>access to transparent and affordable internet and digital infrastructure among the unbanked population of El Salvador.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H581268D6A4E34C66B9E0E90D13A29198"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan To mitigate risks to United States financial system posed by adoption of cryptocurrency as legal tender in certain countries</header><paragraph id="HD699E10081C847329B4185FEAD42EBA7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the submittal of the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a plan to mitigate any potential risk to the United States financial system posed by the adoption of a cryptocurrency as legal tender in—</text><subparagraph id="H5CBF576BA49E4C8F88980B12CCBAF3D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>El Salvador; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7604C6512D0F4112BC3869F8D58FB065"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other country that uses the United States dollar as legal tender.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2074252A3A84BFDA3007F2877F2EB7E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which the plan is submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary of State shall commence implementation of the plan. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E2E80677760477DA2CF2445D6FAEB5F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Subsequent report</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the submittal of the report required by subsection (a), the Secretary of State, in coordination with the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress an updated version of such report, including a description of any significant development related to the risks to the United States financial system posed by the use of a cryptocurrency as legal tender in El Salvador.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6907611B1896406D8EC9C3691D75375F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H4A3DB9AA243645BA8BF32A665000E16F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EBBF360C2B0455D9E56DD78383F3996"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

