<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H61ED4DCB599E4EA19500E9E026ECAA14" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6440 IH: Safer Streets Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6440</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to establish a grant program for jurisdictions with high rates of violent crime, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H101C535DFDFA4EAD95290822CB1788F9" style="OLC"><section id="H485105F772084AFBAAFCAF5BEDAA1CE2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Streets Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCFF6A94C760B4E0DAEF4D880F9DFAD02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10101">34 U.S.C. 10101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H271ABE2C4E0A4F3CBD635D453437A0E4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><part id="HE47E567EC420499291B88CF3BFD2C356"><enum>NN</enum><header>Grants for jurisdictions with high rates of violent crime</header><section id="H4BF481C1AD654BA0B934C2790D71F06D"><enum>3201.</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Attorney General shall, each fiscal year, make grants to eligible units of local government and neighborhood or community-based organizations. </text></section><section id="HEE99CEF1600841B1A34FF476E871EFAA"><enum>3202.</enum><header>Eligibility and incentives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible for a grant under this part, a unit of local government or a neighborhood or community-based organization operating in a covered jurisdiction shall submit to the Attorney General information establishing that the rate of occurrence of violent crime within that jurisdiction is 2 times or more the national violent crime rate and that the population of that jurisdiction is 100,000 or more. Of any amounts made available for grants under this part for a fiscal year—</text><paragraph id="H8BC571F06E6C40CEB391E2F6EB33EB33"><enum>(1)</enum><text>50 percent of such amounts shall be for grants, of an equal amount to each covered jurisdiction, to eligible grantees for which such rate of occurrence is 4 times the national violent crime rate or higher;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40AECB02FD064C20BDD43315087B04A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">20 percent of such amounts shall be for grants, of an equal amount to each covered jurisdiction, to eligible grantees for which such rate of occurrence is 3 times the national violent crime rate or higher;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B648419B0944E999D829BD2ED70869B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">10 percent of such amounts shall be for grants, of an equal amount to each covered jurisdiction, to all other eligible grantees; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC8669DBA684AC1899A5A5AB6DFBEF5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>remaining amounts shall be for emergency grants to such eligible grantees as the Attorney General determines appropriate.</text><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The Attorney General shall be responsible for awarding funds between units of local government and neighborhood or community-based organizations pursuant to each paragraph of this section. </continuation-text></paragraph></section><section id="HCE0CD9D751A64513ABD2CC14AF580344" commented="no"><enum>3203.</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not more than 10 percent of a grant made under this part may be used for costs incurred to administer such grant.</text></section><section id="H249CBCE208514681832CD9EF91898612"><enum>3204.</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Amounts made available as a grant under this part may be used by a grantee for law enforcement purposes or community violence prevention purposes including—</text><paragraph id="HBBD6E3E3821841E081201E6B6804267F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hiring additional law enforcement officers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB031883C7B24ED4834B60299D7DB4A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>investing in surveillance equipment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A9371E3BC3042F593F69B6971FB9A72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevention programs.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H58289927FE9241D7877A32161697168A"><enum>3205.</enum><header>Emergency assistance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any unit of local government or neighborhood or community-based organization in a covered jurisdiction that experiences, for a fiscal year, an increase of 10 percent in the rate of occurrence in violent crime over the preceding fiscal year, shall be eligible for an additional amount equal to 10 percent of the amount otherwise available under this part. </text></section><section id="HC0CBEE7352384BFBA8D175B7F07918B1"><enum>3206.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The term <term>violent crime</term> has the meaning given that term by the Attorney General for purposes of the Uniform Crime Reporting Program, for the fiscal year during which the grants are made. </text></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

