<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8F6326F7EB7C41699020EF378E012BB2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7652 IH: Social Security Guarantee Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7652</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To guarantee the right of individuals to receive Social Security benefits under title II of the Social Security Act in full with an accurate annual cost-of-living adjustment.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA125C08AA9BC4A329DF87BD22FC9AEE0" style="OLC"><section id="HF768A45F64F945019F2FB15A4D3AE4B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Security Guarantee Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H100A16B8CCD947628849C489C370DBAE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Guarantee of full Social Security benefits with accurate annual cost-of-living adjustment</header><subsection id="H7C375CC387204662B2ED27A2813AB349"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>On a date not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue a benefit guarantee certificate to each individual who is determined by the Commissioner of Social Security as of such date to be entitled to benefits under title II of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>). The Secretary shall also issue such a certificate to any individual on the date such individual is determined thereafter to be entitled to benefits under such title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H59144066F63545B2B17039220AE87996"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benefit Guarantee Certificate</header><text>The benefit guarantee certificate issued pursuant to subsection (a) shall represent a legally enforceable guarantee—</text><paragraph id="H74BD7139CF08460396EE3425CA89F50F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>of the monthly amount of benefits to which the individual is entitled under title II of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (as in effect on the date of the issuance of the certificate); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF29EA1AA45BE49F1B734AA1EA4758EAD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that the benefits will be adjusted—</text><subparagraph id="H2431A0DC3D074920B95C0627D541359D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>not less frequently than annually on the basis of an accurate determination of the increase in the cost-of-living of the individual; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC062E4C78EF04902B316BEBD9C56397A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in accordance with such title (as so in effect), to reflect any future changes in the eligibility status of the individual under such title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H614952D5AA0C4A3E9E555F5EA7572C5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Entitlement</header><text>Any certificate issued under the authority of this section constitutes budget authority in advance of appropriations Acts and represents the obligation of the Federal Government to provide for the payment to the individual to whom the certificate is issued benefits under title II of the <act-name parsable-cite="SSA">Social Security Act</act-name> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/401">42 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>) in the amounts set forth in the certificate and adjusted thereafter as described in subsection (b)(2).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

