<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAFB1EE5A5AA446E794045EC5BB513CF0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6529 IH: _____ Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6529</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220128">January 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require owners of a covered federally assisted rental dwelling units to install self-closing doors in such units, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F4DFA736EEB431581C99BD324473F69" style="OLC"><section id="H52C8C9F4B5024CDF812A78DD9519B371" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>_____ Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEB8E91CEC44641B995B66B24653ED695"><enum>2.</enum><header>Self-closing doors</header><subsection id="H27585ECAE69142C59926C59F99C9BC73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each owner of a covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, ensure that all doors, in the building that contains the covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit, that provide access to interior corridors and stairwells are self-closing doors and that such self-closing doors are maintained.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50CFF9D0F66245BDB3F35F8F80C2AA44"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Each owner of a covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit shall certify under penalty of perjury each month to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development in such manner as the Secretary may require that all doors in the building that contains the covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit owned by the owner, that provide access to stairwells are self-closing doors and that such self-closing doors are maintained.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB602A46DB8364FCD89978A4F23E622E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inspection</header><text>The proper installation, maintenance, and functioning of self-closing doors in a building containing a covered federally assisted dwelling unit shall be included in all inspections required by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF736DFD4261044EDBFA2B49EFE34AA73"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide guidance to public housing agencies (as defined in section 3(b)(6) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)(6)</external-xref>)) with respect to how to educate tenants about self-closing doors, and other health and safety measures, to help advance primary prevention and prevent future deaths and other harms in covered federally assisted dwelling units.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA9A91AFC46C94AB5A312F6409247EF8E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H36F2BB93CF0F41C498E9A7F442366F27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the status of the implementation of subsection (a), and includes—</text><subparagraph id="HBBEDBF186B5941F4B64030D6047FA8D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of covered federally assisted dwelling units without a self-closing door;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3588ED0F84374453897446167B5179F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of self-closing doors that have been installed by owners of covered federally assisted dwelling units;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1B0F02BE1B954E18A1C6EC0B2F316976"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of fatalities that occurred due to fire in the 1-year period preceding the date on which the report is submitted in buildings containing a covered federally assisted dwelling unit and what fire safety features such buildings had installed, including whether the buildings had self-closing doors installed;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3874113FB3A1442DB712BFCCFD0FECD9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a list of any owners of covered federally assisted housing that have not complied with the certification required described in subsection (b) in the 1-year period preceding the date on which the report is submitted; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BEC8741B5DE447C80A9F30CC22D42C3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the results of any inspections of covered federally assisted dwelling units conducted by the Secretary that included an inspection of self-closing doors; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7766FB8941CF4FBB87FE864D03312B51"><enum>(2)</enum><text>discloses the results of data collection instituted by the Secretary before the date of the enactment of this Act to determine the prevalence of self-closing doors in covered federally assisted dwelling units.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1ECE5673D0FD4AE986E51469D3C039BC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Relation to State and local law</header><text>This section does not annul, alter, or affect, or exempt any person subject to the provisions of this section from complying with, the laws of any State or unit of local government with respect to installing or maintaining self-closing doors, except to the extent that those laws are more stringent than any provision of this section, and then only to the extent of the inconsistency. The Secretary is authorized to determine whether such inconsistencies exist and may not determine that the law of any State or unit of local government is inconsistent with any provision of this section if the Secretary determines that such law provides for greater protection or safety.</text></subsection><subsection id="H17789E676A5A4AFDB6CC947CB8755122"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For the purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H86CB44F2CA7349DBABF890DBFBE522E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistance</header><text>The term <term>assistance</term> means any grant, loan, subsidy, contract, cooperative agreement, or other form of financial assistance, but such term does not include the insurance or guarantee of a loan, mortgage, or pool of loans or mortgages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37A238C1A2C14AE3888A441BD714D4F0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Self-closing door</header><text>The term <term>self closing door</term> means a door that—</text><subparagraph id="HDB1633B64AA44F67A64DA9338044AEA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>when opened and released, returns to the closed position; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0132DC89DA8C4FBFB5D24A6779DB4FF3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complies with the accessible door standards most recently issued by the American National Standards Institute.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E85F03674A5416AA6D48E2082D16FB9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered federally assisted housing</header><text>The term <term>covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit</term> means a residential dwelling unit that is made available for rental and for which assistance is provided, or that is part of a housing project for which assistance is provided, under—</text><subparagraph id="HEF0F3EBF4C4D4DFAB0A99EAC59CF7AF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the public housing program under the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E7D1E8D8B54B9B8B9EA58A9952E429"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the programs for rental assistance under section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>), including—</text><clause id="H37C0D967E5E44C3689224BF55D705E98"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the program for project-based rental assistance; and</text></clause><clause id="H84F09E0A96BB493F85C31701BDAFE455"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the program for tenant-based rental assistance;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22B7F1FD8FA44CCAA095D0A00BA1DDB4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the AIDS Housing Opportunities program under subtitle D of title VIII of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12901">42 U.S.C. 12901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9D89D8C6ADB42799DCF17CFC0176F9B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for the elderly under section 202 of the Housing Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1701q">12 U.S.C. 1701q</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A078F731008459C8213C2ED45CB5F6B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the program for supportive housing for persons with disabilities under section 811 of the Cranston-Gonzalez National Affordable Housing Act (42 U.S.C. 24 8013); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0987677848E420D8823F4B32045A8A2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the programs under sections 514, 515, and 516 of the Housing Act of 1949.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C4BB6859BA74545B1B3F575376CE34F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Owner</header><text>The term <term>owner</term> means, with respect to a covered federally assisted rental dwelling unit, any private person or entity, including a cooperative, an agency of the Federal Government, or a public housing agency, having the legal right to lease or sublease dwelling units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H662002B5404B4AFE8EA6A2E852CD940D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

