<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H93CD97A120FB42098B1F2F02D0145DF3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8109 IH: Tribal Cultural Areas Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8109</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Tribal Cultural Areas System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2241D1F77EB34798A251D9EB6A510691" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0C5A903F57404666A2D42B5A9F4958E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Cultural Areas Protection Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H55C016CB745641F2902F157E46849B74"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8CF7D73C0B024AD0A57BC51D72B80F8B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing use</header><text>The term <term>existing use</term>, with respect to a Tribal cultural area, means a use that is occurring within the Tribal cultural area on the date on which the Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0EEC8A995C7A47989B68E6177795F777"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Former reservation</header><text>The term <term>former reservation</term> means land that is within the exterior boundaries of the last reservation that was established by treaty, Executive order, or Secretarial order for an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44FCE3BC03A74E8D8243731FD67F5099"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Historic property</header><text>The term <term>historic property</term> means a historic or precontact site, building, structure, or object that has religious, medicinal, or cultural significance to an interested Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE944E609F734A52AD3C021345F898CD"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Indian land</header><text>The term <term>Indian land</term> means land of an Indian Tribe or an individual Indian that is—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5A18D3226E50481E87ECDB26F462A6FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>held in trust by the United States; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9806599E7D9460BAFB9829FB3A1A743"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to a restriction against alienation imposed by the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14E2F0EB1B3A43E4B94AF937F596E96D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> means the governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation individually identified (including parenthetically) on the list published by the Secretary under section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCC252D87C7FD42E2AE77D45E9BCAE4B8"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Interested indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>interested Indian Tribe</term>, with respect to a tract of public land, means an Indian Tribe with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H00CDFCFB83B5404FB71E70A7A004F9E0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>historic, precontact, cultural, or religious connections to a Tribal cultural site located on the tract of public land;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEEC7622D8E6943F2A6AE30B95BA646F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a former reservation located on the tract of public land; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCF0FA5FCC742468FAFE1030F8139EE29"><enum>(C)</enum><text>treaty rights or other reserved rights associated with the tract of public land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA63E917B5B64DE591528E1774E73A4B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the management plan developed for a Tribal cultural area under section 5(d)(3)(A).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEAE51796BEE4CE4A7E3F820431AD44D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National forest system</header><text>The term <term>National Forest System</term> has the meaning given the term in section 11(a) of the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Planning Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1609">16 U.S.C. 1609(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA674C24488274B7EAC5CC4A7D54D82EA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Native knowledge</header><text>The term <term>Native knowledge</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59D0162AE2FE48209B0D5FB7E498D579"><enum>(10)</enum><header>New use</header> 
<subparagraph id="H6EBBCA31B20E4BDE8951E0529EC41D2A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>new use</term>, with respect to a Tribal cultural area, means—</text> <clause id="HA659CBECE8E54F3C987000AFFEBF5745"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a use that involves surface disturbance and is not occurring in the Tribal cultural area on the date on which the Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0A64976FCDDB4B0A97E9923668354E57"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a use that is occurring in the Tribal cultural area on the date on which the Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System, but that is being modified so as—</text> <subclause id="HC358FD7403684ECE8662526E3305E6A3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to create a surface disturbance;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA3078EE4D20F45749E3069162D5F37BF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to significantly expand or alter impacts of the use on the land, water, air, cultural resources, or wildlife of the Tribal cultural area; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB3395D0A5EAB4BDDB7901BC3462F66CC"><enum>(III)</enum><text>to be inconsistent with the purposes for which the Tribal cultural area is—</text> 
<item id="H58C22C74499F476BABC70646A1968F2D"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>designated under section 5; or</text></item> <item id="HA760A58453E64F379101E02A43E41996"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>recommended under section 8.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H96AA35151DE5420090F4A329B31DDB77"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>new use</term>, with respect to a Tribal cultural area, does not include a use that—</text> <clause id="H622B49F132594D75902D43F86A94116B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is categorically excluded from the requirements of title I of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4331">42 U.S.C. 4331 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5FD79B54E5A84575852544705714D41C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is carried out to comply with the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="H33304EB4459846BE99DC49A81EC9AA82"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is necessary to maintain a road, trail, structure, or facility within the Tribal cultural area that is—</text> 
<subclause id="H0B67A0BCDD554E6A841E87F48FFC616A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in existence on the date on which the Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System; and </text></subclause> <subclause id="HA4366531BDFC43CFB78B5399C90E33C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>identified in the management planning documents of the applicable land management agency as a road, trail, structure, or facility intended for continued use; or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H933E095B23754C248198985758410A21"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Secretary concerned determines to be necessary for the control of fire, insects, or diseases, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D68CD7F88DB4EAEB2D315BE080F5719"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Public land</header><text>The term <term>public land</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H599BD5372E8942F3905DDF8839D8F01C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary (other than Indian land); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDB6F058888044428936B872E0DF084B8" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>National Forest System land. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BFEB90CAD71454CABE6E49A4DD94DCD"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Restoration</header><text>The term <term>restoration</term> has the meaning given the term in section 219.19 of title 36, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FF708C4BA704549B78D8187C81E526D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Sacred site</header><text>The term <term>sacred site</term> means a specific, discrete, narrowly delineated site on public land that is identified by an Indian Tribe as sacred by virtue of the established religious significance of the site to, or ceremonial use of the site by, an Indian Tribe. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE30A18A5C7444C6AB0C777BCC7DB9CCB"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF48C3B495B3947BB9866367B2AB3E7A0"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H419C309EFAE84CBD9F45350182DE3D8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary, with respect to public land described in paragraph (11)(A); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H84518A52C38149858E65CE1EB01DED33"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to public land described in paragraph (11)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA7D0F32E93D44C6BB2B7E7A3BD436DF6"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Surface disturbance</header><text>The term <term>surface disturbance</term> means any new disruption of soil or vegetation that would require restoration to return the soil or vegetation to natural appearance or ecological function. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24E63C7D243B4CFAA9B912E140AC9BAE"><enum>(17)</enum><header>System</header><text>The term <term>System</term> means the Tribal Cultural Areas System established by section 5(a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE558A8E9C77540B5B966A536A0DC2933"><enum>(18)</enum><header>Tribal commission</header><text>The term <term>Tribal commission</term> means the Tribal commission established for a Tribal cultural area under section 6(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85CF98680D7247A0BF9EFE63C9A92DAF"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Tribal cultural area</header><text>The term <term>Tribal cultural area</term> means a Tribal cultural site that has been designated for inclusion in the System.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3E8C64C511414947AE90D2D9C8002CFC"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Tribal cultural site</header><text>The term <term>Tribal cultural site</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H9AA63A495142437DAE0DF7347B503BE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a historic property; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9CDF874E29DE4C2EB9584C89A5DD5FBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a landform, landscape, or location that—</text> <clause id="H6495B31703614A57B548BF68A7FA17C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is or may be important to the customs, practices, objects, places, religions, or ceremonies of an Indian Tribe;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H465C9BD2B343475198085D8C1173E718"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is or may be important to an Indian Tribe for the undertaking of religious, cultural, spiritual, traditional subsistence, or other traditional practices;</text></clause> <clause id="H94F06AD4A2B5479FBF1B1A63DC2F06FC" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>contains unique or important traditional Tribal food, medicinal, or material gathering areas; or </text></clause> 
<clause id="HAF4F7E85A8D34C2FAEF629869261D45B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is connected through features, ceremonies, objects, histories, or cultural practices to other sites or to a larger sacred landscape, as determined by an Indian Tribe. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H13AD29D754F84AB6BF466585CC5106E6"><enum>(21)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text>The term <term>Tribal organization</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H176AE0C50998409F89F96E422EEF3AFB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> <paragraph id="H8136DF6BB13E4BA6AFD3B5818CF682B4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Federal Government manages more than 640,000,000 acres of public land that was carved out of the ancestral homeland of Indian Tribes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE006AE050C4347A5B1C952160CA5979E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Indians Tribes and members of Indian Tribes—</text> <subparagraph id="HD4D76FA6B5F2408F83AED0F69FAA683C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have maintained historical, religious, and spiritual connections to land now designated as public land;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB79626896CC495C82DCFE0226B14459"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continue to exercise treaty rights on public land; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF5475A08E23140EFAC22759A412E3AA7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>use public land to pray, conduct ceremonies, visit burial sites, gather plants, and undertake other traditional cultural activities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E2D271C530E4FE8B3A4363147047DCD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>treaties, Executive orders, court decisions, and Federal laws and regulations—</text> <subparagraph id="H43DB4256A55F49EA91FADF77148A482A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>acknowledge the rights of Indian Tribes and members of Indian Tribes on public land; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9AF97E53F022447584C28AFDA1F9550C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require public land managers to consult with Indian Tribes prior to taking action that would impact those rights; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H872DDF6CEC28489A9A0E1F552CAAFC51"><enum>(4)</enum><text>efforts to commercially develop or transfer ownership of public land often ignore the rights and protections of Indian Tribes and have resulted in—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCDB7325FBE374630AE99889D09E17D70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the desecration of sacred sites;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD029F0899FC54049A988A0D499221A3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the diminishment of Tribal treaty rights; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB71536C5B88741CFAEE630C704565CB7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the mismanagement of sacred sites, including the looting of sacred objects and burial sites and the diminishment of harvests of traditional native plants used in religious ceremonies and for other purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H7B4DB0A2B2704CF28722AD68D7390E92"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7D2E5A0ECB1140FA906AA208BA322177"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the preservation of Tribal cultural sites located on public land is in the public interest;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7DF10EFCE4B4F649CE2D072E5D2C747"><enum>(2)</enum><text>through their unique history and traditional knowledge, Indian Tribes have an important role in managing Tribal cultural sites on public land; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC154D510967E48F89856F9926BFB0760"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Tribal cultural sites on public land should be permanently protected for the benefit of Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF2EB8742101345E38F73663B277EB73E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Tribal Cultural Areas System</header> <subsection id="HD9C224F9B93E446FAF8438947E83F0C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>In order to preserve Tribal cultural sites on public land, there is established the Tribal Cultural Areas System.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE1421EB4A2D44578A88280BC19BC0CF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the System are—</text> <paragraph id="H47E98B62D0784F02B4EF7204C6D5D900"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to preserve opportunities for Indian Tribes to undertake religious, cultural, spiritual, medicinal, or traditional practices within Tribal cultural sites;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE03A2A428F924FD489EDB2E100FE1587"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to permanently protect the religious, cultural, spiritual, scenic, ecological, medicinal, and traditional values of Tribal cultural sites; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB647601D3194BCEA6AAA1192F04A0DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to enhance opportunities for Indian Tribes to engage in the preservation and management of Tribal cultural sites on public land.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C60AC142C8240EE97C143634D9D3234"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Areas included</header> 
<paragraph id="HDAC23AD82D4743C281534460D4CAA970"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible cultural sites</header><text>Any Tribal cultural site located on public land is eligible to be designated by Congress as a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H988F026F69F74BF8B8AA5E82241BD068"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation</header><text>A Tribal cultural site may be designated as a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System only by an Act of Congress. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D00A59FD7134364878DC1CFDDBFAA10"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretarial recommendation</header><text>In determining whether to designate a Tribal cultural site as a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System, Congress shall take into consideration the recommendations of the Secretary concerned under subsections (a)(6) and (d)(3)(C)(ii)(I) of section 8.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC664B6613C34F6CB05BF2FF7F11D302"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>A Tribal cultural area may be removed from the System only by an Act of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H314D14C1DF9740C2A420C96CB2CFB95D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Management</header> 
<paragraph id="HBD25D2C8756C45A1AF5BB5C40DB5ACED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, the Secretary concerned shall manage Tribal cultural areas—</text> <subparagraph id="HACA83686116447E888BAD81B5EA5E86B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to preserve Tribal cultural sites within each Tribal cultural area;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DFA34C2BD4A4562BA19DC7FF4FA0E52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in consultation with the applicable Tribal commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H43F35516C816402EAD5A69B958348139"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> 
<clause id="HE0D8504474A94BB19E35A4B0FFB8925E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></clause> <clause id="HFB2897D62BD3421C9FEED62079AE168C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other applicable laws (including regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E969F514E8C47E29900A733DCCCF3EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Uses</header> 
<subparagraph id="H133C7FE0966B49B19DEAD19E79920061"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In accordance with this Act, the Secretary concerned shall only authorize new uses or existing uses within a Tribal cultural area that the Secretary determines, in consultation with the applicable Tribal commission, are consistent with—</text> <clause id="HCEB674AE772A4DAAA2E70892B08DCCE8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the purposes described in subsection (b);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA8B193FEDC2E45C69725EC97E70071D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the preservation of Tribal cultural sites within the Tribal cultural area; and</text></clause> <clause id="HC4E2D5B0646E4539858F7D891FBEDB93"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE3A87ECE7424E4E8417DFC8F42F7834"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New uses</header> 
<clause id="H963C1CA84A494BA1804ECAD65FB8D832"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary concerned determines under subparagraph (A) that a new use is consistent with the requirements of clauses (i) through (iii) of that subparagraph, before authorizing the new use, the Secretary concerned shall request agreement from the applicable Tribal commission.</text></clause> <clause id="HC62F6118D0624435835FEB48F61989D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>If the applicable Tribal commission agrees to the new use for which the Secretary concerned requests agreement under clause (i), or does not respond to the request by the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned makes the request under that clause, the Secretary concerned shall authorize the new use.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H876B9F60A83840D0B2C2440FA190F42C"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>If the applicable Tribal commission denies agreement for a new use by the date that is 30 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned makes the request under clause (i), the Secretary concerned shall—</text> <subclause id="H4E26F00279984B21A3574E4A06945D14"><enum>(I)</enum><text>consult with the applicable Tribal commission to determine specific measures to eliminate or mitigate potential adverse impacts to the Tribal cultural area resulting from the new use; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCB6DF6CD8A1C435F9F22AC69A7CAA147"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorize the new use, subject to the measures determined under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E142A8170FA4C0A9D894D86D6E96273"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management plan</header> <subparagraph id="H22C940C1F09F495B953D804C1C37A3F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which a Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System, the Secretary concerned shall develop a comprehensive plan for the management of the Tribal cultural area in accordance with paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3529894F4F1B4D239F15513509C26990"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In developing a management plan under subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall—</text> <clause id="H65A81A6C12A5451C828D2419DA44B2B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>closely collaborate with the applicable Tribal commission in accordance with subparagraph (C);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7EF28BB79E0248D89506177C1539118F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult with—</text> <subclause id="HF2BCC9858B2346F387393519D0D078F7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Indian Tribes;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H30E047F7CB214501BD740D79422A952C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>appropriate State and local governmental entities; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HC2B1BAE6204E432187D048167A798F2E"><enum>(III)</enum><text>members of the public;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H9AD6B64192F34815AC74231FD1919EBE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at the request of an interested Indian Tribe identified under section 9(a)(1), include the interested Indian Tribe as a cooperating agency in the development of the management plan; and</text></clause> <clause id="H42ADBEF8647049229495FD11F2621B42"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, incorporate Native knowledge.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAB3244C16A84491CAC6305A3F989C378"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Incorporation of recommendations</header> 
<clause id="H9D12CBB6D4C84235975FC112FE2A8C0C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In developing a management plan under subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned shall carefully and fully consider incorporating the traditional, historical, and cultural knowledge and Native knowledge of the applicable Tribal commission, which shall be submitted to the Secretary concerned as written recommendations.</text></clause> <clause id="H64EABB258D2A4C30B98B6C424CFC25EA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>If the Secretary concerned determines that a specific recommendation submitted to the Secretary concerned under clause (i) is impracticable, infeasible, or not in the public interest, the Secretary concerned shall consult with the applicable Tribal commission to determine specific measures to modify, or otherwise address, the recommendation.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3093740D10054A6CB9BE9F13A66455C2"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Written explanation</header><text>If, after consultation under clause (ii), the Secretary concerned determines not to incorporate a specific recommendation submitted to the Secretary concerned under clause (i), the Secretary concerned shall provide to the Tribal commission a written explanation of the reason for the determination by the date that is 30 days after the date on which the determination is made. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B2986C16E8D44ED96F2FFDB3ED0F899"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Road construction</header> <subparagraph id="H69EEC127837B4694940B495C04504DAC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No new roads shall be constructed within a Tribal cultural area.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H848D27747A954D2F89CF2000F7C911A4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Temporary roads</header><text>No temporary roads shall be constructed within a Tribal cultural area, except as necessary—</text> <clause id="H4230B0DB59514A149CD5AAEAF4A456F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to meet the minimum requirements for the administration of the Tribal cultural area;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2527FFB5A48D4C5CB7E47A9B02C19C56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to protect public health and safety;</text></clause> <clause id="HC5671497D9004B9CA1935791BAA62EAF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9582AFF878FA40F8B47DFC9597D718C5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for the control of fire, insects, or diseases, subject to such terms and conditions as the Secretary concerned determines to be appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H488B21A72B624CB2AF7E2EC7B5F6919F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Subject to appropriations, the Secretary concerned shall maintain existing roads determined by the Secretary concerned, in consultation with the applicable Tribal commission, to be necessary for authorized existing uses and the administration of the Tribal cultural area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC86A16D04DBA4B12B1F20097C58FB90C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Motorized vehicles</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD381DF50D5064D9CB09D4E43228033A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the use of motorized vehicles in a Tribal cultural area shall be permitted only on roads designated by the management plan for the use of motorized vehicles.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H600A7AAFC69C494093CAE6E13B35EBDE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The use of motorized vehicles shall be permitted in a Tribal cultural area on roads not designated by the management plan for the use of motorized vehicles in cases in which the use is—</text> 
<clause id="H66F44B5F58934E8CA7D43D760E67A6CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>necessary—</text> <subclause id="H0C80CB0745BE4881A483350498B65440"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for administrative purposes;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HA0EAF0C4A23141699F375156C7D9AAB2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>to respond to an emergency; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB55B27442DE04D67B886872A1A23AAD7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>for traditional cultural purposes, including the exercise of rights secured by treaty, statute, Executive order, or other Federal law; or</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H61EBEF7E43FF4F2891DFD8447DED44BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>determined necessary by the applicable Tribal commission.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H580E9057937E464A9EE279D31E6CB0B4"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph authorizes the use of motorized vehicles on public land (as defined in section 10(d)(1)) within a Tribal cultural area if the use is otherwise prohibited on the public land.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F61DA664E974250A577062AACDDCE9F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Grazing</header> 
<subparagraph id="H3428D257D3C64981AB61FA6E4E4747EC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the grazing of livestock in a Tribal cultural area established before the date on which the Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System shall be permitted to continue.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7DCF75309EF646BD8B165740166EF637"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header> <clause id="H0690E34EB7FE46C3B464E08C0FEC3D7A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Consistency required</header><text>Grazing permitted under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text> 
<subclause id="H5F4778D334A245F19487FF0F7A27DEF9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>subject to—</text> <item id="H4295D72A54EF4480AF4556439CAE4E5A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a determination by the Secretary concerned, in consultation with the applicable Tribal commission, that grazing may be carried out in a manner consistent with the purposes for which the Tribal cultural area is established;</text></item> 
<item id="H26C9D6A41EC14A9AA8D2528A28CAFE2E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary concerned determines necessary; and</text></item> <item id="HD2D0D654D1BA4E3FA7EBEBEB3A35F67A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>applicable law (including regulations); and</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAC4031AD0846423381E5221E1E715EFD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>carried out in a manner consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA6BEBE48F47C45ED8CFD52F3B20392BE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Modification</header><text>On a determination by the Secretary concerned that grazing within a Tribal cultural area is inconsistent with the purposes for which the Tribal cultural area is established, the Secretary concerned shall modify or terminate the grazing permit or lease, as determined appropriate by the Secretary concerned.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7752EA2C3E434875ACF1855F85B63CCF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Voluntary grazing permit or lease donation program</header> 
<clause id="H061A262FBF4B4B2CB1A73351DFD9FB70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Donation of permit or lease</header> 
<subclause id="HF7A225E57788406292076153AFFE1176"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Acceptance</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall accept the donation of any valid existing permits or leases authorizing grazing on public land, all or a portion of which is within a Tribal cultural area.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H1C829CD3E2BC4A08BF0B9545896F5214"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall terminate any grazing permit or lease acquired under subclause (I).</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1BC8B46912E74E629A78B1360457CFE6"><enum>(III)</enum><header>No new grazing permits or leases</header><text>Except as provided in clauses (ii) and (iii), with respect to each grazing permit and lease donated under subclause (I), the Secretary concerned—</text> <item id="HB3E642158E724DB18E68543DFBB8F605"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>shall not issue any new grazing permit or lease within the grazing allotment covered by the grazing permit or lease; and</text></item> 
<item id="HA348E635E1BF439394A89DF9AC953876"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall ensure a permanent end to livestock grazing on the grazing allotment covered by the grazing permit or lease.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H15EA3EEE923749D29447A4AE09823FF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Donation of portion of grazing lease</header> <subclause id="H9E8D941F783548ADA7F6E7FFB21A98E5"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a person holding a valid grazing permit or lease donates less than the full amount of grazing use authorized under the permit or lease, the Secretary concerned shall—</text> 
<item id="HC01A846360C24997AEDA06EE983002BB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>reduce the authorized grazing level to reflect the donation; and</text></item> <item id="HABD0BDDEAD194A66A56646ADB900A585"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>modify the permit or lease to reflect the revised level of use.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H0AC9DBBE8F114AF599FE05E01BC08843"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authorized level</header><text>To ensure that there is a permanent reduction in the authorized level of grazing on the land covered by a permit or lease donated under subclause (I), the Secretary concerned shall not allow grazing use to exceed the authorized level established under that subclause.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H17B829AE26F5458F91E150E3E2503A9D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Common allotments</header> <subclause id="HFA732576AE78470181EE91C64E384413"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a grazing allotment covered by a grazing permit or lease or portion of a grazing permit or lease that is donated under clause (i) or (ii) also is covered by another grazing permit or lease that is not donated, the Secretary concerned shall reduce the grazing level on the grazing allotment to reflect the donation.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5C5BAF0B197D46809CB8BAD0EC5FF59D"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Authorized level</header><text>To ensure that there is a permanent reduction in the level of livestock grazing on the land covered by a grazing permit or lease or portion of a grazing permit or lease donated under clause (i) or (ii), the Secretary concerned shall not allow grazing to exceed the level established under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95438EEBEA08437F9C7DFE9482E03638"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Vegetation management</header> <subparagraph id="HD5A130BE7BFF4F5FA1B80D20DE66EB54"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), vegetation management within a Tribal cultural area may be permitted—</text> 
<clause id="H023065BF9E174A43B252E36699970513"><enum>(i)</enum><text>if necessary to protect, maintain, or enhance a Tribal cultural area (including the enhancement of traditional food or material gathering); and</text></clause> <clause id="HD5DAC32B648244A4966ED82EA7BEB7CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for restoration purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H55222BAFAF3346049E0B240E45CA1B93"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Vegetation management permitted under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text> <clause id="H0E43053866C445078DCAF4CF9250160C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subject to—</text> 
<subclause id="H6811E35B1CCC4AED934587BFF3C3F852"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such reasonable regulations, policies, and practices as the Secretary concerned determines necessary; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H2327497A62B04986917F0C47FAD49C26"><enum>(II)</enum><text>applicable law (including regulations); and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H5BE1AB791D7A4A7D8982D6A8324C5F5F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a manner consistent with the purposes described in subsection (b).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H71B6DF62EFB34235A640B6C5312D0FF9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Valid existing rights</header><text>The designation of a Tribal cultural area shall be subject to valid existing rights.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB363254F4CF149F4A8E59A0A6F2413C2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, all public land within a Tribal cultural area, and all land and interests in land acquired by the United States within a Tribal cultural area, shall be withdrawn from—</text> <paragraph id="H36B4066543C040AEA47F695571E0B0FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C3F4B64625242CB9C8B14025F380099"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H825200BC0C034772A38C1B098E961194"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3F30370BF85941C5A5D7B48A873AC5A3"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Tribal cultural and religious uses</header> 
<paragraph id="H594491A4C98C42A6A3E4D31075D8592B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act diminishes any Tribal rights regarding access to public land for Tribal activities, including spiritual, cultural, medicinal, and traditional food gathering activities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HADD932F1731C4B36BE0475F17FC75F89"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribal uses and interests</header> <subparagraph id="H86231CE623CA4725911DC16776D797C5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Access and use</header><text>In accordance with applicable law, and subject to section 10(d)(3), the Secretary concerned shall ensure access to a Tribal cultural area by members of an interested Indian Tribe for traditional cultural and religious purposes.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H794FF9B6BF794627AAFC4DEB40A0A82D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Temporary closure</header> 
<clause id="H7C2DC4B0E176467686834E3C09BF291D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary concerned, in consultation with the applicable Tribal commission, on request of an Indian Tribe or applicable Tribal commission, may temporarily close to the general public the use of 1 or more specific portions of a Tribal cultural area to protect the privacy of cultural, religious, and food and medicinal and materials gathering activities by members of the Indian Tribe.</text></clause> <clause id="H9E8729307F834CB5B004A45256EADC94"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <subclause id="H7971B79194024647B8A4B48E6E703A23"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any closure under clause (i) shall be made so as to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum period of time necessary.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H29966B46A022410CA2BF92B544B5D4F3"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Access</header><text>Access by members of an Indian Tribe to a portion of a Tribal cultural area closed under clause (i) shall be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996 et seq.</external-xref>) and other applicable law.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H32271A444061474D87D0D605037E2D74"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federally secured rights; indian land</header> <paragraph id="HFB4B78C317A04095BB4739D9B56CA1AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federally secured rights</header><text>Nothing in this Act alters, modifies, enlarges, diminishes, or abrogates rights secured by treaty, statute, Executive order, or other Federal law of any Indian Tribe, including off-reservation reserved rights.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H040E365DB78649FEA5A77F31FB9C7226"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian land</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects any Indian land.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8DCB526665C14CF4BA7417BB1E7D8ACE"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header> <paragraph id="HA7D89035B714498BB8318D2644B29EE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned, in coordination with the applicable Tribal commission, shall ensure adequate law enforcement presence with respect to law enforcement matters under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned to maintain the integrity of a Tribal cultural area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA5FED70E85934CE79251E85402BA82BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on jurisdiction</header><text>Nothing in this Act limits or otherwise affects the civil or criminal regulatory jurisdiction, including law enforcement, for issues under the jurisdiction of an Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H68EBD0540C8B42689C4929C1929BE6CA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Tribal commission</header> <subsection id="HD4382BF05B5648F1ABBF5719CF1A1AAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure that the management of a Tribal cultural area reflects the expertise and traditional, cultural, ecological, and historical knowledge and Native knowledge of members of interested Indian Tribes, not later than 180 days after the date on which the Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System, the Secretary concerned shall establish for the Tribal cultural area a Tribal commission.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA7FDE852C3094BD2AA23F97A451AD938"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>Each Tribal commission shall provide guidance and recommendations on the development and implementation of the management plan for, and policies of, the applicable Tribal cultural area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11463494D14A4C56A4A6DB7DBD9CC857"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header> <paragraph id="HB1CC6A250D4E4FB5B636F40B7060A31D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>Each Tribal commission shall consist of the representatives designated by each interested Indian Tribe with a historical association with the land within the boundaries of the Tribal cultural area for which the Tribal commission is established (with a maximum of 1 representative per interested Indian Tribe). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H949F8F575DF34F15804557DA3ED743C8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Process</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall conduct government-to-government consultation with each interested Indian Tribe with a historical association with the land within the boundaries of the Tribal cultural area for which the Tribal commission is established to determine whether the interested Indian Tribe may designate a representative to be a member of the Tribal commission under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H85AE8E89474A45C692EB31B44A152462"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The <act-name parsable-cite="FACA">Federal Advisory Committee Act</act-name> (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to any Tribal commission.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H917332286A054BA7932354218A59C480"><enum>7.</enum><header>Self-determination contracts</header> 
<subsection id="H365D674BFED8414D917373FB6D4541E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned may contract with 1 or more Indian Tribes or Tribal organizations to perform administrative or management functions within a Tribal cultural area through contracts entered into under the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5301">25 U.S.C. 5301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4AF7528C6163478D816D019BF6B11FEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tribal assistance</header><text>The Secretary concerned may provide technical and financial assistance to an Indian Tribe in accordance with section 103 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5322">25 U.S.C. 5322</external-xref>) to improve the capacity of the Indian Tribe to develop, enter into, and carry out activities under a contract under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H6D797FDB0CBC4F1EABB9318985CEE63D"><enum>8.</enum><header>Agency recommendations</header> 
<subsection id="H14D92D4803624D9AB51C9B1D7A784E41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial agency recommendations</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary concerned, in consultation with interested Indian Tribes, shall—</text> <paragraph id="HD20DAB248A4A4211BB499C3113CD1071"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish criteria for recommending Tribal cultural sites for designation as Tribal cultural areas for inclusion in the System, using the factors described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD691F7BD0BA74577A838A9B7D909A058"><enum>(2)</enum><text>solicit recommendations for Tribal cultural sites on land under the jurisdiction of the Secretary concerned to be designated as Tribal cultural areas for inclusion in the System from—</text> <subparagraph id="H5E3E01DBE1F844EBB6C538D9E1165508"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any interested Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9C3EFE117B0F4FB2AF52D457A3A977B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any applicable State Historic Preservation Officer; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F7C46E879DE4B32A4934A888F4A15AF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any applicable Tribal Historic Preservation Officer;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01C6514AE643442785C260782EFAB57C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review designations in local land management plans to identify Tribal cultural sites that meet the criteria established by the Secretary concerned under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B8590EDD19A49659D151C2AAC2FF2A8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consider any other relevant information, including oral histories, traditional knowledge, Native knowledge, and traditional ecological knowledge, regarding Tribal cultural sites on public land that may qualify for designation as a Tribal cultural area;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA0523B59B22E4403A39530B0223292C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>consider and evaluate Tribal cultural sites, including Tribal cultural sites identified under paragraphs (2) through (4), for designation as a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE1B4752B76124F46B444B3DAF0CEE988"><enum>(6)</enum><text>make recommendations to Congress regarding Tribal cultural sites that the Secretary concerned determines should be designated as Tribal cultural areas for inclusion in the System.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC9D44A06C98459EBD34ADC286F9922A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>The factors that the Secretary concerned shall consider in establishing criteria for recommending a Tribal cultural site for designation as a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System under subsection (a)(1) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H3E42C4E0936D464886947ACB95DD11B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the importance of the potential Tribal cultural area to an Indian Tribe or members of an Indian Tribe for traditional cultural activities, including praying, conducting ceremonies, visiting burial sites, gathering plants, and undertaking other traditional cultural activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1EA10BD9B87B4F57A5CD8D2EB641B29D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the past or present cultural, traditional, and historical affiliations of an Indian Tribe to the potential Tribal cultural area;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D5C23E651254A84AEFE2FE6E0B408DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the existence of rights secured by treaty, statute, Executive order, or other Federal law; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0D305404B3A24018BA20E57274D42303"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations made by 1 or more Indian Tribes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD239ECE552E54C03BA4F2A51AC01512B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ongoing agency recommendations</header><text>As a part of any update or revision of a local land management plan, the Secretary concerned shall identify, evaluate, and make recommendations regarding any Tribal cultural sites on land covered by the local land management plan that would be suitable for designation as Tribal cultural areas for inclusion in the System.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4E23197442A470BB74CA6928DB156B3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional areas</header> 
<paragraph id="HB2E09194E4F64823BD7FEA677A6889B5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>One or more interested Indian Tribes may submit to the Secretary concerned a petition to recommend the designation of a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA24094A960B543D9B885879E949CBA1E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>A petition under paragraph (1) shall contain—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H487968FB347E47BA9F08580061C1C35B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the cultural significance and history of the proposed Tribal cultural area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H88C176F2E5684C11BDC8059AE6BCE816"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a map showing specific boundaries of the proposed Tribal cultural area; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBCE28A76607847ECADB5E231340E424E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a list of interested Indian Tribes that possess cultural, religious, historic, or precontact connections to the proposed Tribal cultural area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9112D3E95DBA4E839CF4126AE18BB45C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Approval process</header> <subparagraph id="H281C958D1AE04BF1AAD51CCF150BAAF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which a petition is submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall approve or deny the petition.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3F838EA6067546699C5CD11180B5A877"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to meet deadline</header> 
<clause id="H44F7BDD4FEA44C5490A843CC79E06C62"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), if the Secretary concerned does not approve or deny a petition submitted under paragraph (1) by the deadline described in subparagraph (A), the petition shall be considered to have been denied by the Secretary concerned.</text></clause> <clause id="HB97BE407D32648B596164D9CB6EEB10D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Extension</header><text>The Secretary concerned and the 1 or more Indian Tribes that submitted the petition may mutually agree to extend the deadline for responding to the petition under subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H52EF10B857A4467EAA05D16C84D863E6"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Approval</header> 
<clause id="H01B37D66BE1D4F34BFD5FAEF7ED3FE35"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall approve a petition submitted under paragraph (1) unless the Secretary concerned determines that—</text> <subclause id="HD38631E60AC44648870F77799EE676BD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the proposed Tribal cultural area does not meet the criteria established under subsection (a)(1); or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5CBA8E50E4DD4B04BAE4B2E541D1DA9F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>approving the petition—</text> <item id="H0FB3ABCE474847B7BBC8BB922601CAC5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>would violate Federal law; or</text></item> 
<item id="H76A5521B79D348D0BFF9F4879C140048"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>is not in the public interest.</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA5B702A7161A4F48924C1E6518D0EC85"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>On approval of a petition submitted under paragraph (1), the Secretary concerned shall—</text> 
<subclause id="HD147E030ED05499FA00DE67A1CA535CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>recommend that Congress designate the proposed Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA7826820E3C04EA0B5109C72920D3366"><enum>(II)</enum><text>manage the proposed Tribal cultural area in accordance with subsection (e).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7E52A196761F44D2867DDC0D7C9D4816"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Denial</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which the Secretary concerned, as applicable, denies a petition submitted under paragraph (1) or fails to meet the applicable deadline described in subparagraph (B), the Secretary concerned shall provide to the 1 or more interested Indian Tribes that submitted the petition—</text> <clause id="HD4B17311825F497EB59A1344BAB4AC3F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a written response detailing the reasons why the Secretary concerned denied the petition; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HDADBB783EB4843DDAA9DA2E06B5DC6B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an opportunity to correct any deficiencies in the petition.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H80796D1B5C784B45B61B71226B4253EB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Management of recommended areas</header> <paragraph id="HDEDD1B0953C94E4A97898D7B1AFD3EFA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Until Congress determines otherwise, the Secretary concerned shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF28D7D41213F495593AAF32F6315D50A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>manage each recommended Tribal cultural area—</text> <clause id="H1A66770CCFE649EEB8E1CB17955CFFEB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a manner so as to preserve the Tribal cultural sites and cultural values of the area; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3389A4F9414843428888142598636828"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in accordance with—</text> <subclause id="H7658F4FEE4B943938E1364031B8EA6AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>paragraphs (4) through (7) of section 5(d); and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HE36B324BC48A4DC6A08E33A7F2582200"><enum>(II)</enum><text>subsections (g) through (i) of section 5; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC15295A78AD4A26984C465EBE51CF52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>only allow such uses in the recommended Tribal cultural area as are consistent with preserving Tribal cultural sites and cultural values of the area, as determined by the Secretary concerned after consultation with interested Indian Tribes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8914B9E9AD94402ABDE4803D5C45A4DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights, until Congress has determined otherwise, the Secretary concerned shall withdraw all public land within a recommended Tribal cultural area from—</text> <subparagraph id="HE0F77261655243708E35BECD8568F0CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCC63BD9676A9426F84E47033ED02DB6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEC1CB33CC3A489EA0A024EE3EDEDB65"><enum>(C)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB248E54573084262875517AC72382423"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall consult with interested Indian Tribes with an interest in a recommended Tribal cultural area not less frequently than twice each year to discuss—</text> <subparagraph id="HC4CCA2D4CA134933910D71A5969E3DF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the protection and management of the recommended Tribal cultural area; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H02F6A03C380F40AD89CD1101939022F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>proposed new uses of the recommended Tribal cultural area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HB998C5ECAE62488AAB02F2A2B43A8C1C"><enum>9.</enum><header>Tribal coordination</header> <subsection id="H02E50126E61143E9AE37B827BB6C0E20"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Selection</header> <paragraph id="HBB75F35F1A1F48458E1F328FB13E5C27"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which a Tribal cultural area is designated for inclusion in the System, the Secretary concerned, in consultation with the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, shall identify 1 or more interested Indian Tribes with an interest in the management of the Tribal cultural area.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB45D802F19E4472CB77B72763C4EAF3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interested Indian Tribes</header><text>An interested Indian Tribe may petition the Secretary concerned to be identified as having an interest in the management of a Tribal cultural area under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HA5FC8D7E3D054C048299250B400B53C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header> <paragraph id="H2FAC1810AEDF4ADD822709C83D4789FF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall consult with the applicable Tribal commission not less frequently than twice each year, unless otherwise mutually agreed, concerning the protection, preservation, and management of the applicable Tribal cultural area, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2F6C3BE0BFED438D9A0839873DDE33A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any proposed new uses within the Tribal cultural area; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4DB1EA21BA7A4545A6EB3D7E68BEC63A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any necessary management actions within the Tribal cultural area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AD0C30C6B4546C1BB13191309950081"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribal management proposals</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall consider any proposals for management actions within a Tribal cultural area submitted by the applicable Tribal commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H892D25CAA2FA46AC97E5AF80B96CABC9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>If the Secretary concerned determines that a proposed management action submitted to the Secretary concerned under paragraph (2) is impracticable, infeasible, or not in the public interest, the Secretary concerned shall consult with the applicable Tribal commission to determine specific measures to modify, or otherwise address, the proposed management action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF058D9391D81427BA0407542EE6F9132" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Written explanation</header><text>If, after consultation under paragraph (3), the Secretary concerned determines not to implement a proposed management action submitted to the Secretary concerned under paragraph (2), not later than 90 days after making such a determination, the Secretary concerned shall provide to the applicable Tribal commission a written explanation of the reason for the determination. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HDABD91240EE34B16A65DEDB2D5DBD340"><enum>10.</enum><header>Effect</header> <subsection id="H87FE31E6F8F0449A8CD20270B0455EEC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Environmental requirements</header> <paragraph id="HBCA440E3BB6E4BFF85442CED8B763A45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of Federal environmental law</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>Federal environmental law</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H242D4E5A26B047D597A3B15544C24657"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1251">33 U.S.C. 1251 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACDF5AF84AED4C489878FE7E129FCD56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C4E9FEE319D4B2492F61B14C93F1018" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other applicable Federal environmental law (including regulations). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C3CC6857B2E487190E01E621CDF2B34"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this Act alters or abridges the application of any Federal environmental law.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF37070387FC246DDA2BB122766AF5414"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Environmental analyses</header><text>Nothing in this Act authorizes the Secretary concerned, an Indian Tribe, or a Tribal organization to waive completion of any necessary environmental analysis under applicable Federal environmental law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H56A1B8CE03AD46B9B162A1F864163D4C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Retention of nepa responsibilities</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall make any decision required to be made under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) or other applicable Federal environmental law with respect to any activity to be carried out on public land under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H09043087A60C4EC3A5F3D4A662C0027D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability of the administrative procedure act</header><text>Nothing in this Act alters or abridges the application of subchapter II of chapter 5, or chapter 7, of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>), to this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H64F4AE616CF34931A95E66551D6FABD9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Fish and wildlife</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7AFCD00DA844788BE57EB553FE7623F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>alters or abridges the application of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF497C133D3004C71B0A14070E24B0E47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>affects—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0D7D84673A3E4463ACCBA8615269F9DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the jurisdiction or responsibilities of a State with respect to fish or wildlife; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C56E1B12BCC4FF89AC12AA61FF8417A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the jurisdiction of any Indian Tribe with respect to fish or wildlife.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H92675D03E0094827B572850AAE379E9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Public access</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this Act, nothing in this Act affects public access to land within a Tribal cultural area or a recommended Tribal cultural area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9D3A61CCD47744A0AEB01433D50AB9E2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Water rights</header> <paragraph id="H3342ED9D972145E993BDE1CE3DE1E766"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H368977BD52E8461FA5DCB59C74469827"><enum>(A)</enum><text>constitutes an express or implied reservation by the United States of water or water rights for any purpose; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C5D903D4EF440A5A42CB640D98C98F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>modifies or otherwise affects any water rights existing on the date of enactment of this Act, including any water rights held by the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H83A9864D627B49E094CB5881E253E596"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State water law</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall follow the procedural and substantive requirements of the applicable State and Federal law to obtain and hold any water rights not in existence on the date of enactment of this Act with respect to any Tribal cultural area.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8A4A105D642041D29217484F1733467D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Special management areas</header> <paragraph id="HFF33296741A04E5891B546A15C7497BF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition of public land</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>public land</term> includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDCD35D03F71440B799BF5A4EACE0CD21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a unit of the National Park System;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CBD4CA9C1B6487EB7AA02115CB1F896"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a unit of the National Wildlife Refuge System; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H87DF26BC78D243FD94BDCF5391A1A40E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a component of the National Wilderness Preservation System;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H266DD0DFBA2C45829CB91D386D9AE6FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a designated wilderness study area or other area managed for wilderness characteristics;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB85D39DDC1784B56B9E48946B6BC21EE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a National Conservation Area; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80F469E753D740D596C049D1F631B165"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a National Monument;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3571A77D73034E099CF25C7453BA7460"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a National Volcanic Monument;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2FCDB8102F4740F2B413FF1C5AC1BFB3"><enum>(H)</enum><text>a National Recreation Area;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H36D92BD8E34343D2AC065BDB6654CFE8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a National Scenic Area;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB19F85C847A0419D922D37D10FA90F35"><enum>(J)</enum><text>an inventoried roadless area within the National Forest System;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B786048D68944C3AF1C188B6A5A3651"><enum>(K)</enum><text>a component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1FA7D2D87C164FF3B790138EDDA33EE4"><enum>(L)</enum><text>any other area identified as National Conservation Lands.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC311E84540F7448DB3931108136E9E5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>The designation of a Tribal cultural area for inclusion in the System shall not diminish the protections granted to, or the management status of, any public land or any portion of public land.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4455B5F2067D4B5694751A962B567838"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conflict of laws</header><text>If there is a conflict between the laws (including regulations) applicable to an area described in paragraph (1) and this Act, the more restrictive provision shall control.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB6950505E5234136BBCE4C05D394C017"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Nondisclosure</header> 
<paragraph id="H7FB6BF49515F4C32B67D8E05B8860655"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary concerned shall not disclose to the public information regarding the nature or location of any sacred site if the Secretary concerned determines, in consultation with any interested Indian Tribe, that such a disclosure may—</text> <subparagraph id="H62186CDB54244BC1AF37A6074B612EF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>risk harm to the cultural resources of the sacred site;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE943810A34A64404B8E926982928513D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cause a significant invasion of privacy; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H882171BA5B8D4C4EB7BFB3C05723F7BB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>impede the use of the sacred site for traditional cultural activities by an Indian Tribe or members of an Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14035B25874246F7BAC38DE5B34C16E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Freedom of Information Act applicability</header> 
<subparagraph id="H69B01ECBC8D24F37A50EFC93A7CBAD30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Information described in paragraph (1) shall be exempt from disclosure under section 552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H578276F313D4496A88BF99F7B1EBD5D6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), this subsection shall be considered a statute described in section 552(b)(3)(B) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

