<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H359A40B2155C4629B951DD61777143C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7553 IH: Warrant for Metadata Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7553</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220421">April 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to require a warrant for the disclosure of records from a provider of electronic communication service or remote computing service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAADBF1E1817D4BBC9064A92CC8A67C8B" style="OLC">
<section id="H9E3CDAB91CD64BA1BF46A0E5A39F0F23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Warrant for Metadata Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0EE43908157A4800AA20CA1BE322611A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Warrant requirement for electronic communication service and remote computing service records</header> <subsection id="HAF6FFF4C3E20411CA5BC5AD38962E53B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Warrant requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2703 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF41E0C8978EF4AC984317BB11128D8AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7DB47ED26D444808A9EA6F389D2C47A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for one hundred and eighty days or less,</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1DB4DEB46F4D472EAB4E90D44A650754"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A governmental entity may require the disclosure by a provider of electronic communications services of the contents of a wire or electronic communication that has been in electronic storage in an electronic communications system for more than one hundred and eighty days by the means available under subsection (b) of this section.</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16320AD3E3C944ECBE45A3088EECE835"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA06AC01A82684FFF82ABAD15F6E31939"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>other information</quote> and all that follows, and inserting <quote>other information, including the metadata (as that term is defined in section 3502 of title 44) of such record or other information, pertaining to a subscriber to or customer of such service (not including the contents of communications) only when the governmental entity obtains a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure (or, in the case of a State court, issued using State warrant procedures and, in the case of a court-martial or other proceeding under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/47">chapter 47</external-xref> of title 10 (the Uniform Code of Military Justice), issued under section 846 of that title, in accordance with regulations prescribed by the President) by a court of competent jurisdiction.</quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF39325EA3A5A49D6AC13B17D577634A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB65881B4BCB8498487D3AB3E3406F68C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE75CB6FE97B44FE2B1FFDF57B2CF9844"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (d) by striking <quote>or (c)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD380A585C514494281337C10EBDCE3A3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Retroactive effect</header> 
<paragraph id="H2487C5E1DC1747929CB321417988636D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall have no effect on any disclosure required by a governmental entity pursuant to section 2703(c) of title 18, United States Code, before the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE63965C13636435BAE8AC39AA74CD390" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsequent disclosure; expanded disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a disclosure required by a governmental entity pursuant to section 2703(c) of title 18, United States Code, before the date of enactment of this Act, any request for a subsequent disclosure related to such disclosure or an expansion of such disclosure made after the date of enactment of this Act shall be treated as a new disclosure under such section (as amended by this Act).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

