<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9BC1C05A841B4B77B7B3E7CC9CFABF4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6956 IH: Service Starts At Home Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6956</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to carry out grant programs to encourage student participation in local government and volunteer service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF7E7D2E1B88544EABA8305EFBC274C08" style="OLC"><section id="H83FC78CD03424F5CAE0A8A78A9003677" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Service Starts At Home Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H165E0649C5EA49609CC6FF8AEB5DCE8C" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to support internships in local government</header><subsection id="H2E27E9F6C2E943C3876F7CC02114AA0D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allocations to States, in accordance with subsection (b), to support paid internships for secondary school students within local government agencies.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4FC84F5315F14A65A9B67E603B6D3C87"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allocations to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated to carry out this section for each fiscal year, each State that has an application approved by the Secretary under subsection (c) shall be allocated an amount in proportion to number of students enrolled in the public elementary and secondary schools in the State for the previous school year relative to the total number of students enrolled in the public elementary and secondary schools for such school year in every State that has an application approved by the Secretary under such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB83E3693284645ED8E9808240A2792E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive an allocation under subsection (b) a State shall submit an application to the Secretary of Education at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F3F5DE2D8924300A121DA28B3AEC8CB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Local government internship program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each State that receives an allocation under subsection (b) shall use such allocation to carry out a program under which the State—</text><paragraph id="HD0AE421AAC9049A784CFD5F44E51F4FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in consultation with local government officials—</text><subparagraph id="H2C129EFD06114764BE1CA80A65F8C528"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies appropriate paid internship opportunities for secondary school students within local government agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H659813EFB0DB407B9417A8D802E2F4C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishes a process for the selection of students to fill such internships; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82C6323E0CA741A79413DE47F663F719"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines hourly rates of pay and other terms and conditions applicable to such internships; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6541C6DE1781457EBEF41F982A8E9578"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provides funds to local government agencies to reimburse such agencies for costs incurred in providing such internships.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H51B1FAAC6C1B4AFEB57A62E8DE96CBBB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for fiscal year 2022 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H053115DDF27F43A9BCD78CC59E22DDFE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Scholarship for service program</header><subsection id="H14FEBE5180F546C682393F8FEC0804D4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Funding for States</header><paragraph id="H1E2918FD9C0342DD82EDA53DCF930841"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall carry out a program under which the Secretary makes allocations to States, in accordance with paragraph (2), to carry out the scholarship program under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE1445437464F408AF0D63D3D6D0246"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocations to States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the amount appropriated to carry out this section for each fiscal year, each State that has an application approved by the Secretary under paragraph (3) shall be allocated an amount in proportion to number of students enrolled in the public elementary and secondary schools in the State for the previous school year relative to the total number of students enrolled in the public elementary and secondary schools for such school year in every State that has an application approved by the Secretary under such paragraph<italic>.</italic></text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE82496C54F9D421382010607A8A668EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive an allocation under paragraph (2) a State shall submit an application to the Secretary of Education at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC4FEFDD2D56247C094793158EDC64915"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State administered scholarship program</header><paragraph id="H0FAA54977F184FA28B5132DE66496D2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State that receives an allocation under subsection (a) shall use such allocation to carry out a program under which the State awards scholarships, on a competitive basis, to eligible students who demonstrate a commitment to volunteer service work.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52AA5EA6A76541E3AA9F5730B16B1FE0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A student who seeks a scholarship under this subsection shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA60FE1213A7D4C608A4A712AFD496A7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Student eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a scholarship under this subsection a student shall meet the following criteria:</text><subparagraph id="HC5A4CCD2C02A45C4AF1AD21C4AFB3839"><enum>(A)</enum><header>First-time applicant</header><text>In the case of a first-time applicant for a scholarship under this subsection, the student shall—</text><clause id="HB0EB9521D0254D359D409627036E7DB9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be enrolled in public secondary school;</text></clause><clause id="HF84BF3ADE28942CFA3558DFD22F74441"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be in the final year of a program of study leading to a regular high school diploma; and</text></clause><clause id="H460625BB71E8422F98170AA669131DD6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have completed at least 100 hours of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary of Education).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFEE753498BF42B0B5018ECB24A2909F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Renewal applicant</header><text>In the case of a student who previously received a scholarship under this subsection and who is seeking a scholarship for a subsequent academic year, the student shall—</text><clause id="H34EA63CADB314B2182E7B8B0003961BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be enrolled in an institution of higher education;</text></clause><clause id="HBF5BB80DD5884C9CB7A04B2DB153680B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be in good academic standing (as determined by the institution); and</text></clause><clause id="HAD0D0F4BEB00451CA86D8E83222DB928"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have completed at least 100 hours of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary of Education).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8848926EC164AA68CE49938493DB72B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding scholarships under this subsection, a State shall—</text><subparagraph id="HFEC29F237D864E14B9B956F97D413146"><enum>(A)</enum><text>first award scholarships to renewal applicants described in paragraph (3)(B); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F17944E881D40BA87A30D59E0C2A15C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>from any funds remaining after awarding such scholarships, award scholarships to first-time applicants described in paragraph (3)(A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB75CDA0E94B24514AA0A17802B754D3B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A scholarship received by a student under this subsection may be used by such student only to pay the student’s costs of attendance at an institution of higher education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H329962C3167947D1B84D07B20855DA6A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each scholarship under this subsection shall be awarded for a period of one academic year. A student may receive a scholarship under this subsection for a total period of not more than four academic years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02C1D71B9102422E964A5849D8E8DF09"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of each scholarship under this subsection shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H614D6D4AF6D94350B450BE74E0056904"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$1000, for a student who completed at least 100 hours, but less than 175 hours, of volunteer service work in the preceding school year (or another one-year period determined by the Secretary of Education);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB064045682ED40D288D191E4761D61F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$2000, for a student who completed at least 175 hours, but less than 250 hours, of volunteer service work in such period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3EC16CC27744CFD8CE7F3C391D858A4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3000, for a student who completed at least 250 hours of volunteer service work in such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBE808B742DAA46D8BACE41759F79BE3A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $100,000,000 for fiscal year 2022 and each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H897DDE41E9C24C66B05CA600E82EC847"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HCDBA2312DB194636B254F3FCA3017C4F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>cost of attendance</term> has the meaning given that term in section 472 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087ll">20 U.S.C. 1087ll</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC2D5906271428992739650090F6D53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>regular high school diploma</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H288F4E402258488C847D4733CA19C528"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H043CDFD1309844D0BA13E67958B83A60"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H12B9D48395114E77A289038CD55EE348"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>volunteer service work</term> means unpaid acts of volunteer service conducted for or on behalf of a government or other nonprofit organization, which may include a community-based organization, faith-based organization, school, national service program, civic or fraternal service organization, local government agency, or other such organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2178F03101F453C988B3C011C96B3B2" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such term does not include acts of proselytizing, conducting worship services, religious instruction, political lobbying, court ordered service, or service conducted primarily for the benefit of the family of a student described in section 3(c).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

