<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFAB145A5735F451F9FF7E7EE343B1424" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8524 IH: Protect Sexual and Reproductive Health Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8524</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220727">July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Office of Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being within the Department of Health and Human Services, to generate a whole-of-government approach to protecting and affirming sexual and reproductive rights, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B7E38E7D6E5431AAF5EB69ABB78971D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H88227F1781F941EAA4701FD44E80A1AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Sexual and Reproductive Health Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H042617BD46714D8DB06EE28425492511"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sexual and reproductive health and well-being; reproductive justice and equity grant program</header> <subsection id="HD35C0FDB6DCF4E2EB5173611489C12E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after title XXXIII of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300mm">42 U.S.C. 300mm et seq.</external-xref>) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H5E7D008AA5C2444C875C93DC7470C127" style="OLC"> 
<title id="HD9D724D7921546CC9535A12FC8F0C3B9"><enum>XXXIV</enum><header>Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being</header></title> 
<section id="H4D9611469E19460ABFFEB4DC797184A5"><enum>3401.</enum><header>Office of Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being</header> 
<subsection id="H29A43CA2E80242F8B4F23713BE2A884D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Office of Population Affairs in the Department of Health and Human Services is hereby redesignated as the Office of Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>), to be headed by a Director of National Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being (in this section referred to as the <quote>Director</quote>). The Director shall be appointed by the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7F61055452684D7F8CAE25089A58E70B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Responsibilities</header><text>The Director shall have responsibility for overseeing activities that promote sexual and reproductive health and well-being, including—</text> 
<paragraph id="H515294C2AE0648BFA3563BC6629810A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>funding, conducting, and publicly disseminating the findings of, research on policies, programs, infrastructure, and other investments that serve to protect and increase access to services related to sexual and reproductive health and well-being;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7B45A2B42BE41CBBE9B161861EB27F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this title, developing a national strategy to promote sexual and reproductive health and well-being, to be known as the Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being Strategy (in this section referred to as the <quote>SRHW Strategy</quote>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C3182CC354043B49B9691CCFA8629F9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>coordinating implementation of the SRHW Strategy by—</text> <subparagraph id="H66C47502B50749DD98F47629A0D16FAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>coordinating among Federal departments and agencies, including the Interagency Task Force on Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being established under section 3402;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H534C4AE2721B44B195DBA80C1581B5DF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assessing Federal regulations and programs funded by the Federal Government with respect to sexual and reproductive health and well-being to ensure that such regulations and programs are consistent with the SRHW Strategy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93FDA00F2977466A8244BFDCAF1FED5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing to the public updates, findings, and recommendations on sexual and reproductive health services collected from the reports made by recipients of grants under section 3403;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H61D08A987D2C403DA199828645567C12"><enum>(D)</enum><text>leading activities to engage the public, including publicly available listening sessions with affected communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8CBB87DBF18E49F68B706DCCE502071B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>coordinating with other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, to develop guidelines and recommendations for health care providers to implement best practices for protecting sexual and reproductive health and well-being;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76232632C9064AC385E37B7A86A86CF8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>supporting and helping to coordinate interagency initiatives that advance, streamline, and otherwise implement research programs, services, and activities that protect and increase access to sexual and reproductive health and well-being;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3DEE24AF149F4E2FB6D7AC88217363D6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>administering grant programs that support State governments, local governments, and community-based organizations in protecting and increasing access to sexual and reproductive health and well-being research programs, services, and activities; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H32A6EEB33BB94120A33D3752AB658235"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consulting with the Attorney General and the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission to develop strategies to—</text> <clause id="HE4B0065F7F804D2BB68DF79FAEAA073B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>protect consumers’ privacy when seeking provision of, or information about, sexual and reproductive health care services; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD1F65775B15D48BBB8BCF837D46C0922"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>strengthen the protection of sensitive information related to sexual and reproductive health care services and bolster patient-provider confidentiality;</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB7E795822824227929278228128BB04"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carrying out community outreach programs to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8C6F41E363CC4B96BA3283FB4BA09545"><enum>(A)</enum><text>inform local communities about the Office; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD850796B28574AF9BBCC6773E1AA4AA3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>notify potential grants recipients of funding opportunities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H656A1C6DBC254F1CA4DEE0540D2EDC40"><enum>(5)</enum><text>submitting to Congress reports in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H310505C7A3EA48B8A95ED59C2679901D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>SRHW Strategy requirements</header> <paragraph id="HBB608279A81840A591B4C49F3E916E40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The SRHW Strategy shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5771E0FC8D044010933713C90EA44081"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify areas to develop and implement a sexual and reproductive health framework that moves beyond a biomedical model of health to include services with respect to health, well-being, economic stability, and freedom from discrimination;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA21F78A4D5FA40969C4F806A3EBA6034"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include recommendations—</text> 
<clause id="HA66E55A829F94CACA355CF95E9A34AA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to integrate sexual and reproductive health equity and reproductive justice into processes and policies used, and programs provided, by Federal agencies;</text></clause> <clause id="HCAE759C7F12941AA8C9F2FDAABD8741B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove Federal barriers to full reproductive autonomy; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H71D696216248467D910C3B3F3A414517"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to support patient-centered care models in hospitals, Federally qualified health centers, and entities eligible to receive funds under title X;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCED934CC1615495ABF11BA9BAB38B880"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the recommendations under subparagraph (B), include goals that are comprehensive, research-based, and long-range; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA6A9A8FB2593426C9E8D0E697937EE20"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include short-term measurable goals to promote sexual and reproductive health and well-being that may be realistically achieved.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9CA4F8E722F4CB4801E2E1ECDBE7936"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the SRHW Strategy, the Director shall consult with—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC4C296A2C8F942AA991E85D6F342A4B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">patients and communities;</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2A0A6F0B0294E4287E1E9880771B1D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>State and local governments; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H40431ADF2BCF403B8CC3A5B70E01FDB9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>nonprofit and nongovernmental entities and community-based organizations.</text></subparagraph> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6BFF90A08BF64C398D3438C631B45484"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this section, and on an annual basis thereafter, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and post on the website of the Office, a report containing—</text> 
<paragraph id="H119A2F7E48254902965B0B2A6BA0AAFE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a summary of the state of sexual and reproductive health and well-being in the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC79A9A3E2E0E453AA55B4F6F5EA61709"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the effectiveness of the SRHW Strategy, including a summary of plans for implementing Federal policy recommendations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9C5BBCC2D978495687B8F9736B3E717D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a detailed description of the actions taken by Federal agencies to implement the SRHW Strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6938881E001C40F2AD1758F4D7ADDAE3"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H8AA969CC0B144E438068A752765411A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Patient-centered care</header><text>The term <term>patient-centered care</term> refers to a health care philosophy where—</text> <subparagraph id="H8FB92316062042A885941ADC0661A6C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the health needs and desired health outcomes of a patient are the driving force behind all health care decisions and quality measurements; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C9EA2D8C6D547DE8DD74F123AA5B794"><enum>(B)</enum><text>patients are partners with health care providers and such providers consider, with respect to a patient, clinical, emotional, mental, spiritual, social, and financial perspectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCDC8D9112B247DD930D43334C0031EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reproductive health</header><text>The term <term>reproductive health</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4E9D95CB68ED4DDD9858F3433161E552"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a state of complete physical, mental, and social well-being; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H39897E2F630B4891B0608AE05A07A5E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes all matters relating to the reproductive system and the functions and processes of such system, and ensuring that an individual—</text> 
<clause id="H2655E28D13C04A3AAE6E44B3D20A081A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is able to have a satisfying and safe sex life; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2E28C07334F64637B59D40970277A87A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>possesses the capability to reproduce and the freedom to decide if, when, and how often to reproduce.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H08BA4C1EE2A7430CA79E4CF72079D97E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reproductive justice</header><text>The term <term>reproductive justice</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H00F87C69CF0B49299CAC768E097FD3C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the human right to maintain personal bodily autonomy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD6F69632FE814CCEA614B3F8AD182198"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ability to choose whether to have children; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA859F6047E9746FEAD0EF278CDBDAD18"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ability to parent children in safe and sustainable communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H052876C7EDF24751A2182F6F7C82950A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual and reproductive health and well-being</header><text>The term <term>sexual and reproductive health and well-being</term> includes having access to trauma-informed, culturally sensitive services and support to attain the highest level of sexual and reproductive health.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD428F3BBE9F4480BBBEA835598FDF3A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Sexual and reproductive health equity</header><text>The term <term>sexual and reproductive health equity</term> means a health policy framework that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HC99862B753DC440CB179E7964926558A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensures that individuals (including individuals across a range of age, gender, race, and other identities) have what is necessary to attain the highest level of sexual and reproductive health including having self-determination and the ability to achieve reproductive goals; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB0FDF83BE3064B86B7D7BA3605E1675B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes government policies that value and support individuals fairly and justly.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HDE0F27A4B6AE4BB289FC70259EF466FF"><enum>3402.</enum><header>Interagency Task Force on Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being</header> 
<subsection id="HCE2FA279A3344492A9365BDDE84A365F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary and the Director of the Gender Policy Council, acting jointly, shall establish and maintain an interagency task force to be known as the Interagency Task Force on Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>) to coordinate and promote Federal programs and activities related to sexual and reproductive health and well-being.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H75C4504B8AAF409EB197937D216192B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Task Force shall be composed of the following members (or their designees):</text> 
<paragraph id="H3D6D0D14135E4676BF5EBE53F772B032"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services, who shall serve as a Co-Chair of the Task Force.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCBAB3431AED148E1B833E1E0CA572189"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Director of the Gender Policy Council, who shall serve as a Co-Chair of the Task Force.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6F4B2102F4024436BFA62402856C8DF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Attorney General of the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E19BEA6B5484F8B8477953490222996"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62CCFF87895E41C5B5B30A653FFF02B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H89F4BB9CF6AC4069BBD244416C9CF1DC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEE9D12645C274852A5DDD5A5E9FB6FE0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD5B002378C44D63999B77E2CEF0F923"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA62C6832F484B789C1E3006AFFA3872"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DC1855D4B75457482B27C7010623068"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B04C86EBFA94CFAB7D99A6EC9D0C598"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Secretary of State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE4C98E55F37241A4A7B5C361A36CF605"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H93F0C0AEC2EA49BEBA82CC66E9A69DED"><enum>(13)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF8F93D32F8784DAC8BE3E8BD9FA31C0E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAF08B60D2007413887D0515966917168"><enum>(15)</enum><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD9FBD2F8BD04A3CB99A53FA4A25735C"><enum>(16)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H718FB5A9682748759EA6F800CDF957A7"><enum>(17)</enum><text>The Chair of the Federal Trade Commission.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9A4182EB17242B49A5093B2CA0ED8E2"><enum>(18)</enum><text>The heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as determined necessary by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and Director of the Gender Policy Council. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H73DD5F8FFCD34F238418383232AD4626"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Task Force shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4D966A6A018540F98B15E98F4EEBBADF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify and coordinate activities to protect and strengthen access to essential reproductive health care and support services, and promote sexual and reproductive health and well-being;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35C5B9E1527C4C24B0B27A3977B167B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate Federal interagency policymaking, program development, and outreach efforts—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1F6FF671F904A0DA69AE904DBE824F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address barriers that individuals and entities may face in seeking and providing reproductive health care services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F020F4A7C014161B10E23B5B298C9DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to promote and protect sexual and reproductive health and well-being;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8ECE864081C42C6A0B71301892374BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>on an annual basis, conduct a comprehensive equity-focused assessment of all Federal funds allocated for, and all Federal programs that support, sexual and reproductive health and well-being;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H286DD1322FC1461CB8B4614F3C985480"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitate ongoing efforts to provide and support a whole-of-government approach to protecting and promoting sexual and reproductive health and well-being; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H632F984DEF034509840B15C1F0861E22"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support implementation of the SRHW Strategy by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF0F85372A0FD46A2B8D0BB4093415DEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>developing agency-specific implementation and accountability plans; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H163FEA1A428B47C0B055123289DC7C62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tracking and reporting, on an annual basis, information related to the Task Force’s activities, assessments, and policy recommendations for protecting and improving sexual and reproductive health and well-being.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H75AB3F761B1B4DFEA3F58E5B9F3AEDB2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>For the purpose of carrying out this section, the Task Force may hold such meetings, and sit and act at such times and places, as the Task Force considers appropriate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0FD78B582CAF498E9494ADF13D93F53D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Task Force may secure directly from any Federal agency such information as may be necessary to enable the Task Force to carry out this section. Upon request of the Co-Chairs of the Task Force, the head of such agency shall furnish such information to the Task Force.</text></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HE67A6152F543444EBEF44B6C8BE9E5F2"><enum>3403.</enum><header>Reproductive justice and equity grant program</header> 
<subsection id="HF32071B49C2C4F0F8DD0FFF2E11AA274"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall award grants to eligible entities to pay for programs and services related to improving patient access to sexual and reproductive health care.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H070F072AF6A54A87BAA00CE55D8F9156"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall solicit applications for grants under this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD6922ED2F24D4D5E9C2B006980E37188"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header> 
<paragraph id="H7F00F0D94B474F37AFACA5A07D7FDFEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Permissible uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant to pay for programs and services related to improving patient access to sexual and reproductive health care, which may include any of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H9EDD66E9F67F4ED7AAEA288F1C337597"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mobile sexual and reproductive health care clinics.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0C08D3EFCF2B4B48BF41A83AF2074197"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Travel expenses.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB7945C1C2044C24BFDE9231F11AB38D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Lodging.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1DE7ABF988F4445A911449834BFA6D2B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Food assistance.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H716C53BB50EF453F946A797572E53D80"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Childcare.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD33CE9F9CECD4FE1A830D61D18FEA2C0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Translation services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCF7F5A059CA04A9796A0141E54B6A201"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Doula care.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC4E6C682EE2C4FEABC41B0BF8AA1E975"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Patient education and information services.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2045085432754661B9EFDF71AECB89B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Direct financial assistance.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE95A6CE35DF9494E85DF83F136254ED7"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Housing assistance.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4798645F96544629A00779A57334C6E6"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Legal aid.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDC7871B5755E4466B589DDCF2C55CC62"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Comprehensive sex education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H185D9EAE8D314060A2B9222EE2FF5BD3"><enum>(M)</enum><text>Medical costs.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4B02A9E60D124C149929A6C3BA099854"><enum>(N)</enum><text>Behavioral health counseling.</text> </subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H79EFFB198AC849FD856B43FAD456DD30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Impermissible uses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall not use the grant for costs with respect to the provision of an abortion service.</text> </paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF68370BA97674811AD87DC05CBEDEEED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting the recipients of grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that—</text> <paragraph id="HB95F8EF6255340CCA6AE6B9251668B8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve people who live in a jurisdiction that has banned or severely restricted access to abortion;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC89EB993EDAE4180BD70CBC5176ACB94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve people who travel to a jurisdiction other than the one where they live to be provided abortion services; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B35D92920CA449DACCEFB74294230E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>have a program in operation, or submit as part of the application required under subsection (d) a plan to establish and operate a program, to help patients access abortion services.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H923452E172E84F17881E8DDB9FAB8967"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H88F8678CA6304E70A7717B4D7921EFBE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term>—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5DA47787DC7848F5B141C7D712332D9C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">means a nonprofit organization, or a community-based organization, that assists individuals seeking an abortion through programs, services, or activities that are unbiased and medically and factually accurate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD823909EFC754DFABB609CB266FE0DBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>excludes any entity that discourages individuals from seeking an abortion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23872CFC1C904490B55A5856A06D28D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization that—</text> <subparagraph id="H65CAEF55764B4CADA768ED6F0E3118CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is described in subsection (c)(3) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3775204EF1AC4908B6CAC63E5A2DF9C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is, under subsection (a) of such section, exempt from taxation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HA5D0FA91C5FB40A08A5CFB90F01DA5C9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text> </subsection></section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3BDAFC9797A34EC58DC814B7271EDA58"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming changes; references</header> 
<paragraph id="HA99FC7B0F0BA4E06B5696908FC160DC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sections 3 and 4 of the Family Planning Services and Population Research Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3505a">42 U.S.C. 3505a</external-xref>, 3505b) are hereby repealed.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DE94D932C9C4891A0B456E649FD4717"><enum>(2)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference to the Office of Population Affairs of the Department of Health and Human Services or the Deputy Assistant Secretary of Population Affairs in any law, rule, regulation, certificate, directive, instruction, or other official paper in force on the effective date of this Act shall be deemed to refer and apply to the Office of National Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being or the Director of National Sexual and Reproductive Health and Well-Being, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

