<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H499CB0F0603A4C78A9CC47409D7D342A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9671 IH: Stateless Protection Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9671</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221222">December 22, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To protect stateless persons in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HA2FF8B20A97A4801AFD367E14671EB48" style="OLC">
<section id="HBFD624C7AC0F4CC3B1EE5241E1657C95" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stateless Protection Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCF7DB4489A3745C88FA88F39B8B080A6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text>
<paragraph id="H70C69ABF1E0741DFAACBA47EAEC38006"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to resolve the status of stateless persons in the United States and to promote their access to fundamental human rights and human dignity; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD3B32FDC5614EAEB4A4BF94B5E6E702"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to prevent statelessness from occurring under United States law or on United States territory.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H0A7A14BFF1CD4A2896CCAC3EAADBE7D7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header>
<subsection id="H5C9A3297630E44FDBE6CB97966E50534"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HAC7BA08B78A84E0CAAC64BE2EFA1E61E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The international community has recognized the significance of the right to a nationality in the International Covenant on Civil and Political Rights, done at New York December 16, 1966, to which the United States is a signatory, as well as the Universal Declaration of Human Rights and numerous international treaties, including the Convention Relating to the Status of Stateless Persons, done at New York September 28, 1954, and the Convention on the Reduction of Statelessness, done at New York August 30, 1961.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H60EC6FBA5EC540A0B45AD44649C5B3F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Statelessness is an abhorrent violation of fundamental human rights and human dignity, and a life of statelessness has been recognized by the Supreme Court of the United States as a form of punishment more primitive than torture.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F85CDD704554EF39BECC5D5B1DB5FEC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Government action and inaction causes statelessness; therefore, governments have the power to resolve and prevent statelessness.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H785C2F33E2274FFCBB1D41E5D56FC53E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees—</text> <subparagraph id="H6A19F128503D4E4EAD9C776263A7DEFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is the United Nations agency responsible for preventing and reducing statelessness; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H64E70730413B4CA7A076FBAA556361FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>estimates that there are more than 4,200,000 stateless persons worldwide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H69B63A1DD54B4C8CBAD8D483A4F5B177"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A 2020 study found that there are approximately 218,000 individuals living in the United States who are stateless or at risk of statelessness.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H71E70C6D0FB74AE6BD43EA285F2B4141"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Stateless individuals live in all 50 States, and many such individuals have lived in the United States for years or decades without relief.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3A4705A2872417791D15C680A3A748E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Despite the presence of stateless persons in the United States, there is no law relating to the identification of stateless persons in the United States or to provide them with a path to legal status.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3EC7B44B026246B9946FAB6C4E7A190C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Stateless persons generally—</text> <subparagraph id="H227D324E44FB4021824523F75D8FE5E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>live without the means to work legally or to travel; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4018162877604FD4B02FA1F1778F9548"><enum>(B)</enum><text>face barriers in opening bank accounts, pursuing higher education, and obtaining health care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2FA08E46D11F4B2095ACE827AA5522A3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>If detained for removal from the United States, a stateless person is often subjected to prolonged detention and cannot be removed because no country recognizes the person as its citizen.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA4BBE98A4AD748C6934A1F4347ABA5B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that to resolve statelessness and its related human suffering, lost potential, and societal impacts, the United States should—</text> <paragraph id="HFD49AE51C23E4CACAA763B3187EE81DC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide a legal status to protect stateless persons; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H98291673E2184AC98A149F315860D6EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urge the international community to take strong action to prevent statelessness globally.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H937821A2CDB54F66A3D0897C2B980F56"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of stateless persons in the United States</header> <subsection id="HEA082997267D48E3ADAA5F7DB9E73EB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Chapter 5 of title II of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 245A the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F2D2AB3930C4A9B8BFFF9B6881B8518">
<section id="HAD143E94E10D46DEB9DA80B62A09703A"><enum>245B.</enum><header>Protection of stateless persons in the United States</header>
<subsection id="H6338F33B7A5647D497D3C54A01199335"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H68745C24BA714077A35ACAED6001AC46"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Competent authority</header><text>With respect to a foreign country, the term <term>competent authority</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="H1D4A9B30464840CDB258D42477CF5FFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the authority responsible for—</text> <clause id="HF99E290D4C9C43C49A6963EAF87B9375"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conferring nationality on, or withdrawing nationality from, individuals; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HB89746A173834E77898FA655ED5E350F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of nationality having been acquired or withdrawn automatically, clarifying the nationality status of an individual; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H48FB7681641C4D48A560DE28853A5BE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a Federal, local, or regional government entity, a consular official, and a government official at any level, notwithstanding any process by which a decision by such an entity or official may later be overridden.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7EE7B8AD1D6746ABA02A350D59DBCAF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>National; nationality</header><text>The terms <term>national</term> and <term>nationality</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HA65D054935844656ABFF568C6FBCAE34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>refer to a formal link, of a political and legal character, between an individual and a country; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0DA5D58CA226442BA551DB3A4422DF1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>do not include the concept of nationality relating to membership in a religious, linguistic, or ethnic group.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74FC9A56CBDA40AB9767D2B4E7F6AA3A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Noncitizen</header><text>The term <term>noncitizen</term> has the meaning given the term <term>alien</term> in section 101(a).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31225585F1B94E959D49753E633BAA1C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Operation of law; operation of its law</header><text>The terms <term>operation of law</term> and <term>operation of its law</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HB981C09C659140439504A96FA67A0BCA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>refer to the consideration by a competent authority of a country with respect to an individual in practice, including under the legislation, ministerial decrees, regulations, orders, judicial case law, and customary practices of the competent authority; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H11972452462648C1ABB45526818B4AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include situations in which the position of the competent authority differs from the law as written, if the position of the competent authority that an individual is not a national of the country is determinative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC571BFDCAB8E49BBB0EFE94999708E41"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant association</header><text>The term <term>relevant association</term> means a natural person’s connection to a country through—</text>
<subparagraph id="H82A5CB52A7A84459A8C7FDD2D8AC0EEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>birth on the territory of the country;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C8C1BC3E0DE4C619E6BCCCE1A2AAEF2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>descent from 1 or more individuals who are nationals of the country;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51ED9654A88D413BA9033B36D3B99929"><enum>(C)</enum><text>marriage to an individual who is a national of the country;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H56C1D2FDEFB84370B5E984F68A8B2A03"><enum>(D)</enum><text>adoption by an individual who is a national of the country; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58ED680EDA2941E69BBC965BEC585861"><enum>(E)</enum><text>habitual residence in the country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7329AC37FAB24B9692F29DB6F53527F7"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Stateless person</header><text>The term <term>stateless person</term> means an individual who is not considered as a national by any state under the operation of its law.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H09CD93394D57480A8F54241046515BD1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mechanisms for regularizing the status of stateless persons</header>
<paragraph id="HE4E6AA8630A84C828D0DF0242ED56D79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stateless protected status</header>
<subparagraph id="H81A74CE206CE4F5E881913C122A65FAF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Principal applicants</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide stateless protected status to a noncitizen who—</text> <clause id="HDEF6B59CFA7C4DB896BA7714B4EBBD5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is a stateless person present in the United States;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF24914114E7240BF9B306D3A7A707376"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>applies for such relief;</text></clause> <clause id="HE9F62632BBC3467E89761BE12A76BB6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>has not formally renounced his or her nationality as a result of voluntary, affirmative, and intentional action after arrival in the United States and after the date of the enactment of this section, unless the renunciation was the result of duress, coercion, or a reasonable expectation that the noncitizen had acquired or would acquire another nationality or citizenship; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3FE2F6D67E0D409E9BA5214D3566F7AB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is not inadmissible under 212(a)(3), except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H58C82F4267DB4EA3BBDDD7CC99FCD4D1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is not described in section 241(b)(3)(B)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7BC811AD9CFC4CCB955FEAE13A0A76D3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of spouse and children</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide stateless protected status to a noncitizen who—</text> <clause id="H97EAB8B8D4D54DBC8021D38CEB9090A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is the spouse or child of a noncitizen described in subparagraph (A), if such spouse or child is not otherwise eligible for admission under that subparagraph;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC55C4F6F280443848941E1CAD563F4ED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is accompanying, or following to join, such noncitizen;</text></clause> <clause id="H717FF9F8705E4D529736FE6791A38F2A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>established the qualifying relationship to such noncitizen before the date on which such noncitizen applied for stateless protected status;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA7203AE8A6344E4180E6B8582C9C38DE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is not inadmissible under 212(a)(3), except as provided in paragraph (2) of this subsection; and</text></clause> <clause id="H62F2B68F249248399A4006FC289A1B50"><enum>(v)</enum><text>is not described in section 241(b)(3)(B)(i).</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB1BD17D97A324EDCBD76ED6969A32EA5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Stateless protected status</header><text>Noncitizens with stateless protected status—</text> <clause id="H63E458D63F42462EB7AF8A2A117CCEA9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall—</text>
<subclause id="H541577E731974ADB884AACF1D1D809C9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>receive relevant protections against deportation, removal, and detention, as described in paragraph (3);</text></subclause> <subclause id="HBBAA31DD2EC84262A5710393F2B5B4EE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>be authorized for employment, as described in paragraph (4); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H35E6D4954B3F4173955CD4C17DCDE16A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>be eligible to apply for a travel document, as described in paragraph (5); and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H051058A0E4814C299D5AFF69A8C0572E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall not face limitations from immigration enforcement officials on their domestic travel.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF86FBDC2CFB7439FA7459E637FD70439"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Concurrent grant of lawful permanent residence</header>
<clause id="H1E6054FAA6AF448EAC742C472DB40A00"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), notwithstanding any other provision of law, immediately on granting stateless protected status to a noncitizen, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall adjust the status of the noncitizen to that of a noncitizen lawfully admitted for permanent residence. </text></clause> <clause id="HB1D5952BA4594ECB84782C716BD8841A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not adjust the status of a noncitizen with stateless protected status who is inadmissible under section 212(a)(2). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDCD890579C443F5B6BA5BF8FFB1D34A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waivers</header>
<subparagraph id="HA4E1BCC6B2E940579D19A946A259DBD2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security may, for humanitarian purposes, in the interests of access to fundamental or enabling rights, to ensure family unity, or when it is otherwise in the public interest, waive the operation of the grounds of inadmissibility set forth in paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 212(a), for relief under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E09D31769554BAEACCE5526A6CCA636"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider all relevant factors, including—</text>
<clause id="H72C01D613B0A47239C80D84AC6408235"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mitigating and aggravating factors of the basis for inadmissibility;</text></clause> <clause id="H75FEAA4AC7F9485498F77CE3E592DD0A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the duration of the noncitizen’s residence in the United States; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HDF0005ECD64A4075AED872CF3FF2CE1C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the degree to which the noncitizen’s removal, or denial of the noncitizen’s application, would adversely affect the noncitizen or the noncitizen’s United States citizen or lawful permanent resident family members. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDC8FB94346B44801882527EC9B22BBDA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Release from post-removal detention</header><text>A grant of stateless protected status under this section shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD67983F74FD644E1A6DC0D38C268FA3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>trigger immediate release of an individual from post-removal detention;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8493048E2CA440E9A8070AE57F6912B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be considered to establish that there is no significant likelihood of the individual's removal in the reasonably foreseeable future; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H48F86F9D6A4142DC909CAC5AA671EDEA" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish a presumption that travel documents are not available for the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE9C801E558BF41D7BCB172F734301189"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employment authorization</header> <subparagraph id="H455FE161CA8F412AB35634208D38C1C2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An individual granted stateless protected status under this section shall receive employment authorization for a renewable period not less than 5 years.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2BB904C0143E4A82AB5E14EACA1AC4E3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Pending application</header>
<clause id="HF491D87587C847FE8EC00979772AFBF1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the 150-day period after the date on which an application for status under this section is submitted, the Secretary of Homeland Security may authorize the applicant to engage in employment in the United States.</text></clause> <clause id="H54E8DE997D144B2CB3713209672220BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Mandatory employment authorization</header><text>If the Secretary of Homeland Security has not issued a decision within the 150-day period beginning on the date on which an application for status under this section is submitted, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall authorize the applicant to engage in employment in the United States until the date on which a decision is issued on the application for lawful permanent residence or stateless protected status.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6F95EAD1DF554142A966F00260C69958"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Travel documents</header>
<subparagraph id="H833883724DD54A8498F5C9B06D2E589B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On request, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to any noncitizen granted relief under this section, a travel document that facilitates the noncitizen’s ability to travel abroad and to be admitted to the United States upon return. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2B339229FF349A8A734688C95C81AFA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Validity</header><text>The minimum period of validity for a document issued under subparagraph (A) shall be 10 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H769FDA9577ED49AD9925D814D305D818"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Naturalization</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual granted lawful permanent residence status under paragraph (1)(D) may apply for naturalization after having resided continuously in the United States for at least 3 years beginning on the date on which such individual is granted lawful permanent resident status.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7E8B6E8297B6402C94105FC0FCE171AC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evidentiary matters</header> <paragraph id="H01032E7D468E431CA310676BE39AAEDA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining if an individual is a stateless person under this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider and obtain any credible evidence relevant to the application, including information from—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H652ABBCB1D3D45F98EC671C5C9E728A1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of State, particularly the Bureau of Population, Refugees, and Migration and the Bureau of Democracy, Human Rights, and Labor; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HA6FE9532D84C4F219E48C7FAC63D8BC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>relevant international and foreign bodies, such as the United Nations High Commissioner for Refugees, nongovernmental organizations, and the competent authorities of other countries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H41FE8B1ED90B4C88A05FEF6C5B7A1444"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of specific groups of stateless persons</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may designate 1 or more specific groups of individuals who shall be considered stateless persons for purposes of this section, and a noncitizen who belongs to a group so designated shall be considered a stateless person.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2750296EB0454399BDCC3094FAEB4487"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Burden of proof</header><text>The burden of proof with respect to evidentiary matters relating to an application under this section shall be shared between the Secretary of Homeland Security and the applicant.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6A3BDAF529994B36B6907F631ABFE6EF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Standard of proof</header>
<subparagraph id="H1BEF23CF95A74A56B30B42C651C3DF9A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A noncitizen shall be considered to be a stateless person if it is established to a reasonable degree that the noncitizen meets the definition of the term <quote>stateless person</quote> under this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B858BF19F39469882C448873F45CCBF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment of nationality</header><text>The nationality of an individual shall be assessed as of the date on which a determination of eligibility under this section is made.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H538D0B7120274338B68D783A14112FAA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Submission of documentary evidence</header>
<subparagraph id="H59DF01F80AB2409D916B5F370515F496"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Supporting documents from applicant</header><text>An applicant for relief under this section shall submit, as part of the application for such relief—</text> <clause id="H536ED56B479845F2BDBBF789E6808EA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a full and truthful account, to the best of the noncitizen’s knowledge, of such noncitizen’s legal status with regard to any country in which the applicant was born or resided before entering the United States or to which the applicant has a relevant association; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H474E6D8F62244F39B4A336755863D4A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all evidence reasonably available, including any valid or expired travel document.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC043CBD8F4174A229D7C51CDC1F71664"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Evidence available to secretary of homeland security</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall obtain and submit to the immigration officer or immigration judge and the applicant or, as applicable, the applicant’s counsel, all available evidence regarding the legal status of the applicant in the applicant’s country of birth or prior residence or any country to which the applicant has a relevant association, including information on the relevant laws and practices of the countries concerned.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF3B2490B34BD46EEABDDBD53771F9E8B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration of response</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may consider as substantial evidence that an individual is not considered by a country to be a national of the country the following:</text> <clause id="H5C86CC8E7CAF4D2998D44F44C4B34539"><enum>(i)</enum><text>After 120 days have elapsed after the Secretary of Homeland Security has requested information from the country with respect to the nationality status of the individual, the lack of response from the competent authority of the country.</text></clause>
<clause id="H7AF8404ADEFE4D09844208F01D94492F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A pro forma response from the country that lacks an application of the law or facts to the particular individual.</text></clause> <clause id="HD48302D66B654C4B8FA4019BDED4DE4B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The refusal of the country to accept the individual for deportation or removal.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H1C484A5C760F4B878B5F636148F3000C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fees</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not charge a noncitizen any fee in connection with an application for, or issuance of, lawful status under this section, employment authorization, or travel documents.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCD1BA3D0FDCC456C86222383225F8189"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Jurisdiction and review</header> <paragraph id="HAD6C5BB3E68345C6898A5A852EF440A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services shall have jurisdiction over an application for stateless protected status and adjustment of status filed by a noncitizen under this section. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H80B919ECC057451B874B253CF3B977ED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>A denial by the Secretary of Homeland Security of an application for relief under this section shall be subject to review by the Administrative Appeals Office of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1152D556E95E4AACB60970CC1C4C9A4B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect on removal proceedings</header><text>With respect to a noncitizen in removal proceedings who files an application for relief under this section, the Attorney General shall postpone the removal proceedings pending the adjudication of the application.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HED4F6AAA7FD24566800E51AC5C41CE47"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Applicants with final orders of removal</header>
<paragraph id="HC24EDD481CBE454688D9FD2A0FBF355A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Motions to reopen</header>
<subparagraph id="HCD96DF128C9A4F208793A8FA1AFD3F1E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A noncitizen whose removal, deportation, or exclusion proceedings were concluded before the date of the enactment of this section, and who is eligible for relief under this section, may file 1 motion to reopen proceedings to apply for such relief not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A0E0AD330624E5CB81E39DA023A19CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of limitations</header><text>A time or numerical limitation on motions to reopen removal, deportation, or exclusion proceedings may not be construed to restrict the filing of a motion to reopen under this paragraph if such limitation is based on previously unavailable evidence or facts, or on changed facts or circumstances, including a discovery by a noncitizen that the noncitizen may be a stateless person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFD3BE4D827924A2A9CAF7A342BA5DAC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Stay of removal</header>
<subparagraph id="HDBDB834E697C4724A44D337F3483277D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An applicant for relief under this section who has been issued a final order of removal, deportation, or exclusion may request a stay of removal, deportation, or exclusion. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC665973402594073817382198805271F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration of request</header><text>With respect to an individual who requests a stay under subparagraph (A), if the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the application for relief is bona fide, the Secretary shall automatically stay the execution of the final order of deportation, exclusion, or removal, and the stay will remain in effect until a final decision is made on the applications. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFD903AD5755044A891E7787C794BE018"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of denial</header><text>If the application is denied, the stay of the final order is deemed lifted as of the date of such denial, without regard to whether the noncitizen appeals the decision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4248E1327E3340E5A71281FD262C6757"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>On the grant of an application for relief under this section to a noncitizen with a final order of removal, deportation, or exclusion, the final order shall be deemed canceled by operation of law as of the date of the approval.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB6EC1ADB6B674A7FB66CA8F5FCA47C8D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exclusion from numerical limitations</header><text>Individuals provided status under this section shall not be counted against any numerical limitation under section 201(d), 202(a), or 203(b)(4).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0DAE5F0158D94DC7A0D185692C0EEAF4"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to authorize or require the admission of any noncitizen to the United States.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H4C77FEA8B81E40FDB04EBDB55DC8D280"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="HB88BEE5F65EA4AA1B642C0C66399FE20"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this section, and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report on—</text> <subparagraph id="H09775EF391594FD9B299CFA72831E292"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of applications submitted under each of paragraphs (1), (4), and (5) of subsection (b) since the date of the enactment of this section, disaggregated by the country of birth of the applicants; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB7219DA43AD74E6AAE239C0F51A6BCC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>average timelines for processing each such application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD951ABF8F3804BEF9D9BC1CBA4524517"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish each report submitted under paragraph (1) on the internet website of the Department of Homeland Security, respectively.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H28CAD1DC5CE7470F900685E28A993CFA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Publication of guidance</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall publish all policy manuals, guidance, and application instructions relating to applications under this section on the internet website of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H654452EDC9F64744B103656C3FCF0E8D"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may issue such regulations as the Secretary of Homeland Security considers appropriate to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H01C17DE53B564EFBB242D1C232479AEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header>
<paragraph id="H70AE66D63D424F71B1F44FFB76E59DF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 245A the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDCE5B2D762D04890823E4BD4AA2F90AC"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">Sec. 245B. Protection of stateless persons in the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A8BA14575554D4CA8729586645B2199"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for unlawful presence of stateless persons</header><text>Section 212(a)(9)(B)(iii) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(B)(iii)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE7D88FADA782480F998D631746E7193E">
<subclause id="H84499E2440E045FD8917FFDD54639B6A"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Stateless persons</header><text>Clause (i) shall not apply to a noncitizen who demonstrates that he or she is a stateless person (as defined in section 245B(a)).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H3031F5EF15294A52BD354D848053C09E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prevention of statelessness</header> <subsection id="H2DFB85C7601C49979FB4843E235EE266"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Births to united states citizens overseas</header><text>Section 301 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HBD0EA6A6C31C496F8796446BBE9277CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD3D370A4D1145EF8AD2B4EE7117E1BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (h), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC2E1F6D6B22D4C568668D38E86CFFA91"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF90035AAC67B4B6886588B4CB71AC833"> <subsection id="H2B9F65330F1D46EEB20CDA7E3735BF72" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a person born to a citizen of the United States outside the United States or in an outlying possession of the United States, if such person is born as a stateless person (as defined in section 245B(a)).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H91F7D12A8A9C43C1A7889E6026773457"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Foundlings</header><text>Section 301 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1401">8 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>) is further amended by striking subsection (f) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6CAAA491A8BC44BBA09E45B3FFA9CAA4"> <subsection id="HF48255248D014715B40A4FD0CE2EBD53" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><text>a person of unknown parentage found in the United States while under the age of 18 years, until shown, prior to the person attaining the age of 21 years, not to have been born in the United States;</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="HF31B3C2EF1E64FB2B6EE0303955007F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Stateless safeguards for derivative citizenship and international adoptions</header>
<paragraph id="H1341F5A50D5D4A31AE3E63608558BAE4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Stateless safeguards</header><text>Section 320 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1431">8 U.S.C. 1431</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H539DF48ACB4F4E09BE72EEB0E54D195B"> <subsection id="HA958E4994D6B4D548621DA83835650E5"><enum>(e)</enum> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE4F23DB71A5A49E7961DA15F3B45590A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, a person born outside the United States or in an outlying possession who is or becomes a stateless person (as defined in section 245B(a)) automatically becomes a citizen of the United States on the date on which one of the following conditions has been fulfilled:</text>
<subparagraph id="HB74BF222748B45CFBDF262967B1CB6BE" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One parent is or was a citizen of the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E3D3C7C51FA415FAB2B2FD01284F1CE" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The person was adopted by—</text>
<clause id="H6399D88F54E24239BC8E533071373FC7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a citizen of the United States; or</text></clause> <clause id="HBC3E545A26CB41119805E37C240F995B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an individual who became a citizen of the United States after the date of such adoption.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H689C98C5CAB44C60A467F1A6306B770C" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>This subsection applies to any person who meets the criteria under paragraph (1) at any time.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6024B3F915CB47CCBE7F48D6BBA325AF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Age</header><text>Section 320(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1431">8 U.S.C. 1431(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H64D34993EA7549C79E838BB3415069AC">
<paragraph id="H523DB9EFDC5F46FA90D57D140156E952"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The child is under the age of 21 years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF84B68C4FCE468395BA500A07862DB0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Entry and custody</header><text>Section 320(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1431">8 U.S.C. 1431(a)</external-xref>) is further amended by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H207C34E8DB9740EBA8C3D853A1101B2D">
<paragraph id="H0DF76E9D65254D8BBCABB8A029A959F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The child is residing in the United States, and provided such child is under the legal age of adulthood in the State in which the parent of the child or the child resides, is in the legal and physical custody of the citizen parent.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H35E91D35BE5445A5B7D4FE9FBFD48B91"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Programs To prevent statelessness</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security and Secretary of State shall jointly establish and carry out initiatives to prevent statelessness from occurring, which may include—</text>
<paragraph id="H6D312F3BDF5442439E884D30D0A370F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of United States citizenship law to determine and amend any provision of law that results in statelessness or a delayed acquisition of nationality that increases the risk of statelessness;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49D7BBD3198F4E09930C3B911D8087F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>studies on the profiles and number of stateless people living in the United States;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H071FC93DFAA94E69AA0EC9C14AF1CD8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>programs to promote inclusive and nondiscriminatory nationality laws and practices in other countries, with particular attention to the prevention of atrocity crimes;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2286676E71884139B06C92CADF4A45C4"><enum>(4)</enum><text>programs to encourage other countries to establish stateless status determination and protection legislation; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H476114A4CA2040C9875BA57F8C4E82B4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>grants to universities and nongovernmental organizations to accelerate research, education, curricula, and knowledge on nationality law and practice and statelessness. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

