<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB213AF03C1564ACA84A6DA7332EDA0E8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9168 IH: Strained Partnership Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9168</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221011">October 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001090">Mr. Cartwright</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the removal of United States Armed Forces from Saudi Arabia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50318C2544BE432E8BC0F616FEFC946A" style="OLC"><section id="HB3883DB0C71643EFB4A058CD270766D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strained Partnership Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCBFB054A16AB4F258C379C03C2EE43E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of United States Armed Forces from Saudi Arabia</header><subsection id="H876C521EA3134CCF8CCD15A499DD57AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Removal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All United States Armed Forces and equipment, including Patriot missile batteries and the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense (THAAD) system, shall be removed from the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia by not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="HDC82AE7DB6704AC1A257C872A29D2E68"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Relocation of equipment</header><text>Patriot missile batteries and the Terminal High Altitude Area Defense system relocated pursuant to subsection (a) shall, to the extent practicable, be relocated to another location or locations in the Middle East, with the priority mission of protecting United States Armed Forces.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA27172EE0BF44D1A92D0D914DE7980DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury and the Secretary of State shall jointly develop and submit to Congress a report on actions taken by the Government of the United Arab Emirates—</text><paragraph id="H491B2F1C26B5486BA61BCAD0414E8D79"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to mitigate money laundering and sanctions evasion by persons linked to Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin, including persons sanctioned by the United States Government under authorities relating to corruption, human rights abuses, and malign actions in Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63095165752B4CAE8AB93C803D10EA62"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to stabilize oil markets with actions designed to help consumers in the United States, Europe, and developing countries mitigate oil price increases, particularly during the coming winter, caused by the decision of the Organization of the Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC) to cut oil production; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D637683CF5C48C7B823666F5ABA6574"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to decrease or maintain its own energy production and exports since OPEC’s decision. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

