<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A750088D94D4B07AECA3A9B872AE2A4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6410 IH: NIST Wildland Fire Communications and Information Dissemination Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6410</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220114">January 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the National Institute of Standards and Technology to conduct research on public safety communication coordination standards among wildland firefighters and fire management response officials.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H80CDE15F8914432190B8FF38285E648E" style="OLC"><section id="H9E94310F2BF643088A972DB93F9B510F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>NIST Wildland Fire Communications and Information Dissemination Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H600095A8AB994BD19206EB83C0CD11FC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4DEB7B948C9A40B995EE7E9E40B5C970"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52C3F248D5484347B65F953FA060C2CB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Member agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>member agency</quote> means a member agency of the National Interagency Fire Center, including the Bureau of Indian Affairs, Bureau of Land Management, National Park Service, National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service, Forest Service, United States Fire Administration, and the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC019C82E5584E418C7582C47A539A03"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Wildland firefighter</header><text>The term <quote>wildland firefighter</quote> means any person who participates in wildland firefighting activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0331751BCB8B4C30B0877B620F4D0541"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Fire management response officials</header><text>The term <quote>fire management response officials</quote> means regional fire directors, deputy regional fire directors, agency officials who directly oversee fire operations, fire management officers, and individuals serving on incident management teams.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C5B0424BC29429699EFF3D424502C9B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Technology manufacturers</header><text>The term <quote>technology manufacturers</quote> means companies that manufacture communications technologies used by Federal, State, Tribal, and local wildland fire authorities.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5ACFCA36E7C84BD894CD66E66B059D67"><enum>3.</enum><header>Research</header><subsection id="HC8DD07147CC24643A8F3EF3473C714F7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To conduct research on public safety</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director, acting through the head of the Public Safety and Communications Research Division and in consultation with the Fire Research Division and technology manufacturers, shall carry out research on—</text><paragraph id="HFF2AD1E3CE3849E693371BC8BAC90A9C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>public safety communication coordination standards among Federal, State, Tribal, and local wildland firefighters, fire management response officials, and member agencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF49EDFF025864465B3EAEAC10D399C3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improving and integrating existing communications systems to trasmit secure real-time data, alerts, and advisories to fire management response officials and wildland firefighters.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFAA419F50BA24DA4B4EB179A4CCC5435"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To conduct field testing of information dissemination and technology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Public Safety and Communications Research Division, in consultation with the Fire Research Division and member agencies, will conduct both live and virtual field testing of equipment, software, and other technologies to determine current times of information dissemination and develop standards for the delivery of real-time data among member agencies, fire management response officials, and wildland firefighters based on findings from research under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H14C0A68C38C643609CCD96D77DD9A51F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Recommendations</header><subsection id="H31481C3EF289476C9E63AB558E1F3B50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To develop and provide recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall develop and publish recommendations for member agencies to improve public safety communication coordination standards among wildland first responders and fire management response officials.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0DE34EE8D418496BBB964666B0A9E182"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To provide recommendations to the Office of Management and Budget, the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and member agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall provide recommendations to the Office of Management and Budget and the Office of Science and Technology Police to assist member agencies with the implementation of the recommendations in subsection (a). </text></subsection></section><section id="HCEDB908BCB4548BEBD93DA4041ACE4BB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><subsection id="H03648D26C5D544B6A3DC6210C3ED699A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To report research findings and recommendations</header><text>The Director shall provide the recommendations published under section 4(a) to the House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology and the Senate Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H93583C7CB00E4161876CDCF3C23D4D37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To report on the implementation of recommendations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the publication of the Director’s recommendations, the Government Accountability Office shall produce a report on the extent to which member agencies have implemented the Director’s recommendations.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8A7B4F6A377249FF8550A433CE6FF7F4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the National Institute of Standards and Technology $3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2027 to carry out this section.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

