<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1D0AB350341F4DA1B70F1EE46228B7CF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9018 IH: Hydrogen Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9018</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to establish a hydrogen infrastructure finance and innovation pilot program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3078152BD3414686AA42F8073BD325CD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBA6F2E2DEF2C4588917DE237AD251BE5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hydrogen Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HABCDB3DFD2174D98BC74B58300C93419"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in coordination with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Council on Environmental Quality, the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, and the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a study subject to notice and public comment—</text> 
<paragraph id="H14522289228E4A6E8AE75618BEFDF8F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to fully assess and report the potential layout of pipeline corridors that are robust against a range of projected hydrogen demand futures;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E05907483664F539AC88071F8A9437C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to synthesize the results from research, development, and demonstration projects on materials and metallurgy for transporting and storing hydrogen and hydrogen-rich fuels;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C83B91192B54E40AFC6C8D8001BEBF4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to determine outstanding questions with regard to research, development, and demonstration of infrastructure for transporting and storing hydrogen and hydrogen-rich fuels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA93C88FFC4B54BB2B58BDA497F6583C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to investigate the behavior and environmental impact of hydrogen leakage in pipelines and from geologic storage sites and nongeologic storage equipment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H432E39AF41BF4917A3DCF2DD8F1E0EE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to determine best practices for the construction and maintenance of hydrogen pipelines;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H534D2CD56D23489BAD58EB282381AEC7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to determine the percentage at which hydrogen must be blended into the natural gas network to substantially reduce carbon intensity; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56434F3B50BB4B87AE02603B57C030EF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to establish a framework for the measurement, reporting, and management of hydrogen leaks. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="HFF40295608594813819EC6647949310E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Supporting hydrogen infrastructure and regional development of hydrogen</header> <subsection id="HA8A00768C4D64B7D8502A58D5E2DBBD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6D9E7F5EDC4247649635345058205FCA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Board-regulated rates</header><text>The term <term>Board-regulated rates</term> means rates regulated by the Surface Transportation Board.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BEDF0B7771C43D89A218186ECB6B311" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission-regulated rates</header><text>The term <term>Commission-regulated rates</term> means rates regulated by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H534408BFD7054CD290106FCD83861B41"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Common carrier</header><text>The term <term>common carrier</term> means a transportation infrastructure operator or owner that—</text> <subparagraph id="HD82A91F32F4A49CB8B02D04EE9DABE47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>publishes a publicly available tariff containing the just and reasonable rates, terms, and conditions of nondiscriminatory service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H48784B95392A469D9D984AA128904E62" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>holds itself out to provide transportation services to the public for a fee. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58BE061648D34A969A16F10B9134093F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Eligible activity</header><text>The term <term>eligible activity</term> means an activity described in subsection (g)(2) relating to, or carried out in connection with, an eligible project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDAA0360890F343249525259FD1731A2F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a corporation, partnership, joint venture, trust, non-Federal governmental entity, agency, or instrumentality, or other entity. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79EF51FC5AA44339AD4F572700DE8D3B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Eligible project</header> <subparagraph id="H39D8E7B6958E4D3386123AAF527EAEF6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>eligible project</term> means an infrastructure project for hydrogen transportation, storage, or delivery, including pipeline, shipping, rail, refueling, or other infrastructure, or associated equipment, as the Secretary determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDA69B945239A48BEA6C08FD83A772D13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of pipeline projects</header><text>The term <term>eligible project</term> includes a pipeline project only if the project is for—</text> <clause id="HC200131202C840C3B5B7935317A0F68E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the construction of 1 or more new pipelines that are capable of handling pure hydrogen; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5C7AE5974B034422BB7602228D8C2108"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the retrofitting of 1 or more existing natural gas pipelines—</text> <subclause id="H5D0E1C791855488F911C6CF453696CCB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to transport a blend of hydrogen and natural gas; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H34DE88422C6A4A2B8838D760A64CCCC8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in a manner that will significantly increase the capacity of the pipelines to transport hydrogen, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8BE825D429B5474BA23C350B6063B47E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Eligible project cost</header> <subparagraph id="H586B62A3801B45C89DF7E506C1AF4528"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible project costs</term> means—</text> 
<clause id="H01B6044D2FCA4412A1502F8161E20670"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the costs of carrying out an eligible activity; and</text></clause> <clause id="HCEA073F5456D4191B60A64047BF19EDC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any costs described in subparagraph (B) relating to, or incurred in connection with, an eligible project.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B24BF08542648B98A9193285A2D09CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Costs described</header><text>The costs referred to in subparagraph (A)(ii) are—</text> <clause id="HBDF1E1734C9D4A66849C2E86D3F480CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the costs of capitalized interest necessary to meet market requirements, the costs of reasonably required reserve funds, capital issuance expenses, and any other carrying costs during construction of the applicable infrastructure; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC95171CCDBDC4AB086D41F6040341666"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>transaction costs associated with financing an eligible project, including the cost of legal counsel and technical consultants.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4EA2D0FA94DC44C6B565BCC5186B9237"><enum>(8)</enum><header>HIFIA pilot program</header><text>The term <term>HIFIA pilot program</term> means the hydrogen infrastructure finance and innovation pilot program established under subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCEB9E18FC18943D3ADBD3A789CB2B857"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Letter of interest</header><text>The term <term>letter of interest</term> means a letter submitted by a potential applicant prior to an application for a grant or a loan under the HIFIA pilot program that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7F61FDD4716A48B38E892B055C73F5BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is in a format prescribed by the Secretary on the website of the HIFIA pilot program;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3491BAC609A84FE68EE133496E265BFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>describes the project and the location, purpose, and cost of the project;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEDEFDE6E6D1843769A968327AFFA7F38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>outlines the proposed financial plan, including—</text> 
<clause id="H71200F653541445C98D80D0ED96F8242"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the requested grant or loan assistance; and </text></clause> <clause id="HF930DF635FCF47D4ADC6A3908EBF5A40"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the proposed obligor, if applicable;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H187417102331433B9C23754884C8A7AB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provides a status of environmental review; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEC75B4474F7A4A878D928C0A2477A884"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provides information regarding satisfaction of other eligibility requirements of the HIFIA pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H88E21D5BA202428B84FB5742CBF5F13B"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Low-income or disadvantaged community</header><text>The term <term>low-income or disadvantaged community</term> means a community (including a city, a town, a county, and any reasonably isolated and divisible segment of a larger municipality) with an annual median household income that is less than 100 percent of the statewide annual median household income for the State in which the community is located, according to the most recent decennial census. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB070636975849EB8B6BEE42C8DD7050"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Obligor</header><text>The term <term>obligor</term> means an eligible entity that is liable for payment of the principal of, or interest on, a loan under the HIFIA pilot program. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC013D3215F064949BD837DA6CA0D9745"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7EB6A7A43F6F41B3BCFB9188003BB34C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header> <paragraph id="H89BCE06BA8F94F1D86C617A214AAC539"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, in consultation with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Surface Transportation Board, and the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, shall establish a hydrogen infrastructure finance and innovation pilot program under which the Secretary shall provide—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H066C36A1B19F4818AE82141171C343E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>financial assistance to eligible entities for eligible projects through—</text> <clause id="HC375073824164E4AA6F8DA78B85CB50A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>grants; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD2EC1EC9DBB44DCBB7AB866C536EB48A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>long-term, low-cost supplemental loans; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H99DE4454B4E7401A86EA5336414508B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>technical assistance in accordance with subsection (l).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA204C5A8BFCD4BCE8D874A35BF461AAF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with hydrogen hubs</header><text>To ensure that the HIFIA pilot program is compatible with and complementary to any hydrogen hubs developed under any other law, the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall coordinate the establishment of the HIFIA pilot program with—</text> <subparagraph id="H72EF699E52E7469BB5F9179CB434CAB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the establishment of any program to support the development of hydrogen hubs that is required to be established under any other law; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDB8365147F654B52B7308CEF47BC6DBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the development of those hubs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCF9B83CC29C4A5DAC467FDA873722C8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header> <paragraph id="HF1AED4C10FC4446883CC1A7004C87C59"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide financial assistance for an eligible project under the HIFIA pilot program if—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF5BD9F74BC534E08B4F6293B0D9C3874"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible entity proposing to carry out the project submits a letter of interest prior to submission of an application under paragraph (2) with respect to the project; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21DD280F66954931ACD7D5E4870A3BDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the eligible entity and the eligible project meet all applicable requirements of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E881624693D40F79D517AEDAC71D335"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5AFEA161C4954313945C7BD95B5AA03C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To be eligible for a grant or a loan under the HIFIA pilot program, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines to be appropriate. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44C6B917E1AB4F1B91D1C9800E28BE47"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Election</header> <clause id="H806F2018CD0C434EB914750C213FB2DB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible entity may elect to apply for a grant, a loan, or both under the HIFIA pilot program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEADDD8D07E4D4A3CA7A34FE808BEA432"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Decision</header><text>The Secretary shall have discretion to award any mix of grants and loans under the HIFIA pilot program as the Secretary determines to be appropriate, including with respect to each eligible entity that applies for both a grant and a loan.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H221CAF2CBE3D4628BAA68F47741CE1DD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Application processing procedures</header> <clause id="H8058A8760AA044448EDB589278962C62"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Notice of complete application</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of an application under this paragraph, the Secretary shall provide to the applicant a written notice describing whether—</text> 
<subclause id="H17961C4D8EDA4FBD83DA9333D7C6FE19"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the application is complete; or</text></subclause> <subclause id="HDD5BAD7AA32247FFBFB6A8CE68EC8963"><enum>(II)</enum><text>additional information or materials are needed to complete the application.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H74BD45F93B8047B284395DB51DC305EE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Approval or denial of application</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of issuance of a written notice under clause (i), the Secretary shall provide to the applicant a written notice informing the applicant whether the Secretary has approved or disapproved the application. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H115A95ACB5704584A899BA4F95AF555E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In selecting eligible projects to receive a grant or a loan under the HIFIA pilot program, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible projects that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H135C14843B054D218E438DB4FA472C92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>will provide greater net impact in avoiding or reducing emissions of greenhouse gases; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H00B54DF7FCAC4DD7B3845A62F3C90B0C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are sited in a manner that minimizes environmental disturbance and other siting concerns, including by being sited within, or adjacent to, existing pipeline or other linear infrastructure corridors.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC6BBD0FD02AD40099FFB284D05E6A1A5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In selecting eligible projects to receive a grant or a loan under the HIFIA pilot program, the Secretary, to the maximum extent practicable, shall select projects—</text> <paragraph id="HC2D3F08BA97D4CC5B3506DA2274C1348"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that are large-capacity, common carrier infrastructure;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C43880754B74AE7900A149905E5386B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that enable geographical diversity in associated projects and supply chains to produce, use, or store hydrogen, with the goal of enabling projects in all major regions of the United States with current hydrogen demand and potential future hydrogen demand;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE0C4F981B4D4DD897A233367C33510E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>that will generate the greatest benefit to low-income or disadvantaged communities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDEF55AA68342464287E941C174492096"><enum>(4)</enum><text>that will—</text> <subparagraph id="HE833C5029DBF4B72AAC529C3BD4AE099"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maximize creation or retention of jobs in the United States; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3B97E9B617E5447CB2324A153A6A746B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide the highest job quality.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE80929CF6C4495095666F479938474F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Loans</header> <paragraph id="H4B574B7BB20E4516BD7C70452D52F821"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the HIFIA pilot program, the Secretary shall make loans to eligible entities, the proceeds of which shall be used to finance eligible projects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF277FCEA4E19473FB19E9D79F07A58FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interest rate</header><text>The interest rate of a loan under the HIFIA pilot program shall be not less than the interest rate on United States Treasury securities of a similar maturity to the maturity of the loan on the date of closing on the loan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4A483009111943889837560FBFFD8902"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Maturity date</header><text>The final maturity date of a loan provided under the HIFIA pilot program shall be the date that is 30 years after the date of substantial completion of the applicable eligible project.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H44FE8715D6854761B911C19FDA9E6A97"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Repayment</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBB0CA1E986B34DB7BDC0242C801E0B11" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a repayment schedule for each loan provided under the HIFIA pilot program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2D636A2A75504317B69B2E89118A0294"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Commencement</header><text>Repayment of a loan provided under the HIFIA pilot program shall commence on the date of substantial completion of the applicable eligible project for which the loan was provided.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5E794A96FB745FD8EC0DEA3431CE854"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deferral of repayment</header><text>If, at any time during the 5-year period beginning on the date of substantial completion of an eligible project, the project is unable to generate sufficient revenues in excess of reasonable and necessary operating expenses to pay the scheduled loan repayments of principal and interest on the loan, the Secretary may allow the borrower to defer repayment of the loan until the end of that 5-year period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HACBAD5C36E3043E1931726B79A14997B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H0BBA1E8C30D14C2FAF02F6F898905EEC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Creditworthiness</header> <clause id="HB8EDA9AB2EF24C26B255AC1870040B6E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each obligor with respect to a loan provided for an eligible project under the HIFIA pilot program shall be creditworthy, such that there exists a reasonable prospect of repayment of the principal and interest on the loan, as determined by the Secretary under clause (ii).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H874C77774AB84C4AB480D7EA40BEB4B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reasonable prospect of repayment</header><text>The Secretary shall base a determination of whether there is a reasonable prospect of repayment under clause (i) on a comprehensive evaluation of whether the obligor has a reasonable prospect of repaying the loan for the eligible project, including evaluation of—</text> <subclause id="H68E2CB195CAB485DA9F262F3DD88D076"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the forecast of noncontractual cash flows supported by market projections from reputable sources, as determined by the Secretary, and cash sweeps or other structural enhancements;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H6D806F9829644099B233141B698D1B0F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the strength of the contractual terms of an eligible project (if available for the applicable market segment); </text></subclause> <subclause id="H4782623064854C228ED181701CE8B416"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the projected financial strength of the obligor—</text> 
<item id="HD554E5E4238D4D0A8DEFE56719B9459A"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>at the time of loan close; and</text></item> <item id="HDDD601B4698D4031A3C27EC133D2B934"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>throughout the loan term, including after the project is completed;</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAC3C5598BACB4D8EAFC47B99918F5247"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the financial strength of the investors and strategic partners of the obligor, if applicable; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9BD42A7D260446588AB07657BACB653A"><enum>(V)</enum><text>other financial metrics and analyses that are relied on by the private lending community and nationally recognized credit rating agencies, as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H33046F0CFB484014B9A29485AA18C693"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Dedicated source of revenue</header><text>An eligible project for which a loan is provided under the HIFIA pilot program shall have a dedicated source of revenue separate from any financial assistance received under the HIFIA pilot program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF3A628D3E1A343D9A54CB55EC05CF29E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of financial assistance</header> <paragraph id="HCABED84A8AF3477D9B76DB0CEDA53447"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant or loan provided under the HIFIA pilot program may be used for any eligible project costs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H258417454AE347DEB8D7330F6201A328"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>A grant or loan provided under the HIFIA pilot program may be used to carry out any of the following activities with respect to an eligible project:</text> <subparagraph id="HC0CF5C11D4484620A8AD4DB1173F0E00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Development phase activities, including—</text> 
<clause id="HBF1FE31FE2404DA08525CF00BE806815"><enum>(i)</enum><text>planning;</text></clause> <clause id="H891AEA7E35844A7287B2FA0E0761C1C2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>preliminary engineering;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCD634506ECDB4E4387A8651D8D8BA27A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>design;</text></clause> <clause id="H071007F968064E8391254000AA683A87"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>environmental review;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H41ED076F48114337AAFA4E5D1482A58A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>revenue forecasting; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9C5CEA4C80174173952AC08D8BB86CB1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>other preconstruction activities.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF27EBC9E4A8844A6ADF5CD0DAFC23642"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Construction, reconstruction, rehabilitation, and replacement activities, including the training of construction personnel in handling and safety.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H021290D1B1A5424FB01B6CDC18D14921"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Acquisition of—</text> 
<clause id="HC09388A89076416AA83D51F0A05CB19E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>real property or an interest in real property; or</text></clause> <clause id="HFC1BD0F33721412DA5A98F7C95952820"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>equipment.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0EA1D5E80F74E58B2C54A3890A1A752"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Environmental mitigation activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H72046F67AE9E4888B4D5B7861CD040F1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Activities relating to construction contingencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD7001023AA2746A6B7872E6D17EC59B0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Federal requirements</header> 
<paragraph id="HFB779B598BD346F8856279F22AA41A70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section supersedes the applicability of any other requirement under Federal law (including regulations).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32CA7E488D69486C9AAF78E16493CE41"><enum>(2)</enum><header>NEPA</header><text>Federal assistance may only be provided under the HIFIA pilot program for a project that has received an environmental categorical exclusion, a finding of no significant impact, or a record of decision under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2C0DFB19D6434C829AA115BC88AC747E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Leak detection</header><text>Each eligible entity that receives a loan or grant under the HIFIA pilot program shall conduct—</text> <paragraph id="H75113F8DD8AB4A838B5113BD923B530D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a hydrogen leakage monitoring, reporting, and verification (also known as <quote>MRV</quote>) program; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB113C8DCB9A14873BFC040B007E150C2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a hydrogen leak detection and repair (also known as <quote>LDAR</quote>) program. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB38AB3C7E9C848759D9B516BC7F3F32C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Maximum Federal involvement</header><text>The maximum Federal share of an eligible project for which a loan is provided under the HIFIA pilot program shall not exceed 80 percent of the eligible costs of the project. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H149DFB39C76A44EEB543BB47B52FFCBF"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 1703(b)(3) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16513">42 U.S.C. 16513(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>Hydrogen fuel</quote> and inserting <quote>Hydrogen technologies applicable to 1 or more end-use sectors, such as power generation, transportation, aviation, storage, industrial, and chemicals, including hydrogen fuel</quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF9F1E1375E9F4F7485E3434E33EBC5DB"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header> <paragraph id="H966451C4244C457FBFE6DE82ED09F997"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary and the National Laboratories may provide technical assistance under the HIFIA pilot program to assess the grading and readiness of existing infrastructure to transport, store, or deliver hydrogen with respect to informal State and regional planning for investments in that grading and readiness.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1C0AFDEF55C4AB1ADCDEFB87DD6FE08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In providing technical assistance under paragraph (1), the Secretary and the National Laboratories shall prioritize—</text> <subparagraph id="H13169CD482FD4EDC957B8F665D0BEC9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preexisting infrastructure corridors; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HADA8A9B67FD54247ACB87DF01B16E346"><enum>(B)</enum><text>geologic storage potential for hydrogen; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB091FC7C68144C5296B260E75AF51BFE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>industrial clusters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEA49C9EE9A8E4F2A98ED6546427FE8F7"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Regulatory assessment To encourage hydrogen transportation infrastructure deployment</header><text>Not later than 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act, each of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Surface Transportation Board, and the Administrator of the Pipeline and Hazardous Materials Safety Administration, in coordination with the Secretary, shall—</text> <paragraph id="H50CCBE18A4EA48189E32264BD570A935"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess jurisdiction over the siting, construction, safety, and regulation of hydrogen transportation infrastructure, including, at a minimum, the blending of hydrogen in natural gas pipelines;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF83793AEEB484C3DBEE07CFAD775C0F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if that assessment indicates that additional authority is needed to support the deployment of hydrogen transportation infrastructure, submit to Congress a report describing the needed authority; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7CA6CB25F0B49CDAF68F455D3750145"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify the eligibility of, and process for, hydrogen transportation infrastructure to receive cost recovery under the HIFIA pilot program through Commission-regulated rates, Board-regulated rates, or other applicable regulated rates, as appropriate, for the transportation of hydrogen in interstate commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4181232211814DAD99AD5DAEB29D510F"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the HIFIA pilot program $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

