<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF345D020D2D453BAD88C2C04C931F3B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7522 IH: Global Criminal Justice Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7522</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220414">April 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage the establishment in the Department of State of an Office of Global Criminal Justice, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H487511D6A0AE405381E7CDB95EF2F07B" style="OLC"><section id="HCEA1780BB0A34A40BA4BE0C6621AF29F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Criminal Justice Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H44DCA2F12FF84B918E1BBE2AA7FE0F68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office of Global Criminal Justice</header><subsection id="H897E01BA51E848EAAB10ED96BD6C2ECD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There should be established within the Department of State an Office of Global Criminal Justice (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>), which may be placed within the organizational structure of the Department at the discretion of the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H451673E937EE444E80440FF69BF27EB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Office should carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="HC77C80E2DD8F4FFAAB8A38F593F2CDF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advise the Secretary of State and other relevant senior officials on issues related to atrocities, including war crimes, crimes against humanity, and genocide.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F249542FD7D41CCA4C4BB3F923F9FEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assist in formulating United States policy on the prevention of, responses to, and accountability for atrocities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E31FA76AE3D4DF29AE5140D3AE004C2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Coordinate, as appropriate and with other relevant Federal departments and agencies, United States Government positions relating to the international and hybrid courts currently prosecuting persons suspected of atrocities around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AA6F53FB863434299633BC6A05A54AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Work with other governments, international organizations, and nongovernmental organizations, as appropriate, to establish and assist international and domestic commissions of inquiry, fact-finding missions, and tribunals to investigate, document, and prosecute atrocities around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC19A513E89234E6D87136215533A6F79"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Coordinate, as appropriate and with other relevant Federal departments and agencies, the deployment of diplomatic, legal, economic, military, and other tools to help collect evidence of atrocities, judge those responsible, protect and assist victims, enable reconciliation, prevent and deter atrocities, and promote the rule of law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE9ACA82C15C49B3B6D1E513B07413C7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Provide advice and expertise on transitional justice mechanisms to United States personnel operating in conflict and post-conflict environments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCC96F6B88CD4E73AEBD80F8F5643A78"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Act as a point of contact for international, hybrid, and domestic tribunals exercising jurisdiction over atrocities committed around the world.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C740FB6C4814E179F81635D0E5D9EF3"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Represent the Department on any interagency whole-of-government coordinating entities addressing genocide and other atrocities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F3F68CC5DC243D199A6FA8C7CF4C6E4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Perform any additional duties and exercise such powers as the Secretary of State may prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H145DCFA4B2FF45D1AE6375A9A4D4CF3F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supervision</header><text>If established, the Office shall be led by an Ambassador-at-Large for Global Criminal Justice who is nominated by the President and appointed by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

