<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE amendment-doc PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/amend.dtd//EN" "amend.dtd">
<amendment-doc amend-type="engrossed-amendment" amend-degree="first"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1082 EAS: Sami's Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<engrossed-amendment-form>
<congress display="no">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="no">2d Session</session><legis-num display="no">H.R. 1082</legis-num><current-chamber display="yes">In the Senate of the United States,</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20221222">December 22, 2022.</action-date></action><legis-type display="yes">Amendments:</legis-type></engrossed-amendment-form><engrossed-amendment-body><section id="idcc097945a91346e0a83d146141f70c32" section-type="resolved"><text>That the bill from the House of Representatives (H.R. 1082) entitled <quote>An Act to prohibit the unauthorized sale of ride-hailing signage and study the incidence of fatal and non-fatal assaults in TNC and for-hire vehicles in order to enhance safety and save lives.</quote>, do pass with the following</text></section><amendment><amendment-instruction blank-lines-after="0"><text> Strike all after the enacting clause and insert the following:</text></amendment-instruction><amendment-block blank-lines-after="1" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic"><section id="idC85BA6ABDB5E4488AFFD61591D4D3747" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sami's Law</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="id4AD8AAC0EC124CD3A6C35CB528AA177F"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical and sexual assault of passengers, TNC drivers, and drivers of other for-hire vehicles</header><subsection id="id9de88d8a98bd4a8eb68d47dcfbcd5d94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that includes the results of a study regarding—</text><paragraph id="id8cb4f0f8c040459384061ff988f7e4f3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the incidence of fatal and non-fatal physical assault and sexual assault perpetrated in the preceding 2 calendar years (starting with calendar years 2019 and 2020 for the first study)—</text><subparagraph id="id94dc1176b9cd4a7ea97c6f44facd79d2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>against TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs) by passengers and riders of for-hire vehicles; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idae336266726d4d52a01384bea4b1ed07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>against passengers and riders by other passengers and TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including the incidences that are committed by individuals who are not TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles but who pose as TNC drivers or drivers of other for-hire vehicles;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idfdf2862fe03e43798417393c820ad37c"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the nature and specifics of any background checks conducted on prospective TNC drivers and drivers of other for-hire vehicles (including taxicabs), including any State and local laws requiring those background checks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id52046717a05c455bbbb50679b26b5a90"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the safety steps taken by transportation network companies and other for-hire vehicle services (including taxicab companies) related to rider and driver safety.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id94ea36c3cc6a4f679ab16a0c33b4ef3f"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sexual assault defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>sexual assault</term> means the occurrence of an act that constitutes any nonconsensual sexual act proscribed by Federal, Tribal, or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</text></subsection></section></amendment-block></amendment></engrossed-amendment-body><title-amends><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>An Act to study the incidence of fatal and non-fatal assaults in TNC and for-hire vehicles in order to enhance safety and save lives.</quote>.</official-title-amendment></title-amends><attestation><attestation-group><attestor></attestor><role>Secretary</role></attestation-group></attestation><endorsement></endorsement></amendment-doc> 

