<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF788A773E5C14B83A227D4FA9584EDE7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9398 IH: U.S. Customs and Border Protection Behavioral Health Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9398</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221201">December 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000266">Mr. LaTurner</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to provide for behavioral health of U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0EE4C2B14FCF465984B44F76AAE9F471" style="OLC"><section id="HB2E106F73B2C44609E7E62C203C3F5E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>U.S. Customs and Border Protection Behavioral Health Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H85E0F8F6D04F4DB282FCE0728264C23E"><enum>2.</enum><header>CBP behavioral health</header><subsection id="HCE329A1AA4254FD6B0BD7759B9AFF6E5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Protection (CBP) should foster a culture of support in the provision of behavioral health care to CBP personnel in order to dispel the stigma of seeking behavioral health care.</text></subsection><subsection id="H316B2BB2A5B54CA5933ADF3A00B27C52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Behavioral health</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 411 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/211">6 U.S.C. 211</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H87CD299FEA7D49418DD6FD6C77158FC0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (o) through (r) as subsections (p) through (s), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E0E0D2CA8D046D9ACBA7B3544B6951B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (n) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="HB09CEF48DB6E4B50AE93293FF52B4A5A"><subsection id="HE830AC64BA68427A9C79F44AA37B826E"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Behavioral health</header><paragraph id="H3E79A4C518424C39959FAE827E035BEF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of office</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in U.S. Customs and Border Protection a behavioral health readiness office to carry out this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E75BED1F3B74FD8BCDA6694619D5FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Behavioral health training</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All initial entry training sites of U.S. Customs and Border Protection shall include basic behavioral health awareness training to enhance awareness and decrease stigma. Such training shall include at a minimum the following:</text><subparagraph id="HDFFFFD78CBEC4EA5AAAC16596EA6F6E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Behavioral health’s impact on organizations and mission readiness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE85752139B0E4F049D06A9F808CBBFEB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Resources available to U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel regarding behavioral health.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6D86C35467B4D10827300250B83297B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Information relating to how to recognize common signs of behavioral health stressors in oneself and colleagues.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1819AF7C096242FC8483363224A84ED1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Steps to take if such signs are recognized in oneself or colleagues.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H653346BC62224CF0B17D32A0B04380DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fitness for duty procedures</header><subparagraph id="H4D85DB419BEF4813B116BBC1B026AD05"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a member of U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel is determined by the Commissioner to be permanently unable to fulfill the duties of such a personnel due to behavioral health concerns in accordance with U.S. Customs and Border Protection’s Office of Human Resources Management Standard Operating Procedure, Fitness for Duty Evaluation (dated March 1, 2022), the Commissioner shall make every effort to provide such a member with alternative employment opportunities within U.S. Customs and Border Protection at similar locations and pay ranges.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99526D84909249E38EF9DB904D40A189"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appeals process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner, in consultation with labor organizations (as such term is defined in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>)) representing U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel, shall establish an appeals process for U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel to appeal a determination under this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FF8DF3AD76841639487A0913BBCEC6F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Behavioral health privacy policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A health care provider furnishing behavioral health care to an individual who is a member of U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel may not notify the Commissioner of such member obtaining such behavioral health care, unless such provider assesses—</text><subparagraph id="H76CC210C44E94092ACDAC626E95D440F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such member poses a serious risk of harm to—</text><clause id="HA7C6443EDA3C46FBBE36D58240086F89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>self;</text></clause><clause id="HCD9FF900D39845519ED9F4116D7A8BD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>others; or</text></clause><clause id="H6B31813E303B48AE93F8A7DB4F6F0B97"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mission;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0231015BF4AA42BA875940172875AED3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there are acute medical conditions that impair the ability of such member to perform the duties of such a member; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD3271CCC1BE45B89FE888211BE31C71"><enum>(C)</enum><text>there is another special circumstance at issue.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Nothing in the previous sentence shall affect the application of any other Federal or State law relating to the privacy or security of information to the extent that such other law is at least as restrictive with respect to the permissible disclosure or use of information described in the previous sentence.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H796F3D8F2B014B0DBF0814BCCA6C5890"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this subsection and biennially thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States, in consultation with labor organizations (as such term is defined in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>)) representing U.S. Customs and Border Protection personnel, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the implementation of this subsection. Each such report shall include recommendations to U.S. Customs and Border Protection regarding agency actions and Congress regarding legislative actions on how to continue to improve behavioral health readiness within U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCDE8DBA2BEA4AB8BB46197C5990A495"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subparagraph id="H49C333BD00EF456FB3AB03BF4B2366B7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commissioner $23,100,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028 to carry out this subsection. Such amounts shall also be used to hire behavioral health providers, who shall be embedded within the operational units of U.S. Customs and Border Protection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE17A095A2024457D9708694CA2119F80" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Incentives</header><text>To provide for the hiring of behavioral health providers pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Commissioner may provide such behavioral health providers with recruiting and retention incentives authorized under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

