<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H395C0D72F42A45F5A324F241E1CF0C96" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9560 IH: Petroleum Price Reduction Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9560</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to provide for the control of and prohibition on the export of crude oil and finished oil products (other than natural gas) from the United States under that Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D2056A05E774EDA81DD02CC7F66D04E" style="OLC"><section id="H0BAB20CDFF5E4B83BD6AB22CC9A5938C" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Petroleum Price Reduction Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6C5C22AB597A4D40B12F767F0026F31C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Control of and prohibition on the export of crude oil and finished oil products (other than natural gas) under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018</header><subsection id="H60338AD254944ECCB2B446B4282F63D7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1754 of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA5756FEA02094110A1621BC8956DC964" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEE3A8497730247FDB5C12442D462516B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Control of and prohibition on export of crude oil and finished oil products (other than natural gas)</header><paragraph id="H9176F93C12C94B3F95052D06DBA5EE78"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law (other than the provisions of this subtitle), the President shall control and prohibit the export of crude oil and finished oil products (other than natural gas) from the United States under the authority of section 1753 at any time if the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that the closing price of front month contracts for West Texas Intermediate crude oil—</text><subparagraph id="H4A844238576D466393B2C8FCF601C8F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has exceeded $70 per barrel for three consecutive trading days;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4968BC73A4A8464CA6C928D695CED31B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has exceeded $70 per barrel for five of the preceding 10 trading days; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2448A7AEFCD54E2A929012D6C31D210C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has exceeded $80 per barrel at any time.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8C42219FD4849D699ADE0C8532CEE3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may terminate the imposition of the prohibition required by paragraph (1) if the President determines and certifies to the appropriate congressional committees that—</text><subparagraph id="H8D0C745F372B46AA8BDFCA6D131B954B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the closing price of front month contracts for West Texas Intermediate crude oil has not exceeded $70 per barrel for 15 consecutive trading days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBFED4BF95BD413EBA11B2EEF8482258"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the current, available supply of crude oil in the United States is stable or increasing. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H396A24837B7245578BDE8EE71BB42752"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Adjustment for inflation</header><subparagraph id="H453B795D430F48498F8E67DB81B75CC0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may adjust the dollar amounts specified in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) and paragraph (2)(A) on the date that is 60 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, and at the beginning of each fiscal year thereafter, to reflect the percentage (if any) of the increase in the average of the Consumer Price Index for the preceding 12-month period compared to the Consumer Price Index for fiscal year 2021.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H842AD7E5BDB242EB86A3C5F06516448F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consumer Price Index defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <quote>Consumer Price Index</quote> means the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F2858DFD4B745C9BD1063F0AD2AE7E8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Waiver</header><subparagraph id="H8D16CEA61A5E4BA684B469BA20E66DEC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the imposition of the prohibition required by paragraph (1) with respect to—</text><clause id="HFFE83B6282C04FF795AFEE461C5531A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the export of crude oil or finished oil products (other than natural gas) pursuant to a contract or other legally binding obligation of an exporter that is in force as of the time the prohibition is to go into effect; and </text></clause><clause id="HA8E24C39856D41EAB5C91E675E0C09B6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the export of crude oil or finished oil products (other than natural gas) to any foreign country if the President determines that it is in the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7B07292BF4A4DE1983763FAC639760E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Congressional certification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a certification with respect to each exercise of the waiver authority pursuant to subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E91EA542A2E415A96016CD915D5D0E1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD4576872BAFB4F5E98A09C7DF09E56F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date that is 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

