<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8EAFAF4E01534B01B1E693027385C0FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9014 IH: Promoting National Service and Reducing Unemployment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9014</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Committee on Appropriations</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for supplemental appropriations to increase the number of Americorps members and to increase the living allowances of such members, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5DF4486AB31C43C39EF8F5FE6F1DD8ED" style="OLC"><section id="HFF8257A648F74AC69DA5436EA3FDC664" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting National Service and Reducing Unemployment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEEF87F1C3B8C414C96CB256092492506"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supplemental appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to any amounts otherwise appropriated or made available, there is appropriated such sums as may be necessary, for the fiscal year ending September 30, 2023—</text><paragraph id="H990819A8F0C3415C87299AE7F9B15CA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to increase by not less than 500,000 the number of national service positions approved under subtitle C of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H428F08C6C05E4FE38854EC046FBB9243"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enable an increase in the living allowance of each participant of a national service program to 200 percent of the poverty line, as specified under section 140(a)(1) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (42U. S.C. 12594(a)(1)), as amended by section 3.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H29FEE9780A84484686B76C56C7D95D1C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Permanent increase in living allowance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 140(a)(1) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12594">42 U.S.C. 12594(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H262735CD0EAD4A71B2FC0D2CB4925338" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HE93FA8C56F4C42A190536912F2FC348C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Living allowance required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), a national service program (including a national service program carried out using assistance provided under section 121) shall provide to each participant of such program a living allowance in an amount equal to 200 percent of the poverty line (as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, and revised annually in accordance with section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>)) applicable to a family of the size involved), and adjusted each year after 2023 for inflation as measured by the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3D604FC3591448DA829E8293F9F9452E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Permanent increase in cost per member service year</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 189(a) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12645c">42 U.S.C. 12645c(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>$18,000 per full-time equivalent position</quote> and inserting <quote>125 percent of the amount of the minimum living allowance of a full-time participant per full-time equivalent position</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

