<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6FBAAC6E272344C48F1DD5B2BC75EAEF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9659 IH: Building Technologies Research and Development Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9659</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221221">December 21, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to carry out a research, development, and demonstration program with respect to building technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HDF144EFEEE6844D2B2DC252F04A3282F" style="OLC">
<section id="H566F2F68C295484B82F59A201145B647" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header>
<subsection id="H29B881C46ECD4E899F0ABCEE48CD8C4A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Technologies Research and Development Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC655895024BE4820B1B0F48FF8F720B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text>
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded">
<toc-entry idref="H566F2F68C295484B82F59A201145B647" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD15E7D143A4B47E5BE38057433FE368D" level="section">Sec. 2. Low emissions research and development.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H63212CD9E79E4964A2C0E76E804F7F36" level="section">Sec. 3. Building technologies research and development.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H122D4099B9A64E47AED45F47B17A8420" level="section">Sec. 5. Solid state lighting research and development.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H04187A5C4E414CA7A2806E91ADD875AE" level="section">Sec. 6. Better buildings research, development, and demonstration program.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="H72C58638B54E4415B5AC144CCE0F3A1D" level="section">Sec. 7. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry>
<toc-entry idref="HD1CCD197BAEB48F784E370F96E27489A" level="section">Sec. 7. Clerical amendments.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section>
<section id="HD15E7D143A4B47E5BE38057433FE368D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Low emissions research and development</header>
<subsection id="HD7CA17F7603747A28EA74AA0CDA16EF9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>Section 902(a) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16181">42 U.S.C. 16181</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HA13DC8806445451383CC687C1731A4E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A2262DC27C14B1999B393A4A3F0B885"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (5) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block id="H63FEE69DAD244DB3AC4D038661C811FB" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="H2E770CF3D5484D3F9B74789F2C4C46BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>decreasing the environmental impact of energy-related activities, including by deeply reducing emissions; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8C4079E81E9A4315A7BDB7AD375DB203"><enum>(6)</enum><text>improving energy-sector resilience to climate change.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1F511D14CBAA4EBC95B0C56B0F0778F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emissions defined for goals</header><text>Section 902 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16181">42 U.S.C. 16181</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H8B16B7474DB744999A97345901B04478" style="OLC">
<subsection id="HF830D81745754AB588AF40A031D9BC99"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Emissions defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>emissions</quote> means greenhouse gas emissions or other pollutants.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HAA69297E1E72461F8148125012592A10"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Emissions reduction</header><text>Section 911 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16191">42 U.S.C. 16191</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H1A395D380A794F7281953FE74F005495"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">and emissions reductions</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">energy efficiency</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDF68D94E4EFB481FB80F94E15E82322B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H530D3421F545446D8F7E1E2E699AA5DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H3CC1F6897AF34886B67B597EDB6D9F58"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and emissions reductions</quote> after <quote>energy efficiency</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H22592E5DB50B408D9DB0F655867B0207"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, and reducing emissions from,</quote> after <quote>efficiency of</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0399818AADEA4CBBAA237A97D8E6E383"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
<clause id="HC5AB164ACEF7416D890407C0482F54AA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending the matter preceding subparagraph (A)(i) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H83B8EC0BD8D7491A93053FE2A5C13EEA" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H647204D910994C958E4F5ACAE33584BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>advanced, cost-effective technologies to improve the energy efficiency and environmental performance of, and reduce emissions from, vehicles, including—</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause>
<clause id="HD7877C8AE5934C0FBE48EE63085AC902"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HE749362BB4554C92B7E98B568AC7C7C4" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HF84E9226DFBD4177A5AA4E67839FB691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>cost-effective technologies for new construction and retrofit, to improve the energy efficiency and environmental performance of, and reduce emissions from buildings, using a whole-buildings approach, including onsite clean energy generation and beneficial electrification;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause>
<clause id="H4FD9F59B02234A5CA761D3192F474F99"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="H5E38653368AC4F57AA5482E19E6877D1" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HAB10D5E80B394F93B90D6600059C3497"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advanced technologies to improve the energy efficiency, environmental performance, and process efficiency of, and reduce emissions from industry, especially energy-intensive and waste-intensive industries;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27B7DED54C774E5FA861245CB51D9786"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block id="HAC8BB02CAE714FDBA67DF862CAB4A96B" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HB18CBCAE7C4445F1AC59124D8AB525F5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Emissions defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>emissions</quote> means greenhouse gas emissions or other pollutants.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H543609F345CE4851A06831215126A088"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clean energy</header><text>Section 911(a)(2)(E) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16191">42 U.S.C. 16191(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>, including combined heat and power units and increased use of renewable resources, including fuel</quote>. </text></subsection></section> <section id="H63212CD9E79E4964A2C0E76E804F7F36"><enum>3.</enum><header>Building technologies research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle A of title IX of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16181">42 U.S.C. 16181 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="HFB739C49BD2C4428996C7CF4A575A0AA" style="OLC">
<section id="HB8055D5BED6444BE84425815B478F7A5"><enum>919.</enum><header>Building technologies research and development</header>
<subsection id="H85B077009AF44D538AD7FEC7297169CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of the Building Technologies Research and Development Act, the Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application to develop cost-effective tools, technologies, and practices that reduce emissions from, increase productivity and well-being of occupants in, and increase the energy efficiency and beneficial electrification of new and existing commercial and residential buildings, including retrofits and electrification of existing buildings, rural housing, low-income housing, multi-family housing, public housing, and manufactured housing.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEF7B768A4A6B48C3A4CB83F7CFCF4733"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Energy equity</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out research to identify barriers to, and strategies for, expanding the use of low-emissions and energy efficient building technologies and appliances in the buildings where members of frontline communities live and work. In carrying out this section, the Secretary may coordinate with other Federal agencies on housing and rural development programs. Research topics covered under this subsection may include—</text>
<paragraph id="HD70DD7A8E215474DBA77748ABB664DDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>barriers to and solutions for the purchase, integration, and use of technologies developed under this section in rural, low-income, multi-family, public, and manufactured housing;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H16E31B0030AB4731A04552C9E6FA3E44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>causes of, and solutions for, inequitable energy costs or high energy burdens in housing in frontline communities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD545581DA4D542DAABCD87659821BE43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solutions that ensure that housing in frontline communities are energy efficient as well as affordable.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB8FCB5B9585B48C193F7D487786B0CF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Non-Technical barriers</header><text>The Secretary shall support research and analysis to identify non-technical barriers and methods to address such barriers, to enable greater use of tools, technologies, and practices developed under this section in new and existing commercial and residential buildings, including rural, low-income, public, multi-family, and manufactured housing.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HECC1996C2F034233808DD965C0A67CDB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Resilient buildings</header><text>As part of the program established in section (a), the Secretary may, in consultation with relevant Federal agencies including the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, the United States Geological Survey, the National Institute of Standards and Technology, National Science Foundation, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency, support research and development on principles of resilient building design, construction, and operation to address current and future predicted risks over the lifetime of a building, including considerations of regional differences such as natural hazard exposure, resource availability, and fuel mix and energy production.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0E4D2AFC674F4EA286E3F2119B3ABF3F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Advanced building construction, design, and retrofits</header><text>As part of the program established in section (a), the Secretary shall support research and development on technologies and methodologies to enable advanced building design, construction techniques, and retrofits. In supporting research and development under this section, the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H0F35FA5B3DF14C8B914DBA3057A054DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include considerations of a full lifecycle analysis inclusive of building design, manufacturing, and construction, including environmental considerations, embodied energy and embodied carbon in building materials, transportation of materials, and implications for building retro-commissioning as well as final disposal and recycling;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4DC6DFD15FD64E189285EFAF3AC26AB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>incorporate considerations of regional differences such as climate, season, temperature, energy production, fuel mix, and precipitation, in consultation with the Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, for proposed building designs, building sites, or existing buildings, including the development of tools, technologies, and practices to address such regional differences and improve building energy resilience in the face of natural disasters, wildfires, extreme weather events, and natural hazards;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H84C3FEBB97AB4ED2BFF051972D29E36C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support research and development on the use of various potential energy sources and distributed generation to supply cooling, heating, and power for buildings, including integrated and adaptive control solutions that improve traditional building energy management and emerging technologies such as batteries, and thermal storage compatible with all sizes of buildings;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H549088860038489E9E1D44653C6F9084"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support the development of technologies that enable low-emissions and energy efficient or advanced buildings, such as lighting systems, heating, ventilation, air-conditioning, and refrigeration systems and other appliances that are cost-competitive over the life of the product as compared to conventional technologies and that incorporate considerations of integration in new and existing buildings, retrofitting, and ease of installation, using a whole-systems and whole-buildings approach;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4BEE4DBD75A7406D9C2F8EBCC46562FF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support the development of cost-effective next-generation window and building envelope technologies that incorporate considerations of integration in new and existing buildings, retrofitting, and ease of installation, including advanced building materials;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7DEFD0D6B17441CB8401C230035F7D3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support development of alternative working fluids and refrigerants for use in buildings equipment to reduce global warming potential;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H07E9BB673159473FA795DA019C709E88"><enum>(7)</enum><text>support research on methods to enhance the comfort, health, and well-being of individual occupants in buildings that also result in improved energy efficiency and emissions reductions, including indoor air quality; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BA4654DE2A540688A476908F1AC1B80"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support research on modular or off-site construction techniques and technologies for manufactured housing that advance energy efficiency, reduce emissions, and enhance affordability of buildings.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD4AEA6048C67439D921CD52AE2D82FA5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Modeling and data analysis</header><text>As part of the program established in subsection (a), the Secretary shall support the development of building models, including for the design and operation of buildings, the analysis of relevant data to enable smart buildings, and building energy modeling. In particular, the Secretary shall focus on the development of—</text> <paragraph id="H3DCA7F758B72478DA4B8082430A639F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advanced modeling capabilities that include modeling of grid interactivity, resilience, and relevant behavioral, community-scale, and urban-scale activities in order to—</text>
<subparagraph id="H165B35CDDC364E88A0499941D7B67B4D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide system-level analysis of new technologies, including distributed generation and storage;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H223FDE32C2A34D95B58B594C8D399B44"><enum>(B)</enum><text>evaluate system benefits such as emissions reductions, community resilience, distribution grid reliability, and service to underserved communities; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4CBA1C11564940F3B92FC1EB0128E1CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide data, derived from both simulation and demonstration projects established in subsection (h), to inform decision making new business models;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73D07DF8ED1D4EDD8E6B7A87129CC093"><enum>(2)</enum><text>automated methods to generate models of proposed or existing buildings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD5976752977D46989E1DA68048FCA00F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>methods to address barriers, including non-technical barriers, to commercial application of building models for building operation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF7CB19796AB4497A9B9B7575B89A85D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>methods to analyze data collected by technologies in smart buildings and collections of buildings;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7D303FC61D41407EAFB026198C30B503"><enum>(5)</enum><text>artificial intelligence and machine learning approaches to building energy management; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE24122DE43614BC1A18C410CA6E459D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>advanced data collection and monitoring methods for utilities at the building level and component level.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H440B63CCF33D4CEC909075D720BACB88"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Demonstration program</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a competitive grant program for the demonstration of advanced building technologies and systems developed under the program established in subsection (a) that—</text> <paragraph id="HC519873909734D0BB9934DA8BB2B161B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>focuses on a range of new and existing building types, including low-income housing, rural housing and agricultural buildings, multi-family residential buildings, manufactured housing, and small- and medium-sized commercial buildings; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H354695FC9A2D4C4AAEA6D9503134ED20"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes community-scale demonstration projects.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H32212568C9724A298BA761EEAC09EC5E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Testing and validation</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H96C69159499C45AA86DF3A3DAC096DA3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support testing and validation activities to improve the commercial application of relevant tools, sensors, technologies, and methods, including the use of testbeds and the development of test methods to determine cost savings and performance in realistic scenarios; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5020A996DB6B4340A74467D764B3222D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support analysis, testing, and validation to accurately determine energy savings, emissions reductions, cost-savings, and other potential impacts of the highest-performing appliances and equipment that are commercially available.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HDD75A067E9ED4350A14B62513FD06B39"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>In carrying out the activities authorized in this section, the Secretary shall work with utilities, State and local energy offices, building owners, technology developers and manufacturers, contractors, building developers, connected building system manufacturers, and other relevant entities to guide the focus areas of the activities of the program authorized in paragraph (a), provide feedback on roadmap documents, and encourage the commercial application of these technologies by building owners, operators, developers, occupants, contractors, or other relevant entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3B1A4F40488248D488E5A013CB4CDC4D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall coordinate across all relevant program offices at the Department, including the Office of Electricity, the Office of Fossil Energy and Carbon Management, the Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy, and the Office of Cybersecurity, Energy Security, and Emergency Response.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC807EDE631C548D18B97D286E872041F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H74275E004E0144D1B1BA91820DFE5044"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emissions</header><text>The term <quote>emissions</quote> means greenhouse gas emissions or other pollutants.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD03C28F75AD741B48A028D3CA08C069E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frontline community</header><text>The term <quote>frontline community</quote> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and indigenous communities, that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4A5A9A8CF5DB47E0872E980967E5EDF2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD2A8CBE913AD49FD90CE8369A36C7E66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>faces an above average proportion of their income directed to the payment of energy-related costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07A456A4569B4CB0B00ECF35BA20315F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Smart building</header><text>The term <quote>Smart Building</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1007(a) of Division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H554BDDC23B4C43C6BCAE4A4E40050F31"><enum>4.</enum><header>Grid-interactive efficient buildings research and development</header>
<subsection id="HA8AF39174F55412B9A7E7793DA276B05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the research and development program authorized in section 3 of this Act, the Secretary shall carry out a grid-interactive buildings research and development program authorized in section 426 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17086">42 U.S.C. 17086</external-xref>), as amended in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3A8CBD566F9347909978CC9CFDE6C37A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grid-Interactive efficient buildings research program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">426(a) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17086">42 U.S.C. 17086(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HFAAE8768B31F4CF0A632956A7710C12F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (8) as paragraph (12); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3DA2A7E82DB4244A64949FEB0C10466"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (7) and inserting the following:</text>
<quoted-block id="H313293C4546B4D7199822FF6DED2E4D7" style="OLC">
<paragraph id="HC7F230163354442C87F0F4EE6E9BB622"><enum>(7)</enum><text>advanced building energy management systems through the integration of sensors and advanced control technologies and systems that allow whole building optimization and integration with other energy systems including photovoltaics, electric vehicles, and energy storage technologies such as thermal storage;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD79CF593B50E4C46B0B63D68C84F6C37"><enum>(8)</enum><text>building energy storage capabilities, including load shifting, to modulate peak and off-energy demand;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1A8E055A9D2D4519AEDC4E284E40FCBE"><enum>(9)</enum><text>distributed energy resources at the community- and building-level through localized electric grids;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5A4BCD5BA5A489FA7B3174124E83813"><enum>(10)</enum><text>technologies to reduce energy use and emissions in connected communities and neighborhoods located in a variety of climates, including by enabling transactive energy concepts;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA501FA9F2A3C4391B114179580390465"><enum>(11)</enum><text>cybersecurity best practices, including those that protect privacy and personally identifiable information and addressing security vulnerabilities of building systems or equipment; and</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H122D4099B9A64E47AED45F47B17A8420"><enum>5.</enum><header>Solid state lighting research and development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 912 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16192">42 U.S.C. 16192</external-xref>) is amended as follows:</text>
<paragraph id="HF723E1B852EA4EC2870B0B630A50253F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsections (a)(1), (a)(4), (a)(5), (b), (c), by striking <quote>white</quote> in each place it appears; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B943141ADCE445DADFC06CC59B556DF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by amending subsection (i) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block id="H1BF2801F778E4658AC4C086757A8BB2A" style="OLC">
<subsection id="H91735A3F2F514CE590AFF95D6316AE03" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Solid state lighting research and development</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the enactment of the Building Technologies Research and Development Act, the Secretary shall establish a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application on advanced solid state lighting technologies, controls, and systems that provide energy and emissions reductions. In particular, the Secretary shall support projects related to—</text> <paragraph id="H7237C5B84F7E4DD78F78426DF6838C82" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>communication and data capabilities that leverage solid state lighting technologies and systems, including those that enable energy savings through energy reporting, interoperability, or cybersecurity capabilities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4FDCA7F7B4C941ACA46242E788E3E925" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>innovations to support domestic manufacturing and other United States economic benefits of solid state lighting technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD90019509DA74429810DF960141A9EC4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solid state emitters; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4F219CF72BEC40C4826EB11D57250C8A" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the uses and benefits of solid state lighting technologies in a variety of settings such as health care, agriculture, other commercial or industrial buildings, and vehicles.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H04187A5C4E414CA7A2806E91ADD875AE"><enum>6.</enum><header>Better buildings research, development, and demonstration program</header> <subsection id="H18506A369CA64D57BFE17E8DB53BF12B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Better buildings demonstration program</header><text>Section 1007(d) of Division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021 is amended by striking <quote>and commercial buildings sectors</quote> and inserting <quote>and laboratory, industrial, commercial, and residential sectors, including in rural housing, low-income housing, multi-family housing, and manufactured housing, through partnerships.</quote>.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE59D421ACD6E4860B8922632F58ADE91"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Better buildings research programs</header><text>Section 1007 of Division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021 is amended by adding after subsection (d) (and redesignating subsequent subsections accordingly)—</text> <quoted-block id="H61F7A4AE0B6E43CAB4770F23E8E87EE5" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HCC74EEB0CCD84B3AB5A6FE72206D2EEF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Education and outreach</header><text>The Secretary shall support education and outreach activities to disseminate information and promote public understanding of building technologies and the building technologies workforce.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HE7BE320891D04663B3E5ED068C1C361C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Building america program</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out a research, development, and demonstration program on tools, technologies, and practices to reduce energy use and emissions in new and existing residential buildings, in partnership with industry entities.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H72C58638B54E4415B5AC144CCE0F3A1D"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the activities under section 1007(d) of Division Z of the Consolidated Appropriations Act of 2021, section 426 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17086">42 U.S.C. 17086</external-xref>), and the amendments made by this Act—</text>
<paragraph id="HDDE2B3906619403989132A8CF89AA364"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$392,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H390E92D630F648E5A46827AE0149C977"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$411,600,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF77782252A2E489DB2DA356105CFA0E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$432,180,000 for fiscal year 2025;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H32F064FA5A2445F1A1D2FEE2282EF28F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$453,789,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAB43F8DAE06A44E9A5845AC15691D619"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$476,478,450 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD1CCD197BAEB48F784E370F96E27489A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Clerical amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of sections for the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="H84BD255321564A61BA7F4DB40A20C4F8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the item relating to section 911 by inserting <quote>and emissions reductions</quote> after <quote>energy efficiency</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08BD87142E0049A38FDFEB72FA5E7690"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding after the item relating to section 918 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H03EB6A6034084FE79682E294DF230379" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 919. Building technologies research and development.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


