<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCDC744D87AAF4E12ABE3DF97C5B6F11E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7259 IH: Medical Controlled Substances Transportation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7259</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220328">March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to direct the Attorney General to register practitioners to transport controlled substances to States in which the practitioner is not registered under the Act for the purpose of administering the substances (under applicable State law) at locations other than principal places of business or professional practice.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBD3C845C8E3C44278D0E8138AC70E225" style="OLC"><section id="H3D39C2D735CA402791E082CDB4D62880" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medical Controlled Substances Transportation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF679E9DF57FA4474B708D0B44D5630D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Registration for transport of controlled substances to States in which the practitioner is not registered under the Controlled Substances Act for the purpose of administering the substances at locations other than principal places of business or professional practice</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 303 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/823">21 U.S.C. 823</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD657357BBE104C0B8D1ACFA9772E8A9C" style="OLC"><subsection id="H52B3A762C37948F4AB3B9709191B13BB"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Registration for transport of controlled substances to States in which the practitioner is not registered for the purpose of administering the substances at locations other than principal places of business or professional practice</header><paragraph id="HBAB543AF8584448FAD92F6EF3A15BC32"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon application by a practitioner (other than a pharmacy) who is registered under subsection (f), the Attorney General shall issue a separate registration to the practitioner authorizing the practitioner—</text><subparagraph id="H6F4558F3EF3549F9951078F24C113241"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to transport one or more controlled substances in schedule II, III, IV, or V from the practitioner’s registered location in a State to one or more States in which the practitioner is not registered under subsection (f) for the purpose of the practitioner administering the substances at locations other than a principal place of business or professional practice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1F2FBAC3FA24C13A69799B2F16760FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to so administer the substances.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD350B33296054611B548173A26ACD3E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a practitioner to be authorized to transport and administer controlled substances pursuant to a registration issued under paragraph (1), all of the following conditions must be satisfied:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H917DD58C174C49109335FEC8F7B689FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The practitioner must be licensed, registered, or otherwise permitted by the State in which the controlled substances are administered to carry out such activity at the location where it occurs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H50295925628A4B8B9F4248DAADAC6B8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The practitioner must—</text><clause id="H21C3DF23A98B481BB99145C26AA7F22B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>limit the time of transport and administering of any controlled substance pursuant to such registration to not more than 72 consecutive hours; and</text></clause><clause id="H811F5276C5604DA98F780D890939DE61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by the conclusion of such 72 hours, return any such controlled substance so transported but not administered to the registered location from which such substance was obtained.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45ADBC1F4E824359954F713CE264A752"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H78B962DA96AA40C6AD068F1FB629C1F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The practitioner must maintain records of the transporting and administering of any controlled substance pursuant to this subsection.</text></clause><clause id="H82A6CF5291DA45088FB3E3500008F9BA" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such records shall be maintained, in accordance with the requirements of section 307(b), at the practitioner’s registered location from which the controlled substances were obtained and shall include—</text><subclause id="H4E45476E4B1D40ED9CFEDD07767A8C5B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the location where the controlled substance was administered; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H08CA3D9CBEE44FAD82F9A770530A2469"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other information as may be required by regulation of the Attorney General with respect to records for dispensers of controlled substances.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H760A48181AD14832809503B2DBD3A98F" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding clause (ii), the exception in subsection 307(c)(1)(B) shall not apply to records required by this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5FDA88A562E3406EB70CF07B6AF2A236"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grounds for denial or revocation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may deny an application for registration under this subsection, or a renewal thereof, or revoke such registration, based on the criteria listed in section 304(a), except that the applicant shall not be required, as a condition of initially obtaining such registration, to present proof of State authorization to administer controlled substances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79F08673816F4075881A950D40AABA24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Automatic termination</header><text>A registration issued under this subsection shall automatically terminate if the practitioner no longer has an active registration under subsection (f) due to revocation, suspension, surrender, or other termination.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DAC883F09BB4E5DBD87BCEAB2A68D0B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>registered location</term> means, with respect to each registration issued to a practitioner under subsection (f), the address that appears on the certificate of registration.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

