<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8187FF71501B4A54817EAD415EB40C81" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6654 IH: Climate Adaptation Science Centers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6654</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish a National Climate Adaptation Science Center and Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers to respond to the effects of extreme weather events and climate trends, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H07A8513B4BAE45E2B0CA1CE6BF959AF4" style="OLC">
<section id="H1A88A7AFF70045648232E9D163DCE48A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Climate Adaptation Science Centers Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CASC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HE0E402AC644A4A96A1C9EEAB4BD8AF34"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H2D21F0DDC1484FD999E7D4EBB6151314"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adaptation</header><text>The term <term>adaptation</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HB789E8D2DCE146D3BC6E7C417F5B1E33"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the process of adjustment to actual or expected climate and the effects of extreme weather, climate trends, and climate variability; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0D5AB860008148B0B10C9AF8968932D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>protection, management, and conservation efforts designed to maintain or enhance the ability of people, fish, wildlife, plants, land, ecosystems, and water of the United States to withstand, adjust to, or recover from the effects of extreme weather, climate trends, and climate variability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED4FCFE70F264130A5897ACC5DE9D089"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cultural resources</header><text>The term <term>cultural resources</term>—</text>
<subparagraph id="H000F3A8EF07D491BB4D69B513C4B458D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means those features and values related to cultural heritage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H93B712CBBBE04522B5194BD049895416"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes biological species with cultural heritage or ceremonial importance, and historic and prehistoric sites, trails, structures, inscriptions, art, and artifacts on Federal lands or representative of the culture of Indian Tribes, Native Hawaiians, and Native American Pacific Islanders.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4455D177F92D4737BF2C5D5E8C7F212B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committee</header><text>The term <term>Committee</term> means the Advisory Committee on Climate and Natural Resource Sciences established under section 6.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD676A22CA07143C39F47B2C8885DE55C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consortium institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>consortium institution</term> means college, university, State cooperative institution, State agency, Indian Tribe, Tribal College or University, Historically Black College or University, Tribal organization, Native Hawaiian organization, minority-serving institution, or other educational institution or organization, Federal agency, public or private organization, individual, or any other party within each Regional Center other than the United States Geological Survey and the host institution.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00AB24BD491C45CB90B2892FCB4E053B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H43FF18EDC62A4EBE81693E7F1E40F727"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Ecosystem services</header><text>The term <term>ecosystem services</term> means those benefits that ecosystems provide humans and human society, including clean air, clean water, and other economically important services.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H11A2E7441AE74F8D988C5737408A5630"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Historically Black Colleges and Universities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Historically Black Colleges and Universities</term> has the same meaning given to the term <term>part B institutions</term> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1896820805A4272B6916C388D1AF08C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Host institution</header><text>The term <term>host institution</term> means the non-Federal lead organization within each Regional Center.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H68E31BD064484CF6BE02CA2AA3C09AF0"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE6C9C69F2C240D2BB0A0D6A3AECA2EF"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means a Hispanic-serving institution, an Alaska Native-serving institution, a Native Hawaiian-serving institution, a Predominantly Black Institution, an Asian American and Native American Pacific Islander-serving institution, or a Native American-serving nontribal institution as described in section 371 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00DBF231C7D54CC5985287101BCE0A61"><enum>(11)</enum><header>National Center</header><text>The term <term>National Center</term> means the National Climate Adaptation Science Center established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF70C387F0B9541F78504CF4B7FFD4C57"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Native American pacific islanders</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Native American Pacific Islanders</term> means any descendent of the aboriginal people of any island in the Pacific Ocean that is a territory of the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBDEA3AB45C474373A1BC0D3495228A15"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Native Hawaiian</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Native Hawaiian</term> means any individual who is a descendant of the aboriginal people who, prior to 1778, occupied and exercised sovereignty in the area that now constitutes the State of Hawaii.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H039D3DB882D14B5EB5AB36FBAAE75BCC"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Native Hawaiian organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Native Hawaiian organization</term> means any organization which—</text>
<subparagraph id="H9A71E01D7A6F42ED99396610AB30A021"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serves and represents the interests of Native Hawaiians;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFB8B9105C17E4213903F4A278BBA4872"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has as a primary and stated purpose the provision of services to Native Hawaiians; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBD54C85121BC4A2083AF728F28B349CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has expertise in Native Hawaiian Affairs, and shall include the Office of Hawaiian Affairs and Hui Malama I Na Kupuna O Hawai’i Nei.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEE98D24D7F3412AB6E9243212B844EA"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Natural resources</header><text>The term <term>natural resources</term> has the meaning given the term in section 11.14 of title 43, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBAE0D65F590947728F4B0AD2EB1B5007"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Regional Center</header><text>The term <term>Regional Center</term> means one of the Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers established under section 3(a) that provide support for specific geographic locations in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25AA6D6F6724407C99C47F445BEA3383"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H65F6ABC4ABFF4C6D8A97443DD5A6721A"><enum>(18)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HBB7A41197FCF4D5D96CC8852B9F5BDD6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State of the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE87D2A5D95044F6C9894F8F87EA69C07"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the District of Columbia;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6CFA1635469D41CFB991AFB2960A6676"><enum>(C)</enum><text>American Samoa;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD9C3C1F5D7FB43EB9D02622BCF322FD5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Guam;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H64F82D2CE00C46AAB4656B0745212E51"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD97C23110EE42068BA61F6624FFC483"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Puerto Rico; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H915037F90143462AA1B15AF2B2FF8714"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Virgin Islands of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H72112BC9AA6C432A8B88F79B40F430B8"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Tribal college or university</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> means an institution that—</text> <subparagraph id="HFB62F897FA9E4BEC8D8235D184F041F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>qualifies for funding under the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1801">25 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Navajo Community College Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640a">25 U.S.C. 640a</external-xref> note); or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H71EC85FE797A43A5B8840D4F763361BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is cited in section 532 of the Equity in Educational Land-Grant Status Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/301">7 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AB4568C6FD44ED688206FCD3432E01A"><enum>(20)</enum><header>Tribal organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal organization</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H84FF96076949487C8D8C20A44EA690C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the recognized governing body of any Indian Tribe; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3D65DC1F3EF4ACD834BEDDCBE593A77"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any legally established organization of Indians that is—</text>
<clause id="HF9CD8B9887E34468929142341A46774F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>controlled, sanctioned, or chartered by the recognized governing body of an Indian Tribe; or</text></clause> <clause id="H1A56A9B4737F4E2E9AF8DC55DFE6C987"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF7C45AB42BDA4F40A7BA647B7AC5D6E8"><enum>(I)</enum><text>democratically elected by the adult members of the Indian community to be served by such organization; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H2B946E701C634C058D860F9FFAA8F804" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>includes the maximum participation of Indians in all phases of its activities. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03F5789338444BB180AF765C7EFD56F4"><enum>(21)</enum><header>University</header><text>The term <term>university</term> has the meaning given to <quote>institution of higher education</quote> as that term is defined by section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HDD8A21B7471541D4B04F4FE0E0205CCB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment and duties</header>
<subsection id="H62A240C96DB3433988167F033B536EDB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header>
<paragraph id="HD8DBBBD0E5C14960B8CC47A3C03CA4D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with States, Indian Tribes, and other partner organizations, shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>National and Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers</quote> to provide scientific expertise to managers of natural resources, cultural resources, and ecosystem services for the purpose of informing decisions that aid adaptation to a changing climate and extreme weather events. The program shall include a National Climate Adaptation Science Center and Regional Climate Adaptation Science Centers, which shall be administered by the United States Geological Survey.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A2254150E3A447486C3CE884E4C7454"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chief; Directors</header><text>The Chief of the National Center shall be a United States Geological Survey employee. Each Regional Center shall have a Federal Director and a Host Institution Director who shall work cooperatively to further the mission of the Regional Center. Federal Directors of the Regional Centers shall be United States Geological Survey employees who report directly to the Chief of the National Center.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HC1F6987E588B471F98811468C5F88A75"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the National Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In collaboration with Federal agencies, States, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, Native Hawaiians, Native Hawaiian organizations, Native American Pacific Islanders, and other partner organizations, the National Center shall—</text> <paragraph id="H79BD24EFDF394DB9ACDE3E111D129A47"><enum>(1)</enum><text>serve as the national office for the Regional Centers;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H60D4C7AE6D7F4705A348A99D417353D4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide leadership and guidance on administration, partnerships, information management, and communications;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A1EED2459B243DA9023FD988EF1C6BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>develop and facilitate coordination among the Regional Centers;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4573B83198964BC087D607C970B29605"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinate with other Federal agencies working on similar research and activities; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AA1BC61F7684DE68CF7B9D6EF9ED18C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct research on cross-regional and national science priorities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6FCAA6E7CD7744CA9A9D9A9D616DE5F9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>support Regional Centers that—</text> <subparagraph id="H7B0EB377BD244A83B680CD6AE69D78AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are hosted at a university, or a consortium of universities or other research institutions, within the region of each Regional Center;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA55BBEA58F7A4E96867107A8905B3397"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are collaborations between the Federal Director and the Host Institution Director and their staffs to address the broad scientific mission and goals as defined by the National Center in a manner that is relevant to its specific geographic region and in cooperation with State and local governments, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, Native Hawaiians, Native Hawaiian organizations, Native American Pacific Islanders, and other entities within that region;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD510FE79D7434124A0F28C412F255F20"><enum>(C)</enum><text>promote research, education, training, and advisory service activities and broad and prompt dissemination of knowledge and techniques; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6BB6D7E02F9D44A7ABEF6BA794229ABD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>receive funding at the host institution through cooperative agreements, contracts, and grants under section 4; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H755DAE485ADE49E6B3D338352F89480F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><text>acting through the Chief of the National Center, with respect to the Regional Centers—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF07AE8B4BCC44C06ACB69D34BBFD2DA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluate and assess the performance of the programs of Regional Centers every five years, using the priorities, guidelines, and qualifications established by the Secretary under this section, and determine if the programs are well managed and carry out high-quality research, education, training, and advisory service activities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H44E2D5C6EF4D4AC8BC4CD1A88703BF0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>subject to the availability of appropriations, allocate funding among Regional Centers so as to—</text>
<clause id="HABFEC7CC15CC487DA2176EF50BE1CDAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>conduct regionally relevant research, education, training, and advisory service activities in each of the regions;</text></clause> <clause id="H368C3242FBAB4FA1AA0136F0C12C5421"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>encourage collaborations among Regional Centers to address regional and national priorities established under this section;</text></clause>
<clause id="H628C471ECEAA4CDEBD84D1E6D81AACE9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>ensure successful implementation and operation of Regional Centers;</text></clause> <clause id="HDC2F75EA0E2446A4BC6955EB59EFF49C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>to the maximum extent consistent with other provisions of this Act, provide a stable base of funding in support of the Regional Centers; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H4BB1395B2E60403890B765BEA4DA326F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>encourage and promote coordination and cooperation between the research, education, training, and advisory service activities of the Department and those of the host and consortium institutions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF6300CECBD5741CC9DAD903F5CDEC446" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorities of the National Center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Center may—</text>
<paragraph id="H8E0579EDE45E4511B270F72850003CDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procure the services of appropriate public and private agencies and institutions and other qualified persons to conduct its work; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB267734DF28B4E6EA22D6629138FCD05"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operate and fund a network of not fewer than nine Regional Centers that shall address the impacts of climate trends and variability, including extreme weather events, on natural and cultural resources and ecosystem services.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB8B341FB9A244564931FD855ADC8648C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Designation of the Regional Centers</header>
<paragraph id="H0041F24ED6AC460ABE4D1532851763BA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Existing Regional Center Designations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any institution or consortium of institutions designated as the host institution of a Regional Center before the date of the enactment of this Act, shall not have to reapply for designation as a Regional Center if the Chief of the National Center determines that the institution or consortium of institutions meets the guidelines established in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H454208EE703C408CAC8D26E39B858B83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reviews of the Regional Centers</header><text>The Chief of the National Center, in consultation with the Committee, shall establish guidelines related to the activities and responsibilities of the Regional Centers. Such guidelines shall include—</text>
<subparagraph id="HB0DEBDD416784D5A9CC41F6AE1EF689A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>requirements for the merit review of the Regional Centers;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32420080B16749D38891FC4278FE0A74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the circumstances by which a host institution may not be continued as a host institution;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1C772D8D81148B9902AEFFED8CD55AE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the schedule for reviews according to the criteria in the schedule for reviews; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H270121526C1046ED98319DD9C5D0FE2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the process to select a new host institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H521339E490174840BC49265E92E5EA54"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Changes to Consortium Institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief of the National Center, in consultation with the Federal Director and Host Institution Director of a Regional Center, may add or remove consortium institutions at any time to address regional and national priorities established under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H467E00DFBFA74DF9BC267F8B73B89EEC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>FACA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Committees, subcommittees, and working groups appointed by Federal Directors of the Regional Centers pursuant to this subsection shall not be subject to the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HB678727D101E46BA949980CC9E8A3944"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties of the regional centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In collaboration with Federal and State natural resources agencies and departments, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, Native Hawaiians, Native Hawaiian organizations, Native American Pacific Islanders, Tribal Colleges or Universities, Historically Black Colleges or Universities, minority-serving institutions, universities, other research or educational institutions, and other partner organizations, Regional Centers shall develop research, education, training, and advisory service priorities regarding the impacts of climate trends and variability on natural and cultural resource management in their regions for the purpose of climate adaptation.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H4CF81FE14FB3471392392FF7B3C8A465"><enum>4.</enum><header>General authority to enter into contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, and interagency agreements</header> <subsection id="HDB51E6192DDC424180B7CFC70581678B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Director of the United States Geological Survey is authorized to enter into contracts, grants, cooperative agreements, and interagency agreements with a host institution or consortium institution to further the research, education, training, and advisory service activities of the Department or its partners relating to impacts of climate trends and variability. This authority supplements all other laws relating to the Department and is not to be construed as limiting or repealing any existing authorities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H08C467E8794D4CC5AB30826190998970"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal instruments</header><text>The Director of the United States Geological Survey may use a contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or interagency agreement as the legal instrument reflecting a relationship between the Secretary and a host institution or consortium institution, to further the duties under section 3 without regard to—</text> <paragraph id="HD8A15F1DA82B456C9098453B455358B7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any requirements for competition;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5498B8422C704C00A90AA37A04473F19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>section 6101 of title 41, United States Code; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC3EC65FED254B058963C8DE966BFA04"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subsections (a) and (b) of section 3324 of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFE506AB0F7B24B9299F009C58EB0D696"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Participation of Federal agencies</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any Federal agency may participate in any such cooperative agreement under this section by contributing funds through the National Center or otherwise if it is mutually agreed that the objectives of the agreement shall further the authorized programs of the contributing agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEAE594EAB0B34F23BD00CE1643294F80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Title to assets</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the United States Geological Survey, may vest title to expendable and nonexpendable assets, including equipment, supplies, and other tangible personal property in the contractor or recipient when the contractor or recipient purchases such assets with contract, grant, cooperative agreement, or interagency agreement funds and the Secretary deems such vesting of title a furtherance of the research, education, training, and advisory service objectives of the Department.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1115AC4F79094E559AEB059276FCC7BC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Approval required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case where a contract is let or grant made to an organization to perform services benefitting more than one Indian Tribe, the approval of each such Indian Tribe shall be a prerequisite to the letting or making of such contract or grant.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H2C1C6545F71B4ED595165E71029DFD65"><enum>5.</enum><header>Interagency cooperation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each department, agency, or other instrumentality of the Federal Government, that is engaged in or concerned with, or that has authority over, matters relating to natural and cultural resources, ecosystem services, or climate variability or change, including all member agencies of the United States Global Change Research Program—</text>
<paragraph id="H17CC0F04C47F47ED8F6D59E4390D0333"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may make available, on a reimbursable basis or otherwise, any personnel (with their consent and without prejudice to their position and rating), service, or facility which the Chief of the National Center deems necessary to carry out any provision of section 3;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1DE377927B1947C092BE5D1F3E48C17D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall, upon a written request from the Secretary, furnish any available data or other information that the Secretary deems necessary to carry out any provision of section 3;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H50CA18AB1E46417299684792D48D9B31"><enum>(3)</enum><text>shall cooperate with the National Center, Regional Centers, and duly authorized officials thereof; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE7477185293F4907A26AD26A61DACF3E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>may transfer budgetary resources or otherwise enter into interagency agreements, including funding, facilities, computational resources, data, or other tangible or intangible resources, between the National Center or Regional Centers to aid collaborative work among Federal agencies, when approved by the Chief of the National Center and their counterpart in the other Federal agency.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H5BCA4239E962454BBC296516DD9D1ADF"><enum>6.</enum><header>Committees</header>
<subsection id="HF0C0F3BF165A4136A5C886A417A243F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To establish committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief of the National Center may establish committees or working groups and procedures to facilitate public participation in the advisory process, such as a national advisory committee for the National Center, stakeholder advisory committees and science implementation panels for the Regional Centers, and working groups for review of competitive or noncompetitive proposals.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1E3E743971044CDFB7B1CA21ECB1F831" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory Committee</header> <paragraph id="HDD472BB4C5AA47BA9935AEA18C946EAA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and pursuant to the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.), the Secretary shall establish an Advisory Committee on Climate and Natural Resource Sciences.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H38BCCE76D2D14539A8AAA89E73BEB393"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The Committee shall have not fewer than 15 members, each of whom is an employee of—</text> <subparagraph id="H9093F2A934BB453FAFE5525CD7F54639"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H844380A08183446E8F6F3267F3F12622"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Tribal organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H420F85D686A34CD89A7AB71C3C1CAF45"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Native Hawaiian organization;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3215155BD65E4F4294AA7CE3EF4EBE5F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a State or local government;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H68956A8E15B94F2CA69C0F524C75A194"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a host institution of a Regional Center;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7A8066A512854E9CAB762FE34FBDDDD9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a nongovernmental organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H519271F9387040BBB0FB557C34DB5147"><enum>(G)</enum><text>an academic institution; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEC807789C66B444880A743F3A5A04C52"><enum>(H)</enum><text>an organization of the private sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CFEF876D48A4C39977AE1ABE96BB30B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Director of the United States Geological Survey shall appoint a Committee Chair from among the members of the Committee.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7F207CC6845B4447ABA306E04784EC3F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Committee shall identify and recommend priorities for ongoing research needs on the issues described in section 3(e) to inform the research priorities of the National Center.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21B8A8408C3E4829A045F54A3010A83E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Term of Office</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB970C19BB9C644CA8363510BA63AB713"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term of office of a voting member of the Committee shall be not more than 3 years.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A8A6609155A460790AF2AB3A8208731" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>No person may serve more than two consecutive terms as a voting member of the Committee.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H056A468059364E9E945EB561A42A30B6" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Chair may extend the term of office of a voting member of the Committee by up to 1 year.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFF0BEDE7C7FF4F6789276FB3B251BA37" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any individual appointed to a partial or full term may be reappointed for one additional full term.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7CC8AE6FE04404BA4DCBF6A41655FFC" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Not less than once each year, the Secretary shall publish a notice in the Federal Register soliciting nominations for membership on the Board.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5B5D7BC484464ADABA6A6986E91333C7" indent="up1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Committee shall select one voting member to serve as the Vice Chair, who shall act as Chair in the absence or incapacity of the Chair.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7307DFDC88AF4C7B9FA7D3F1B7A0A2FC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Committees; working groups</header> <paragraph id="HD5205ED52064411ABD94CCA962E6402A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At the direction of the Secretary, the Chief of the National Center may establish committees or working groups to provide input on the science priorities, implementation of science programs, review of competitive and noncompetitive proposals, and evaluation of processes, procedures, and outcomes of the National Center and the Regional Centers.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0A08960938724AE7A4654F739B09DD51" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The committees or working groups shall, to the extent practicable, include members from Federal and State government, universities, private sector, nongovernmental organizations, Indian Tribes, Tribal organizations, and Native Hawaiian organizations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FE1326286D44F4A9C496055CAA59163" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public participation</header><text>The Secretary may establish procedures to facilitate public participation in the advisory process, including providing advance notice of meetings, providing adequate opportunity for public input and comment, maintaining appropriate records, and making a record of the proceedings of meetings available for public inspection.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H33822EFFD6704E6C8179648871AECA45" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Implementation; availability of records</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the procedures described in paragraph (3) are adopted and implemented and that the records described in paragraph (3) are accurately maintained and available for public inspection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H11CE2CC6E9914D22A7F10DD9D853529E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>FACA</header> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HECC5D048E09441EB994B267633103040"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The committees or working groups shall not be considered advisory committees under the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H778BE1EAB1FB42B4952A5D4873B8782F" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Seeking advice and input under subparagraph (A) shall not be subject to the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6E64D982F9BC43F3B4D525652331BBD3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this Act not less than—</text>
<paragraph id="HE8C0EBA86D3E499D8367A80DE346FDC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$97,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECB4C78825BC4CE8A4DD3EFD0ECB0030"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$109,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAF3D21AFA4A445718F28FB405CACE90D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$121,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5D0DAF81BDB4FA6A0AC2565AF173EC2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$133,000,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAB64C76D182E4E5B82FC977F0C27B569"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$145,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

