<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5C0153B891524A8ABA10C45A28738DCB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 7012 IH: Ukraine Assistance and American Energy Acceleration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7012</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220309">March 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001311">Mr. Bishop of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide appropriations for certain activities relating to Ukraine, prohibit the importation of certain petroleum products from Russia, Iran, and Venezuela, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H18CC646703C84489B4BFC094BEEC0EC0" style="OLC"><section id="HB4197DBAB46F4C50B74AFFE21D45FEC0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ukraine Assistance and American Energy Acceleration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF68BDF60D7064F55ABCDE9A7E2DB20CA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Appropriations for Department of Defense for emergency assistance</header><subsection id="H7CEB4786B53843CDA35FB466169DD9E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Provision of defense assistance to Ukraine</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,000,000,000 to the Secretary of Defense for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended, for <quote>Procurement, Defense-wide</quote> to provide the Government of Ukraine the following:</text><paragraph id="H3888276E37E242E0A3788638013FBEDA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Small arms, grenade launchers, and ammunition previously allocated for provision to Afghan Security Forces under the Afghan Security Forces Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0CCEC598A884AFE91BCC02B8A7940B3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Man-portable missiles and rockets in a ready-to-fire configuration, including Dragon, Javelin, FIM–92 Stinger Missiles, and other light anti-tank weapons (66mm), shoulder-launched multipurpose assault weapon rockets (83mm), M136 (AT4) anti-armor launchers, and cartridges (84mm).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67157A85ABFB4DDFA254AC7355FDCC05"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Night vision devices, including fused panoramic night-vision goggles, squad binocular night vision goggles, and night vision and thermal and infrared sights for crew-served weapons.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE28B1DC8A7214DB1A366A69154FBBFFA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Unmanned aerial vehicles (tactical and armed) and crew-served weapons ammunition with low-light and infrared night sights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E881A491E2349E0B1C4099ED899B717"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Secure, commercial-off-the-shelf communications capabilities, including hand-held secure communications devices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA68635694AE94854BFB87AB6BA2355D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Individual protective equipment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE373940F97D4421497783D6823918BC4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Field rations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18C5B7D7466840FA87BDA549D9502452"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Field medical kits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB511048CD574FE79BBB7B477C767392"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of defense assistance to North Atlantic Treaty Organization members</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,000,000,000 to the Secretary of Defense for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended, for <quote>Procurement, Defense-wide</quote> to provide the Governments of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization with planes, tanks, munitions, and anti-air and anti-tank weaponry to bolster the deterrence efforts of those Governments against an invasion by the Russian Federation and to replace equipment donated by those Governments to the Government of Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F192128808E423A87186CE6974D719A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procurement of replacement defense articles</header><paragraph id="HA34323923E454293A14D0BAB092D09EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,000,000,000 to the Secretary of Defense for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended, for <quote>Procurement</quote> to procure defense articles to replace defense articles transferred to Ukraine and members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5317FE4C146E44FFB83E07314F614F19"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definition of defense article</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>defense article</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4FBD4AE511074F7097312B14670CD544"><enum>3.</enum><header>Appropriations for Department of State for emergency humanitarian assistance</header><subsection id="H3DFE52807006476DADE6118FA3B4E822"><enum>(a)</enum><header>International disaster assistance</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $500,000,000 to the Secretary of State for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended, for <quote>International Disaster Assistance</quote> to address humanitarian needs in Ukraine due to the impact caused by the Russian Federation’s invasion.</text></subsection><subsection id="H239908FEE2AF4AF992F4226586D4DFC5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Refugee relocation assistance</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $250,000,000 to the Secretary of State for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended, for <quote>Refugee Relocation Assistance</quote> to provide monetary and personnel assistance for the Polish, Moldovan, and European Union member states that are accepting Ukrainian refugees.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1712507DBA144245BE4C91A7D1CCE8FB"><enum>4.</enum><header>Appropriations for Department of Energy for emergency assistance</header><subsection id="H125D01FA584E4001BC133E281CD1B5C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Electrical grid integration</header><text>There is appropriated, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $30,000,000, to the Secretary of Energy for fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended, for <quote>Electrical Grid Integration</quote>, to integrate the Ukraine electrical grid European Network of Transmission System Operators for Electricity.</text></subsection></section><section id="H80C4B6BA4A4841598FAC8E5135BA8C3B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on importation of Russian, Iranian, and Venezuelan petroleum products</header><subsection id="H9203B005489C4790A2B5FAC0885F3E2E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>The President shall prohibit the importation of all petroleum products (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6202">42 U.S.C. 6202</external-xref>)) originating from Russia, Iran, or Venezuela into the customs territory of the United States (as such term is defined in General Note 2 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7EE6C1B40CF44872ACBB2F66BA500A96"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The President is authorized to use appropriate authorities to impose such civil or criminal penalties as may be necessary to enforce the prohibition under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A29E26C9D2C4E36903FF0E5CD2FD283"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="HDD34DD3A5C1C40D8B4A79BDE2371D25E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H494C1890766A400BB25D8FEDDA5AAC84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC28A7C64D2064CFE88FD52C13C73BF48"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Committee on Appropriations, the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1007D4844E2942ABB2A9ACAA9AF7BFE7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of Keystone XL Pipeline</header><subsection id="H7C1BF0E360FE4024A5F4578EB15DA78A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. may construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline facilities at the international border of the United States and Canada at Phillips County, Montana, for the import of oil from Canada to the United States described in the Presidential Permit of March 29, 2019 (84 Fed. Reg. 1310).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F42210C342748349763CB92CF04D403"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Presidential permits</header><text>No Presidential permit or any other Executive order shall be required for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of the pipeline facilities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H291212CE89934AD9AFE8F2591112031B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Prohibition on moratoria of new energy leases on Federal land and waters</header><subsection id="H1DDCB3A397C140C9B76F71383E1BDAD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H155C90C6312647DBA0C3C9F7F3707215"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text>The term <quote>critical mineral</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 7002(a) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1601">30 U.S.C. 1601(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3380BE0846B4E9ABB1616663A94CD16"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal land</header><subparagraph id="H726BF6FA084C4D0D8D8487FC9FC603AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land</quote> means—</text><clause id="HC8EDFC8240EA436AB54F4698F5672F27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>National Forest System land;</text></clause><clause id="HEC65CF5621164853B27DBC47C2FC3E8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>public lands (as defined in section 103 of the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1702">43 U.S.C. 1702</external-xref>));</text></clause><clause id="H9444A7EDB83F48B4BDE13C465D73DCF6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the outer Continental Shelf in section 2 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="H6E648CCF20D14557BC6BBCFC4A71218B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>land managed by the Secretary of Energy.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB28A0B0150342C686915898C6CDAA53"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <quote>Federal land</quote> includes land described in clauses (i) through (iv) in subparagraph (A) for which the rights to the surface estate or subsurface estate are owned by a non-Federal entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB8BBBAADFD44157B697FF9D446235DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>President</header><text>The term <quote>President</quote> means the President or any designee of the President, including—</text><subparagraph id="H498AA96973AC4F3FB452912468C1B1F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0A8A3C05F194EA888B3D756999C5A09"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61FD4E1B022947E48179573C1CE7BA3B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C8707CFBF734C469C413E33DF8D97BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><paragraph id="H5E0AEDDCDC31460BBE27F0986ECA30CD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may officially not carry out any action that would prohibit or substantially delay the issuance of any of the following on Federal land, unless such an action has been authorized by an Act of Congress:</text><subparagraph id="H49809DB9E4864DE9AA397F331A7DBEF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>New oil and gas leases, drill permits, approvals, or authorizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF153A7286C64F188B742CCB75EFB324"><enum>(B)</enum><text>New coal leases, permits, approvals, or authorizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C434919844143AB85126E979175D683"><enum>(C)</enum><text>New hardrock leases, permits, approvals, or authorizations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF91B63671FE64D7492915BB24068420E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>New critical minerals leases, permits, approvals, or authorizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H131FAE582470499897E078FBF2376067"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on withdrawal</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may not withdraw any Federal land from forms of entry, appropriation, or disposal under the public land laws, location, entry, and patent under the mining laws, or disposition under laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing or mineral materials unless the withdrawal has been authorized by an Act of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8447FC8B766D40D984307E948ED41752"><enum>8.</enum><header>Oil and natural gas leasing</header><subsection id="H1C294337C1334BFAA67EA6893CF060BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Onshore lease sales</header><paragraph id="HD88802C94CF34763B072364D01016277"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement to immediately resume onshore oil and gas lease sales</header><subparagraph id="HE89E68CF06E14EF481578A44A540E5D0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall immediately resume oil and gas lease sales in compliance with the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H29C80DFFE8564A0086B6D3768E52949A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that any oil and gas lease sale under subparagraph (A) is conducted immediately on completion of all applicable scoping, public comment, and environment analysis requirements under the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>) and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87EF88B317B44269806CC49EF36D7444"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual oil and natural gas lease sales</header><subparagraph id="H57D70DB5961D421EB5155118645058A1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in accordance with the Mineral Leasing Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/181">30 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>), April 1, 2022, the Secretary shall conduct a minimum of 4 oil and natural gas lease sales annually in each of the following States:</text><clause id="HFBED39CB4B8347FB965F87AC13A3E381"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Wyoming.</text></clause><clause id="HA1A460257B344074A74316282EC5C4CF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>New Mexico.</text></clause><clause id="H61588887FB264A719B5AA2F7BEE8F4B1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Colorado.</text></clause><clause id="H59EDA487F29F4B9BB7B8151EBC3FB741"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Utah.</text></clause><clause id="HCF3BA96D68D049BE8BA48D48F4711E63"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Montana.</text></clause><clause id="H0F1A24CF51D44C39991428BE10611D30"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>North Dakota.</text></clause><clause id="H8C06796B418849A79127713A276B9E62"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Oklahoma.</text></clause><clause id="H07DE060F64ED44F9890BB060CB9AAA61"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Nevada.</text></clause><clause id="HD3EB0CE560BD4A46B68D7B474656C444"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Any other State in which there is land available for oil and natural gas leasing under that Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C41F9009AA9468A90DB830CF6ED62FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In conducting a lease sale under subparagraph (A) in a State described in that subparagraph, the Secretary shall offer all parcels eligible for oil and gas development under the resource management plan in effect for the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA144C9D8F5FD4ACCA0AE51840D7C081B"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Replacement sales</header><text>If, for any reason, a lease sale under subparagraph (A) for a calendar year is canceled, delayed, or deferred, including for lack of eligible parcels, the Secretary shall conduct a replacement sale during the same calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9BB88E7826E4932BD54C49371718DC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Offshore lease sales</header><paragraph id="H7A26D3EC2F7C49CAA5D570CF9DAD33B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall conduct all lease sales described in the 2017–2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Proposed Final Program (November 2016) that have not been conducted as of the date of enactment of this Act by not later than April 1, 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H480536613B1B4FAF944D7E2CBB3E589D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gulf of Mexico region annual lease sales</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provisions of law, no later than 30 days following the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a minimum of 4 region-wide oil and natural gas lease sales annually in the Gulf of Mexico Region of the outer Continental Shelf, which shall include the following areas described in the 2017–2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Proposed Final Program (November 2016):</text><subparagraph id="H8A8C92999B5246D9A9CEF25DD09E2EF0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Central Gulf of Mexico Planning Area.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28C2A3FA95534B4C9089BFB6F0A4D474"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Western Gulf of Mexico Planning Area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED1CFB54319E42C18A583B530DE6F00A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Alaska region annual lease sales</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning 30 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall conduct a minimum of 2 region-wide oil and natural gas lease sales annually in the Alaska Region of the outer Continental Shelf, as described in the 2017–2022 Outer Continental Shelf Oil and Gas Leasing Proposed Final Program (November 2016).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB831C6F77914070A3C4A25E442D7DE6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>In conducting lease sales under paragraphs (2) and (3) the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H6CBF893031494EF1A915CE4287D35339"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issue leases to the highest responsibly qualified bidder or bidders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFB94DC409A244BAA94CEB5FDC46C3EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include in each lease sale all unleased areas that are not subject to restrictions as of the date of the lease sale.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4E87546F97849E2A0F952ED0A720E1A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Outer continental shelf oil and gas leasing program</header><text>Section 18 of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1344">43 U.S.C. 1344</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H68F6D242361041B59FF2E7C57612FAE9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the first sentence of the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>subsections (c) and (d) of this section</quote> and inserting <quote>subsections (c) through (f)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FD26745E3FA4A41A89540B63DDFE8C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) through (h) as subsections (g) through (i), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H430702AC9E5844D682D54852DB83EA9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2C62B3BDFE1F41D6AB81BEAFC88AD505" style="OLC"><subsection id="H5E5DC94100814253B2B1B52F64CC6D79"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subsequent leasing programs</header><paragraph id="HCFBD19D861B24DC594395AEC452AFB16"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 36 months after conducting the first lease sale under an oil and gas leasing program prepared pursuant to this section, the Secretary shall begin preparing the subsequent oil and gas leasing program under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45A9B63EDA3D423DBA12C1659DFFD461"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Each subsequent oil and gas leasing program under this section shall be approved not later than 180 days before the expiration of the previous oil and gas leasing program.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H27835758ED4E4560AD601449CB819BED"><enum>9.</enum><header>Expedited approval for natural gas interstate pipelines</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 7 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717F">15 U.S.C. 717F(c)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H79C59E9134D24C41A0819B4A1FA8267D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H4F27A92AD4C942E78EDD16C19587C619"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certificates of public convenience and necessity</header><paragraph id="H93FB1FB43CBB40288F645B3938C62EBF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="H36070D11226845A1B6DA7358BAECB6DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement to apply for certificate</header><clause id="HA8D21AF502444CDFAF85F7BF15753E29"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No natural-gas company or person which will be a natural-gas company upon completion of any proposed construction or extension shall engage in the transportation or sale of natural gas, subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, or undertake the construction or extension of any facilities therefor, or acquire or operate any such facilities or extensions thereof, unless there is in force with respect to such natural-gas company a certificate of public convenience and necessity issued by the Commission authorizing such acts or operations.</text></clause><clause id="HD8C8A3100DB947278D68248130F40E7F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Prior operations</header><text>If any such natural-gas company or predecessor in interest was bona fide engaged in transportation or sale of natural gas, subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission, on the effective date of this amendatory Act, over the route or routes or within the area for which application is made and has so operated since that time, the Commission shall issue such certificate without requiring further proof that public convenience and necessity will be served by such operation, and without further proceedings, if application for such certificate is made to the Commission within ninety days after the effective date of this amendatory Act. Pending the determination of any such application, the continuance of such operation shall be lawful.</text></clause><clause id="HA9F2E62E713240799EED81DF48B1EE65" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Projects that meet safety regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to any application for a certificate of public convenience and necessity under clause (i) for which the Commission determines that project covered by the application meets all safety regulations in effect as of the date of the application, the Commission shall issue the certificate without requiring further proof that public convenience and necessity will be served by the project, and without further proceedings.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B4BB68358914F568F99F04807A4990A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In all cases other than the cases described in clauses (ii) and (iii) of subparagraph (A), the Commission shall set the matter for hearing and shall give such reasonable notice of the hearing thereon to all interested persons as in its judgment may be necessary under rules and regulations to be prescribed by the Commission; and the application shall be decided in accordance with the procedure provided in subsection (e) of this section and such certificate shall be issued or denied accordingly: <italic>Provided, however</italic>, That the Commission may issue a temporary certificate in cases of emergency, to assure maintenance of adequate service or to serve particular customers, without notice or hearing, pending the determination of an application for a certificate, and may by regulation exempt from the requirements of this section temporary acts or operations for which the issuance of a certificate will not be required in the public interest. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC8159318172743D3A61B537A2BAAEBC1"><enum>10.</enum><header>Domestic environmental impacts</header><subsection id="HEEA652E4E4C44333B27EB1DF208176A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 102(2) of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4332">42 U.S.C. 4332(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H91745B15E651411B97033CC831ADE4BC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subparagraph id="H0830FF36E50B40F68823006A9BC5BD2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>in the United States</quote> after <quote>human environment</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E028D48BE64EAEB506C5EC0A30B6C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>in the United States</quote> after <quote>proposed action</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49718CCFCD5846B4ACA204AFDE63C211"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>in the United States</quote> after <quote>environmental effects</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F27AD224F5B4750B446DEA6B2118E70"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by inserting <quote>in any proposal or other major Federal action that involves the funding or development of projects outside the United States or the exclusive economic zone of the United States,</quote> before <quote>recognize</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC3196B697B2C4F258652C47CBE80385F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementing regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Council on Environmental Quality shall revise the implementing regulations of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>) under subchapter A of chapter V of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations), in accordance with the amendments made by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H42F8872BC5274A4CAF614ADB73F3EF41"><enum>11.</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to carry out Federal Energy Regulatory Commission Updated Pipeline Certificate Policy Statement (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/18/1">Public Law 18–1</external-xref>–000) updated February 17, 2022.</text></section><section id="idFD7B2F8F1B17486D855562237FF5DFC5"><enum>12.</enum><header>Responsible energy production in the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge</header><subsection id="id89FF5B443DD3414A97CFFF5798F045BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applicability to section 1002 of the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge</header><paragraph id="idD9A8668B9DD048DCABB3010D920E8444"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, title II of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/97">Public Law 115–97</external-xref> is the law of the land and any Executive order, secretarial order or regulation aiming to block this title shall have no force or effect.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF72AF72F903E44CF8A712B707F885676"><enum>13.</enum><header>Natural gas exports</header><subsection id="H1D0E29C20DA048AA8150A7AC2748B478"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H272DDCE57DFC4FD19CCC673A227D4B95"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing clean and safe natural gas exports will lead to increased investment and development of domestic supplies of natural gas that will contribute to job growth and economic development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD05D1B44062149269826966FD1CCBF01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the export of clean and safe natural gas to other nations is of vital national interest to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3602F61244DF45698B02CB1A9FC2DDB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Natural gas exports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3(c) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFEA81797428B47D39E746111D71CEFFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or any other nation not excluded by this section</quote> after <quote>trade in natural gas</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4055255F02C44E269F629B10FDEF084F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and in any event by not later than 60 days after the date on which the application is received</quote> before the period at the end; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFBC515995064292A215633A70B7864B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(c) For purposes</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H69A8CC4AF22C441A8FF3BEF23960A36B"><subsection id="H4A81FD6574AA410A8863FBFC1DFB722E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited application and approval process</header><paragraph id="HB8A0EC8E303541A48294A7A8BECD3875"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C78F5FDE0224730A08BE8C69F4AD988"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H256414E117A64915BC4622AC0AAFC69C"><paragraph id="H9C50869D07934057965836CB7CF827A5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><subparagraph id="HC92F42CA17114045B41753BB464C9EA1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any nation subject to sanctions or trade restrictions imposed by the United States is excluded from expedited approval under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5FBBC9ECE014FFE9B25356348FD13A8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation by President or Congress</header><text>The President or Congress may designate nations that may be excluded from expedited approval under paragraph (1) for reasons of national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H719AC017A55E43ADA5E0CD5503D471F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Order not required</header><text>No order is required under subsection (a) to authorize the export or import of any natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H45164C743B3449858077C8CA91405919"><enum>14.</enum><header>Pending applications to export natural gas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">All applications to export natural gas from the United States to a foreign country submitted under section 3(a) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b(a)</external-xref>) during the period beginning on January 1, 2020, and ending on January 1, 2025, are deemed approved. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

