<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H00E1C2D08355496EABF07D3807AD85BB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7757 IH: Emergency Migration Response Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7757</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220512">May 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for an emergency response by the Department of Homeland Security to migration surges, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H113AEFDB3ECA47B2A4F14F7FA0B94B2D" style="OLC"><section id="H9062D2A7CDD849C2BC8038980B9778A7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Migration Response Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBE6237C506444D798EE85CCC9D925273"><enum>2.</enum><header>Emergency response to migration surges</header><subsection id="H09DC3EE9562E49FAB1CC6D90FA97C9AC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority To declare an extraordinary migration event</header><paragraph id="H0F9D6C643D3046B5932076485E6D37CC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, at the request of the Secretary of Homeland Security or a State or local government entity, may declare an <quote>extraordinary migration event</quote> that is of such a magnitude that an appropriate, timely, or effective response is beyond the scope of the existing infrastructure and staffing levels of the Department of Homeland Security or State or local governmental resources. The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal, State, and local agencies, should establish quantitative and qualitative parameters described in paragraph (2) to determine if an event is an extraordinary migration event and when such a declaration of such an event should terminate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E8D9BDD78964BA1AABE369C057C7AA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Parameters described</header><text>Quantitative and qualitative parameters described in this paragraph may include the following: </text><subparagraph id="HB3A88C261E2B4B629FEF5B39868E6B3C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The average number of border apprehensions per week by U.S. Customs and Border Protection compared to historical data.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9EB690C778F42E38AF711A7C907ED26" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Staffing and resources available to the U.S. Border Patrol operating in sectors affected by a migrant surge.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA4A7C60266845AEA19164D2684E43B6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Migrant population composition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0C878C74A25469DB2390256824C32AC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Projected or assessed changes in any of the parameters described in this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF179E25223F14343AFCCB60C07BEAF84"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review and revision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal, State, and local agencies, should, not less frequently than annually, review and, if appropriate, revise the quantitative and qualitative parameters described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4EEAF78DADB492BA071D3C7C672B1F9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If a quantitative or qualitative parameter described in paragraph (2) is revised pursuant to paragraph (3), the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, not later than 30 days after each such revision notify the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate of each such revision.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA3DF84C2BE9C495B88DD86DECC9C6C21" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment of a Federal coordinating officer</header><paragraph id="H4C63FB5B79E646B58A96CA81F2A1EE4F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President, the President shall appoint an official of the Department of Homeland Security to serve as the Federal coordinating officer. Such officer shall report to the Secretary of Homeland Security and shall—</text><subparagraph id="H670EC751215D463BB2BD7BB1AB990E4B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an appraisal of the types of resources, including relating to transportation, facilities, personnel, health, and intelligence, necessary to respond to such an event; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB71E285E36F044389B0EB4D0D3F4C55E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate—</text><clause id="HB15269D66CAD4386905C1E8396984A85" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the administration of assistance and support offered to the Department by other Federal departments and agencies in response to such an event;</text></clause><clause id="H1685B1BEC89242638783B0511341D54D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>activities of State and local governments when requested by such governments in response to such an event; and</text></clause><clause id="H9F1D87DA34B14229909105FA63A5ACA3" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>activities of nongovernmental organizations providing relief and assistance operating in the area of such event and providing services to migrants in response to such event when requested by such organizations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF64CB164CF5947648F5884D0A3FDAA98" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>advise the Secretary and the President regarding appropriate timing relating to the termination of such an event.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1500B5293B2B4F3D95E308FAF0545318" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in paragraph (1) may be construed as prohibiting the senior coordinating official of the Southwest Border Coordination Center of the Department of Homeland Security from serving as the Federal coordinating officer appointed pursuant to such paragraph if the President determines such is appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBF5BD0F6593149E4A11B3DC53DFC958B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Southwest Border Coordination Center</header><paragraph id="H22EC11B933C34BE1870509D8145EAF84" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may utilize the capabilities of the Southwest Border Coordination Center of the Department of Homeland Security (SBCC) in response to the declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President. The Center may be staffed by officers and officials of the Department, including U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement (ICE), and United States Citizenship and Immigration Services (USCIS), as well as officers and officials of relevant Federal departments and agencies, including the Department of Justice, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC327F5EAA33A4376BDF59F43FBFE21DB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lead field coordinators</header><text>Subject to the direction of the Federal coordinating officer under subsection (b), the senior coordinating official of the Southwest Border Coordination Center may establish lead field coordinators in response to the declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB6FE0957749492BB41A0A7E74E44A60"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Incident management assistance teams</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the direction of the Federal coordinating officer under subsection (b), the senior coordinating official of the Southwest Border Coordination Center may establish incident management assistance teams to support the Center and lead field coordinators under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE795FAB7E14683BE20A641AE47926F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Incident Action Planning Process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In responding to the declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President, the Southwest Border Coordination Center shall use an Incident Action Planning Process to address emerging resource requirements related to such event.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DE845D7DEB848779914B65D27DD5E00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Formation of migration response teams</header><text>Upon the declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President, the Federal coordinating officer appointed pursuant to subsection (b) shall establish migration response teams to be deployed to assist the Southwest Border Coordination Cell under subsection (c), including relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="HF25372F57BDB43438E605126417FE628" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Coordinating the construction of specialized migration processing facilities with staff from other Federal departments and agencies, State and local governments, and nongovernmental organizations to assist with the humanitarian needs of arriving migrants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2208B694946948B286937E2F52CF925D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Working with U.S. Customs and Border Protection, the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the Department of Health and Human Services, and other appropriate organizations to establish temporary holding facilities for migrants.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA26700160CB04BDAB1D4E6E992B15882"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Coordinating with the National Disaster Medical System of the Department of Health and Human Services, and, as appropriate, FEMA Corps, the private sector, and the National Guard, to ensure such facilities are staffed with health professionals who are able to provide medical and mental health assistance and other humanitarian support to such migrants.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1DAC52C6C8A4452C8A1D4C0E21FE362C" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Formation of processing teams</header><text>Upon declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President, the Secretary of Homeland Security may take such actions as may be necessary to process in a timely manner individuals arriving at the border, including by—</text><paragraph id="H99C0C33B29484E73A82D020C95547451"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reassigning United States Citizenship and Immigration Services asylum officers and interpreters to U.S. Customs and Border Protection border facilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72BA10D76D9043E0BEB8333D48F76F14"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">surging resources to process migrants in their countries of origin.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3FE20A06FF8E477CBB1814EDEDC56680"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Arrangements with relief and assistance organizations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Federal coordinating officer under subsection (b), and their designees may enter into arrangements with nongovernmental organizations providing relief and assistance operating in the area of such event to utilize the personnel and facilities of such organizations to provide essential services, including housing, temporary shelter, medical, legal, or other essential services, to migrants. Any such arrangements shall include provisions assuring that use of Federal facilities, supplies, and services adhere to regulations prohibiting duplication of benefits and guaranteeing nondiscrimination.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA0AC7C4D8CB4224B50E1395C0E00DCC" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There is established an Emergency Migration Response Fund. There is authorized to be appropriated to the Fund for fiscal 2023 up to $1,500,000,000 to be made available to carry out this Act in the event of a declaration of an extraordinary migration event by the President, including—</text><paragraph id="H58308E3E9298408AAF0A83452B2394A0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$1,060,000,000 for U.S. Customs and Border Protection soft-sided facilities, medical care, transportation, and personnel costs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H112886A1F6BB405494F8E00D1C20D82A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$150,000,000 for the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s Emergency Food and Shelter Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95C15F161C2A4701ADD05D83AA1C7226" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for United States Citizenship and Immigration Services personnel costs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E88E0E31610484785DB91797E119A4E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$50,000,000 for Federal Emergency Management Agency for grants to supporting relief organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1735394F015F44F48066CEF2122597C9" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the President declares an extraordinary migration event, the President shall transmit to Congress a notification relating thereto. Such notification shall include information describing the actions taken pursuant to this Act in response to such an event, including information relating to funding, personnel, and resources.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

