<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4404095A8344FA8AA7A01A6E7A7F4E9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9513 IH: Honest Ads Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9513</legis-num> 
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20221213">December 13, 2022</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To enhance transparency and accountability for online political advertisements by requiring those who purchase and publish such ads to disclose information about the advertisements to the public, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H590272539B8F4F5DA454045A0A88287D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H966CEC86A9944E07914312926C915789" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Honest Ads Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H25FE0DF42AD049F4B703212E4EA44FC1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to enhance the integrity of American democracy and national security by improving disclosure requirements for online political advertisements in order to uphold the Supreme Court’s well-established standard that the electorate bears the right to be fully informed.</text></section> 
<section id="HFA6F3219A3E8436598552F8D5350BC17"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> <paragraph id="HB86262496CBE4E03A4277C7DD9A3B0E2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In 2002, the Bipartisan Campaign Reform Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/107/155">Public Law 107–155</external-xref>) became law, establishing disclosure requirements for political advertisements distributed from a television or radio broadcast station or provider of cable or satellite television. In 2003, the Supreme Court upheld regulations on electioneering communications established under the Act, noting that such requirements <quote>provide the electorate with information and insure that the voters are fully informed about the person or group who is speaking</quote>. The Court reaffirmed this conclusion in 2010 by an 8–1 vote.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A19680DAA36458BBF43DFF187121C6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In its 2006 rulemaking, the Federal Election Commission, the independent Federal agency charged with protecting the integrity of the Federal campaign finance process, noted that 18 percent of all Americans cited the internet as their leading source of news about the 2004 Presidential election. By contrast, Gallup and the Knight Foundation found in 2020 that the majority of Americans, 58 percent, got most of their news about elections online.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DC30C16CA4C45CFAB2574FDC3607E59"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to a study from Borrell Associates, in 2016, $1,415,000,000 was spent on online advertising, more than quadruple the amount in 2012.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H35F8259D06AA4C7D8374B8AC7029383D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Effective and complete transparency for voters must include information about the true and original source of money given, transferred, and spent on political advertisements made online.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF33B1C5DB4C49CA95464A55B1D8AA98"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Requiring the disclosure of this information is a necessary and narrowly tailored means to inform the voting public of who is behind digital advertising disseminated to influence their votes and to enable the Federal Election Commission and the Department of Justice to detect and prosecute illegal foreign spending on local, State, and Federal elections and other campaign finance violations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2D0ADEECF7041BEA364695BF6B49A4D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Paid advertising on large online platforms is different from advertising placed on other common media in terms of the comparatively low cost of reaching large numbers of people, the availability of sophisticated microtargeting, and the ease with which online advertisers, particularly those located outside the United States, can evade disclosure requirements. Requiring large online platforms to maintain public files of information about the online political ads they disseminate is the best and least restrictive means to ensure the voting public has complete information about who is trying to influence their votes and to aid enforcement of other laws, including the prohibition on foreign money in domestic campaigns.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92160C4FBA664285A5B8A2A1EEEEDA42"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The reach of a few large internet platforms—larger than any broadcast, satellite, or cable provider—has greatly facilitated the scope and effectiveness of disinformation campaigns. For instance, the largest platform has over 210,000,000 American users—over 160,000,000 of them on a daily basis. By contrast, the largest cable television provider has 22,430,000 subscribers, while the largest satellite television provider has 21,000,000 subscribers, and the most-watched television broadcast in United States history had 118,000,000 viewers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H889C193447E94BAAB84BD0B5FC61070F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The public nature of broadcast television, radio, and satellite ensures a level of publicity for any political advertisement. These communications are accessible to the press, fact-checkers, and political opponents. This creates strong disincentives for a candidate to disseminate materially false, inflammatory, or contradictory messages to the public. Social media platforms, in contrast, can target portions of the electorate with direct, ephemeral advertisements often on the basis of private information the platform has on individuals, enabling political advertisements that are contradictory, racially or socially inflammatory, or materially false.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC77049DF180A466C8219A309465F6AEC"><enum>(9)</enum><text>According to Comscore, 2 companies own 8 of the 10 most popular smart phone applications as of June 2017, including the most popular social media and email services which deliver information and news to users without requiring proactivity by the user. Those same 2 companies accounted for 99 percent of revenue growth from digital advertising in 2016, including 77 percent of gross spending. 79 percent of online Americans—representing 68 percent of all Americans—use the single largest social network, while 66 percent of these users are most likely to get their news from that site.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H90742E46C51B497D851319B48859DA6D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Large social media platforms are the only entities in possession of certain key data related to paid online ads, including the exact audience targeted by those ads and their number of impressions. Such information, which cannot be reliably disclosed by the purchasers of ads, is extremely useful for informing the electorate, guarding against corruption, and aiding in the enforcement of existing campaign finance regulations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H234C949DE4D1406EB0863A5E25901599"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Paid advertisements on social media platforms have served as critical tools for foreign online influence campaigns—even those that rely on large amounts of unpaid content—because such ads allow foreign actors to test the effectiveness of different messages, expose their messages to audiences who have not sought out such content, and recruit audiences for future campaigns and posts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB19B8021B884229AFD7A7C6922ED713"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In testimony before the Senate Select Committee on Intelligence titled, <quote>Disinformation: A Primer in Russian Active Measures and Influence Campaigns</quote>, multiple expert witnesses testified that while the disinformation tactics of foreign adversaries have not necessarily changed, social media services now provide <quote>platform[s] practically purpose-built for active measures[.]</quote>. Similarly, as Gen. Keith B. Alexander (RET.), the former Director of the National Security Agency, testified, during the Cold War <quote>if the Soviet Union sought to manipulate information flow, it would have to do so principally through its own propaganda outlets or through active measures that would generate specific news: planting of leaflets, inciting of violence, creation of other false materials and narratives. But the news itself was hard to manipulate because it would have required actual control of the organs of media, which took long-term efforts to penetrate. Today, however, because the clear majority of the information on social media sites is uncurated and there is a rapid proliferation of information sources and other sites that can reinforce information, there is an increasing likelihood that the information available to average consumers may be inaccurate (whether intentionally or otherwise) and may be more easily manipulable than in prior eras.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HED056AE4C16844D08974AB2AD26A11AB"><enum>(13)</enum><text>On November 24, 2016, The Washington Post reported findings from 2 teams of independent researchers that concluded Russians <quote>exploited American-made technology platforms to attack U.S. democracy at a particularly vulnerable moment * * * as part of a broadly effective strategy of sowing distrust in U.S. democracy and its leaders.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0549BE3D427546D180CD4F79C4B5629D"><enum>(14)</enum><text>On January 6, 2017, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence published a report titled <quote>Assessing Russian Activities and Intentions in Recent U.S. Elections</quote>, noting that <quote>Russian President Vladimir Putin ordered an influence campaign in 2016 aimed at the U.S. presidential election * * *</quote>. Moscow’s influence campaign followed a Russian messaging strategy that blends covert intelligence operation—such as cyber activity—with overt efforts by Russian Government agencies, State-funded media, third-party intermediaries, and paid social media users or <quote>trolls</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE56DDA4648164CC181E24C17F3B6DF7D"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On September 6, 2017, the nation’s largest social media platform disclosed that between June 2015 and May 2017, Russian entities purchased $100,000 in political advertisements, publishing roughly 3,000 ads linked to fake accounts associated with the Internet Research Agency, a pro-Kremlin organization. According to the company, the ads purchased focused <quote>on amplifying divisive social and political messages * * *</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H483433D644FA4764B311AD33AC17BEA8"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Findings from a 2017 study on the manipulation of public opinion through social media conducted by the Computational Propaganda Research Project at the Oxford Internet Institute found that the Kremlin is using pro-Russian bots to manipulate public discourse to a highly targeted audience. With a sample of nearly 1,300,000 tweets, researchers found that in the 2016 election’s 3 decisive States, propaganda constituted 40 percent of the sampled election-related tweets that went to Pennsylvanians, 34 percent to Michigan voters, and 30 percent to those in Wisconsin. In other swing States, the figure reached 42 percent in Missouri, 41 percent in Florida, 40 percent in North Carolina, 38 percent in Colorado, and 35 percent in Ohio.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59B9436D7A314A428A258DE8B884972A"><enum>(17)</enum><text>2018 reporting by the Washington Post estimated that paid Russian ads received more than 37,000,000 impressions in 2016 and 2017.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBDD86BE35CB2477781C5FF2E655C759C"><enum>(18)</enum><text>A 2019 Senate Select Committee on Intelligence’s Report on Russian Active Measures Campaigns and Interference in the 2016 U.S. Election Volume 2: Russia’s Use of Social Media with Additional Views, the Committee recommended <quote>that Congress examine legislative approaches to ensuring Americans know the sources of online political advertisements. The Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 requires political advertisements on television, radio and satellite to disclose the sponsor of the advertisement. The same requirements should apply online. This will also help to ensure that the IRA or any similarly situated actors cannot use paid advertisements for purposes of foreign interference.</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H381F52E63F2249B5AB02413D4A219FA2"><enum>(19)</enum><text>A 2020 study by researchers at New York University found undisclosed political advertisement purchases on a large social media platform by a Chinese State media company in violation of that platform’s supposed prohibitions on foreign spending on ads of social, national, or electoral importance.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7B01CEA27FAB4398A6EDF9926B1CF7D5"><enum>(20)</enum><text>The same study also found that <quote>there are persistent issues with advertisers failing to disclose political ads</quote> and that in one social media platform’s political ad archive, 68,879 pages (54.6 percent of pages with political ads included in the archive) never provided a disclosure. Overall, there were 357,099 ads run on that platform without a disclosure, accounting for at least $37,000,000 in spending on political ads.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCDC34D117EF4451D9152E7E688BF7975"><enum>(21)</enum><text>A 2020 report by the bipartisan and bicameral U.S. Cyberspace Solarium Commission found that <quote>Although foreign nationals are banned from contributing to U.S. political campaigns, they are still allowed to purchase U.S. political advertisements online, making the internet a fertile environment for conducting a malign influence campaign to undermine American elections.</quote>. The Commission concluded that Russian interference in the 2016 election was and still is possible, <quote>because the FECA, which establishes rules for transparency in television, radio, and print media political advertising, has not been amended to extend the same political advertising requirements to internet platforms,</quote> and that <quote>[a]pplying these standards across all media of communication would, among other things, increase transparency of funding for political advertisements, which would in turn strengthen regulators’ ability to reduce improper foreign influence in our elections</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD4B96D1EF9D4EAE916947C378FF7BD2"><enum>(22)</enum><text>On March 16, 2021, the Office of the Director of National Intelligence released the declassified Intelligence Community assessment of foreign threats to the 2020 U.S. Federal elections. The declassified report found: <quote>Throughout the election cycle, Russia’s online influence actors sought to affect U.S. public perceptions of the candidates, as well as advance Moscow’s longstanding goals of undermining confidence in U.S. election processes and increasing sociopolitical divisions among the American people.</quote>. The report also determined that Iran sought to influence the election by <quote>creating and amplifying social media content that criticized [candidates]</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1C17169032E34D6BA64704D7955D37C2"><enum>(23)</enum><text>According to a Wall Street Journal report in April 2021, voluntary ad libraries operated by major platforms rely on foreign governments to self-report political ad purchases. These ad buys, including those diminishing major human rights violations like the Uighur genocide, are under-reported by foreign government purchasers, with no substantial oversight or repercussions from the platforms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3442BEE2318C47EB92E712EF07DE495C"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Multiple reports have indicated that online ads have become a key vector for strategic influence by the People’s Republic of China. An April 2021 Wall Street Journal report noted that the Chinese Government and Chinese State-owned enterprises are major purchasers of ads on the U.S.’s largest social media platform, including to advance Chinese propaganda.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2C2FE836FE184586883617A2725BCC32"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Large online platforms have made changes to their policies intended to make it harder for foreign actors to purchase political ads. However, these private actions have not been taken by all platforms, have not been reliably enforced, and are subject to immediate change at the discretion of the platforms.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC90D1983AF8A46718DAFDF9EE95D5A41"><enum>(26)</enum><text>The Federal Election Commission has failed to take action to address online political advertisements and current regulations on political advertisements do not provide sufficient transparency to uphold the public’s right to be fully informed about political advertisements made online.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HC1959C569B1E4669AA8B017BD857C22A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4046D7FE218F4EAE8E16CB0B8C677EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the dramatic increase in digital political advertisements, and the growing centrality of online platforms in the lives of Americans, requires the Congress and the Federal Election Commission to take meaningful action to ensure that laws and regulations provide the accountability and transparency that is fundamental to our democracy;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB9DF89196BCF42EE92A4368761DAD22A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>free and fair elections require both transparency and accountability which give the public a right to know the true sources of funding for political advertisements, be they foreign or domestic, in order to make informed political choices and hold elected officials accountable; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2403CCBBB376429EA770FD4FA46BED30"><enum>(3)</enum><text>transparency of funding for political advertisements is essential to enforce other campaign finance laws, including the prohibition on campaign spending by foreign nationals.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HCDA057BA77FD461DA3C4938101211405"><enum>5.</enum><header>Expansion of definition of public communication</header> <subsection id="H322F570E24F4459285319BD102FE1F78"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (22) of section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101(22)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or satellite communication</quote> and inserting <quote>satellite, paid internet, or paid digital communication</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9DCCF75568834E899C0C648F617D20A6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Treatment of contributions and expenditures</header><text>Section 301 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H3A7B2E7ACBCF4BEFB44C263EA0498D53"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (8)(B)(v), by striking <quote>on broadcasting stations, or in newspapers, magazines, or similar types of general public political advertising</quote> and inserting <quote>in any public communication</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H319A346622EC44C494853CD4B6CB77D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9)(B)—</text> <subparagraph id="HCC4499000945441A8297CDD7E39BEBB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6C03AAB57A56484F9A37B9B09B2CC086" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="HE8F8FF60F1D44ECAA840B25CB5EC3416"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any news story, commentary, or editorial distributed through the facilities of any broadcasting station or any print, online, or digital newspaper, magazine, blog, publication, or periodical, unless such broadcasting, print, online, or digital facilities are owned or controlled by any political party, political committee, or candidate;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3E3DEDDC3FA24D978173C6C474168703"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>on broadcasting stations, or in newspapers, magazines, or similar types of general public political advertising</quote> and inserting <quote>in any public communication</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0826978E07FE4033A70F7F3BB1E1C1DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure and disclaimer statements</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 318 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30120">52 U.S.C. 30120</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HC68427960C7B40BA9FADB3D1650749BA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>financing any communication through any broadcasting station, newspaper, magazine, outdoor advertising facility, mailing, or any other type of general public political advertising</quote> and inserting <quote>financing any public communication</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H533C7C3E05654A30B1983574B2D71B4C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>solicits any contribution through any broadcasting station, newspaper, magazine, outdoor advertising facility, mailing, or any other type of general public political advertising</quote> and inserting <quote>solicits any contribution through any public communication</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H75E98622B6B847BD9AF905453726E211"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall take effect without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated the final regulations necessary to carry out this part and the amendments made by this part by the deadline set forth in subsection (e).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H878289F08E3E4E7186F6CDE7B0F2766E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Election Commission shall promulgate regulations on what constitutes a paid internet or paid digital communication for purposes of paragraph (22) of section 301 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30101">52 U.S.C. 30101(22)</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), except that such regulation shall not define a paid internet or paid digital communication to include communications for which the only payment consists of internal resources, such as employee compensation, of the entity paying for the communication.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H6257D09511D646838A20929F0DBF965C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Expansion of definition of electioneering communication</header> <subsection id="H5D8338AB20D24D87BB9733773111E366"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expansion to online communications</header> <paragraph id="H93474CC9409B4467ACFB0BE8F8786EAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application to qualified Internet and digital communications</header> <subparagraph id="H4333406E97634E0C9D3B1BA0B87FD24F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subparagraph (A) of section 304(f)(3) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104(f)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or satellite communication</quote> each place it appears in clauses (i) and (ii) and inserting <quote>satellite, or qualified internet or digital communication</quote>.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA008331B5144C458E5EF041EEFB102D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Qualified internet or digital communication</header><text>Paragraph (3) of section 304(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBAEA3786C4504CA9B0B00944F3362B7C" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H9ACC7B397F08475E8F94C0A514868DB5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Qualified internet or digital communication</header><text>The term <term>qualified internet or digital communication</term> means any communication which is placed or promoted for a fee on an online platform (as defined in subsection (j)(3)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9286AEBD7E1241AB9C5B663049611124"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonapplication of relevant electorate to online communications</header><text>Section 304(f)(3)(A)(i)(III) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104(f)(3)(A)(i)(III)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>any broadcast, cable, or satellite</quote> before <quote>communication</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H8B4A2FDF227D4D1D83D97C8625C1E71E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>News exemption</header><text>Section 304(f)(3)(B)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104(f)(3)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H78AEA6BCBBC44809A4995EDC232FC70A" style="OLC"> 
<clause id="H2D3F3521CE524883937AC87E2CBA9A55"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a communication appearing in a news story, commentary, or editorial distributed through the facilities of any broadcasting station or any online or digital newspaper, magazine, blog, publication, or periodical, unless such broadcasting, online, or digital facilities are owned or controlled by any political party, political committee, or candidate;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HE59E6CBAB2934C4A92469A76447F4606"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to communications made on or after January 1, 2023, and shall take effect without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated regulations to carry out such amendments.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="HF64EDDF08E4F4973BC70BAF9D7756E57"><enum>7.</enum><header>Application of disclaimer statements to online communications</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H9D06B6021BA041C2937FC8CBD7011119"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clear and conspicuous manner requirement</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 318 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30120">52 U.S.C. 30120(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H06323425031E44679AAA8B92913309F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall clearly state</quote> each place it appears in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3) and inserting <quote>shall state in a clear and conspicuous manner</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H690AB9697CD440FD827132CF19730611"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following flush sentence: <quote>For purposes of this section, a communication does not make a statement in a clear and conspicuous manner if it is difficult to read or hear or if the placement is easily overlooked.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HF8886DE4900C44A785C77EA9BBBF31BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special rules for qualified Internet or digital communications</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HB2456FC5D86B4E0580F17B941C8FBBF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 318 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30120">52 U.S.C. 30120</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF0AD8B61C4EC4E229BC35F2FFA9B65DF" style="OLC"> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H2E2A21AD3E6343A890B968F605D54B6B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Special rules for qualified internet or digital communications</header> 
<paragraph id="H2B2E7B4F1B874F5F96B5F23258F77740"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Special rules with respect to statements</header><text>In the case of any qualified internet or digital communication (as defined in section 304(f)(3)(D)) which is disseminated through a medium in which the provision of all of the information specified in this section is not possible, the communication shall, in a clear and conspicuous manner—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H924ABCDCB02640BA98A00CF7F954283B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>state the name of the person who paid for the communication; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H9195531BEB664FCE83526C132050102C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a means for the recipient of the communication to obtain the remainder of the information required under this section with minimal effort and without receiving or viewing any additional material other than such required information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5550C4787DC9478B88E30CDA9917909F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Safe harbor for determining clear and conspicuous manner</header><text>A statement in qualified internet or digital communication (as defined in section 304(f)(3)(D)) shall be considered to be made in a clear and conspicuous manner as provided in subsection (a) if the communication meets the following requirements:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HDFFE2F4C4B644191A3AEE17B55A40DA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Text or graphic communications</header><text>In the case of a text or graphic communication, the statement—</text> <clause id="H5BD3B971B63845489A729D4B47CFA611"><enum>(i)</enum><text>appears in letters at least as large as the majority of the text in the communication; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H817DA035D844417D8EA2404F0FC976D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>meets the requirements of paragraphs (2) and (3) of subsection (c).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H95976707263F4A31986D000A73609AB1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audio communications</header><text>In the case of an audio communication, the statement is spoken in a clearly audible and intelligible manner at the beginning or end of the communication and lasts at least 3 seconds.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4DADB53C323A4392AD1235F0D4C1D7D5"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Video communications</header><text>In the case of a video communication which also includes audio, the statement—</text> <clause id="H4CD2C92F106A45DB92748C2E74572A8A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is included at either the beginning or the end of the communication; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1B8F91021A534049850131BB168470F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is made both in—</text> <subclause id="H11D9A6E5D8BE4E9BA049F6E3CD381A8C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a written format that meets the requirements of subparagraph (A) and appears for at least 4 seconds; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1132AF48B08547DD9D93CF854571AC6F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an audible format that meets the requirements of subparagraph (B).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3A8C269303BE496FB3681F28AEA07991"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Other communications</header><text>In the case of any other type of communication, the statement is at least as clear and conspicuous as the statement specified in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H443B1E5F317146C0859F4417DBC1F049"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Nonapplication of certain exceptions</header><text>The exceptions provided in section 110.11(f)(1)(i) and (ii) of title 11, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor to such rules, shall have no application to qualified internet or digital communications (as defined in section 304(f)(3)(D) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H85E483EE8E65456D9CB4C87FEC7DE7E3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Modification of additional requirements for certain communications</header><text>Section 318(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30120">52 U.S.C. 30120(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H7BEA2EA766F5429AB55B781B6EA92827"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H06963057926A442190F5EC46DD4CF4CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>which is transmitted through radio</quote> and inserting <quote>which is in an audio format</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HB745DDD1A7534C3A9BFF8945E00E50E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">By radio</header-in-text></quote> in the heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Audio format</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H98E381F1C2314FF5ADB7668263D6A773"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(B)—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H0DE00A9B889B4A25BDE6590E0747CF82"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>which is transmitted through television</quote> and inserting <quote>which is in video format</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HBE7B5A4F864B47C285A8BE804099D09F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">By television</header-in-text></quote> in the heading and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Video format</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HD680C0B4FEA144919B1BB7069B36FD50"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H3BCBE452EDCD436FB2F9213BA991BBBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>transmitted through radio or television</quote> and inserting <quote>made in audio or video format</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBE904FA7F71B463BA2C0CE2B2DF20374"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>through television</quote> in the second sentence and inserting <quote>in video format</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4B1D4195C5F84D4A859B91B6F710719D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall take effect without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated regulations to carry out such amendments.</text></subsection></section> 
<section commented="no" id="HFFFB50F106BD47C6A1373687103389D2"><enum>8.</enum><header>Political record requirements for online platforms</header> 
<subsection commented="no" id="H6D3A07FA1D3B466B81AB05FDDA6B049A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 304 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H10208DDE96C84D29A08EA1CC1F332310" style="OLC"> <subsection commented="no" id="H79CAD38D4BEC4C52B7E182230C1E5A4B"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Disclosure of certain online advertisements</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="H315BB3A70F034911B5B65B138362B9EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HB090BBB4682C44A786B70B5096E0EA03"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirements for online platforms</header> <clause commented="no" id="H60C6D5150DF341899F080EA67920D415"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An online platform shall maintain, and make available for online public inspection in machine-readable format, a complete record of any request to purchase on such online platform a qualified political advertisement which is made by a person whose aggregate requests to purchase qualified political advertisements on such online platform during the calendar year exceeds $500.</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H33AE8C29908B48C2AF2BC15533599C67"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement relating to political ads sold by third-party advertising vendors</header><text>An online platform that displays a qualified political advertisement sold by a third-party advertising vendor as defined in (3)(C), shall include on its own platform an easily accessible and identifiable link to the records maintained by the third-party advertising vendor under clause (i) regarding such qualified political advertisement.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H317E64ABD7594817B4C1D48FCDF86BDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for advertisers</header><text>Any person who requests to purchase a qualified political advertisement on an online platform shall provide the online platform with such information as is necessary for the online platform to comply with the requirements of subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAA53B50835624248A9E723874FAF56B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of record</header><text>A record maintained under paragraph (1)(A) shall contain—</text> <subparagraph id="HF6DB083B30864CB4AEB50D68330C9309"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a digital copy of the qualified political advertisement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HC3D9F2E8E48846D0ADDDC1A4D69B4A50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of the audience targeted by the advertisement, the number of views generated from the advertisement, and the date and time that the advertisement is first displayed and last displayed; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91CCC57576F64FF39D10017861B0A675"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information regarding—</text> 
<clause id="HC7CD0FF6A1724D008D42E78666FE9F5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total cost of the advertisement;</text></clause> <clause id="HF4A7354AEC854CAB96FD08E61EADD564"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name of the candidate to which the advertisement refers and the office to which the candidate is seeking election, the election to which the advertisement refers, or the national legislative issue to which the advertisement refers (as applicable);</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE80B24711654E829A7C0D6F2DC99ACD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a request made by, or on behalf of, a candidate, the name of the candidate, the authorized committee of the candidate, and the treasurer of such committee; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB86C3E43240E42E1899AE709EF2DA34A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in the case of any request not described in clause (iii), the name of the person purchasing the advertisement, the name and address of a contact person for such person, and a list of the chief executive officers or members of the executive committee or of the board of directors of such person.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE7CCAF5EE8E346EE83694418745985CD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Online platform</header> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H974F001928F74A56B6712AB138EBAFB6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>online platform</term> means any public-facing website, web application, or digital application (including a social network, ad network, or search engine) which—</text> <clause id="HEBDA7887BA134E63BCE008F003E60076"><enum>(i)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4904CE039B4F4E47A466EB97935B6780"><enum>(I)</enum><text>sells qualified political advertisements; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8AF548534A604E358FCBD1655AF0CC23" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has 50,000,000 or more unique monthly United States visitors or users for a majority of months during the preceding 12 months; or</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1EB25D5404F64100B12361DBEEE0B80A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is a third-party advertising vendor that has 50,000,000 or more unique monthly United States visitors in the aggregate on any advertisement space that it has sold or bought for a majority of months during the preceding 12 months, as measured by an independent digital ratings service accredited by the Media Ratings Council (or its successor).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA246810DC1B940E6A4C4499B995CD8BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Such term shall not include any online platform that is a distribution facility of any broadcasting station or newspaper, magazine, blog, publication, or periodical.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F9F37BE7F8447D7B69FC001EF97F7FE"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Third-party advertising vendor defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>third-party advertising vendor</term> includes, but is not limited to, any third-party advertising vendor network, advertising agency, advertiser, or third-party advertisement serving company that buys and sells advertisement space on behalf of unaffiliated third-party websites, search engines, digital applications, or social media sites.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33C877737CFB4D3AA004A0B8C114D761"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualified political advertisement</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>qualified political advertisement</term> means any advertisement (including search engine marketing, display advertisements, video advertisements, native advertisements, and sponsorships) that—</text> <subparagraph id="H9748290E89424A3490D3647B1CEAE226"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is made by or on behalf of a candidate; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE5D6C517AF374ECD8FA060BE461765C0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>communicates a message relating to any political matter of national importance, including—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H4A313A44A9A341AF88FF36A1728694E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a candidate;</text></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="HDEEB916F298642689A0C1F7824A6E297"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any election to Federal office; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="HC808E7A8B5F9418382C9CE9829B44822"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a national legislative issue of public importance.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E780F6969944779A7B2AA3D2F7143F3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Time to maintain file</header><text>The information required under this subsection shall be made available as soon as possible and shall be retained by the online platform for a period of not less than 4 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CEF0161B43443728EDBA61DCE1BD4A3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, multiple versions of an advertisement that contain no material differences (such as versions that differ only because they contain a recipient’s name, or differ only in size, color, font, or layout) may be treated as a single qualified political advertisement.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0FCDCD68F485452A842BEA5727E428A9"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>For penalties for failure by online platforms, and persons requesting to purchase a qualified political advertisement on online platforms, to comply with the requirements of this subsection, see section 309.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H56DB81E293B34C7BA40B40A33C47E691"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act and shall take effect without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated the final regulations necessary to carry out this part and the amendments made by this part by the deadline set forth in subsection (c).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9AA8027B3CF4E58A6AEB5359837B425"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Election Commission shall establish rules—</text> <paragraph id="H9366082D1756463AA45A7533E818EB16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requiring common data formats for the record required to be maintained under section 304(j) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (as added by subsection (a)) so that all online platforms submit and maintain data online in a common, machine-readable and publicly accessible format; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BF54DF1BAFF42609375131FB7F3E3B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establishing search interface requirements relating to such record, including searches by candidate name, issue, purchaser, and date.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7516360BF8CB4AADA87EAE4967612CF1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, the Chairman of the Federal Election Commission shall submit a report to Congress on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFFBFBE4E4FF449DFA037B1771F9C7925"><enum>(1)</enum><text>matters relating to compliance with and the enforcement of the requirements of section 304(j) of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, as added by subsection (a);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H006081B612DD44E8BC69605EB3C0E9BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations for any modifications to such section to assist in carrying out its purposes; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BA2D63C46C748B495FDC38BC27EFF9E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying ways to bring transparency and accountability to political advertisements distributed online for free.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H164674A9E60A44A8B860505F38F5C958"><enum>9.</enum><header>Preventing contributions, expenditures, independent expenditures, and disbursements for electioneering communications by foreign nationals in the form of online advertising</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 319 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30121">52 U.S.C. 30121</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD33CE5B72AD043F79B37BD7CDCC778E0" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H9611ECE24AA9477985F3EC2217DEE816"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibilities of broadcast stations, providers of cable and satellite television, and online platforms</header> 
<paragraph id="HC51FF5B09FC44D3B8CE7331C1D455E68"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each television or radio broadcast station, provider of cable or satellite television, or online platform (as defined in section 304(j)(3)) shall make reasonable efforts to ensure that communications described in section 318(a) and made available by such station, provider, or platform are not purchased by a foreign national, directly or indirectly.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE98F8BAEB8C74308BC9B3269C65F6116"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Commission shall promulgate regulations on what constitutes reasonable efforts under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H75ECCDEA77484A9ABE5CEB110F636F5F"><enum>10.</enum><header>Requiring online platforms to display notices identifying sponsors of political advertisements and to ensure notices continue to be present when advertisements are shared</header> 
<subsection id="H2E0D08ACE03646EA8BC61D226EB56F58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 304 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30104">52 U.S.C. 30104</external-xref>), as amended by section 8(a), is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC5C3A1259F434FAC9A46BAF83F6B7054" style="OLC"> <subsection id="HF6EF412DA1F04E30A406B63CDD9CC34E"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Ensuring display and sharing of sponsor identification in online political advertisements</header> <paragraph id="H042CDC733BD54C34B8FF0E1C8B8DD1CA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>An online platform displaying a qualified political advertisement shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA12D81429DA64046BB3BBCAC2CE80C67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>display with the advertisement a visible notice identifying the sponsor of the advertisement (or, if it is not practical for the platform to display such a notice, a notice that the advertisement is sponsored by a person other than the platform); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5AD1C0B1E2944DC998F1E1BC52426A5D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the notice will continue to be displayed if a viewer of the advertisement shares the advertisement with others on that platform.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H76CE63F243D3428C9D7ADD27A7874AA9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text> <subparagraph id="H9BCC8AC988054789B4950BDF9249C3CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>online platform</term> has the meaning given such term in subsection (j)(3); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBB41D045FC8C475CBE7D44D8EC4CB4EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term ‘<term>qualified political advertisement</term> has the meaning given such term in subsection (j)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC8530310DF264A6F9AB7E4F45549CD8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall take effect on the date of the enactment of this Act without regard to whether or not the Federal Election Commission has promulgated regulations to carry out such amendment.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
</bill> 


