<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H034F3E2A41EC4CCC88FBA75CDB260E0C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9639 IH: Higher Standards for Higher Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9639</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Education to report default and other data for each program of study of certain institutions of higher education for which the Secretary annually reports cohort default data under the Higher Education Act of 1965.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB4E090C69FF7419D8F8B788F5E589EF6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5E263D6A0E104F2FBCD75E1FA4ABB12D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Higher Standards for Higher Education Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDE14A69C491440EB89F874EA75685576"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collection and reporting of default data for certain programs of study</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 435(m)(4) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(m)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H04FE8A167ECA48AEBB72D4BC3C6B640D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H487D7CFAD23347508CDEC89B0BE47056"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Program of study reporting requirements</header> 
<clause id="H9B22DE160AF24CD88DDFFB3F4DCD878E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to clause (ii), for each fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Higher Standards for Higher Education Act</short-title>, the Secretary shall include in the annual report required under subparagraph (C), for each covered institution for which a cohort default rate is calculated under this subsection for a fiscal year, the following with respect each program of study of such institution in which one or more current and former students at the institution who enter repayment in that fiscal year on Federal Direct Stafford Loans, Federal Direct PLUS Loans, or Federal Direct Unsubsidized Stafford Loans, received for attendance at the institution, are enrolled (in the case of a current student) or were most recently enrolled prior to entering repayment (in the case of a former student):</text> <subclause id="HFDACD0C96F3E4D4E95C4C4B687C0C9EF"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of those current and former students who enter repayment on such loans (or on the portion of a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan that is used to repay any such loans) in that fiscal year. </text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="H44A0C4606C704ADC96994E86D6DD4609"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the students identified in subclause (I), the percentage who default on any such loan before the end of the second succeeding fiscal year following the fiscal year in which the students entered repayment. </text></subclause> <subclause id="H2498FE14046248C68E407DC0F4ED2CCA"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage who are between 31 and 360 days delinquent on any such loan before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF92F572EED4C4BE6B350F53175290432"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage who are in forbearance on any such loan before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCF3D81F63EEF4F3E82B1F333D2B42BE8"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Of such students, the percentage who are in deferment on any such loan before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF93D201CD7BC410D80C2ECECBBFE0F7F"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage who—</text> <item id="HFC9031517DCF4372AF19935509D68E32"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been making regular payments on such loans, but for whom—</text> 
<subitem id="H7E2BD1AB04574AB0A8B88A3AFED662C8"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>on any day before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year, the sum of the outstanding balance due on such loans, exceeds</text></subitem> <subitem id="H00E9E9508E71436C882FE3344C795286"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum of the outstanding balance due on such loans on the date that is one year preceding the day in subitem (AA); and</text></subitem></item> 
<item id="HD591482813824663A981DFB5CB7A1233"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not described in subclauses (II) through (V).</text></item> </subclause> <subclause id="H92759E769FC444F2BAEDEA490E81B01F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage who—</text> 
<item id="HAFCD72DF288842EF8AF11D19F9F3388F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have been making regular payments on such loans, and for whom—</text> <subitem id="H1D6596A24FF3472DAE6DFCE952E9BA74"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>on any day before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year, the sum of the outstanding balance due on such loans, is less than</text></subitem> 
<subitem id="H54060AF56FC24013A0A80BA8416C5283"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the sum of the outstanding balance due on such loans on the date that is one year preceding the day in subitem (AA); and</text> </subitem></item> <item id="HE69ADAD9E9C3453696246EA7FB790AA5"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are not described in subclauses (II) through (V).</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H87820D7D6B0F4155AA773FDE30EE38D0"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage who, before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year—</text> <item id="HB1683AC7A7CD4A9A927D3BD9E71F9086"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are making regular payments on such loans, and for whom—</text> 
<subitem id="H9A399E7C1E5F483D8C3CE8A6ACBE33CB"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>the sum of the outstanding balance due on such loans, is less than</text></subitem> <subitem id="H9564B779F9EA4799833E1E1196D41414"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>the sum of the original balance due on such loans; and</text></subitem></item> 
<item id="H54E59777AE8243B0AFFFB8CADAE6A353"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>are not described in subclauses (II) through (V).</text> </item></subclause> <subclause id="H11C88F533C4E4A9684EE83688DC7DAA4"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage who have paid each such loan in full before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H47D323DF190E4E4DBAB71DA40CCE94A7"><enum>(X)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of such students, the percentage whose obligation to repay all such loans has been discharged under section 437 before the end of such second succeeding fiscal year. </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H09FA52CED93C4F66AADD7B29C3E97639"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exclusion of certain programs of study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall exclude under clause (i) information with respect to any program of study if the number of students (or former students) of such program is insufficient to yield statistically reliable information or the results would reveal personally identifiable information about an individual student (or former student).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H105EE20A3EAB4C2FB581951988957A6B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subparagraph:</text> <subclause id="HD933E865EB924401B8A7A001E1B9EC9B"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Covered institution</header><text>The term <term>covered institution</term> means an institution that is the beneficiary of an endowment fund that has a total value of not less than $1,000,000,000.</text> </subclause> 
<subclause id="HEB3F93E8EC5A44F6807299617F40B663"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Endowment fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>endowment fund</term> means a fund established by State law, by an institution of higher education, or by a foundation which is exempt from Federal income taxation and is maintained for the purpose of generating income for the support of the institution, but which shall not include real estate</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

