<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H20581F7C2C0C4739B07F745CACAC895D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8808 IH: Cobalt Optimizes Batteries And Leading Technologies Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8808</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220913">September 13, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001307">Mr. Baird</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000103">Mr. Rosendale</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To acquire cobalt refining capacity in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H19EC4E01F6614224932070C111396153" style="OLC">
<section id="H27AF2C369C7B4605A9AA9F9788D91849" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cobalt Optimizes Batteries And Leading Technologies Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>COBALT Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HCEE447D72BE64E5B97266C14B154B95C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Congress makes the following findings:</text>
<paragraph id="H81E78CA63A434E5E8A2B58A98CF608E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Defense Stockpile lacks sufficient cobalt reserves, falling from 13,000 tons during the Cold War to only 333 tons today.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8BC93B975334F1BAD566BE5961DF560"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The United States currently produces zero newly refined cobalt, making the United States dependent on foreign imports and secondary scrap materials for nearly 100 percent of its cobalt consumption.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCA5FD1F02DA040E3B2680CC219931084"><enum>(3)</enum><text>China is the world’s cobalt lynchpin, supplying 72 percent of global refined cobalt.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1589733E67D04848BA5F0DB92B80B4E0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The International Energy Agency forecasts a cobalt supply deficit by 2030, ultimately projecting cobalt demand in 2040 to range from 6 to 30 times higher than today’s levels.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFFBC9CB9FC724875BDE6780E09DE8117"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Cobalt supply chains often face an untraceable mine-to-refinery chain of custody, risking inadvertent financing of slave and forced child labor.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H853CEA18EB8347BBB6AED856F1DD710C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Cobalt refineries generally use the process of hydrometallurgy (e.g., acid leaching) and pyrometallurgy (e.g., smelting), jeopardizing the environment.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H2075F8DDB1FE403380B68BA537BC15BA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="HAECC190EA2E14372A607EA60F66F5555"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States lack of cobalt refining capacity is a serious vulnerability to America’s critical mineral supply chains;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27E7702569E141DDB20A599239A8AFFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the People’s Republic of China’s dominant share of the refined cobalt market and the unprecedented global demand growth for refined cobalt are threats to the national security, economic stability, and competitiveness of key industries in the United States; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5CAC2FEF4C2545939877426CC407A20E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Department of Defense should—</text>
<subparagraph id="H140C104DFB594F76A1FDD38AA074839F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make purchases and purchase commitments with new refineries in the United States to encourage them to scale up production;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73164EDB7A0348A69F2E655ACEE8DBA6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>stockpile an increased amount of domestically refined cobalt to decrease the vulnerability of the United States to supply chain interruptions; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HED603ABAC257488DB2B9658FB74B89AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require cobalt refineries in the United States to present a transparent mine-to-refinery chain of custody to curb accidental financing of slave and forced child labor; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC75BC61099D6408EA52ECE8B42D1E160"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize purchasing cobalt refined through the environmentally neutral process of chemical vapor metallurgy to prevent harm to the air, water, and soil.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="HF3540A4DDE6748269F9E1878A9FDBCB5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="H3FBDF7C371A34973A4961DDBD2428D19"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support critical mineral refineries in the United States through purchases and purchase commitments;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA41339EB7696481FA0A18B229DBD8C01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>increase the amount of domestically refined critical minerals in the National Defense Stockpile;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBB2D9BD37F754EEC88BD483217C22273"><enum>(3)</enum><text>decrease the dependence of the United States on critical minerals refined in foreign countries, including China;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H79FE0FA231254467B1C0387B1B3BC60C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>combat slave and forced child labor in critical mineral mining and refining; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1025BD9CE5334AB4971D98A47E8357F9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>protect the environment from harmful industrial practices related to critical mineral refining.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HBF24275446E54BB6B0F79055D66113B3"><enum>5.</enum><header>Purchase program for domestically refined cobalt</header>
<subsection id="HC14B571F6FE443D0AA16E5B2A8D89936"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President, acting through Secretary of Defense and the Defense Logistics Agency, and in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, and the Secretary of the Interior, shall use the authorities provided under title III of the Defense Production Act of 1950 to increase the amount of domestically refined cobalt in the National Defense Stockpile by awarding eligible entities with purchases and purchase commitments of cobalt nanopowder and sub-nanopowder refined in the United States through the environmentally neutral process of chemical vapor metallurgy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H11DE461D1EBD4C3A9416954386A627A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>To carry out subsection (a), the President shall use $800,000,000 during fiscal year 2024 through fiscal year 2028 from the Defense Production Act Fund.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6A9077A28BE048ACAE77FD0B33A0A2C8"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HCED192B7B9DA4E589387848681A088F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a refinery—</text>
<subparagraph id="H15D91FC4754447039BB8AB7A693153D5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is owned by United States persons and operating in the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCC10BA47C0664207A588078C45283D58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whose primary business activity, or that of its parent company, is refining critical minerals;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H185EEA203AD540BF8DFDCA412E1A4FE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that refines critical minerals through chemical vapor metallurgy; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2A6E4EA7DEA449AA1D4932824C44CA9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that provides the Secretary of Defense with a mine-to-refinery chain of custody, including proof that the cobalt ore is free of slave and forced child labor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC74D757F763C41D8B78DB5FEA1055F36"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chemical vapor metallurgy</header><text>The term <term>chemical vapor metallurgy</term> means the process of producing cobalt nanopowder by chemically vaporizing cobalt ore concentrates near atmospheric pressure at relatively low temperatures.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4BA5DCA6006545B9B647F219047BEA70"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cobalt nanopowder</header><text>The term <term>cobalt nanopowder</term> means cobalt powders, including pure cobalt and cobalt salts, refined to the nanopowder scale.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEAC7EAA1382F4AAAB1FB66D617F98253"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Critical mineral</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>critical mineral</quote> means a mineral contained on the list published by the U.S. Geological Survey of the Department of the Interior titled <quote>2022 Final List of Critical Minerals</quote> (87 Fed. Reg. 10381; published February 24, 2022).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4D774623D8C34625B81DE3F949A87C4E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Domestically refined</header><text>The term <term>domestically refined</term> means cobalt refined exclusively in the United States.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H31009202A2BB414FB20C21672894CD8F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Environmentally neutral</header><text>The term <term>environmentally neutral</term> means having minimal impact on the air, water, and soil.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

