<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H95866C9FEEE14BD6A370F101B13814FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7842 IH: Protecting Families and the Solvency of the National Flood Insurance Program Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7842</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to expand opportunities for families living in areas of high flood risk to access Federal assistance for voluntary relocation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD1DB0B41D1864EDA8C6062F2BF0706CE" style="OLC"><section id="H6FF3B1DF00F341C488E035D745F184CA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Families and the Solvency of the National Flood Insurance Program Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC2045E51B710478E8873BD8632681C71"><enum>2.</enum><header>Voluntary buyouts in lieu of flood claims</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1312 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4019">42 U.S.C. 4019</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H5ED092DA6224448084270383B0F82233" style="OLC"><subsection id="H8275FF73BDAE467CB9EAD40E8A70A6DF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expedited voluntary buyouts</header><paragraph id="H21B02A1F7B834A64913F32A1AA6D1822"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expedited assistance in lieu of claims</header><text>The Administrator may provide for expedited mitigation assistance for cases in which a policyholder making a claim with respect to a property expresses interest in a voluntary buyout in lieu of a claims payment. Such determinations shall apply regardless of location of a property in relation to an area designated as an area having special flood hazards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H195320ED4F254F3B8FF1FC4FEDFF3DB7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administration may provide expedited assistance under this subsection with respect to a property only if both of the following requirements have been met:</text><subparagraph id="HB0F0088E723E40C19C0316A1FFF7F3FE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Property eligibility</header><text>The insured property—</text><clause id="H72C7294639E64596BA4A7A0EC35D32C6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been identified as a repetitive loss or severe repetitive loss property;</text></clause><clause id="H087D02DD74B3459896F1AA85B67A719A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has been designated by the participating community as substantially damaged; or</text></clause><clause id="H4DE8CD43849C4094810E8F77D0D599C4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>would otherwise be filing a claim for the maximum level of coverage.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H938B162253E644949CEB08B8348590AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Community eligibility</header><text>The relevant community participating in the national flood insurance program agrees to take title to the property in accordance with the terms under section 404(b) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c(b)</external-xref>) and has prioritized mitigation to such property or to the area in which such property is located through an appropriate action or plan, as determined by the Administrator, including—</text><clause id="H04A97C380C574017A3543CE669D99BA6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a repetitive loss area analysis plan conducted for and consistent with criteria for the community rating system authorized under section 1315(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4022">42 U.S.C. 4022(b)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HA38E7E0EC2454620993CDA0DD58652CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a locally adopted plan completed in compliance with requirements of section 1361(e) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102(e)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HAC66DCEE8DCB453C8B047A7BF2EF9AC5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a locally adopted flood risk mitigation plan consistent with the requirements of section 1366(b) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(b)</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H078C8350898245F08E8A2D714FE71992"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an ongoing local or State program for property buyouts to address flooding problems that conforms with such requirement as the Administrator may establish; or</text></clause><clause id="H12B01E03D7F14ABFAF5FA561B528B831"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other action or plan as the Administrator may provide.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FCD9CF1825D4AB082B3DD2C6C0A8ABB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Long-term benefits to Fund</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whenever claims are filed and the conditions under paragraph (2) exist, the Administrator shall expeditiously determine, considering current and future risks, if a property buyout would result in long-term benefits to the National Flood Insurance Fund. For buyouts determined to be beneficial, amounts in the National Flood Insurance Fund may be used immediately to make acquisition offers under this subsection in lieu of full claims payments. Such offers may exceed the amount of the claim and shall comply with requirements for buyout offers authorized under section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c</external-xref>). In no case shall such expedited buyout offers delay or reduce the amount of claims due to a policyholder for contents coverage or necessary clean-up costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H56433BD3DD764807B3DCAA559ABF2B7B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Community action to address repetitively flooded areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1361 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H288BD9D429314EBEBE5CF485397582F9" style="OLC"><subsection id="H78535F0D434A49A8874F60805E894DE6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Community action for repeatedly flooded areas</header><paragraph id="HA89C4EAE2C7347088831B4F246E9D8B8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the following definitions shall apply:</text><subparagraph id="HB319D0255CF94386A30D596D35962FE7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Covered community</header><text>The term <quote>covered community</quote> means a community—</text><clause id="HC6D0B3721B864F4C90339801432274A7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is participating in the national flood insurance program under section 1315 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4022">42 U.S.C. 4022</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="HBA57718497B64ACA986CCE706A6E2720"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within which are located—</text><subclause id="H057C2FFFF7E84264ACC0CBE42C0298EE"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not fewer than 50 repetitive loss structures; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE2824874E1C345B2B086419853CACA38"><enum>(II)</enum><text>not fewer than 5 severe repetitive loss structures for which mitigation activities meeting the standards for approval under section 1366(c)(2)(A) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4101c">42 U.S.C. 4101c(c)(2)(A)</external-xref>) have not been conducted; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE0A1B2AF0DB74F9BB70B5A761DFE302E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>which has been identified by the Administrator as a priority for assessment and mitigation in accordance with the regulations authorized by this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66E0BCFC13914D1BACFF22FF8FF840D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Repetitive loss structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>repetitive loss structure</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1370 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4121">42 U.S.C. 4121</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA261BE622A604B6C9578BBD38B4648C0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Severe repetitive loss structure</header><text>The term <quote>severe repetitive loss structure</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1366(h) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4101c">42 U.S.C. 4101c(h)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8954089B64C4690A520CE4E58ACC3B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for covered communities</header><text>The Administrator shall, by regulation, require a covered community to—</text><subparagraph id="H54FD13E568EA4603A157703261DFB533"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine, with assistance from the Administrator, the areas within the covered community in which properties described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii) are located in order to identify areas that are repeatedly damaged by floods;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H012D6F6CCD014E7EB0C2F468D67613D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assess, with assistance from the Administrator, future conditions which may represent continuing risks to the repeatedly damaged areas identified pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17D30416FA404E9DBEABB69A492A3124"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop a community-specific plan for mitigating continuing flood risks to the repeatedly damaged areas identified pursuant to subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A5090A13CAE4D7C812728DB5D41B650"><enum>(D)</enum><text>submit the plan described in subparagraph (C) and any plan updates to the Administrator at appropriate intervals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B31E5D423C74606BF80BD7C62F14D30"><enum>(E)</enum><text>implement the plan described in subparagraph (C); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB54B981D4D9F4FD6A880799928676581"><enum>(F)</enum><text>subject to section 552a of title 5, United States Code, make the plan described in subparagraph (C), any updates to the plan, and reports on progress in reducing flood risk available to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08608126A95C4447B7186E862110D488"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with existing planning efforts</header><text>As determined by the Administrator, a covered community may address the planning requirements of this subsection in coordination with other planning efforts, including—</text><subparagraph id="HF207546236A14544A803BAEA2DFB04AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan developed under section 1366 of this title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6AC7805C100B4462ACB2F71DFF691FDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan developed under section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E58D7865DD4451F84E9ECF60E690320"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan completed for, conducted for, and consistent with criteria for the community rating system authorized under section 1315(b) of this title (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4022">42 U.S.C. 4022(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AF3F566A0384A90939BCA3C01EBDD80"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Authorization and assistance</header><subparagraph id="H59A4C01E8BAD48BA9366958069D3D9F6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may issue appropriate policies and regulations to assist covered communities in identification of repeatedly flooded areas and in implementing practical plans for addressing the identified flooding problems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB44916E240B43D3B639859821E931CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Types of assistance</header><text>Assistance authorized under this section may include—</text><clause id="HB07B75D752F7403598D9A9BFED7131F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">sharing of information in accordance with the requirements of section 552a of title 5, United States Code, and the subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code;</text></clause><clause id="H76C21780EEA34F6AA8A5170582843675"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consideration of possible sources of financial assistance to communities, including—</text><subclause id="H4E4B78214DDD4AE59C6DF8B978B28606"><enum>(I)</enum><text>potential waiver or lowering of non-Federal cost shares for mitigation of properties; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7FE4109794304BA2B6F86FFCAD2FE06A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>potential priority for applicable grant mitigation funding managed by the Administrator;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE9ACD2908C3C4311874903CF50AAC085"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>additional technical assistance to communities the Administrator may deem most at-risk for repeated flooding events;</text></clause><clause id="H1ED962D331024961B793363A7F1915BD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reasonable considerations and targeted assistance for communities defined as small and impoverished or high-risk under section 203(a) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C 5133(a)); and</text></clause><clause id="H9A8EAEB6440845A08DFBE1AAE0EDDB87"><enum>(v)</enum><text>special assistance aimed at implementing Executive Order 13985 (January 20, 2021) on Advancing Racial Equity and Support for Underserved Communities Through the Federal Government, as defined by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H511C98454E194FA4BC8A7E500860337E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special considerations</header><text>In determining an appropriate level of assistance for a covered community, as provided in subparagraph (B), the Administrator shall consider the extent to which the community is working to remedy problems associated with repeated flooding and the resources available to the covered community, including—</text><clause id="H5B3DB4636D6845ABA78290A313A287A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any Federal or State funding received by the covered community;</text></clause><clause id="H9B033108F73B464A9693CDD152F224D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the portion of the covered community that is located within areas having special flood hazards; and</text></clause><clause id="H4787DDEE7CC6418FAFA1D415B93F6C26"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other factor that makes it difficult for the covered community to conduct mitigation activities for flood-prone structures.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD48985EE76BD4A1FA49D59928B1B9DA1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this subsection, and not less frequently than once every 2 years thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Congress a report regarding the progress made by covered communities with respect to implementing plans developed under paragraph (2)(C) and, to the extent possible, the trends in numbers of repetitive loss and severe repetitive loss properties.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HB7D4CEF4B76C475F9B04AE049B6D1B39"><enum>4.</enum><header>Flood mitigation assistance</header><subsection id="HB879252F3DD84AE1AF63F41617F5977D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 1366(a) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(a)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H858D2D17B62F459AA806F3F2C70AACE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>repetitive loss structures,</quote> after <quote>damage to</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDFE418DFB0D42CAA8AE2FDA6FC34048"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting before <quote>; and</quote> the following: <quote>, and other structures within an area that has been identified by the State or community as a repetitive loss area or has been determined by the Administrator to pose a significant risk of recurrent flooding</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCDC4F4B78C046DDB500ACEFF9532526"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible mitigation activities</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H61C6C042E01E4C6188BCC8DC4EF45820"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H088C640EB6674D9F9AC5A06C0936A24D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">fairness</header-in-text>,</quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">cost-effectiveness</header-in-text></quote>;</text><clause id="H5C30FA8FEF074BA6A0490DF2B17A88E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="H12D3484B58024B91B27967AF078F6493"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><item id="H12842943DCB7426D9B38DF2A4491B74E"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>, equitable,</quote> after <quote>feasible</quote>; and</text></item><item id="HC3FEE2D65895462291EE61CBEB79231B"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>over the long term</quote> after <quote>cost-effective</quote>; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HA8593C6ABD174BDE8D1346D2AA77112C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>repetitive loss or</quote> before <quote>severe</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H11373A6635B94846BBC74D75211D419C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B) by inserting <quote>, including benefits that provide needed assistance to vulnerable populations</quote> before the period at the end;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F9CB0E013B44D46945BE58E505AD716"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H5411C27E630D46E2BFECE620D9222926"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><clause id="H89BE2A76767E47C4A375FF0BD6A35F67"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for public use,</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HCDC0DA309BA3443ABB2A135B625B5653"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, considering current and future risks</quote> before the period at the end;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BA8BA30D2FB4A4A9BACA939EA7EF484"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H) by inserting <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9E7A2B3835F46CCBD6F85A44EA718B2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I) by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA28A218757DB4F3FACC466695BF4A20A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (J); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5675220E25C344E0B0B9055D4C46E397"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by adding after the period, the following: <quote>In any case in which elevation or rebuilding is authorized by the Administrator, the appropriate level of elevation shall incorporate appropriate freeboard or other safety factor based on an assessment using the best scientific information to determine risk levels over the expected lifetime of the structure.</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9716EFA10A9D4B3887721CA0D1680222"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Matching requirement</header><text>Subsection (d) of section 1366 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4104c">42 U.S.C. 4104c(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3A105481BC644788B173895E5C0F3514"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, except in cases in which the repetitive loss structure lies within an area identified under a local plan adopted pursuant to section 1361(e) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4102">42 U.S.C. 4102(e)</external-xref>). In such cases, mitigation activities, including acquisitions, shall be funded in an amount up to 100 percent of all eligible costs</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4479BAC43081426BB8A474131C089F37"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F8466E70FD942D0A603FB8C5B2D0DFE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HA3FF93D389064534BB9AA5C33F55455D" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H06A48485BF464AFFB92860E8C7791FF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver of matching requirements for properties within underserved communities</header><text>The matching requirement under this subsection shall be waived for the following properties:</text><subparagraph id="HA78988A1833A499589BF98F5E15C651C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Properties located within a census tract with a Centers for Disease Control and Prevention Social Vulnerability Index score of not less than 0.5001.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C4A880E46424F669536C08478B0E3EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Properties serving as the primary residence for a household having a household income of not more than 100 percent of the applicable area median income.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6152DA2A9E9E4E9D86CFECA79E63ACC4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Predisaster mitigation</header><subsection id="H94712541C4B64A758B67266090D299DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C 5133) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H21E6551967F146E2809EE2FF47F85189" style="OLC"><subsection id="H3187E100C7F34E298E87D83E76AFC55A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of small impoverished community and high-Risk community</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="HF21134DD7D464B15AF71636A4C6485D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>small impoverished community</quote> means a community of 3,000 or fewer individuals that is economically disadvantaged, as determined by the State in which the community is located and based on criteria established by the President; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15FA79D4D8494E07836DCAB9D791E368"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>high-risk community</quote> means a community that has significant risk to health, safety, or economic stability from natural disasters and also has limited resources to plan for and mitigate against such risks, as determined by the Administrator. In making such determination, the Administrator may consider information on past natural disasters, claims against the National Flood Insurance Fund, and other federal expenditures for disaster response and recovery as well as data related to size of the community, social vulnerability, poverty levels, unemployment, housing shortages, or other factors that affect the community’s capacity to prepare for and recover from natural disasters.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4D7A85903A5847328CFE980E3FF8B876"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State recommendations</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 203(d)(2) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C 5133) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H84143892B1494418A226717ECC12A19C" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H7D40257EBC244BD19A279E806DAA860D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>In providing assistance to local governments under this section, the President may select a local government has been identified as a small impoverished community or a high-risk community, or, if the President determines that extraordinary circumstances justify the selection and that making the selection will further the purpose of this section, another community that has not been recommended by a Governor under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H195B345945334BDDBC63B34609C9E9A7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Criteria for assistance awards</header><text>Subsection (g) of section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C 5133(g)) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9B622EDEE59C46389A283E6A0909C153"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by inserting <quote>, including the likelihood that identified hazards will increase in severity, frequency, or impact in the future</quote> before the semicolon at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BA7B392388941549D820F5CDC5523F7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (8) by inserting <quote>, including securing improved protections for vulnerable populations</quote> before the semicolon at the end; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2958E01A94984228AABA1D7074398212"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (9) by inserting <quote>and high-risk communities</quote> before the semicolon at the end.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H61869BA0269C44DA8579AA3A543B3734"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>Paragraph (2) of section 203(h) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C 5133(h)(2)) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H128F88E4D63C4C3290820EA9000DF5F0" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H214C55C5FAEF4ED4AB014DC99E7C442A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Small impoverished and high-risk communities</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the President may contribute up to 100 percent of the total cost of a mitigation activity carried out in a small impoverished community or in a high-risk community.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HE2DACC73197947B7A09D81DC5581BC98"><enum>6.</enum><header>Hazard mitigation grant program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5170c">42 U.S.C. 5170c(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H41903D70CB4F466B8847E0FBBDEB8AEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H6D545E565F704E1A91334F2B9A171CD3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>section</quote> and replacing with <quote>Act or under the National Flood Insurance Act (42 U.S.C. 4001 et. seq.)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7504DA574A814A468D60626D28395466"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after the period at the end the following: <quote>In providing such assistance, the Administrator shall allow for participating property owners, as well as any affected tenants, to be treated as displaced persons under the Uniform Relocation Assistance and Real property Acquisition Policies Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4601">42 U.S.C. 4601 et seq.</external-xref>).</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1094CD82C2D4C14898394B813C4B595"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HA10944185F0947468E019B98D3501951" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H7C6A53429F06400E8A2658142950B82A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special considerations</header><text>In the case of an acquisition or relocation project undertaken in cooperation with a community which meets the criteria set forth under subsection 1312(d) of the National Flood Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4019">42 U.S.C. 4019(d)</external-xref>), the Administrator may recognize for credit toward necessary local cost shares any properly documented expenditures related to such project which may have been made before the date of the grant award. Such expenditures may include costs related to structure inspections and appraisals, title searches, outreach to potentially affected property owners, real estate counseling and other necessary assistance, and planning for reuse of the properties in compliance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

