<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF7781886381845F4A5E80EAC78310809" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8818 IH: Wind Safety Standard Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8818</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220914">September 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Occupational Safety and Health Administration to issue an occupational safety and health standard to protect workers from wind-related injuries.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE2FAC2CD8CE84685929B64BE772E84A2" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HC8FD796F08384E6EAC33519083622421"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wind Safety Standard Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAD5AF0A3707E483FAFAA125CCC3E88A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>OSHA safety standard for protection from high winds</header><subsection id="H90027CAFBCEC431596CD565D25FE139D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Proposed standard</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall, pursuant to section 6(b) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655(b)</external-xref>), promulgate a proposed standard on prevention of workplace injury from high winds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1183C488EB734D03BBFEF4B69D5E7AD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final standard</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 42 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall promulgate a final standard on prevention of workplace injury from high winds that shall—</text><paragraph id="H93E238BAB935473ABE5C3F55CDEA05AE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide no less protection than the most protective wind protection standard adopted by a State plan that has been approved by the Secretary under section 18 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/667">29 U.S.C. 667</external-xref>) and, at a minimum, include the requirements described in section 4; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H562A40064C794E87B60468A2567117CC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be effective and enforceable in the same manner and to the same extent as any standard promulgated under section 6(b) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EDB9B36A1B44438BB87F5AEE30F8ADF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Interim final standard</header><paragraph id="HCFE43642281242C19DA7128C7ACF8B6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the proposed standard described in subsection (a) is not promulgated not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Labor shall promulgate an interim final standard on prevention of workplace injury from high winds not later than 2 years and 60 days after such date of enactment—</text><subparagraph id="HE86E94597EEE463DB4CAF1C2F362FDD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to require covered employers to develop and implement a comprehensive workplace wind protection plan to protect covered employees from excessive winds that may lead to wind-related workplace injuries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H863D528CCC8044879CF59CAA81596455"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that shall, at a minimum—</text><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB9E2C8FB0DA14B3CB082DF2CE5791045" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide no less protection than the most protective wind protection standard adopted by a State plan that has been approved by the Secretary under section 18 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/667">29 U.S.C. 667</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H6691131646464343937FE0652BA9FB84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include a requirement to protect employees from discrimination or retaliation for exercising the rights of the employees under the interim final standard.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFEB678B831F4FA699B16D89EB1B4267" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of other statutory requirements</header><text>The following shall not apply to the promulgation of the interim final standard under this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HBEEB565E46444FE0995193A8C756CBEC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The requirements applicable to occupational safety and health standards under section 6(b) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B004F6BF6944EAC8ECC25BD09240CA3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The requirements of section 553(c) of chapter 5 and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/6">chapter 6</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A33210FDACF47BEB56F0C503D38F9CB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H36EAB007B14F4FF9978523EAEAF5AE5F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date of interim standard</header><text>The interim final standard shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7FECEFD0F0AD4E768F523F5DF45B1920"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take effect on a date that is not later than 30 days after the promulgation of such standard, except that such interim final standard may include a reasonable phase-in period for the implementation of required engineering controls that take effect after such date;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFA16EA4C50B47A79282EB287A18725B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent as any standard promulgated under section 6(b) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655(b)</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC0DFE79359346A1918D6469F3A16A36"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be in effect until the final standard described in subsection (b) becomes effective and enforceable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H30E33220D685401E9E1731F237AD8B30"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H7F47955E34804CEEA17DBBE0AD74F218"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered employee</header><text>The term <term>covered employee</term> includes an individual employed by a covered employer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65D50A55CB96467F9DADB7633D2DF6AA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered employer</header><text>The term <term>covered employer</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H9499A91A3DC2497ABA4969DED3A5E3D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an employer that employs an individual to work at a covered workplace; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9ACA68FC7F0433A9B6EE33082F34CBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a contractor, subcontractor, a temporary service firm, or an employee leasing entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C964E7CA5AB46119506925D5A741BD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered workplace</header><text>The term <term>covered workplace</term> includes a workplace with occupational exposure to high winds, including—</text><subparagraph id="H55DCF4BC1F5240878DAAB5BBFDD5DC69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any workplace in which covered employees perform services for a covered employer outdoors during high winds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E5DCFCD4579418A9AE7A98B14E05C94"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any workplace in which covered employees perform services for a covered employer indoors in any case in which such covered employees may be at risk during an extreme weather event involving high winds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF438AED351464E8EA158E63D3F5C31"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/652">29 U.S.C. 652</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9091529EEC54231A43814C8EA531EE4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>High winds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>high winds</quote> means winds of such velocity that one or more of the following hazards would be present:</text><subparagraph id="H671E2B8E083D48B4B6603EF03CA87B50"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The winds could blow an employee from an elevated location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF904060242BF495F94C3E2D6885125D5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The winds could cause an employee or equipment handling material to lose control of the material.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20B29B3EC9A14FD29CE6EEC40C6A6009"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The winds would expose an employee to other hazards not controlled by the standard involved.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Winds exceeding 64.4 kilometers per hour (40 miles per hour), or 48.3 kilometers per hour (30 miles per hour) if the work involves material handling, shall be presumed to be of such velocity unless the employer takes precautions to protect employees from the hazardous effects of the winds.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF880A030D2741B7A3B0A194DCBF8F04"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="HAE4E991B5CC94116A21A92936981C178"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements for final standard on prevention of occupational exposure to high winds</header><subsection id="H95E2D47994074210A14DCB2CA75E1859"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final standard promulgated under section 2(b) shall, at a minimum, include the requirements described in subsection (b) with respect to covered employers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H97B7C2065FD243ACA3F0F145206B92F2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The final standard promulgated under section 2(b) shall, with respect to covered employers, include the following:</text><paragraph id="H1A67FDF16639460F9F8F8454D05B1791"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Monitoring of wind conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered employer shall monitor wind conditions using data from the National Weather Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4462A6114A834DA4B432E681F2B7C50F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employees working outdoors during high winds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each covered employee who performs services for a covered employer outdoors during high winds—</text><subparagraph id="H139BB56ADFD64F43BE5262A454D015E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employee shall receive training in work with high winds, including training relating to—</text><clause id="H9CEE5C41B3D94F3AA6514BA90FD37C71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the impact on work at heights;</text></clause><clause id="H560E9FF5296D425B92EF27C5889D8107"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the impact of wind on certain equipment such as lifts, cranes, scaffolding, ladders, and mobile elevated work platforms;</text></clause><clause id="H5CA1BFDAC39D4417A829B841935CE67B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the risk of foreign object debris; and</text></clause><clause id="H6B7C46F3BD274B8A8F7C4D68B9EFAE61"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the impact of wind on exposed skin and the risk of wind burn;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD01855F28B6D4F3F93A4F53573E81C73"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such employee shall not be required to work in high winds without a safety harness system, tie-off restraints, or other appropriate safety equipment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H395F819CBF604B27B8004F79C9DE0220"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such employee shall not be required to use any equipment that is not rated for the level of high winds in which the employee is requested to work;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H226456D4E0534910BF18B0A50CD4B0BF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HD2E35B00FA8A487983AFAFEAC21FDF39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>such employee shall have the right to refuse to work in high winds and be assigned alternate work without penalty in any case in which the employee determines that high wind safety procedures are inadequate to mitigate the risk of such work; and</text></clause><clause id="H06DB6AFD0A22413B8FA61C79B37F8EBD" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in any such case, the employer shall conduct a hazard assessment and immediately investigate and correct any identified hazards and implement any control measures as necessary to adequately mitigate such risks;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D52FCB227454E0FA6A72892F0780A35"><enum>(E)</enum><text>such employee—</text><clause id="H130332174B3D4C94B52F19CDD26F29C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be instructed on how to properly secure all tools and any other object that could act as foreign object debris;</text></clause><clause id="H53F4CB0D21644BFCBCD5AB98A888BDA7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not be required to work in high winds if all such objects cannot be secured; and</text></clause><clause id="HFB3F69C9E5FA423E9D810A6E91C9F320"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be provided with proper personal protective equipment including eye protection while working in high winds; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F8A32A9ED8544BEAABADA8D3D381B9C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such employee—</text><clause id="H1B841C73591D40FF8DE0EF3F66A85D8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall receive training on wind burn prevention, identification, and treatment; and</text></clause><clause id="HEE15A0B9EA1340F2B3F46F91E0F08B2D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall be provided by the employer with personal protective equipment at no cost to the employee to prevent wind burn, except to the extent such equipment would result in a net increase of hazards to the employee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67850B8727444AD8F4A9CAEE9DDDAAB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employees working indoors and outdoors during extreme weather events involving high winds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each covered employee who performs services for a covered employer indoors or outdoors in any case in which such covered employee may be at risk during an extreme weather event involving high winds, the covered employer shall—</text><subparagraph id="HB66DC056E2AC408BB23A8685B05B3068"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop, implement, and maintain a wind emergency plan for each such employee, similar to an emergency action plan described under section 1910.38 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, which shall include—</text><clause id="H71A228D9F5E64262BA7EF3B3957EBB9B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evacuation plan which details employer and employee responsibilities;</text></clause><clause id="HA49393964533445F9B436506E33F8A69"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a shelter in place plan, including a plan for mobile workforce and employees at remote or satellite locations;</text></clause><clause id="H3881EB59521F4A2DA56DE98D298E76E3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>specific plans for extreme weather events such as tornadoes and hurricanes that include a trigger to activate such plans and appropriate training and drills;</text></clause><clause id="HAD2F63DB5D1A4D15AA80C4E0633A7F93"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specific plans for high-risk buildings and mobile worksites (such as vehicles or trailers), to be updated as needed upon remodeling; and</text></clause><clause id="H659D6C440A384160A7AEE4ACD5ECEBB7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>job protections for employees who evacuate due to unsafe conditions;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE36EC64CA0E94DD0B4F990B0C8A7FF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a hazard assessment to identify unsafe working conditions or hazardous equipment that can be impacted when extreme weather advisories are issued; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D05C386EF1A436CB3E77206A9B64D9A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that emergency shelters are designed and built to industry best practices for performance criteria like Safe Rooms for Tornadoes and Hurricanes (FEMA P–361) or ICC/NSSA Standard for the Design and Construction of Storm Shelters (ICC–500).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA620D4E0D878489E8E807414814FF466" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Training and education</header><subparagraph id="H21F46856ED5443959BAFB7129A18C51B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Employee Training</header><text>A covered employer shall provide annual training and education to covered employees who may be exposed to high winds, which shall cover the following topics:</text><clause id="H4B76271D096E4203804E32BD726C2489" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Personal factors that may increase susceptibility to high winds.</text></clause><clause id="H3388DAD77FF74B5F8C6C9351D666F08A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Signs and symptoms of wind-related injury.</text></clause><clause id="HC8F5755A7D124466AA5EF787A9AC66BD" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Engineering control measures.</text></clause><clause id="H8EF63465871947C48D54A9811D856F33" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Administrative control measures.</text></clause><clause id="H403EA3DCE1F8402886D7BF9F845AB10B" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Emergency response procedures.</text></clause><clause id="HD34C7D67C2F64239B5662E300C9D6A1A" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Employee rights.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E23313FC18E41BEB34CCB04BD2C48F2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Supervisor Training</header><text>In addition to the training and education required in subparagraph (A), training and education shall be provided annually to covered employees who are supervisors that shall cover the following topics:</text><clause id="H52DBC60F72274F71A0E1F17CCBE850F4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The procedures a supervisor is required to follow under this Act.</text></clause><clause id="H929EBAFA7B5F449F9E9C4A07B1ECECA7" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>How to recognize high-risk situations, including how to monitor weather reports and weather advisories, and not assigning an employee to situations that predictably compromise the safety of the employee.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6977C5E45CD147DC82D2273228E0B8D9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>General training requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The education and training provided under this paragraph to covered employees shall meet the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="HE524793BD9654218B95A2A536756F1E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>In the case of such an employee whose job circumstances have changed, within a reasonable timeframe after such change of job circumstances, education and training shall be provided that shall be—</text><subclause id="H50D2D149AFC7439591F53C4397D57DE1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in addition to the education and training provided under clause (ii), subparagraph (A), and, if applicable to such employee, subparagraph (B); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H09B228AAD74A4240968EB30075566CDB" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>applicable to such change of job circumstances.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBDA12267E7244D0391E85FFEFFC4A1E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Applicable education and training shall be provided for each new covered employee prior to the employee’s job assignment.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H062D0F4352814796BC4E9A43F64E678D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The education and training shall provide such employees opportunities to ask questions, give feedback, and request additional instruction, clarification, or other follow-up.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HC2C148DEC934468F864B1C1560CD7276"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The education and training shall be provided by an individual with knowledge of wind injury prevention and of the plan of the employer under this section.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H4316D2FDDF0B42B68133B681F72A7977"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The education and training shall be appropriate in content and vocabulary to the language, educational level, and literacy of such covered employees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A537F3B83EF42BAAC328F4CD4B20AC0" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered employer shall—</text><subparagraph id="HDFE37624D37944FABD8FB1D12FDA6CE1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comply with all requirements under the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 relating to the reporting of wind-related injuries;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3204A11029645619CE2DDB81A042871"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain at all times—</text><clause id="H8936C7A64B4F4C8E8A5319E028875CF5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>records related to each plan of the employer under paragraph (1), including high wind risk and hazard assessments, and identification, evaluation, correction, and training procedures;</text></clause><clause id="H8271F87DF4834DA6998D63CFC0CD71C2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>data on all wind-related injuries and deaths; and</text></clause><clause id="H76E6D86CA2FD48B1B990706C49237A28" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>data on environmental and physiological measurements related to high winds; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BDE395AC87348BCAB57B74B4F1D5B6C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>make such records and data available, upon request, to covered employees and their representatives for examination and copying in accordance with section 1910.1020 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as such section is in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF00F671B80143E28A48A9350547330C" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><subparagraph id="HC26E8D7FEA9244DCA78977BE6046429D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Policy</header><text>Each covered employer shall adopt a policy prohibiting any person (including an agent of the employer) from discriminating or retaliating against any employee for—</text><clause id="HA556D6CC13E645AE92DEA3385BDD68F6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exercising the rights of the employee under this Act; or</text></clause><clause id="HA7899ED2B1964D8A830C559057356D74" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reporting violations of the standard to any local, State, or Federal government.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE52448CD200405597AD729AC9331509" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No covered employer shall discriminate or retaliate against any employee for—</text><clause id="H695B60771F9E43D69A20900EAFD4882D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reporting a high wind-related concern to, or seeking assistance or intervention with respect to high wind-related health symptoms from, the employer, local emergency services, or a local, State, or Federal government; or</text></clause><clause id="HF6C8A642D95A45C9A640DA6E9CC4CB8D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>exercising any other rights of the employee under this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC248675A3C14B829E8BB547983FB698" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text>This paragraph shall be enforced in the same manner and to the same extent as any standard promulgated under section 6(b) of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/655">29 U.S.C. 655(b)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

