<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3B0182C076DA4194967CA4723D068FCE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7340 IH: To provide for congressional oversight of certain sanctions imposed with respect to the Russian Federation.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-31</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7340</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for congressional oversight of certain sanctions imposed with respect to the Russian Federation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4140D4C71AA24D0C9DE7A390A402B241" style="OLC"><section id="H1370A1036C3D48FB968651FD45439F88" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Congressional oversight of certain sanctions imposed with respect to the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="HB3B210E43A434CC3A3F85762D2626D5D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving a request from the chairman and ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a person, foreign person, or foreign financial institution, as the case may be, meets the criteria of a person described in a covered Executive order, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H79B0313CF19B4875852B6679F5244617"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine if the person, foreign person, or foreign financial institution, as the case may be, meets such criteria; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H528EEB24FF7D47068DA24A305CC22D2B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a classified or unclassified report to such chairman and ranking member with respect to such determination that includes a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions with respect to such person, foreign person, or foreign financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52A54A933FF0453F990B7AE349982E5E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HABE9409E3D194BB29475DA5CB90B45D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD2A0EE9CFE694368A368A0A3282FEE7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D02FB77D1D64D21B5E47FCC0FDC11A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H22C9628F13554939B76B9C48CBA48BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered Executive order</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered Executive order</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="HAA39D1CC3E7E4BB49A7FB0E103A1C361"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Executive Order 14024 (86 Fed. Reg. 20249; relating to blocking property with respect to specified harmful foreign activities of the Government of the Russian Federation) or any directive issued pursuant to such Executive order; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B5C7B19C593416D81FF069A70712DC5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Executive Order 14039 (86 Fed. Reg. 47205; relating to blocking property with respect to certain Russian energy export pipelines) or any directive issued pursuant to such Executive order.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

