<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8489B5E002A94268B1E2EA77E77950D1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8541 IH: Aqua Alert Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8541</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220727">July 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to establish a pilot program to improve the issuance of alerts to facilitate cooperation with the public to render aid to distressed individuals under section 521 of title 14, United States Code, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H566D93B433CA401A906B2ECC8BA336BA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB48C1BF71386484FA17BBA4192D3C99B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aqua Alert Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H49E03E74DF0B4642BCD2FAB7AE619A2E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Aqua alert notification system pilot program</header> <subsection id="HB98978BAD61547C4BC90F14461B29155"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commandant of the Coast Guard shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, establish a pilot program to improve the issuance of alerts to facilitate cooperation with the public to render aid to distressed individuals under section 521 of title 14, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H364B2B469A6643F987282B301770A3E1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot program contents</header><text>The pilot program established under subsection (a) shall, to the maximum extent possible—</text> <paragraph id="H821C3B6EB1F640418675A8B747AF6B58"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a voluntary opt-in program under which members of the public may receive notifications on cellular devices regarding Coast Guard activities to render aid to distressed individuals under section 521 of title 14, United States Code;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC0C5DBC6A8849268FA5D53524FC0ACA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cover areas located within the area of responsibility of 3 different Coast Guard sectors in diverse geographic regions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D89A64AACB241D3A6AA9AC6CBD00CF5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide that the dissemination of an alert be limited to the geographic areas most likely to facilitate the rendering of aide to distressed individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08D33F7CCABD455A947BA7E1C8214A4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation with other agencies, States, territories, and political subdivisions</header><text>In developing the pilot program under subsection (a), the Commandant shall consult any relevant Federal agency, State, Territory, Tribal government, possession, or political subdivision.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2CBC4145A5B746288152C1F557E465BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter through 2026, the Commandant shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, and make available to the public, a report on the implementation of this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB87122F29E34461A9B09E0C1CFC3BB39"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="HB4DF6B432D8F49B0A7592DF59D89556A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $3,000,000 to the Commandant for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20D6C33431A64E958E750F13539839D2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to paragraph (1) shall remain available until expended.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

