<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H556BBE1B18474A2B990CEC58AC66E0F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9454 IH: Developing Innovative Partnerships and Learning Opportunities that Motivate Achievement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9454</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To strengthen student achievement and graduation rates and prepare children and youth for college, careers, and citizenship through innovative partnerships that meet the comprehensive needs of children and youth.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFC167B1AA49047399F203E41FBA09015" style="OLC"><section id="HAC6B4D75FD224EDBA5F73B09382AC461" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H31F7B2A805BA4CEAB39319B7C24F4B9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Developing Innovative Partnerships and Learning Opportunities that Motivate Achievement Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>DIPLOMA Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0E3748FB608E4C64B734856D7DD6711C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HAC6B4D75FD224EDBA5F73B09382AC461">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7566E26259EB4985B9F41C7E62E1FA84">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H4AF5C2FDB7F64D7AA1736A45AA629B99">Sec. 3. Purposes.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7F0B96AF58234BCAA5ACEBEDE31A4972">Sec. 4. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H170E8D7746484389A73E979F5B67C09F">Sec. 5. Demonstration program authorized; allotment to States.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HB78BA666184E44779D284BD109046A13">Sec. 6. Demonstration competitive program authorized.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H42700DBC374C446C84B1BBA92EE0C8BA">Sec. 7. State child and youth strategy.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H97CBDD757ACC4945A08ABF8913C7432A">Sec. 8. Coordinating body; State applications.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HECD9522731CB4305AFD14C21CC4DF3CD">Sec. 9. State use of funds.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H109A65E59AF242B59D0FB527B42B9243">Sec. 10. Local consortium application; local child and youth strategy.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H3E641FB8836C492B82C03C0338A386DA">Sec. 11. Local use of funds.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HEEA1EC9D9AE744B694ABEA616C839655">Sec. 12. Construction.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H20C0816A9EBE4915AB6EA71D08D4090B">Sec. 13. Accountability and transparency.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF55BC65F4C1B42BC9DB1E170683AE278">Sec. 14. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H7566E26259EB4985B9F41C7E62E1FA84"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4527E492B10946D6AD5ADDBE8D089FFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The future strength of the Nation’s democracy, as well as the Nation’s economy, is dependent upon the investments made in children and youth today.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A7EC33B1E674B1D85410ECF933963C3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Evidence demonstrates that effective partnerships among schools and communities increase student achievement by addressing the academic needs of students as well as the challenges the students face outside the classroom. For example:</text><subparagraph id="HA6B95A12D3AE41E0A365FAB0B8FC1DA1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Chicago public schools lead one of the Nation’s largest community school initiatives and found that students in grades 9 through 12 who attend a community school have 61 percent fewer school-day absences than their non-community school counterparts. When compared to non-community school counterparts—</text><clause id="HEF03C0E67FEF4247B47B925B62542FEA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>students in grades 9 through 12 were found to have more positive educational experiences; </text></clause><clause id="H5D93E23BA36A42EAA8417DC0BD6579B9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>students in grades 4 through 8 had higher emotional health scores on the survey; and </text></clause><clause id="HDE4D0ACD76454D8B81E4B37BDA45FCDF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>students in kindergarten through grade 3 had 53 percent fewer suspensions and 55 percent fewer misconducts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62168C9D2B714B0481E968EBCD84FFD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In a 7-year study of 200 Chicago public schools, sociologist Anthony Bryk found that in schools where grassroots organizations forge strong connections with their schools, trust levels and parent involvement are greater.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5AAC6B149D654054B7E11C0303CC006C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>United Way of Salt Lake’s Promise Partnership, an initiative across multiple school districts in the Salt Lake, Utah area, has helped increase student achievement and graduation rates. Since the program’s launch in 2014, 5 out of the 8 targeted indicators have improved, even in light of the challenges posed by COVID–19. Kindergarten readiness in numeracy increased by 3 percent, 8th grade math proficiency improved by 8 percent, high school graduation rose by 5 percent, postsecondary readiness grew by 4 percent, and postsecondary completion increased by 5 percent. To overcome pandemic-related learning loss in literacy, Promise Partnership school Mill Creek Elementary collaborated with 80 volunteers from organizations including Goldman Sachs and Dominion Energy to offer tutoring support through the iReady program. By the end of the 2020–2021 school year, the number of 3rd grade students participating in the program testing at or above grade level tripled.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB4BAEDF47564ACE81486B2AD203FE4B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>From 2015 to 2018, the New York City Community School Initiative improved attendance, on-time grade progression, and graduation rates across elementary and secondary students. During the same 3-year period, this initiative led to a reduction in disciplinary incidents for elementary and middle school students while also improving math achievement scores. Middle school students attending community schools scored 4.2 percentage points higher on math exams compared their peers at non-community schools, and high school students attending community schools earned 12 percent more credits per academic year than students enrolled at non-community schools.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H282D3D47FF7948179AB3E41822BDBFDD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In Wisconsin, where formal partnerships with community agencies are required for grant programs, non-traditional partners have proven to be instrumental for smaller communities to enrich after school programs. Those partners have included—</text><clause id="H2CD6A6D4D2204541BCAAB1348AA4A042"><enum>(i)</enum><text>local trucking companies; </text></clause><clause id="H7276376A0FE949DE88D1762FF02ED801"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>statewide nonprofit organizations, such as The Grange;</text></clause><clause id="H7155DFCB4C1843658F60059A06CA63C0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Farm Bureau; </text></clause><clause id="H2CC6D6CE4DE04576A01D178E1898BA6A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>small retailers; and</text></clause><clause id="H9B0B67886C714E1C8C210F85A8C6B419"><enum>(v)</enum><text>retirees.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6019B3BCBC34EC4B0697CDB157AB488"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Union City Public Schools school district in New Jersey proves that by breaking down institutional <quote>silos</quote> and creating deep partnerships, through collaboration and municipal involvement, schools can be vibrant places of hope despite poverty, unemployment, and lack of affordable housing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED842BB09A4F4FF6B0340B862B4E4A8F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Six family resource centers housed in community schools in Redwood City, California promote school readiness among children while also providing parents with educational services, community resources, and leadership opportunities. A 2017 report indicates that with the assistance of English language proficiency supports, 70 percent of Redwood City community school parents were able to participate in their children’s school meetings, attend professional development programs, and engage in family-to-family education and outreach. Over the course of a 3-year period, students whose parents participated in family engagement programs had a 40 percent increase in attendance and were more likely to see improvement in their math and English language test scores.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9B968FE8D41432C8625A3C7D2782582"><enum>(H)</enum><text>By meeting the comprehensive needs of students, Communities In Schools, a national dropout prevention organization, found that 99 percent of participating students stayed in school, 78 percent of participating students met or made progress toward their attendance goals, 90 percent met or made progress toward their behavior goals, and 88 percent met or made progress toward their academic improvement goals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H411F455FC6604262943B011CC0B0B203"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In adopting the Every Student Succeeds Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/95">Public Law 114–95</external-xref>), Congress recognized community schools as a strategy to significantly improve the coordination and integration, accessibility, and effectiveness of services for children and families, particularly for children attending high-poverty schools, including high-poverty rural schools. Congress recognized community schools as an effective use of funds for school districts in the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED499A353AE946CEBE238C3D611B8634"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Approximately 86 percent of 9th graders graduate from high school within 4 years. Of students who graduate from high school, 63 percent enroll in a 2- or 4-year college in the fall after completing high school. Only about half (64 percent) of first-time, full-time college freshmen seeking a 4-year degree receive a bachelor’s degree within 6 years or less.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFA2F5E96B4049339E4EA01594991E84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Over the past 4 decades, the United States has slipped from being first in the world in high school and college graduation rates to 21st and 14th, respectively, putting the Nation at a growing competitive disadvantage with other countries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3CD870D40E24944803EC473E82A1CA2" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The 2022 National Assessment of Educational Progress Long-Term Trend Assessment results indicate that between 2020 and 2022, students experienced a 5-percent drop in reading scores, the largest drop since 1990, and a 7-percent decrease, the first ever drop, in math scores. Black student scores in math fell by 13 percent as compared to a 5-percent decrease by their White peers, thus expanding the achievement gap from 25 percentage points to 33 percent percentage points in just 2 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC75033C069754D09A9BAC31AC7996186"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In a study conducted by Hanover Research, data showed that quality partnerships between schools and their communities can result in improved attendance, motivation, conduct, and academic achievement. Community-level strategies like focusing on parental involvement, community building, and cultural competence were shown to contribute to decreases in the achievement gap between lower- and upper-income students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31E63905788D453D97C0E5ACF557F328"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Research from the Government Accountability Office found that students who change schools less frequently are more likely to perform at grade level and less likely to repeat a grade than their less stable peers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F0066F0036A4A239E8A61BD98DE90E5"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In research studies in psychology, health, and education by Teachers College, Columbia University, school <quote>connectedness</quote> is identified as important to student learning, achievement, and well-being. When students feel a sense of connection with the larger world and community institutions, they are more engaged in instructional activities and express greater commitment to school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48EBCDFFF45C4EF7B2A25AF2150439D3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>It has been learned from successful experiences that hundreds of thousands of arts, cultural, service, sports, college, and other youth organizations, as well as civic and faith-based groups, want to partner with schools and educators to reinforce learning, but far too often, neither the school nor the community know how to effectively connect with each other.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3079779FDCB34FE48E8C5FE8C847C967"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In order for the United States to compete in a global economy, the co-partnering efforts of government, social services, business, arts, home, community-based organizations, and philanthropy need to concentrate their efforts where they are most needed: in our schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H156BB28EDC4D41E6AF0F651269EC871D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Research from Johns Hopkins University has shown that access to summer learning opportunities leads to significant student learning gains not experienced by students who cannot access summer learning opportunities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4F6D5B283894E33A976C881021D64E7"><enum>(13)</enum><text>A 2011 study conducted by the RAND Corporation found that students who attend summer learning programs, particularly those featuring individualized instruction, parental involvement, and small class sizes, experience clear benefits in overcoming the achievement gap between low- and upper-income students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E967EF007EC4D9CA65E63AE6ECCADBF"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Research from the Community School Partnership found that community schools see a return of $7.11 for every dollar of investment in community schools coordinators.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H676E0CFD41A04D0FA46B066EEAA75C08"><enum>(15)</enum><text>A 2017 report from the Learning Policy Institute found that teacher retention has a direct impact on student learning and academic performance. Implementing strategies such as teacher residency programs, high-quality mentoring, grow your own models, principal training and State leadership academies can lead to higher rates of educator retention and career satisfaction. For example, California’s Paraprofessional Teacher Training Program has prepared more than 2,200 paraprofessionals to become fully certified teachers with 92 percent of graduates obtaining teaching positions in California public schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38DBA94A046545F099E94BB97F7A7530"><enum>(16)</enum><text>According to the National Center for Education Statistics, 44 percent of public schools reported having at least 1 full-time or part-time vacant teaching position in the spring of 2022. Of those schools with reported unfilled teaching positions, 51 percent cited resignation as the leading cause of vacancies.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H4AF5C2FDB7F64D7AA1736A45AA629B99"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of this Act are—</text><paragraph id="H2B042A60C73142A78676BD53DB4D5614"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to create engaging learning experiences that—</text><subparagraph id="HD45A011EBA044A7CB1ED0C78A99419F6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>strengthen academic achievement, build civic capacity, and provide a continuum of supports and opportunities for children, youth, and families; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H14E0E6412C7B48C5995156449E603A3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare children and youth for college, careers, and citizenship through results-focused partnerships that mobilize and coordinate school and community resources;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H79341DD0EA3D4BC9B7E1DBDEC8F93C6E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure the academic, physical, social, emotional, health, mental health, and civic development of disadvantaged children and youth and thereby strengthen their families and communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE19BC258A8D4B17B2E1547C3771FADA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to engage and support parents, care givers, and families in their role as first educators of their children;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECE1A8F3F2B14A5CB508AD15E464B966"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to promote community and family engagement in education;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD041D79431E4659A55FB0A7AFCCF757"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to leverage and integrate the human and financial assets of local communities, schools, State governments, the Federal Government, and the natural assets of communities—</text><subparagraph id="HBFF8207B915A4052AB411B4A8F1D5B2B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>toward better results for children, youth, and families; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H459C15B21D6248F792B6DBD3A4A10D2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for sustained civic capacity;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D78101BD8524F21BAADB93E37E02C13"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to develop school improvement strategies that incorporate approaches that meet the comprehensive needs of children and youth, such as full service community schools, community-based, integrated student services, and related approaches;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H715D49414C864D418CA25C215ACF0F5E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to ensure that schools and neighborhoods are safe and provide a positive climate for learning; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD046E66174104DCB92DB79C0A27D30BA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to address learning loss as a result of the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7F0B96AF58234BCAA5ACEBEDE31A4972"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H89793D7666984A348505BF6707C1566D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Child with a disability</header><text>The term <term>child with a disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD03475CF94B7482A9797A925FBA96D73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Chronically absent</header><text>The term <term>chronically absent</term>, when used with respect to a student, means a student who misses not less than 10 percent or not less than 20 days of school days in an academic year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCABEC878CF8F4F4AA6B7BF891958CC30"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Community-based, integrated student services</header><text>The term <term>community-based, integrated student services</term> means interventions, coordinated through a single point of contact, that improve student achievement by connecting community resources with the academic and social service needs of students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2F271F41F0E46AEA4A56EE57BD0515B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Community engagement in education</header><text>The term <term>community engagement in education</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H6A8095B6833D42598921833ACC4C3B52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means systematic efforts to involve, engage, and collaborate with parents, community residents, members of school communities, community partners, and other stakeholders in exploring the needs of their students and schools, developing plans to address those needs, and working together to address those needs; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1B302533C244929AE186ED020F01A59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes effective community engagement in an ongoing process to develop a welcoming school and school system, mobilize the community’s assets to support student achievement and growth, engage those individuals and stakeholders who traditionally have not participated in the school or school system, improve working relationships, and deepen the commitment to student success.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18BA18C33C934778897F21861BAB7812"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Digital learning</header><text>The term <term>digital learning</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H6EF89CA34763408F93FF4E807541D8F2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means instructional practices that effectively use technology to strengthen the student learning experience; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43E366E323CF43D4959FB02240F1A01C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include online and formative assessments, instructional resources, online content and courses, applications of technology in the classroom and school building, adaptive software for children with disabilities, learning platforms, and online professional communities of practice.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4991D88629CD467BA2B754D526813767"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based</term>, when used with respect to a goal or service, means a goal or service that meets an evidence level described in subclause (I), (II), or (III) of section 8101(21)(A)(i) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801(21)(A)(i)(I)</external-xref>, (II), and (III)) or section 8101(21)(A)(ii) of such Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA2400F148AE45ACA0B6B0267918EA67"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Family engagement in education</header><text>The term <term>family engagement in education</term> means a shared responsibility of families and schools for student success, in which schools and community-based organizations are committed to reaching out to engage families in meaningful ways that—</text><subparagraph id="H5EC7AB2D5F5F44FCB8C9CFAC51DC7F29"><enum>(A)</enum><text>encourages the families to actively support their children’s learning and development, as well as the learning and development of other children; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8BC676E622E4338AA3F819072110DCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is continuous from birth through young adulthood and reinforces learning that takes place in the home, school, and community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF53C89BC5B174D59ADF9710D0D3DD12D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Full service community school</header><text>The term <term>full service community school</term> means a public elementary school or secondary school that—</text><subparagraph id="H2EC8590C5B8249B69918DB8B313802BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participates in a community-based effort to coordinate educational, developmental, family, health, and other comprehensive services through community-based organizations, specialized instructional support personnel employed by the school or the local educational agency, and public and private partnerships; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6BF4C03A27F4366BBE83E0EF320CEB2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides access to such services to students, families, and the community, including access during the school year (including before- and after-school hours), and during the summer.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F09E92C16F1431D9D626C773B53CE9B"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Local consortium</header><text>The term <term>local consortium</term> means a consortium consisting of community partners that—</text><subparagraph id="H8F7170C8FBEB4EAF9F61807B0B970191"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall include—</text><clause id="HEFE222B3AD4D4A219066C0946D6A278A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a local educational agency; and</text></clause><clause id="HDE4BB4D550984AFDA4756E9F7C9E76E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not less than one community partner that is independent of the local educational agency, such as—</text><subclause id="H4BC660E70BA04A95AE7CA5FCD23D4387"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a community-based organization;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC254F3DD61EB440CBEC191C32EE59295"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a child and youth serving organization or agency;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9065E6CF3F18438699AC6459AB371FC2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an institution of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause id="H9A171B053BE1418580504FE27214989A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a foundation;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBE9C9E8CA2AC4125BD2964D3D7462D01"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a business;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD2EAC2D491F94091AFD3E1B26717C3CC"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a teacher organization;</text></subclause><subclause id="H701A306DB790416788ED245034D2459F"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>an organization representing education professionals;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7A2D036F26464B3096696014F993BBA7"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>a local government, including a government agency serving children and youth, such as a child welfare and juvenile justice agency;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCB61279F9D304CDF930B0C8FA13B6248"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>an organization representing students; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H603E48BC3A4A44BC87AA0E2D48F1DF50"><enum>(X)</enum><text>an organization representing parents; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFDF7735C353435BA4258D39DC2BB642"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may include additional community partners from other communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8662BBAFED804250B0880422F464FAB9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text>The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFFB81484552451DB98B883B27D8D29F"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Outlying area</header><text>The term <term>outlying area</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA377C3D02CD14405BC8FBAE515F6083D"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FD7305ADCF64E38A14C3EDDCFB1FE52"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Specialized instructional support personnel</header><text>The term <term>specialized instructional support personnel</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HD6675EEADD684D23ACC60F5D1474573B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>school counselors, school social workers, and school psychologists; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EE00B8C632F4DCABAFAFAE533F407C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other qualified professional personnel, such as school nurses, speech language pathologists, community school coordinators, and school librarians, involved in providing assessment, diagnosis, and counseling, and educational, therapeutic, and other necessary services (including related services as that term is defined in section 602 of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1401">20 U.S.C. 1401</external-xref>)) as part of a comprehensive program to meet student needs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H24BF96352FEF48F3AB34E9AB2DA82C47"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Specialized instructional support services</header><text>The term <term>specialized instructional support services</term> means the services provided by specialized instructional support personnel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C76CE4FADD04EC08FA9F5EA56B224DC"><enum>(15)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States of the United States, the District of Columbia, and the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42E50BA385AA41848198407524A4575A"><enum>(16)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text>The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H925335B9B4E540C198ACCE8F7D31A8BA"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Target schools</header><text>The term <term>target schools</term> means schools that are identified by the State for comprehensive support and improvement in accordance with section 1111(c)(4)(D)(i) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(c)(4)(D)(i)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H170E8D7746484389A73E979F5B67C09F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Demonstration program authorized; allotment to States</header><subsection id="HBFAF11F8229B41C69D9007A43F02B361"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Formula grants authorized</header><paragraph id="HA2A16539A1B34F6AB29DC91875DC78FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From allotments made under subsection (c), the Secretary is authorized to award grants to States having applications approved under section 8(b) to enable the States to award subgrants to local consortia to leverage and integrate human and financial assets at all levels in order to—</text><subparagraph id="HED77EEE8DDE249FA906DAE61032AFDA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the academic, physical, social, emotional, and civic development of disadvantaged youth; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20C0B7F0857D4175951ACD857C5C62C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strengthen the families and communities of the disadvantaged youth and achieve the results developed pursuant to section 7(c)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F1EC7D499394D47A6D7FD5E012A38FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Secretary shall award a grant under this subsection for a period of 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H062A9A5957CB41B9863A92BD30A2D7D1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>The Secretary may renew a grant under this subsection for a period of 5 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8ADE8CE65E645EBA97FF0A044537771"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reservation</header><text>From the funds appropriated under section 14 for any fiscal year, the Secretary shall reserve—</text><paragraph id="H5D0BB1AC47514F53A97CD1955CFC1229"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 2 percent for national activities, which the Secretary may carry out directly or through grants and contracts, such as—</text><subparagraph id="H7829F1D36FD34986B97DBB3EA06AFE8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing training technical assistance to local consortia and organizations partnering with local consortia to carry out services under this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC622ADCCD7034CDF9C130AFBF8BF1D10"><enum>(B)</enum><text>conducting the national evaluation pursuant to section 13(a)(3); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H00BE0FEFCBF747D5888BD11986C75DD1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 1 percent for payments to the outlying areas and the Bureau of Indian Affairs, to be allotted in accordance with their respective needs for assistance under this Act, as determined by the Secretary, to enable the outlying areas and the Bureau of Indian Affairs to carry out the purposes of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5C479C046A754B2F82F81907248C941C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>State allotments</header><paragraph id="H9B2D85A86057407495F6108EA1F6E106"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>From the funds appropriated under section 14 for any fiscal year that are equal to or greater than $200,000,000 that remain after the Secretary makes the reservations under subsection (b), the Secretary shall allot to each State for the fiscal year an amount that bears the same relationship to the remainder as the amount the State received under subpart 2 of part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6331">20 U.S.C. 6331 et seq.</external-xref>) for the preceding fiscal year bears to the amount all States received under that subpart for the preceding fiscal year, except that no State shall receive less than an amount equal to ½ of 1 percent of such remainder.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H697D4A457FAC4B53A9615E48720D5069"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reallotment of unused funds</header><text>If a State does not receive an allotment under this subsection for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall reallot the amount of the State's allotment to the remaining States in accordance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB78BA666184E44779D284BD109046A13"><enum>6.</enum><header>Demonstration competitive program authorized</header><subsection id="H0902372B13ED4593A725BCEAA8B9C06E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For any fiscal year for which the amount appropriated under section 14 is less than $200,000,000, the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to local consortia to enable the local consortia to carry out local strategies in accordance with sections 10 and 11.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD98FAF9BE0BC4F7DA021C29269C365D2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A local consortium desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require. The application shall demonstrate the capacity for successful implementation of the local strategies in accordance with sections 10 and 11 through a history of successful collaboration and effectiveness in strengthening outcomes for children and youth.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1832B66B0447491797F63313B6641271"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Targeted local consortia</header><paragraph id="H1CE6AB81BED444E2A650E99384C2933A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall award a grant to a local consortium under this section only if the local consortium submits an application that proposes—</text><subparagraph id="H00B9734D0FAA4520B80760CEE401BD15"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to serve children and youth in schools or communities with the highest proportions of students from low-income families; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3FF2FB503314692B462957327739A05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide a comprehensive continuum of services, including not less than 1 service from each of not less than 3 categories of services described in paragraphs (3) through (11) of section 11(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DFCA94BFBC3485FBF01F8B07112ACEC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Low-income families</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>low-income family</term> means a family with an income that is not more than 138 percent of the poverty line (as defined in section 673(2) of the Community Services Block Grant Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9902">42 U.S.C. 9902(2)</external-xref>)) applicable to a family of the size involved.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBFE2D99D01F9499F92102DC797DBF86D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Accountability and transparency</header><text>The Secretary shall apply those provisions of section 13 that the Secretary determines applicable to local consortia receiving funds under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H42700DBC374C446C84B1BBA92EE0C8BA"><enum>7.</enum><header>State child and youth strategy</header><subsection id="HBBA3F096148F44AF8847361F67E106F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this Act shall use the grant funds to develop and implement a State child and youth strategy (referred to in this Act as the <quote>State strategy</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9B1E67865EE347D5AD25E6D0F193C2A4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy requirements</header><text>The State strategy—</text><paragraph id="H3D318A6FEDD549CA8204BF14CAD53625"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be developed by the State educational agency in consultation with the Governor of the State;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H579069D4CAB34F99B890A93063318EC9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall include the components described in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80563F82E063489B9714173C7057EEA5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may include other components as the State educational agency determines necessary to strengthen results for children and youth.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H49BEF14A3F0045B09F36D9F52E1545C9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Required components</header><text>The State strategy components required under subsection (b) are the following:</text><paragraph id="H3A41D3B314DB4C72969E7706E2328346"><enum>(1)</enum><header>State results framework</header><text>The State strategy shall contain comprehensive, evidence-based annual goals and aligned quantifiable indicators demonstrating continuous improvement with respect to children and youth, particularly disadvantaged children and youth, that shall serve as targets for each year with respect to which the State strategy applies. The State's annual goals shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H7C58946EF66C434E9525FC092F6E8B06"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Children and youth are ready for school.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB9BC7A474614C0B97747473DD7118C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Students are engaged and achieving in school.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H956339C49E7744F6A5FF3920CD564CE6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Schools and neighborhoods are safe and provide a positive climate for learning.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8889C2F0E72A4C0AB9F19050AFFF7943"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Families and communities are supportive and engaged in their children’s education as equal partners.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H323264C5397843FEB693AD2A904750FD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Graduates are ready for postsecondary education and 21st-century careers.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF4B75486B346C6B8200FE2D643C4F3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Students are contributing to their communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2587E731773646C296D3A3AEB581D408"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Students are not chronically absent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26A571950C2742968BC1AD435FBECAFA"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Additional annual goals set forth by the State in alignment with the purposes of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H28E86069ED314D1EB3C6DBAC7716ED9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Needs and assets assessment</header><text>The State strategy shall contain an assessment of the children and youth’s needs, and of assets within the State that can be mobilized, coordinated, and integrated to achieve the State strategy’s annual goals, which may include data collected by the Federal Interagency Forum on Child and Family Statistics. Such needs and assets assessment shall identify populations of underserved children and youth across the State, based on the State’s evidence-based goals and aligned quantifiable indicators for the goals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6258A0C7792483E991A712A07DCCCAD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State child and youth plan</header><text>The State strategy shall include a description of the State’s plan to achieve the goals described in paragraph (1) for children and youth from birth through the transition to adulthood, including the following:</text><subparagraph id="H5B520F0A817C4E35AA626BEE914DE584"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Leverage and integration</header><text>A description of how funds received under this Act will be coordinated and integrated with other Federal and State funds in order to achieve the State's annual goals developed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE78097382D1494489466B7E9BA7C4E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elimination of state barriers to coordination and integration</header><text>A description of how funds received under this Act will be used to identify and eliminate State barriers to the coordination and integration of programs, initiatives, and funding streams to achieve the State's annual goals developed pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B0CA68716034275B3913788DF751253"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Community engagement in education</header><text>A description of the State’s plan to increase community engagement in education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30E7241557D24BEF8CACADE3B4A88CB0"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Family engagement in education</header><text>A description of the State’s plan to increase family engagement in education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65B6FA87BA194050AB1447EF9DCAD8FF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing plans, strategies, and assessments</header><text>Existing plans, strategies, needs assessments, or assets assessments may be used to satisfy the requirements of this section if such existing plans, strategies, needs assessments, or assets assessments include the information required by this section, or can be modified to do so, and are submitted to and accepted by the Secretary with such modifications.</text></subsection></section><section id="H97CBDD757ACC4945A08ABF8913C7432A"><enum>8.</enum><header>Coordinating body; State applications</header><subsection id="H445668ADA4964A5EB91D89405B9F410D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordinating body</header><paragraph id="HDAC20927FCF94C02ADDA9D5F97B410C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order for a State to be eligible to receive a grant under this Act, the State educational agency shall designate or establish a coordinating body for student learning and development that shall—</text><subparagraph id="H1CA8D3B68FF541BAA7D688541E732DA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>administer funds provided under this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05D01FD8CF9F41FC9D25B6373028350A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitate communication between the public and the State educational agency pertaining to issues impacting children and youth from birth through the transition to adulthood, including issues pertaining to service coordination and integration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB4B5BFF138D540C09C48A4F66A3A1EAA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>identify and eliminate State barriers to the coordination and integration of programs, initiatives, and funding streams, and facilitate coordination and collaboration among State agencies serving children and youth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H883D911FEEC24914957F9B992F17A518"><enum>(D)</enum><text>strengthen the capacity of State and local organizations to achieve positive outcomes for children and youth through training, technical assistance, professional development, and other means;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H470F6B15D9074F7098A73AF59802A96C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assist the State educational agency in developing and carrying out the State strategy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5B5355D643343A48565308C528022C2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>coordinate the submission of the State application under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H56A364F6CD244C5EB08478F783AD3A24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Designation of coordinating body</header><text>The State educational agency may designate an existing agency, Children's Cabinet, P–20 Council, child and youth development partnership, or other organization as the coordinating body for student learning and development described in paragraph (1) if the agency, cabinet, council, partnership, or organization—</text><subparagraph id="HDF53254FE6514C368A27046EE66ACDD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>performs duties similar to the duties described in paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06A86EE04C06445CA0EEC33F6C46F81A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the duties of the agency, cabinet, council, partnership, or organization can be modified to include the duties described in paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF445DFA341A94EEF9F097CA0E6274D78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State application</header><paragraph id="HB9AD4928292044578A2E1F06BDDD4DAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State desiring a grant under this Act shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H184613A5AC9D4178AE584F0D3BC6518D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>Each application submitted under this subsection shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC37F7A0E0C1340A1A035F789FE07CCF7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>State strategy</header><text>A description of how the State will develop the State strategy, including how the State will—</text><clause id="HE8DD67D3F7AB4C8FA35E45B65AE4FB2E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>coordinate with the State educational agency;</text></clause><clause id="H30DCE270F1F04691BDB2664E0710A958"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consult with potential community partners; and</text></clause><clause id="H280DAC4513194E448040D992A7C38C8D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>allow for the meaningful participation of parents.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6B1CD9ACB684BA5A26BDD874D5CE2AA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Grants to local consortia</header><text>A description of how subgrants to local consortia will be awarded pursuant to section 9, including the criteria used by the State in such determinations and how the subgrants will facilitate community planning and effective service coordination, integration, and provision at the local level to achieve the goals developed by the State pursuant to section 7(c)(1) within the context of local needs and priorities. Such criteria shall include a priority for applications from local consortia intending to serve target schools with the greatest needs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C3FCA939D8A4DEC8C79088BA32189BD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text>A description of how grant funds received under this Act will be used to provide professional development, training, and technical assistance opportunities for staff for the purpose of building State and local capacity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBEF59671B43F49C39847007E6E24DEE2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Accountability for results</header><text>A description of the State’s plans to adhere to the accountability and transparency requirements described in section 13(b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A9F969BA82A4E2CA2FE4A6B56BB84A1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Revised application</header><text>Each State desiring to renew a grant under this Act shall submit a revised application to the Secretary every 5 years based on an assessment of the activities conducted under this Act. Such renewal application shall update the State’s annual goals based on such assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HECD9522731CB4305AFD14C21CC4DF3CD"><enum>9.</enum><header>State use of funds</header><subsection id="H4737AA3CEBCB48D68606F6245240CD50"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From the grant funds made available to a State under this Act for any fiscal year—</text><paragraph id="HF237CD7C314C4A3794BACA94EA52F7A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State shall use not less than 93 percent to award subgrants to local consortia under subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB9B0FDCCD6B4533B44FFF5AEFD0C0BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the State may use not less than 5 percent for educator and specialized instructional support personnel recruitment and retention, evaluation and capacity building activities, including training, technical assistance, and professional development; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1D312386379460EB4CC3F26860F6A5A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the State may use not more than 2 percent for the administrative costs of carrying out responsibilities under this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94F0858EB4A946438A6E6AC94F91D08F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Subgrants to local consortia</header><paragraph id="H04EF0EF07183459399D58F1FB1C923E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HB53509CCEED34F9DB023541C18267DB5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this Act shall use the portion of the grant funds described in subsection (a)(1) to award subgrants to local consortia.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9690E5A2718349248C17E93DEDB38338"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reservation for rural areas</header><clause id="HDC40E38EB7C540CF9B6B9AF120BE616C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From the total amount of funds available under subparagraph (A) to award subgrants to local consortia for a fiscal year, the State may reserve 5 percent to award subgrant to rural local consortia for such fiscal year.</text></clause><clause id="H954282BA2A644DF781E9F0AF858D207D"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rural local consortium</header><text>In this subsection the term <term>rural local consortium</term> means a local consortium serving an area of the State that has a locale code of 41, 42, or 43.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF1CE339297C419FBA550C02D7BCFC17"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding subgrants to local consortia, a State shall give priority to applications from local consortia—</text><subparagraph id="HD30AE7D1278143BB94731C7BAB359871"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that propose to serve children and youth in target schools; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB69EE51803F47D497D64B65403401A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that submit a proposal with a plan to provide a comprehensive continuum of services, including not less than 1 service from each of not less than 3 categories of services described in paragraphs (3) through (11) of section 11(b), and which application—</text><clause id="H0B25645CECA54E0BAE23A1DBE97D485B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is submitted by local consortia comprised of a broad representation of stakeholders and decision makers in the community, including a multitude of community partners described in section 4(9); or</text></clause><clause id="H35886D9B5D3346F0BF73EF56FA5105E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>demonstrates the capacity for successful implementation through a history of successful collaboration and effectiveness in strengthening outcomes for children and youth.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E142F185CE249DCA95FBFE32B60D4DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duration of grant</header><text>Each subgrant awarded under this section shall be for a period of 5 years and shall be renewable based on progress toward achieving the results described in section 10(b)(2)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD86A7D7E13614D9CBA053EABC5FB890C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Planning grants</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this Act may award planning grants to local consortia to enable the local consortia to develop the local strategy described in section 10(b). Such planning grants shall be for a duration of—</text><paragraph id="H8464A0A3B28D472F9197CEEA423B1F4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not more than 6 months and in an amount of not more than $50,000; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H304C95B455534E5FB8D6205C1A06A8CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not more than 1 year and in an amount of not more than $100,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2154055F56F34AC682F088EB7F86070C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>A State that receives a grant under this Act shall use the grant funds to supplement, not supplant, Federal and non-Federal funds available to carry out activities described in this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H109A65E59AF242B59D0FB527B42B9243"><enum>10.</enum><header>Local consortium application; local child and youth strategy</header><subsection id="H9041021B9921402AB608AF9A92188813"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Local consortium application</header><paragraph id="H4C8426CC23994BFAA2FF5E2603CFAAB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A local consortium that desires a subgrant under section 9 shall submit an application to the State at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the State may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13B0AE5127294E93947AB2FC82AFD9AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>An application submitted under this section shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HF7C4A3C8E9AC4D7ABDC4B18631F04772"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of the local consortium, including which public or nonprofit entity participating in the local consortium shall serve as the fiscal agent for the local consortium;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FB8282ECF6F40E68BDD11240A89716D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the local child and youth strategy (referred to in this Act as the <quote>local strategy</quote>) described in subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FE6181DE5194110817BB9CF478D3C8F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the local strategy will be coordinated with the local educational agency plan required under section 1112 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6312">20 U.S.C. 6312</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5789F78E7F7941CB903D51AB755F2E84"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a list of schools identified by the local consortium to receive comprehensive, coordinated continuum of services and support in accordance with the local strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H43D5DFCFBC6D48DD967B79EBE4757516"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local strategy</header><paragraph id="H953D1DF5576744B284D0D53076835A7B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The local strategy—</text><subparagraph id="H94910CC1A3E245E2BB87A9422ADAFA1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be developed by the local consortium;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4550086CFA414889AECB51406A0A421A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include the components described in paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFB26E9374124FC2A87A682C7F6C04CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may include such other components as the local consortium determines necessary to strengthen outcomes for children and youth from birth through the transition to adulthood.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC817AD83E05A4346B69C5E3695067B57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The local strategy components required under paragraph (1)(B) are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBB3A6DFE6F1F45939D09EDE422E59607"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Local results framework</header><text>Comprehensive, evidence-based goals and aligned quantifiable indicators for the goals, with respect to youth, particularly disadvantaged children and youth, that shall serve as targets for the year with respect to which the local strategy applies. The goals shall be set forth annually and include the following:</text><clause id="H3C896B4800FE44FC992BD6037D0FAF30"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Children are ready for school.</text></clause><clause id="HD1338A1EC26843FAA848330D136BF753"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Students are engaged and achieving in school.</text></clause><clause id="H9AAA2655DC424250A47B43401DC186A8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Schools and neighborhoods are safe and provide a positive climate for learning.</text></clause><clause id="H3BCBCA6398E145449C5B7378C6797DC9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Families are supportive and engaged in their children’s education.</text></clause><clause id="HD99AD8BE10FD45388276FBA8D9EC8E94"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Students are ready for postsecondary education and 21st-century careers.</text></clause><clause id="H0DD0352CC3EB4A75B41F173E58AB2368"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Students are contributing to their communities.</text></clause><clause id="HAB9D692B70A7474FB80E3D56DA2122BA"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Students are not chronically absent.</text></clause><clause id="HB3415FD3D71E41CCB26FE9D6DDF5B4D1"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Additional annual goals set forth by the local consortium in alignment with the purposes of this Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC003C2B16DD4C479E57436897B4BA1D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assets assessment</header><text>An assessment of potential resources, services, and opportunities available within or near the community and schools identified by the local consortium to receive support under the subgrant that children and youth, their families, and resources in the community may be able to access in order to meet the needs identified under subparagraph (C), to help achieve the goals and indicators under subparagraph (A), and to support students to achieve the challenging State academic standards (described in section 1111 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311</external-xref>)), including the variety of services that can be integrated—</text><clause id="H5487CDA2FB5B40A99A6A080BAE0FDE9D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>into a community school site; and</text></clause><clause id="HADC9320B3EDD4836BDAB5AED5F33242E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through the presence of specialized instructional support personnel and local educational agency liaisons for homeless children and youth designated pursuant to section 722(g)(1)(J)(ii) of the McKinney-Vento Homeless Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/11432">42 U.S.C. 11432(g)(1)(J)(ii)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66DBB021B2AC419CA8FD89A2535CF884"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Needs assessment</header><text>An analysis of the comprehensive needs of the students served by the local consortium, their families, and the community that—</text><clause id="H78F0F3B3264A4AB7A771FB63F627FDD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>includes input from students, parents, and community members, including input from such individuals connected to schools identified by the local consortium to receive support under the subgrant;</text></clause><clause id="H883288696BED40D59455BB97D0A82659"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>identifies populations of underserved children and youth, based on the State’s evidence-based goals and aligned quantifiable indicators for the goals;</text></clause><clause id="H1DCEE59004114FAF82BD9EBA3C02EE92"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>assesses the academic, physical, social, emotional, health, mental health, and civic needs of students and their families enrolled in schools identified by the local consortium to receive support under the subgrant; and</text></clause><clause id="H907FF59CF23E4BDB864A6C99B91C22D1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>may impact students’ ability to meet the challenging State student academic achievement standards.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFAD2F2FA3B4450F82521B21D7DC67F7"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Service integration and provision</header><text>A plan to coordinate and integrate services and provide services in order to meet the needs identified under subparagraph (C) and achieve the results and aligned quantifiable indicators described in subparagraph (A), including—</text><clause id="H0EEF3D7FE3A94F0AA23E0CC0667F44C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a description of the services administered by members of the local consortium that are funded through grants provided under the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6301">20 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>) that will be coordinated as part of the subgrant provided under section 9; and</text></clause><clause id="HAB4F48189C174F53B8F58F687986CFD4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if applicable, a description of the coordination among services provided by community-based organizations and services provided by specialized instructional support personnel serving local educational agencies participating in the local consortium.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A5B85B1024948A78713026DFCA70A92"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Community engagement in education</header><text>A plan to increase community engagement in education.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0652413E082C482CBFEA181B37B0ED69"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Family engagement in education</header><text>A plan to increase family engagement in education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H578B80AFA7DC4074951A28875427DEE8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Existing plans, strategies, and assessments</header><text>Existing plans, strategies, needs assessments, or assets assessments may be used to satisfy the requirements of this section if such existing plans, strategies, needs assessments, or assets assessments include the information required by this section, or can be modified to do so, and are submitted to the Secretary with such modifications.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3E641FB8836C492B82C03C0338A386DA"><enum>11.</enum><header>Local use of funds</header><subsection id="H82863759C1574506A7C7AB54F52803AB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory use of funds</header><text>A local consortium that receives a subgrant under section 9 or a grant under section 6 shall use the subgrant or grant funds—</text><paragraph id="H366A0C61EDC54508A7682F0CD3800E27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to integrate services into a comprehensive, coordinated continuum that meets the holistic needs of children and youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C79CAE998949419F89643333B3A777"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to implement the comprehensive, coordinated continuum of services described in paragraph (1) through evidence-based services producing quantifiable results that align with the local results framework described in section 10(b)(2)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC36FF4CD363049AAB3494916735BAB9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to address the needs identified in the needs assessment carried out pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(C) by leveraging the assets identified in the assets assessment carried out pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(B); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H07DD4831C8934DD5B1C042D608A15116"><enum>(4)</enum><text>if applicable, to coordinate efforts with the teachers, school leaders, paraprofessionals, and specialized instructional support personnel serving local educational agencies participating in the local consortium, and promote capacity building activities with the local educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H981319BE8E084C1C9BD01173AA5411E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissible use of funds</header><text>A local consortium that receives a subgrant under section 9 or a grant under section 6 may use the subgrant or grant funds to coordinate, integrate, and enhance existing services, and provide new services, in order to provide children and youth with research-based, comprehensive services at, or that are connected to, schools, including—</text><paragraph id="HE55965040F614B1496F6623B95E9D466"><enum>(1)</enum><text>community-based, integrated student services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48281C18B32946C0A39634F1CC4A3798"><enum>(2)</enum><text>full service community schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DE15B0AAA37473085CDC2953D6A68FD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>high-quality early childhood learning and development, including—</text><subparagraph id="H0DFCE0938C5B4092828F7560CADD32B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>early childhood education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75F617FA864A416688B6D23ACED5E9C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>programs under the Head Start Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9831">42 U.S.C. 9831 et seq.</external-xref>), including Early Head Start programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF056741570D445F8AA83F44C1321A29B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>early reading first programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5305B9C6DDD444C4943FF95C680CFF4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>child care services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FDC546789FB4D3CBECA88BFBC43EAA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>early childhood-school transition services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A8C2194D9C24E35AF79F5E74223E455"><enum>(F)</enum><text>home visiting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBBFC3F85003443DB66BFB2133BD876B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>parenting education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9142250A05644FE9865EA5CB89AD1FA7"><enum>(H)</enum><text>services for children with disabilities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE13934801BA945BBAEB3257280F8224F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>academic support services for students (including children with disabilities), including—</text><subparagraph id="H126276C7744C4CF793878EB4F1FB1B45"><enum>(A)</enum><text>tutoring;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38973056ABC64E58AB42BFE572CE49C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>extended day programs, afterschool programs, or both such programs, which shall include services provided through 21st Century Community Learning Centers under part B of title IV of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7171">20 U.S.C. 7171 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC950E45F4F245D39604E0A685F9AAF4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>academic support services for English-language learners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H358391595778470F981E69F845F2895B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>programs for students and parents to learn together, including opportunities in such fields as technology, art, music, and language acquisition;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF38ED39766D48A7A2E031AC3661DC51"><enum>(E)</enum><text>multiple pathways toward attaining a high school diploma and preparing students for college, including—</text><clause id="H927E9C30D208487D9613A5953465D18F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dual enrollment programs;</text></clause><clause id="H2F5664B22DDB40A5B4D3E479D8F00E9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>early college high schools;</text></clause><clause id="H29CBE464DCF24BF7A4B8FEABFC7F38A7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>strategies for preventing at-risk youth from dropping out of high school;</text></clause><clause id="H4A605E45DC694E7B8406F975CF2B84A9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>dropout recovery strategies, including strategies that award credit based on student performance instead of instructional time; and</text></clause><clause id="H9A45914626E54CA6879706EE6551C93D"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other activities that combine rigorous coursework, personalized learning environments, practical applications, and comprehensive support services; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB9A8F3DD5B6458C973E343027C30660"><enum>(F)</enum><text>summer enrichment and learning experiences;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A950C1C452D447AB6324F9E87E53945"><enum>(5)</enum><text>health services, including—</text><subparagraph id="H6C6754FE847542EFAEF7307C1699EA7B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>primary health care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6E29935A7994CA7AF0136EAC405BDEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>dental care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51EBA6A86DE74486972BFBF70A9A60C2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>vision care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H129E9EDD6DD942D5B3A3AD802C933908"><enum>(D)</enum><text>speech and hearing care;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E93ADB701D4BD8B22C4921FCABB13D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>mental health services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24159EAEB6584F95920B79DACCA19F73"><enum>(F)</enum><text>nutrition services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H934CD5DDC5E5411597662D9493F8F9C3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>health education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B3B32E501514555A1F9719E218E2FCD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>developmental and habilitation services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92BDE23795748BAB3CB1D0CDFDFC21F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>youth development, including—</text><subparagraph id="H7FB0BBAC870F4489B72629510D9997F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>mentoring and other youth development programs, including programs that engage older adults;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D157F2FBFBC4AA7AD60B4EA87D187DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recreation and physical education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BAC94D6E0AC40E797C6F99FA7386D25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>service learning, civic education, leadership development, entrepreneurship, and community service opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3FF3FE40FA045548019650D45D0F817"><enum>(D)</enum><text>job training, career counseling, and internship opportunities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CF71B8D719D496F81532546A9CDF044"><enum>(E)</enum><text>career and technical education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D6860B3DB02459DA3F16EEFD3EFA6C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>college preparation and counseling services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47E5347704CE4B0C904B8239CC4E21D6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>positive behavioral interventions and supports;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H708897D2D27941D087E4026BD5AB3023"><enum>(H)</enum><text>financial literacy and Federal financial aid awareness activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BBD9DEF0E0442B0B69EBA43FE8CC8A1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>social and emotional learning;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E9E40EC716748FE8CB31BFF1456CA70"><enum>(7)</enum><text>social services for students and families, including—</text><subparagraph id="H40940E282EE34FD3B696E6C26E98C3E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>family support programs, including housing assistance, counseling, financial education, crisis intervention, and related services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DE9654973EB40AD9B58AD386C24CB87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>programs that provide assistance to students who have been truant, suspended, or expelled;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC95F7DBA7FD488CAEE86D6E3F2B91E0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>programs or efforts intended to identify young people without a high school diploma and reengage the young people in school so that the young people may attain a high school diploma;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H824BCFEA8CCD4EB09A8F4B968C378FF5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>strategies that engage older adults as resources to students and families; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB93C565559B54DC7B3548CD9B0146D82"><enum>(E)</enum><text>services for homeless students, foster children and youth, students previously under the custody of the juvenile justice system, and students who are pregnant and parenting;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H15FA3D4EAE154330AD29090C892C78D7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>parent and adult education programs, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2B823C488C5A4D0389A91330E2501BF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>programs that promote family literacy, including family literacy programs for English-language learners;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEABD03CA09C54149B71CFFC295325EDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>parent and caregiver leadership and parent and caregiver education activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3888302E29414ABF94934312EB4F2DBD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>translation services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1607D7CFBBD044008D472E8000365FB2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>adult education, including instruction in English as a second language, and job training; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA11013E3C38042E2AE66DEF9B5D3DF4B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>citizenship preparation for individuals choosing to become United States citizens;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B0C8AD6D29544FC9D50E52D2FF579FA"><enum>(9)</enum><text>juvenile crime prevention and rehabilitation programs, including—</text><subparagraph id="H5D5991B25ED241BDB000D2DC499D2B1F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>youth courts, teen courts, peer juries, and drug courts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H279671AA08A1403CBC9D1003DFDE468C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>tribal youth programs;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AB887B88BFE4A36AFAAA423FC20B6C5"><enum>(10)</enum><text>specialized instructional support services, including specialized instructional support personnel;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA4A4D4589EA46C5BEE94E1635CDC008"><enum>(11)</enum><text>service coordination staffing that ensures young people receive comprehensive services to meet the holistic needs of the young people;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7753606716C34AFB92321B1186D05C91"><enum>(12)</enum><text>training, technical assistance, and professional development for school-based and community-based personnel to build capacity and skills to educate English-language learners;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DB2A238005E442584396FE0CF7CBBFC"><enum>(13)</enum><text>training, technical assistance, and professional development for school-based and community-based personnel providing comprehensive services to children and youth;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD0059841AF4FDC97CBF44203132B0E"><enum>(14)</enum><text>subgrants to nonprofit and other organizations to implement the requirements and allowable services under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA97739856FDC4DE5B7422B42ACF3966A"><enum>(15)</enum><text>reasonable program administration and planning associated with the activities required under this section, including—</text><subparagraph id="H3185AE3C746543DFAAD0C5A2279B203A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recruiting teachers and specialized instructional support personnel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA6B28FDC7D542CDADCD286581AD925E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing programs designed to retain and promote school-based personnel, including—</text><clause id="HD110E548D39346919CF16AB843B8B184"><enum>(i)</enum><text>mentoring programs;</text></clause><clause id="H3B0955AB2D354F81A22769D2FE23F092"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>grow your own programs; and</text></clause><clause id="HC065E314991C40F294BB2C4E4E356753"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>leadership and career advancement programs; </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H51F4C4B8DDC8497CBD6675E3BDD51F8B"><enum>(16)</enum><text>access to and training on digital learning; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57FBF205BC1541F1B21AFC85CC14F9C5"><enum>(17)</enum><text>other services consistent with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEEA1EC9D9AE744B694ABEA616C839655"><enum>12.</enum><header>Construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to alter or otherwise affect the rights, remedies, and procedures afforded school or school district employees under Federal, State, or local laws (including applicable regulations or court orders) or under the terms of collective bargaining agreements, memoranda of understanding, or other agreements between such employees and their employers.</text></section><section id="H20C0816A9EBE4915AB6EA71D08D4090B"><enum>13.</enum><header>Accountability and transparency</header><subsection id="H2574E061F54241EEA57AE7979F895979"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal accountability and transparency</header><paragraph id="H616C3C9FBFAB45B89D82B27D919E0181"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>On an annual basis, the Secretary shall report to the public, Congress, and the President—</text><subparagraph id="H61B1B71A3D4F4F10A63E711EA779B175"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the collective progress made by—</text><clause id="HC208EBFC63544B17A5DF0220CD67B491"><enum>(i)</enum><text>States in achieving the goals established within the State results frameworks described in section 7(c)(1); and</text></clause><clause id="H6D9E7364EA8A4D5A90AE07A443D426E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>communities in achieving the goals established within the local results frameworks pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(A);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB17ED8A8AF9D42C69E6087D13AC75AA8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how funds under this Act were used by States and local consortia to improve the lives of children, youth, and families, including—</text><clause id="H217451DF9E9E4779905FB597DFDCCCBD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the characteristics of the children and youth and families served by the activities and services assisted under this Act;</text></clause><clause id="H8F15ABD2F9934E789E085FF6B71E33C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the services and supports provided under this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H613E92C11C3F44688BD2E55EEF952359"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>outcomes resulting from the activities and services funded under this Act;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAD4B15B081240868AE0F96B04398732"><enum>(C)</enum><text>actions taken pursuant to paragraph (2) regarding misuse or ineffective use of funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9000E45F74CB47C2B0ABA13654D649BA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>other information the Secretary determines to be of interest to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93EE3D2C639E439583D45464AE746617"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Correction of deficiencies</header><text>If the Secretary determines, based on a review of State annual reports, State strategies, State data submissions, evaluations, or other documentation, that a State or entity that receives funds through a grant or contract made under this Act makes insufficient progress toward achieving the goals established within the State results framework pursuant to section 7(c)(1) within 3 years of receiving a grant under section 5(a), or is misusing, ineffectively using, or otherwise not complying with the requirements of this Act, the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H278F2A37C56546C6ABF8A1EFA09831E8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the State of the deficiencies that require correction and request that the State submit a plan to correct the deficiencies within 6 months;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B158F3AB60B4EDD84824C9A83930D18"><enum>(B)</enum><text>negotiate a plan to correct the deficiencies, and provide appropriate training or technical assistance designed to assist the State in complying with the requirements of this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83FD979BCCC443CC924FBCCCED77AD53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case that the State fails to submit or negotiate a plan to correct the deficiencies or fails to make substantial efforts, within 6 months after the date of the notification described in paragraph (1), to correct the deficiencies and comply with the requirements of this Act—</text><clause id="HBC811759BB154934AA5F96079214E83D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>terminate the provision of funds under this Act to the State or entity for the remainder of the period of the grant or contract; and</text></clause><clause id="H09686BCC78354B68B446EF8808F81D66"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>redistribute the terminated funding in the manner described in section 5(c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16A147CDD6F5407EB10323DA7ABB08F9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent ongoing evaluation</header><subparagraph id="H8EA4E42A83C34B6AAB30737D3BF772FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out an ongoing evaluation of the activities conducted under this Act and shall submit the evaluation results to Congress and the public by not later than June 30, 2023, and June 30, 2025.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBBB579D5756D494B8C8410970AE67893"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rigorous and independent evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into a contract with an entity independent of the Department of Education to carry out the evaluation required under this paragraph. To the extent the Secretary determines feasible, the evaluation shall include large-scale, longitudinal, randomized studies to identify the most effective combinations of academic and nonacademic interventions, including interventions administered by community-based organizations, to achieve improvements in academic and other outcomes for students.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB342928A4C344DC6A5A6294CB52DAD8F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Evaluation outcomes</header><clause id="H4E458E75C477491590C0D792F42BDC5C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The evaluation required under this paragraph shall measure the process of developing and implementing effective partnerships among schools, school districts, families, students, and community partners, as well as the impact of activities conducted under this Act, which may include impacts on the following outcomes:</text><subclause id="H2A6A1B8316A24867B405BFF34DD4161E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Student achievement as measured by assessment data, classroom grades, and other means of measuring student performance.</text></subclause><subclause id="H53E0D63C9A7D4A6EA51D2A061A4ECFC3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Graduation rates.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC0C449D2BCBB4D7598F0DEB205AA9BC9"><enum>(III)</enum><text>School readiness.</text></subclause><subclause id="HAC78B10378B049E981BE495E8E563F0A"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Numbers of detentions, suspensions, and expulsions and the use of seclusion and physical restraint.</text></subclause><subclause id="H16644DF8857A49FE84D603544803009F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Enrollment in postsecondary education.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5AD21786A0704FDD890B0CB4FD2C4FA4"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The degree of communication between schools and families.</text></subclause><subclause id="H3F4CCAC3191A46D889F3596335E367D8"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The degree of parental participation in school activities.</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D10975F10774F6E9A599A3B70D21FB1"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>Student health, including mental health and risk factors at birth.</text></subclause><subclause id="H2F6320C0420F46A7A771500043B3AA74"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>Student civic participation.</text></subclause><subclause id="H81F2A7F4B5AF490AA74AA85A082C20E0"><enum>(X)</enum><text>Attendance.</text></subclause><subclause id="H8CC8EC2FFFB6472FA896129F5505A7D8"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>The number of students and families receiving services.</text></subclause><subclause id="HCD5978C0F731450899903ACDF5459492"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>Other outcome areas as determined by the Secretary in consultation with State educational agencies, local educational agencies, teacher organizations, secondary students, and nonprofit organizations providing services to children and youth.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5622138458C54CA49FE68BA535D91144"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Disaggregation</header><text>The outcomes described in clause (i) shall be disaggregated by all subgroups identified in section 1111(b)(2)(B)(xi) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311(b)(2)(B)(xi)</external-xref>), and family income.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD764A07B22E04665AC6A90C18C5A4390"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State accountability and transparency</header><paragraph id="H988180774A8F4127A2719D9B843E95D2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>On an annual basis, each State shall report to the public and the Secretary such information as the Secretary may reasonably require, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9A105103AA9D4BE2B9E574408E22A2C2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>progress made toward achieving—</text><clause id="HCB1DD61A82BF497A909E5FAFFBEE7466"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the goals established within the State results framework pursuant to section 7(c)(1) disaggregated in the same manner as information is disaggregated under subsection (a)(3)(C)(ii); and</text></clause><clause id="H0249A8D694E24BAFB87AE7C7E750F583"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the goals established within the local results frameworks pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(A);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H853181C9F09B473EA63D7D7EF1566FEC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how funds under this Act were used by States and local consortia to improve the lives of children, youth, and families, including—</text><clause id="H0C8DAE863E984B1D8F8E2FA631922586"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the characteristics of children, youth, and families served by the activities and services assisted under this Act;</text></clause><clause id="H5B6D85F2940B4788A5B5AC06D6C6D1A8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the services and supports provided under this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H95453D7BF5414442B15BBF542368B206"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>outcomes resulting from the activities and services funded under this Act;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB00937FFF8348E29225A7338D32ECE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information on Federal and State barriers to effective State and local coordination;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E2A68D8112D4765BAE7ACF69805C544"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent of coordination between State departments and agencies providing children and youth services in place to achieve the goals within the State results framework pursuant to section 7(c)(1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H598BA69578B14FA399478DCDFEDC32CC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the extent to which the objectives and budgets of State departments and agencies providing child and youth services were consistent with the recommendations of the State strategy for the preceding year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3176563A664463C8006F8847028B12D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the efficiency and adequacy of State and local programs and policies with respect to child and youth services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EDE37E3A4534137A9F985EDCCA136AF"><enum>(G)</enum><text>actions taken pursuant to paragraph (2) regarding misuse or ineffective use of funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F19F21A51EC41CCB19372607E535F4B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>other information the State determines to be of interest to the public.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB37CAEF824B24DF5B88D12CA1DF7764F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Correction of deficiencies</header><text>If the State determines, based on a review of annual reports submitted in accordance with subsection (c), data submissions, evaluations, or other documentation, that a local consortium or organization that receives funds through a subgrant made under this Act makes insufficient progress toward achieving the goals established within the local results framework pursuant to section 9(b)(2)(A) within 3 years of receiving a subgrant under section 8, or is misusing, ineffectively using, or otherwise not complying with the requirements of this Act, the State shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3BE9394D62AD4B55BC2F907ECE0D67A7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the local consortium of the deficiencies within 6 months that require correction and request that the consortium submit a plan to correct the deficiencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC12F1F226444A7CA45F2F4921DE62C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>negotiate a plan to correct the deficiencies, and provide appropriate training or technical assistance designed to assist the local consortium in complying with the requirements of this Act and make progress in achieving the goals established within the local results framework pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1149A2136DAB470EB3A7A5AD08CBEF95"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in the case that the local consortium fails to submit or negotiate a plan to correct the deficiencies or fails to make substantial efforts, within 6 months after the date of the notification described in subparagraph (A), to correct the deficiencies and comply with the requirements of this Act, terminate the provision of funds under this Act to the local consortium or organization for the remainder of the period of the subgrant and redistribute the terminated funding in a manner determined by the State to be in the best interests of the children and youth in such State in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECC3DC2011794C208640D7727E1BC848"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Local accountability and transparency</header><text>On an annual basis, each local consortium shall report to the public and submit to the State a report containing such information as the State may reasonably require, including—</text><paragraph id="H0FE8696902964B5B8FD08B1416F5835E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>progress made toward achieving the goals established within the local results framework pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(A) disaggregated in the same manner as information is disaggregated under subsection (a)(3)(C)(ii);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FCF6BA369CF4F998C110613BD709B04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how funds under this Act were used by the local consortium and subgrant recipients to improve the lives of children, youth, and families, including—</text><subparagraph id="H80291354803A4FC2931D1AF76899705F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the characteristics of the children and youth and families served by the activities and services assisted under this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAD5E5E01DE840809DBB6EDFEB53FC80"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the services and supports provided under this Act;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H15DFCE645C964268B4AA4549B46C5ADD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the capacity building efforts provided under this Act, including the types of professional development provided to staff of the local educational agency in the local consortia; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E5D235ADC1B49E98DDFC909A2633D39"><enum>(D)</enum><text>outcomes resulting from the activities and services funded under this Act, in accordance with the State's annual goals;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE2606C442BA4FADA45CAE111A60C9F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>information on State barriers to effective local coordination of private and public services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59DB9069CF514F6CB0431F65F2F3EA85"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the extent of coordination between local agencies and organizations providing services to achieve the goals within the local results framework pursuant to section 10(b)(2)(A); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D3A0C81F9CB4F8AB1EAB914CD34149B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other information the local consortium determines to be of interest to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF55BC65F4C1B42BC9DB1E170683AE278"><enum>14.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act such sums as may be necessary for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

