<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7DF22E5B8B794D59855FAC9DB62BD3C0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7246 IH: Student and Student Athlete Opioid Misuse Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7246</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220328">March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use to award grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements for planning, establishing, or administering programs to prevent and address the misuse of opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used in pain management or injury recovery, as well as the co-use of one or more such drugs with other substances, by students and student athletes, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC67072E2B57949B298CB0E071C4BF1A5" style="OLC"><section id="H13B8A5F9A79040C98D819324179456D8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student and Student Athlete Opioid Misuse Prevention Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Student Athlete Opioid Prevention Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H54F9E0B8AC184F8C855D09EB5AE3EBEF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants for opioid misuse prevention</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part A of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290aa">42 U.S.C. 290aa et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2161B6181E0E401DAD3DDD88BA01D5EA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H91E7FCAF9A3C40C6A4D1975C2050851D"><enum>506B.</enum><header>Grants for student and student athlete opioid misuse prevention</header><subsection id="HC5CFB7597E594ECEAF0EDC045789392E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education, may award grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements to eligible entities for planning, establishing, or administering programs to prevent and address the misuse of opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used in pain management or injury recovery, as well as the co-use of one or more such drugs with other substances, by students and student athletes.</text></subsection><subsection id="H633A0623187D40F59FFF4E25794C8A8A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this section, an entity shall be—</text><paragraph id="H8CF2CDA8D50049CDA4F709BCF300A34F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State or other public entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0144B1144FEE45FF989D205660AF0BEE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9256FF3893F4F189D87F8A543DC67E1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a drug-free community coalition.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67B6A97FEA564027B3E67C72618801AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of Funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts received through an award under this section may be used for any of the following:</text><paragraph id="H8D2A51CFE7374EF29D22A39BD9202810"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carrying out one or more school-based programs concerning the dangers of the misuse of, and addiction to, opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used in pain management or injury recovery, as well as the co-use of one or more such drugs with other substances, which programs may include—</text><subparagraph id="HA043B92E03DF41ED9FAE95202F08F5FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>initiatives that give students the responsibility to create their own anti-drug abuse education programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00FB986C6B8D427EBDD362E278AEEC9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">school-based programs that are focused on school districts with high or increasing rates of misuse of, and addiction to, opioids, and targeted at populations that are most at risk to start misusing such drugs, including schools that do not have a certified athletic trainer on staff; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE55ED41B629649319786458250617F9C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">school-based prevention programs that are focused on student athletes and the risk of misuse of, and addiction to, opioids, as well as the co-use of opioids with other substances, as part of injury recovery and pain management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA6A317978264D46980D530F8768CEFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carrying out community-based misuse and addiction prevention programs relating to opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used in pain management or injury recovery, as well as the co-use of one or more such drugs with other substances, which programs may include—</text><subparagraph id="HBFA1FDCF77F941398D7B6B940512C416"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such programs through youth sports organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E4036413B048F7977D43D28C094976"><enum>(B)</enum><text>community-based prevention programs that are focused on populations within the community that are most at risk for misuse of and addiction to opioids; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H024C2C4562C240CB8DA9BAABAE9F6726"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">community-based programs that are focused on youth athletes and the risk of misuse of and addiction to opioids, as well as the co-use of opioids with other substances, as part of injury recovery and pain management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C368C62E4F44AEB85E8FFB0FB649914"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engaging youth, high school, or collegiate athletic and recreation programs and associations concerning the dangers of the misuse of and addiction to opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used in pain management or injury recovery, as well as the co-use of one or more such drugs with other substances, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="HB0CF35F7E9F14C80938C9DC590033F83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>initiatives that give student athletes the responsibility to create their own anti-drug abuse education programs for their schools; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3449827508D436D99AA0DC0EB006803"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collegiate-based programs that are focused on collegiate athletes, including club sports and recreation sports, and the risk for misuse of and addiction to opioids, as well as the co-use of opioids with other substances, as part of injury recovery and pain management.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCF3950E524F4FAA88BDD282A539DD94"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assisting local government entities to conduct appropriate prevention activities relating to youth and the risk for misuse of and addiction to opioids, as well as the co-use of opioids with other substances, as part of injury recovery and pain management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA012EF5EE8F4D2BB050A8920916374B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training and educating State and local officials, youth athletics organizers, school administrators and staff, teachers, athletic directors, athletic trainers, coaches, collegiate administrators, directors of campus recreation, and campus-based medical providers, on the signs of misuse of opioids and the options for treatment, including holistic and comprehensive pain management solutions, and prevention of such misuse.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D48931B7744B7589979B5E481AD03E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Evaluation; reporting</header><paragraph id="H6247F67B95EE467997540CBAAF9BE5C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Assistant Secretary, in consultation with the heads of other relevant Federal agencies, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H226F39A344C84643931F6785DCA9BA03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct or support periodic evaluations of the programs funded under this section and other effective programs to prevent and address misuse of and addiction to opioids, related drugs, and other drugs commonly used for pain management and injury recovery; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB38888B56EE14FF2839D806C227FE964"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop strategies for disseminating information about and implementing such programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H260A2FF6A67B481B968F257FFA7E8816"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary shall annually submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, a report on the programs evaluated under paragraph (1)(A) and the strategies developed under paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D2C1F8C195B443FAB9BE0E512394BDA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section the term, <quote>drug-free community coalition</quote> means a community-based coalition that is a current or former recipient of a grant under section 1032 of the Anti-Drug Abuse Act of 1988.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0672931F27174A809BE89097ACD3F96F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HD791A4AAA7534C60ABA6405BF177C4A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated—</text><subparagraph id="HA7C447B8B2E242648A0FC4BF5DF311CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000,000 for fiscal year 2023; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CDE6803087F4B3488A17B22925F5540"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA5526D175C44CB888C41AF38617920"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation</header><text>Of the amount authorized to be appropriated by paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, not more than $500,000 shall (subject to the availability of appropriations) be used to carry out subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

