<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39F11C329BC244DE8EA5577A8EB34A9A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9295 IH: To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Incorporated, is recognized as a Village Corporation under that Act, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9295</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221114">November 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000619">Mrs. Peltola</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act to provide that Alexander Creek, Incorporated, is recognized as a Village Corporation under that Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8DEF57DB598A407E87C5B99CF9D403CE" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HA67027F394934CEE8E9CD2B4FE6D4097"><enum>1.</enum><header>Alexander Creek recognition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC252021170FE4546952E40D912D67BD7"> <section id="H18AABE88ECD649149FC06E38CCCFF87C"><enum>43.</enum><header>Alexander Creek recognition</header> <subsection id="H044A9BBD74FB42EF80AC83102DDEB58C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H17E2D057784C46D5A860388C9BE69745"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Alexander Creek, Incorporated</header><text>The term <term>Alexander Creek, Incorporated</term> means Alexander Creek, Incorporated, the entity organized and recognized—</text> <subparagraph id="H3DD95F72D2024424AA68BAC1DF47C720"><enum>(A)</enum><text>on the day before the date of enactment of this section, as a Group Corporation; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H92C8A2EBAAB74682A639E6F337EDF82F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>effective beginning on the date of enactment of this section, as a Village Corporation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE0F049710BF94F969B353B98171EFA0A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alexander Creek village</header><text>The term <term>Alexander Creek village</term> means the community—</text>
<subparagraph id="H83397AE8A5344604889EBF430C352E24"><enum>(A)</enum><text>located in T. 15 N., R. 7 W., Seward Meridian, in the State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3ADB2B2161C7443A9EDDA1CA0F1695BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recognized as a Native village under subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB06F834A16A943C79716FC5AFBCB982E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Region</header><text>The term <term>Region</term> means Cook Inlet Region, Incorporated, the appropriate Regional Corporation for Alexander Creek, Incorporated, under section 14(h).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0F4B54F2643746098756309AB52A0A43"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recognition of Alexander Creek</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1432(d) of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/96/487">Public Law 96–487</external-xref>; 94 Stat. 2543) and the deadline described in section 11(b)(3), subject to the requirements of this section—</text>
<paragraph id="H102A4791D2C046179A9EF000C4F1FDEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Alexander Creek, Incorporated, is recognized as a Village Corporation pursuant to this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7650582A2CB941C49F56E846C02280EC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Alexander Creek village shall be recognized as a Native village, notwithstanding any other provision of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H46052426755146059C66E541EEE76960"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Organization of Alexander Creek, Incorporated</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this section, Alexander Creek, Incorporated, shall submit to the Secretary—</text> <paragraph id="H9FD6589DC9F941A096F4F0AE119AC199"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any amendments to the State corporate charter of Alexander Creek, Incorporated, necessary to convert Alexander Creek, Incorporated, from a Group Corporation to a Village Corporation; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3C962C1B1B55440292D7D9633A7C0A1C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if necessary, any amendments to the State corporate charter or governing business documents of Alexander Creek, Incorporated, that fulfill the terms of the agreement described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H007B74F2666D49428525BA9F8EAAD17F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Agreement</header> <paragraph id="HB776E778C39646A486C363B55430833C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Negotiations</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary shall offer to enter into negotiations with Alexander Creek, Incorporated, for the purposes of fairly and equitably settling—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF7E946455A624F6FA2B3DA9261E57D6F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the aboriginal land claims of Alexander Creek, Incorporated; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC775026C7053492CA8734B3544E03944"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other claims of Alexander Creek, Incorporated, against the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE40F8D61155C4530A5EFBB3C1D88A4E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Condition</header><text>As a condition of recognition as a Village Corporation under this Act, Alexander Creek, Incorporated, shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary to achieve the purposes described in paragraph (1) by not later than 13 months after the date of enactment of this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFC132BDADAEC41E5BC6C6AA5068C436B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parity</header><text>To the maximum extent practicable, the agreement under this subsection shall achieve parity, with respect to approximate value, with similar agreements of other Village Corporations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE7B4D51B6E98496C988D9DB1A9E33AD5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment for Federal property purposes</header>
<subparagraph id="H82A36781B2BA43E7818589CE540BF339"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coordination with GSA</header><text>The Secretary shall coordinate with the Administrator of General Services with respect to any surplus property to be transferred to Alexander Creek, Incorporated, pursuant to the agreement under this subsection.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0C8CEF017D14BE7AF91F857711AB8BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Status as a State and State agency</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraphs (2) and (3) of section 549(a) of title 40, United States Code, Alexander Creek, Incorporated, shall be considered to be a <quote>State</quote> and a <quote>State agency</quote> under that section for purposes of the agreement under this subsection.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H80427D22501C47BAA691CDF6041C510F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Surplus property</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, Alexander Creek, Incorporated, shall be eligible to receive real property declared to be surplus under section 1303 of title 40, United States Code, for purposes of the agreement under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6F0531D368B9441F969142839A55AB70"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Shareholder participation</header> <paragraph id="H2A3D72BD5C004D448CB07DD3D593E477"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Alexander Creek, Incorporated, shall notify each member of Alexander Creek village that—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD05626275A344E65B367B3FF4292CF5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>effective beginning on the date of enactment of this section, the members shall cease to receive benefits from the Region as at-large shareholders pursuant to section 7(m); and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBEE4E2C0AD6A44B7AC0F97B49450B1AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all future resource payments from the Region shall be retained by Alexander Creek, Incorporated, pursuant to section 7(j).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBFB3842988E349E5B1DFB0442A6403F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Liability</header><text>The Region shall not be liable under any State, Federal, or local law, or under State or Federal common law, for damages arising out of or relating to the cessation of payments to members of Alexander Creek village under paragraph (1)(A).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBF04D73A2FB84D2A969AA52167D4D65F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Construction relating to land entitlements</header> <paragraph id="H74297610FF7E448F8BA60ECFE8038A1E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this section with respect to Alexander Creek, Incorporated, nothing in this section modifies or amends any land conveyance entitlements or conveyance agreement between—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCE7155A901034BF7B6250677E2215200"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Region and Village Corporations other than Alexander Creek, Incorporated; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB2D1C7FD54B646E09012AB61B7EC4BF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Region and the Federal Government; and </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6DA2FB2FCA2140FE8EE99F4B6B070F91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any party described in subparagraph (A) or (B) and the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H12FC060DD5B14CE2BA2B242E56DC8E07"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Current Alexander Creek, Incorporated, land</header><text>Nothing in this section reduces the land entitlement of Alexander Creek, Incorporated, as a Group Corporation before the date of enactment of this section, including any land selected by and conveyed to Alexander Creek, Incorporated, before that date of enactment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

