<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0E8B04FD5F424073BCFCC9559CCA1F88" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9416 IH: To establish an allowance to provide a housing stipend for Members of the House of Representatives.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9416</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221202">December 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an allowance to provide a housing stipend for Members of the House of Representatives.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1504CCBE1514218A1C62C065DB22CF3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0C651C3DC6EC47EF82E342D3B3245B66" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Housing allowance for Members of House of Representatives</header> 
<subsection id="H440742AA8F174211A542EBF0BECD9A9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of allowance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the House of Representatives an allowance which shall be available to pay a housing stipend of $2,500 to each eligible Member of the House of Representatives for each month in which the Member serves in the House.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H484AB67B317D44B1BBF63F544C063EC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>A Member is eligible to receive a stipend under this section if the Member submits to the Chief Administrative Officer of the House of Representatives an application which includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H32F1DC7F85D14FF2AD0B16A5FC99DB8C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement that the Member will not use the Member’s office for personal overnight accommodations on an ongoing basis; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9797AE6CE21F4594ACFB30C169E381DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other information and assurances as the Chief Administrative Officer considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCD5AB51A31BE4EF6A2165856DAC65E64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Member shall use a stipend received under this section to obtain housing in the Washington metropolitan area.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5F460D8353A541C08F35B84F6DE5D445"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall be carried out in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Committee on House Administration.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB56187FD6CD547AEBFAD2B7D3DEDD6AB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text> <paragraph id="HAD3AC2402D04457886B71D66B64EEA28"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>Member of the House of Representatives</term> includes a Delegate or Resident Commissioner to the Congress; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB65A3C014D474ED4A8445B4DFEAECE05"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <term>Washington metropolitan area</term> means the District of Columbia, the Counties of Montgomery and Prince Georges in Maryland, and the Counties of Arlington, Fairfax, Loudon, and Prince William and the Cities of Alexandria and Falls Church in Virginia. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

