<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HADF1AF7F72B64E83A382B4774722BD24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9434 IH: Airport Energy Resiliency and Renewable Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9434</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221206">December 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program to incentivize the energy resilience of air carrier airports to acquire or install solar photovoltaic panels, battery storage systems, microgrids, and related electric infrastructure for on-site renewable energy generation and storage, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0A586E5AA72C407499444785CBD4A63D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9A55EC0D93964E7684C8651B41F83DC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Airport Energy Resiliency and Renewable Energy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H85C155404EB54A2E9C58B2E5C2626CC7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header> <subsection id="H3C5BECF646B640248E08475119710DA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header> <paragraph id="H438E7BA52BE74371B649DA6E6F50BA8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program under which the Secretary shall award grants to sponsors of air carrier airports for an eligible project that directly and substantially benefits the airport.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37E4085BDDDC44ABA7283D09ABBB3D6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>A sponsor of an air carrier airport seeking a grant under the program under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including an assurance to comply with any labor regulations set forth in subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/471">chapter 471</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4F52A032B93F444C819B82ECF4CBEEF9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>For purposes of this section, an eligible project includes any project to acquire or install new renewable energy generation resources, such as solar photovoltaic panels, battery storage systems, or microgrids.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF64ED510128F4A64BF19B11B8BCAEC9B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The maximum Federal share of allowable project costs for an eligible project carried out with a grant under this section is 90 percent.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3B37A46A6F11413B85117DDC48815D71"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>Of the amounts made available under subsection (f), the Secretary may reserve up to 2 percent for the administrative costs of carrying out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1261D81844914AEEB2D40E2B9B94A550"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In implementing this section, the Secretary shall consult with the Secretary of Energy.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H34BD7E70239A48B1B7D8A8B22504E62D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>In addition to any amounts otherwise made available, there are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary, out of any funds in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 for the purpose of carrying out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H1722A7E12C65457DA54E092B8E4F5A0F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HB5A3CD1B645D464FB252D3BE5D6162E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Air carrier airport</header><text>The term <term>air carrier airport</term> has the meaning given that term in section 47102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2683C87CC84E462D84CB9C2713AB5847"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Microgrid</header><text>The term <term>microgrid</term> has the meaning given that term in section 641 of the United States Energy Storage Competitiveness Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17231">42 U.S.C. 17231</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD325A378BE49444088DA6C101B3C6F53"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H18DF2828222D4EB6B4A742310B0CDBA5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sponsor</header><text>The term <term>sponsor</term> has the meaning given that term in section 47102 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

