<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60875F3CDC134849A84F459AF9A112D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7617 IH: Preventive Care Awareness Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7617</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000797">Ms. Wasserman Schultz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a national public health education campaign, grant program, and task force for recommended preventive health care services during the COVID–19 pandemic and future pandemics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3D07781AB3384771A95BF02156F917D9" style="OLC"><section id="H290A49DB4E3C437EA75CCBAE3E915EC4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventive Care Awareness Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H61545CF61F0440E78799432174C061AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public health campaign regarding preventative health</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in consultation with the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Surgeon General of the Public Health Service, and the Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, shall carry out a coordinated, focused national public health education effort to enhance access by individuals and providers to evidence-based and evidence-informed health information about preventive health care, with particular consideration for decreasing disparities in utilization of recommended preventive health care services by individuals in rural and underserved communities who have delayed or forgone receiving recommended clinical preventive health care services during the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></section><section id="H25644F5CBEEE4596B2F803C1B8C61B02"><enum>3.</enum><header>COVID–19 preventive health care grant program</header><subsection id="HF5DA3CAC02B74C1F88D44D9AD8B076E0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of allotments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1904 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300w-3">42 U.S.C. 300w–3</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HECF660F16CAD4AC5AA18814E24988001"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="HBBA42FE9B450450AA6898CBAA982C6E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (E) through (G) as subparagraphs (F) through (H), respectively;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H227422A1939E4823B8C9ABB9F42B646D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), as redesignated, by striking <quote>(A) through (E)</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) through (F)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H339AF1518E6D4834AA81A4AACAFF2099"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), as redesignated, by striking <quote>(A) through (F)</quote> and inserting <quote>(A) through (G)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE716767C70345FABC24E3C74CF63AF9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (D) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEA23BF7786C34D4B9A31E46E1CC9F172" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HABAEA6768C44445CBDF2CFF9A32AC676" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities to increase patient uptake of recommended clinical preventive health care services during the COVID–19 pandemic, with particular consideration for decreasing disparities in utilization of such preventive health care services by reaching individuals in geographically diverse rural and underserved communities who have delayed or forgone receiving recommended clinical preventive health care services during the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC427BFDDE04C42509DC250F44E7A9016"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), in the matter following paragraph (5), by striking <quote>subsection (a)(1)(E)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (a)(1)(F)</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFEF49C1DE19B42CC8681E35A4503B824"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Allotted amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 1904 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300w-3">42 U.S.C. 300w–3</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H42D1EAD7B1E04602B79016530ECF8022" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HED922F7E0FC248DE9005578077D86167" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the total amount paid to the States under section 1903 for each of fiscal years 2023 and 2024, the Secretary shall ensure that the States, in the aggregate, use at least $50,000,000 for activities under paragraph (1)(E).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2C7381603A3943C88B234FBC501EBA86"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1920(a) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300x-9">42 U.S.C. 300x–9(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In addition to the amounts authorized to be appropriated by the preceding sentence, for the purpose of carrying out paragraphs (1)(E) and (4) of section 1904, there is authorized to be appropriated $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 and 2024.</quote>. </text></subsection></section><section id="HD354C9FC411C485D87A55D407506CEE8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Task force on preventive health care during public health emergencies</header><subsection id="HFFDB195229D845088313810847A96976"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Task force on preventive health care in response to the COVID–19 public health emergency</header><paragraph id="H7B37138AB7B243E68C9A5BAA963C8BA3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall convene a task force to develop Federal recommendations regarding preventive health care during the COVID–19 pandemic and future pandemics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C6950CDB21F4AF58460D6C33CD0E8DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The task force established under paragraph (1) shall develop and publicly post, in a manner than is accessible for those with disabilities or limited English proficiency, Federal recommendations to promote preventive health care visits and improve health outcomes during and after the COVID–19 pandemic and during future pandemics, with particular consideration for outcomes of rural or underserved communities. Such recommendations shall—</text><subparagraph id="H56EF562EF176428DBB296C61A58B938C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>address, with particular attention to ensuring equitable services, reducing disparities in health outcomes, and promoting culturally and linguistically appropriate care—</text><clause id="H7D8CA818EE104CD795C01CBE60FB6DAE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measures to facilitate preventive health care;</text></clause><clause id="HEA6925C46B0A4FECBCF19422A3F72321"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>strategies to increase access to care for individuals at high risk or with elevated risk factors;</text></clause><clause id="H14CE53B541604B9C855B52084A756183"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>how to identify, prevent, and treat mental health and substance use disorders which may have arisen or increased during the COVID–19 pandemic;</text></clause><clause id="H0032EAB45AA64D38B3788CF46DAA21F9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>strategies to address provision of preventive health care services, maintain the delivery of common health services and preventive health care services, and increase the ability to accommodate patient care preferences while maintaining safety and quality; and</text></clause><clause id="HB4C57250AA6144C0A8C29ECD125BADAD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other matters as the task force determines appropriate;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD372EC8178874C959DDCB6EE3736FB26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify barriers to the implementation of the recommendations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H909F66E36E234CA58A1D8F86CDF63AE4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>take into consideration existing State programs and other programs that have demonstrated effectiveness in promoting preventive health care during the COVID–19 pandemic, for purposes of future public health emergencies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C5400811FDE4A51A617C0A962C60745"><enum>(D)</enum><text>identify—</text><clause id="H429E38047E43447F8020362C05ECC5D3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>policies specific to COVID–19 that, as the public health emergency declared with respect to COVID–19 under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>) abates, can be safely discontinued when appropriate or necessary; and</text></clause><clause id="HED0B78088DEE4015B46989683E4039D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>policies implemented during such public health emergency that should be continued.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H679E1D99F3DD496B976B2A43C145A62C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The task force established under paragraph (1) shall be comprised of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H66311A015AA74F4199624D2AF46B80AA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>One representative of each of the following:</text><clause id="H5F536B4126E54346822159117F4A6BED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></clause><clause id="H829155D893CB4CAA9F6208C4F4CBBD67"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration.</text></clause><clause id="H1125969519024673AF7E946FA90CFBD4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use.</text></clause><clause id="H659A5634F5784BED8444AFC6A71DDCE7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services.</text></clause><clause id="H7ED43F58BFC44FBF99C746375BE5B4A4"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Director of the Agency for Healthcare Research and Quality.</text></clause><clause id="H3E620B2F5A634808B423A7D37CE0702F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Director of the Indian Health Service.</text></clause><clause id="H05F546DFF3294DC19FD91B7427194D34"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Deputy Assistant Secretary for Minority Health.</text></clause><clause id="H134ACF022CDB42EB8D445B9D6877873F"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Director of the Office on Women’s Health.</text></clause><clause id="H172B990FFA0E46AB8BC9981FA19B1CAD"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23B529F8D12D4AA2979078EB94FB35A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Such other members as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

