<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" dms-id="H23D26A6A787C480680AE9F438CED8A4A" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6270 : Advanced Aviation Infrastructure Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to establish a pilot program to provide grants related to advanced air mobility infrastructure, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF624FB5AB9EA489A929ACBDC7926DF9F" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="H5C050AFE9D374327A5E9EDDD98464E72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Advanced Aviation Infrastructure Modernization Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AAIM Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD06D2D4BBE4E42F7B5C28D1125BF3BC0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Advanced air mobility infrastructure pilot program</header><subsection id="H2D8734785D6C4DB09C2F8B987117E60C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall establish a pilot program to provide grants that—</text><paragraph id="H5059FAA1ED9648B1A1508950C1653141"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assist an eligible entity to plan for the development and deployment of infrastructure necessary to facilitate AAM operations in the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64C16DD5DFAF4DA59AD773D685A6A395"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make funding available for costs directly related to construction of public-use vertiports or associated infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E28D9F539E7468CB4443AD53EE5B229"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Planning grants</header><paragraph id="H9F674B6356B44C06AAD2947DC0591DBD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide grants to eligible entities to develop comprehensive plans under paragraph (2) related to AAM infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5D0DDD9062F4D70A7EECD36F043ABF4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header><subparagraph id="H1017F8CBF20240CE9BD8B7D350724852"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after receiving a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary a comprehensive plan in a format that may be published on the website of the Department of Transportation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D430F6621D440F7AF52E39EA3DA8735"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Plan contents</header><text>The Secretary shall establish content requirements for comprehensive plans submitted under this subsection, which may include the following:</text><clause id="H1112D02D8F164BBBACD22B2E28685B6E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The identification of planned or potential public-use or private-use vertiport locations.</text></clause><clause id="H05FF9929D2C44110BB033F2AB14C340E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of infrastructure necessary to support AAM operations.</text></clause><clause id="H1470C4FCD44B444C80997678A3783F96"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A description of types of planned or potential AAM operations.</text></clause><clause id="HED5F6A19986B41508C615D8D0DE28F49"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The identification of physical and digital infrastructure required to meet the standards for vertiport design and performance characteristics established by the Federal Aviation Administration (as in effect on the date on which the Secretary issues a grant to an eligible entity), including modifications to existing infrastructure and ground sensors, electric charging and other fueling requirements, electric utility requirements, wireless and cybersecurity requirements, and other necessary hardware or software.</text></clause><clause id="H34652E66292B41ECB618008BD0B20C32"><enum>(v)</enum><text>A description of potential environmental effects of planned construction or siting of public-use vertiports, including efforts to reduce the adverse effects of potential aviation noise.</text></clause><clause id="H34FEC980A61D4B3FB481670D32121E4B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A description of how planned public-use or private-use vertiport locations, including new or repurposed infrastructure, fit into existing State and local transportation systems and networks, including—</text><subclause id="HB207B5F5921743E39AFC117C548ECEF4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>connectivity to existing public transportation hubs and intermodal and multimodal facilities;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA2263E468E394EC2AC4C5BD1DA3F7910"><enum>(II)</enum><text>opportunities to create new service to areas underserved by air transportation, without compromising safety and efficiency of other facilities and airspace users; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H55322758A439486095AC98ED2794C187"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any potential conflicts to existing aviation infrastructure that may arise from the proposed location of the vertiport.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7D8689773E114E5DB2D0FBA7BAFA31A7"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>A description of how public-use vertiport planning will be incorporated in State or metropolitan planning documents.</text></clause><clause id="H36A1B927053842D8A793343878267FB4"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The identification of the process an eligible entity will undertake to ensure an adequate level of community engagement for planned public-use vertiport locations and planned or anticipated AAM operations, including engagement with underserved communities, individuals with disabilities, and racial and ethnic minorities, to address equity of access and other priorities.</text></clause><clause id="H00EE32344104453AB2B397D1CE844076"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The identification of the actions necessary for an eligible entity to undertake the construction of public-use vertiports, such as planning studies to assess existing infrastructure, environmental studies, studies of projected economic benefit to the community, lease or acquisition of an easement or land for new infrastructure, and activities related to other capital costs.</text></clause><clause id="H02902B98C2754029925E557DBF0DDD6B"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The identification of State, local, or private sources of funding an eligible entity may use to assist with the construction or operation of a public-use vertiport.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H180CF6133345443984F78B086B920BBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To apply for a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall provide to the Secretary an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB740C6673D414E63A5A74C9EFE25D0C9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection</header><subparagraph id="HB3A9E719571941FB80331351A99688CA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In awarding grants under this subsection, the Secretary shall consider the following:</text><clause id="H81AE9E97E211467BA0B1B3B3A1DCA6FA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Geographic diversity.</text></clause><clause id="HDFE46ECC14E6408481ED8B44A44D168B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The need for comprehensive plans that—</text><subclause id="H675E2EBBDEC7494889B2561BB9B9E719"><enum>(I)</enum><text>ensure the safe integration of AAM operations into the National Airspace System;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF3661851D27E4A248CD37BC9D73FBA81"><enum>(II)</enum><text>improve transportation safety, connectivity, access, and equity in both rural and urban regions in the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3D8BD54C0FA94A9099151EDF499F4484"><enum>(III)</enum><text>leverage existing public transportation systems and intermodal and multimodal facilities;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD2D1A8D7203046A4A3276E6E343F9C6F"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>reduce surface congestion and the environmental impacts of transportation;</text></subclause><subclause id="H985235CFABAE4D2D9CC4E0D0693D80C6"><enum>(V)</enum><text>grow the economy and create jobs in the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAEB1E7486E764193965DF9605A6BE04B"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>encourage community engagement when planning for AAM related infrastructure.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H858A13D2EB8647289EBF5DD0C0E082CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize awarding grants under this subsection to eligible entities that partner with commercial AAM entities, institutions of higher education, research institutions, or other relevant stakeholders to develop and prepare a comprehensive plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8E05D01D5324CBD8E1EAFDC2DC89A56"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant amount</header><text>Each grant made under this subsection shall be made in an amount that is not more than $1,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EF214F4182C460E8E459A8D0BD6C837"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Briefing</header><subparagraph id="H01CCD9DE87E0420F8BDB906D128CEA5C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the first comprehensive plan is submitted under paragraph (2), and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary shall provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress on the comprehensive plans submitted to the Secretary under such paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DBED1956B9643EBA5F2B767ECCBBF70"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The briefing required under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="HBBDBADFE8EAA41BC83BD773E931D6212"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an evaluation of all planned or proposed public-use vertiport locations included in the comprehensive plans submitted under paragraph (2) and how such planned or proposed public-use vertiport locations may fit into the overall United States transportation system and network; and</text></clause><clause id="H09C18BFAEF4545AAAEC045EB68F9399E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of lessons or best practices learned through the review of comprehensive plans and how the Secretary will incorporate any such lessons or best practices into Federal standards or guidance for the design and operation of AAM infrastructure and facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDA386315E134DA7AFF450F55FA5E922"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Construction grants</header><paragraph id="HAF1B1DEE05ED43D2A965DE69546FD7A1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award grants to covered recipients to carry out construction activities described under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFD800500F974B35ABE9F6B174E99C90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible uses</header><text>A covered recipient may use grant funds awarded under this subsection for design, bidding, and environmental study activities, and other capital costs, as the Secretary determines appropriate, directly related to the construction of a public-use vertiport or associated infrastructure pursuant to the comprehensive plan submitted by such covered recipient.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20D145D8D3FF4BBFB906BD9C35A3E465"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The requirements of subsections (b) and (c) of section 47112 of title 49, United States Code, and section 50101 of such title, shall apply to a grant awarded under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78136E828448408A84CBB24CD725E35A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The Secretary may not award a grant under this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H1224A76FD40548E29550B4F63BE70F39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the acquisition, conversion, or retrofitting of AAM aircraft; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC7707C285EE4391ABBD697227796D67"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the construction of private-use vertiports or associated infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0A7F7345D04474FB2882E7B78248CDA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant timing</header><text>The Secretary may not issue a grant under this subsection until—</text><subparagraph id="HDF67EE7E8E674A2183B77583B49E7B2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration has—</text><clause id="H3A64E2E21998494AACD65F809649FCAF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issued type certificates for 2 or more models of aircraft designed to provide AAM transportation; and</text></clause><clause id="HB0ACFA7143DD4473BD7D32F45422DBF2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>published an advisory circular containing appropriate standards for vertiport design and performance characteristics and vertiport siting; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H858D3D410A5746E8ADEA4AEDE99DECED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary has—</text><clause id="H0BA31D376A8746B79874380FF6CAD2FC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determined that 2 or more AAM operators hold certificates under part 119 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, for such operators to perform air carrier operations covered under part 135 of such title; and</text></clause><clause id="H223EE222C5DA4ABBAE4BA37F948AB87C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>issued, to 2 or more air carriers formed to provide AAM transportation, certificates under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/411">chapter 411</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H031352F5DD0A4F03831329B6B6DDFB1C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HAECFAD1C87DE4ED49C8C484C430CFB0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out this section $12,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 and 2023, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6C7140FC4484AA6B1A25EC439D220EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Of the amounts made available under paragraph (1), the Secretary may retain up to 1 percent for personnel, contracting, and other costs to establish and administer the pilot program under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED93F419A9174E23A2AF4DDA1C850BBB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="H8B6C63E90CBA47BAAB27F2F79F754CAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No grant may be awarded under this section after September 30, 2023.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10CCF8E2550F4691AD9AD6B1350C1341"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued funding</header><text>Funds authorized to be appropriated pursuant to subsection (d) may be expended after September 30, 2023—</text><subparagraph id="HCF7876494B1343B1832321C03742D8CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for grants awarded prior to September 30, 2023; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAC90DAA45204A38A4A5DAE36D10A9EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for administrative expenses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09A4A00292804E439D3EEBF5C7D7CE65"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H25520A93660342248A047D2E0ABAD5B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced air mobility; aam</header><text>The terms <quote>advanced air mobility</quote> and <quote>AAM</quote> mean an air transportation system that transports individuals and property between points in the United States using aircraft, such as remotely piloted, autonomous, or vertical take-off and landing aircraft, including those powered by electric or hybrid driven propulsion, in both controlled and uncontrolled airspace.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3938F9973ACF4E38A08F91FE004836EC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of congress</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate committees of Congress</quote> means the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9FDC7082CBC421BA8BD223A1D3256AF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Commercial aam entities</header><text>The term <quote>commercial AAM entities</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H26247145D8DC42ED8EF6AF8B382509CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>manufacturers of aircraft, avionics, propulsion systems, and air traffic management systems related to AAM; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7FF04016E634CC4B64C9DDD6923C5EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intended commercial operators of AAM aircraft and systems.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE47BEEE47DD4D0D9D0503C59566B24E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered recipient</header><text>The term <quote>covered recipient</quote> means the recipient of a grant under subsection (b) who has submitted a comprehensive plan—</text><subparagraph id="HE71E6CF3DD6B49669A2A34C2B3C8F160"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that has been reviewed by the Secretary pursuant to subsection (b); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H829D0C81C5384E108CA3CBAF741EA0C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that the Secretary has determined contains proposed projects that comply with the standards for vertiport design, performance, and siting characteristics described in a published advisory circular.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB14B0363454441C82BE54232EAEDE92"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H510313BB6DAA41C8AE04F20C6FC80EEE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State, local, or Tribal government, including a political subdivision thereof;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA114F7E8AE14973A6B915EA30F70C14"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an airport sponsor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0951E72E765541798F008AC78B5B8483"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a transit agency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83F5BB052E134A2FA32A83148E2B4065"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a port authority;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8620AD7E9A5B49B38C897C54C515CDEE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a metropolitan planning organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H525E1DC913F041B3BC9B191F8F2C85C1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any combination or consortium of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H87D1FF29595145BDB747F41E9E787894"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Metropolitan planning organization</header><text>The term <quote>metropolitan planning organization</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 5303(b) of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D53F465D39549EEB0BEEF09FB0ADBFF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Public-use vertiport</header><text>The term <quote>public-use vertiport</quote> means a designated location used or intended to be used for public purposes and to support AAM operations, including the landing, takeoff, loading, taxiing, parking, and storage of vertical take-off and landing aircraft.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FED06240D7E4CAFBB6967D498F9FB1F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means a State of the United States, the District of Columbia, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, the Northern Mariana Islands, and Guam.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB13DBE2B47634D4591E217388097A4B4"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Transportation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAEE648829F94A6B8897FD85332594F9"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Vertical take-off and landing aircraft</header><text>The term <quote>vertical take-off and landing aircraft</quote> means an aircraft with lift/thrust units used to generate powered lift and control and with 2 or more lift/thrust units used to provide lift during vertical take-off or landing.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0FEBAD02E83F4DCAA2672E0CD81BA10C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed as conferring upon any person, State, local, or Tribal government the authority to determine the safety of any AAM operation or the feasibility of simultaneous operations by AAM and conventional aircraft within any given area of the National Airspace System.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220613" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 13, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

