<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1B5FDF465C6F4D8B9EE6E570AA45A111" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7066 IH: Russia and Belarus Financial Sanctions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7066</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220311">March 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require United States financial institutions to ensure entities and persons owned or controlled by the institution comply with financial sanctions on the Russian Federation and the Republic of Belarus to the same extent as the institution itself, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9CE4538BE7D44CDE97DF602D05339DBD" style="OLC"><section id="HCD6A68C3CE09449C9B3B7DAFDEB498A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Russia and Belarus Financial Sanctions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE0E82350009C4329AF6499B4CCF80686"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements</header><subsection id="HB4F0E63B35A440AFA769C69F7FDD5C86"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A United States financial institution shall take all actions necessary and available to cause any entity or person owned or controlled by the institution to comply with any provision of law described in subsection (b) to the same extent as required of a United States financial institution.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4FE566189154E0EB8964B05BED8EA77"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provision of law described</header><text>A provision of law described in this subsection is any prohibition or limitation described in statute, regulation or order applicable to a United States financial institution concerning the Russian Federation or the Republic of Belarus, involving—</text><paragraph id="H22373D901CFF46EB9F10D391C0BE51FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the conduct of transactions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H578E58018D0841A78EFCAF161544A789"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the acceptance of deposits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA62027665168488988714EACD5E0F750"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the making, granting, transferring, holding, or brokering of loans or credits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2EF47D551CE4B49BFE5684BE09F4D8E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the purchasing or selling of foreign exchange, securities, commodity futures, or options;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBCF549084784F0097716E29DA5B47FC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the procuring of purchasers and sellers described under paragraph (4) as principal or agent; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB67A99D661314A3EB54A055A79B385F5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other good or service provided by a United States financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF66011F68E9A4D3CB1FA8BEF0D776FD5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A United States financial institution that violates subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties described in the applicable statute, regulation or order applicable to a United States financial Institution.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5A6E8FBAEA0044459A8D95B948B6AE24"><enum>(d)</enum><header>United States financial institution defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>United States financial institution</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>U.S. financial institution</quote> under section 561.309 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

