<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4585135C8C241F687ABADF1E018BA27" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7488 IH: Freedom of Association in Higher Education Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7488</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000595">Ms. Letlow</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for certain freedom of association protections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7A1267FB2DF54B4595EEB0EF982F0F15" style="OLC"><section id="H2319C895297D4FFAA8086CFBBF6F574E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Freedom of Association in Higher Education Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBB24617B70AF46BE89DAAB32BDE8D356"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purposes</header><subsection id="H5474930C94A64DCD800041CDD60BD5FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of this Act are as follows:</text><paragraph id="HE1DF65BE6D7248CBA69F1E77D0F9EFB8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Protect any student in a single-sex social organization or any single-sex social organization from any adverse action by an institution of higher education based solely on the membership practice of such organization of limiting membership only to individuals of one sex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD74245062C594BEEBE67FA343C0D4A85"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Ensure any student in a single-sex social organization or any single-sex social organization is treated without bias in comparison to students at an institution of higher education who do not participate in single-sex social organizations, or other social organizations at an institution of higher education that are not single-sex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FA3601D417B4CEEA6B3115E65CF6139"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Protect the rights of students to freely associate with and participate in social organizations, including single-sex social organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDB143679C3874A889ECA9B4AC373A6EF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Freedom of association protections for students in social organizations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title I of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1011">20 U.S.C. 1011 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA50CD1F84CC14E6D96294CEB943746F3" style="OLC"><section id="H353752B49C97419BB572026D73BAFAB8"><enum>124.</enum><header>Freedom of association protections for students in social organizations</header><subsection id="H4E4C80DAB543435684A281A786021F3C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Upholding freedom of association protections</header><text>Any student (or group of students) enrolled in an institution of higher education shall—</text><paragraph id="H64C1CA83F1EC4614A1153B636B86C434"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be able to form or apply to join any recognized or unrecognized social organization, including any single-sex social organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44B19AE7B72D4D74BAD9B17997B94322"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if selected for membership by any social organization, be able to join such social organization and participate in such social organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F7CC7DE134A4D31B6756DCB7085DDE2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Non-Retaliation against students of single-Sex social organizations</header><text>An institution of higher education that receives funds under this Act, including through an institution’s participation in any program under title IV, shall not—</text><paragraph id="HE95213540EF040379603DEA4015A5356"><enum>(1)</enum><text>take any action to require or coerce a student or prospective student who is a member or prospective member of a single-sex social organization to waive the protections provided under <internal-xref idref="H4E4C80DAB543435684A281A786021F3C" legis-path="124.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, including as a condition of enrolling in the institution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9989A8F52AE3430EBDDE8721C549429F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take any adverse action against a single-sex social organization, or a student who is a member or a prospective member of a single-sex social organization, based solely on the membership practice of such organization limiting membership only to individuals of one sex; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75A52F81A9F64B17A39B56997FD771E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>impose a recruitment restriction (including a recruitment restriction relating to the schedule for membership recruitment) on a single-sex social organization recognized by the institution, which is not imposed upon other student organizations by the institution, unless the organization (or a council of similar organizations) and the institution have entered into a mutually agreed-upon written agreement that allows the institution to impose such restriction.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C2007E0FDDF45F2B9F85175D0792C93"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall—</text><paragraph id="H57109992D86D4DBE9F85403B28A04CC7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require an institution of higher education to officially recognize a social organization, including a single-sex social organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4241AA6520924460B6E6345AFD1EAB8D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prohibit an institution of higher education from taking an adverse action against a student who joins a social organization, including a single-sex social organization, for a reason including academic misconduct or nonacademic misconduct, or because the organization’s purpose poses a clear harm to students or employees of the institution, so long as that adverse action is not based solely on the membership practice of the organization of limiting membership only to individuals of one sex;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H882DA87EC00143B68E603F1C20E6CEA6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>prevent a social organization from regulating its own membership;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0322B5055D848B4A617C18F7EACC33D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>inhibit the ability of the faculty of an institution of higher education to express an opinion (either individually or collectively) about membership in a single-sex social organization, or otherwise inhibit the academic freedom of such faculty to research, write, or publish material about membership in such an organization; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA5E85E184954B50A66E6D63107511FA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>create enforceable rights against a social organization or against an institution of higher education due to the decision of such social organization to deny membership to an individual student.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38266FA681FE4169ABA850A1A60209F7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H68B421549E1C4FA69C4D6A0F2615BB91"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adverse action</header><text>The term <term>adverse action</term> includes the following actions taken by an institution of higher education with respect to a single-sex social organization or a member or prospective member of a single-sex social organization:</text><subparagraph id="H195258A9DDAD49E1AA4851A93DA4D9B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Expulsion, suspension, probation, censure, condemnation, formal reprimand, or any other disciplinary action, coercive action, or sanction taken by an institution of higher education or administrative unit of such institution.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3649E514FB7949959187D9CE197A157E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An oral or written warning with respect to an action described in <internal-xref idref="H195258A9DDAD49E1AA4851A93DA4D9B0" legis-path="124.(d)(1)(A)">subparagraph (A)</internal-xref> made by an official of an institution of higher education acting in their official capacity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9DB813779414D7AB57473CBB050222D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An action to deny participation in any education program or activity, including the withholding of any rights, privileges, or opportunities afforded other students on campus.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEEFE593C0364193B7507B9DA8B772B3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An action to withhold, in whole or in part, any financial assistance (including scholarships and on-campus employment), or denying the opportunity to apply for financial assistance, a scholarship, a graduate fellowship, or on-campus employment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5D8E14A40F344A2A5145AC2A083CECA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An action to deny or restrict access to on-campus housing.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6767CFB55FC94BFDBB20036FF4D4B016"><enum>(F)</enum><text>An act to deny any certification, endorsement, or letter of recommendation that may be required by a student’s current or future employer, a government agency, a licensing board, an institution of higher education, a scholarship program, or a graduate fellowship to which the student applies or seeks to apply.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H530873024ADF460E832E72236D87B763" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An action to deny participation in any sports team, club, or other student organization, including a denial of any leadership position in any sports team, club, or other student organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H26DDE8FECFBF4D36A61DB92416FEE431"><enum>(H)</enum><text>An action to withdraw the institution’s official recognition of such organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC47B5C21FFF4E7CACB5D71D93467E08"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An action to require any student to certify that such student is not a member of a single-sex social organization or to disclose the student’s membership in a single-sex social organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4573F31A04654BE5AAA199C9B7EB72EE"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An action to interject an institution’s own criteria into the membership practices of the organization in any manner that conflicts with the rights of such organization under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) or this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA4D3EF62D84418EA9510F20C767A1FD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Single-sex social organization</header><text>The term <term>single-sex social organization</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H951F52EA6BBF466B8B4A25EB708CC397"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a social fraternity or sorority described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 which is exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code, or an organization that has been historically single-sex, the active membership of which consists primarily of students or alumni of an institution of higher education; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H788D54EF7FDC44778DA672A4B9503E9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a single-sex private social club (including an independent organization located off-campus) that consists primarily of students or alumni of an institution of higher education.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

