<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4CAE74A2472C42D08D66DADEB263E59B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8757 IH: To express the Sense of Congress relating to the United States-India Defense Partnership.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8757</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220830">August 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To express the Sense of Congress relating to the United States-India Defense Partnership.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B10645C38D64CED90738626346921A7" style="OLC"><section id="HBBC9737D53004007B278DAA1E3317763" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>United States-India Defense Partnership</header><subsection id="HB8237095C0B74C75A022E9E8AA75F199"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strong United States-India Defense Partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H96E06448F8804F24B455212AEF92E23B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a strong United States-India defense partnership, rooted in shared democratic values, is critical in order to advance United States interests in the Indo-Pacific region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF4B843300AB43DE9E52673C8DF41A23"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">this partnership between the world’s oldest and largest democracies is critical and must continue to be strengthened in response to increasing threats in the Indo-Pacific regions, sending an unequivocal signal that sovereignty and international law must be respected.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H338CD52CCBAE43BCB756573BF00E62EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United States-India Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technologies (iCET)</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress finds that the United States-India Initiative on Critical and Emerging Technologies (iCET) is a welcome and essential step to developing closer partnerships between governments, academia, and industry in the United States and India to address the latest advances in artificial intelligence, quantum computing, biotechnology, aerospace, and semiconductor manufacturing. Such collaborations between engineers and computer scientists are vital to help ensure that the United States and India, as well as other democracies around the world, foster innovation and facilitate technological advances which continue to far outpace Russian and Chinese technology.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCB71D52B95294F1DA83094A18A944D22"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Border threats from China and reliance on Russian-Built weapons</header><text>Congress recognizes that—</text><paragraph id="H89EC06FADCF74FE386C7834816A2701D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">India faces immediate and serious regional border threats from China, with continued military aggression by the Government of China along the India-China border,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0A04B1DE08C45949DAC18B4C75D5189"><enum>(2)</enum><text>India relies on Russian-built weapons for its national defense, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5AA0AFAFF31413EB7D1A8FB9F7FDFBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should take additional steps to encourage India to accelerate India’s transition off Russian-built weapons and defense systems while strongly supporting India’s immediate defense needs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5EBDED49FD34081BCF86AC3527D7A07"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver of CAATSA sanctions in best interests of United States and the United States-India Defense Partnership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While India faces immediate needs to maintain its heavily Russian-built weapons systems, a waiver to sanctions under the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act during this transition period is in the best interests of the United States and the United States-India defense partnership to deter aggressors in light of Russia and China’s close partnership.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

