<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F1077E32B6D4E138A4D48B4F28A665B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8096 IH: PREA Rights Enforcement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8096</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create a civil action to enforce the standards promulgated under the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H36527558FAA04BF1BD7BC35BB191E323" style="OLC"><section id="H63D9A409F8F947458CB741A81D8F286D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>PREA Rights Enforcement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDD2BBA67CA7E4413BD626CD425D6CB94"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prison Rape Elimination Act cause of action</header><subsection id="HEDCBA526F1C241EE843FE31D62E73EC8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of the Prison Rape Elimination Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/30307">34 U.S.C. 30307</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9F77A35762284183AB127B8898DF39FC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (b) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA66A9FAF747E4B2FB453408CFF666023" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H05AC37F009BC465E93591DA867C858E9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability to Federal Bureau of Prisons</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The standards adopted under subsection (a) shall apply to facilities operated by the Federal Bureau of Prisons and to facilities operated under contract with the Federal Bureau of Prisons.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA77704A232A453CA1DEB7DA89C1EF6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2)(A)(i), by inserting <quote>and has in effect a law that authorizes a cause of action for violation of such standards, which is substantially similar to the cause of action under subsection (f)</quote> before the semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CF0418491EB42A4889BEAF4B90636E5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H622325E7EFC846CA880A5B70F20B88C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H198A0475D3664CA0A32DC79177FAB487"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Violations</header><paragraph id="HFFC21FA47D16481094CEA0815E3A56FE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cause of action</header><subparagraph id="H743CDE3ED7544121AB5C975F0E8AB1A3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In any case of an alleged violation of the national standards in effect for the Bureau of Prisons, the Department of Health and Human Services, or the Department of Homeland Security, with respect to facilities operated by, or operated under contract with, any such agency, a person aggrieved by such a violation may bring a civil action against the United States in an appropriate district court for declaratory or injunctive relief, after exhausting the procedures under paragraph (2), as applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD6F461C2EE54B0596EDD72600A115EB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Attorney’s fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a civil action under this subsection, the court may allow the prevailing party (other than the United States) reasonable attorney’s fees, including litigation expenses and costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H304FF9EA0A164FF2A40779BD70BC44B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice</header><subparagraph id="H07251C237E1E4EDE9FD63C12E43046E7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A person aggrieved by an alleged violation of the national standards in effect for the Bureau of Prisons, the Department of Health and Human Services, and the Department of Homeland Security, may provide written notice of each such alleged violation to a PREA Compliance Manager or PREA Coordinator.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFB3E477C28E4CB08268EDD91D85FAAA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Opportunity to correct</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 10 days after a notice is submitted to a PREA Compliance Manager or PREA Coordinator pursuant to subparagraph (A), such manager or coordinator shall—</text><clause id="HEADAB8889BE84895888EC0B6AFAC5EAB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>determine whether a violation has occurred; and</text></clause><clause id="HEDCED77F6907466A8779C0B74201E02A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>correct any violation determined to have occurred.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D766BC4413945A4A37675F53228A688"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special circumstances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(A), exhaustion of the procedures under this paragraph shall not be required with respect to any allegation of a violation for which the aggrieved person shows the existence of special circumstances making written notice to the PREA Compliance Manager or PREA Coordinator impracticable or likely to be harmful, including due to—</text><clause id="H6E0F98C9398B407C805AEDC304AD6AF2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>illiteracy;</text></clause><clause id="HD398B62BC2A54149B73AAEBE54D84933"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>intellectual disability;</text></clause><clause id="H39A7D72625034145A5A2B58DF6494176"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>developmental age, in the case of individuals who were under 18 years of age at the time of the offense;</text></clause><clause id="H55FE4DAF17A44161AD4ACF209350CA79"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>lack of access to writing implements due to restrictive housing;</text></clause><clause id="H1DB95EB86E77440182CD88EB282C130B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>imminent risk of serious bodily harm or death of the aggrieved person; or</text></clause><clause id="HBA50416CDB734EA4B2AAED01D030CFEA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>allegations of personal misconduct by the PREA Compliance Manager or PREA Coordinator.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF97E610BD341FF8394E9FCB875DF80"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removing certain requirements of suits by prisoners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any action brought under this subsection is not subject to section 7 of the Civil Rights of Institutionalized Persons Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15DFD50456E641E89083C8AD0A0AEAF5"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H14AB514329254E39BC2E430E0FAB88DB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>PREA Compliance Manager</header><text>The term <quote>PREA Compliance Manager</quote> means an individual who works collaboratively with the PREA Coordinator to oversee and sustain an agency’s compliance with the Prison Rape Elimination Act program in a specific facility.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27D9EEEA32474619B9B6AD5C3A5659BA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>PREA Coordinator</header><text>The term <quote>PREA Coordinator</quote> means an individual who has the authority to oversee the design and implementation of the Prison Rape Elimination Act program for each facility in an agency’s jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C0EAFAD5F6D41B69262077ABD0C1807"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This Act and the amendments made by this Act shall take effect 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and shall apply with respect to violations occurring in fiscal year 2024 and every fiscal year thereafter.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

