<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3835265A99214396A168EE854834714F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7731 IH: Consumer Protection and Fuel Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7731</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220511">May 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to revise labeling requirements for fuel pumps that dispense E15, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF43A88C654F1476AA65450CEE9FEBDE8" style="OLC"><section id="H2D76A92FFCE04D6B8B7CB48FA322106F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Protection and Fuel Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H88DB83A2EE08415B8B58096F4C798B9A" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withdrawal of E15 Fuel Dispenser Labeling and Compatibility With Underground Storage Tanks proposed rule</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency shall withdraw the proposed rule titled <quote>E15 Fuel Dispenser Labeling and Compatibility With Underground Storage Tanks</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 5094 (January 19, 2021)). </text></section><section id="H73765230A5624CA1BDA03E784D479046"><enum>3.</enum><header>E15 fuel dispenser labeling</header><subsection id="HBB4FF1B04B114A799AEBCCA4E273EB48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revision of rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall revise the labeling requirements for fuel pumps that dispense E15, including by revising the rule described in subsection (c) with respect to such requirements.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEFF36E17460E4C98B7FBAED7A83398A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Input and requirements for label</header><text>In revising the labeling requirements for fuel pumps that dispense E15 under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="HA2DAD07C9BE744FFA4CB632B320D64DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>solicit input from—</text><subparagraph id="HC24EF3E675AB42FDA43096D1FA834D81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>industries that manufacture vehicles, engines, and equipment that are prohibited from using E15, including boats, lawnmowers, chainsaws, motorcycles, snowmobiles, and pre-2001 model year vehicles;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A240DF3BAF4741B006CBCD56057362"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consumer groups that represent users of such vehicles, engines, and equipment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE08BCF9244D64E06B98BBE37854797BB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consumer label experts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3B6B9E3EE9648ADB51E8E7931E9CAE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retailers (as defined in section 101(7) of the Petroleum Marketing Practices Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/2801">15 U.S.C. 2801(7)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B4503F686004EB69097E5529B77844B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require that the label for fuel pumps that dispense E15—</text><subparagraph id="H76ECFD59211F4AD894952893B57590D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>include the word <quote>WARNING</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D4569FA0884453BCB1C8D428E06E85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include the words <quote>Check your owner’s manual</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21DE81F68D114E38B5B28167E215E946"><enum>(C)</enum><text>be 5 × 7 inches or larger;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC254CB942C574EADABCB716139DA5C14"><enum>(D)</enum><text>include—</text><clause id="H04B4EDC397F1427895EE815115D607A8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicators with respect to vehicles, engines, and equipment that are prohibited from using E15, including—</text><subclause id="H0AE42A7B915D4592A76DD52AE6BBEACE" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>pictograms depicting a boat, lawnmower, chainsaw, motorcycle, and snowmobile; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H10F08075F1FA415FB9754788697CD0C0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>warnings with respect to pre-2001 model year vehicles; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H5BF9B579CE064649824AF7B2105B17FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other indicators developed by the Administrator, in consultation with the American National Standards Institute and the Federal Trade Commission; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CFC1E75598549D599BB35CCF0D88052"><enum>(E)</enum><text>be focus group tested to ensure effectiveness; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5760762BE3D64EF1A7C3D94A191C22C1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>with respect to blender pumps, in addition to the requirements under paragraph (2), with input from industries, the Federal Trade Commission, and the American National Standards Institute, require an additional warning label on each such blender pump to warn consumers of the residual gasoline left in gasoline pump hoses from the previous individual dispensing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF616A6F7559C421EAC18A0081D26E3BA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rule described in this subsection is the final rule titled <quote>Regulation To Mitigate the Misfueling of Vehicles and Engines With Gasoline Containing Greater Than Ten Volume Percent Ethanol and Modifications to the Reformulated and Conventional Gasoline Programs</quote> published in the Federal Register on July 25, 2011 (76 Fed. Reg. 44406).</text></subsection></section><section id="HE963FB29DBF6463ABE59456F291A7206"><enum>4.</enum><header>Education</header><subsection id="HF45D68E4843E45199B64A7ED75567ED5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with affected industries, shall develop and publish on the website of the Environmental Protection Agency educational materials to inform the public regarding—</text><paragraph id="H030242DA30A744EBB74532E8D4562BC5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the risks associated with the improper use of E15; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98CD3F17622C4151AC114CF2A58A7F44"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the vehicles, engines, and equipment that are prohibited from using E15, including boats, lawnmowers, chainsaws, motorcycles, snowmobiles, and pre-2001 model year vehicles.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HCC83D0D1886F49B5A7126B53EE957F02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Registration entities education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in collaboration with State entities responsible for boat registration, shall distribute, at the time of initial registration of a boat and at the time of the renewal of a registration for such boat, educational materials described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8DE0A2615C2045B2B941D2FAE0E6ED39"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the impact of the publication and distribution of the educational materials described in subsection (a), including data and metrics on consumer awareness of E15.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6DF267AE0DB2453E9B8B4FC7CA81F73C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H98D36FCA671741A1894D87EABD0D2266"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD9CAD1234B84ECA850E9688DC7446B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Blender pump</header><text>The term <term>blender pump</term> means a fuel pump that may dispense multiple blends of fuel, including E15.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0302A847390B4ABBB472D379E73CDF9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>E<enum-in-header>15</enum-in-header></header><text>The term <term>E15</term> means gasoline containing 15 percent ethanol by volume.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

