<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H251F81BA873B451B8BE7CDEA8C3DD6DD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 7174 IH: National Computer Forensics Institute Reauthorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7174</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220318">March 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000609">Mr. Palmer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to reauthorize the National Computer Forensics Institute of the United States Secret Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H54057CBD2A414DE5BC8F85DD7D1C1A1C" style="OLC"><section id="H997D58C515C949EBAAF7E7DD75CB5F85" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Computer Forensics Institute Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6175E8A9C04F40C999E2780B6B004A62"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of the National Computer Forensics Institute of the Department of Homeland Security</header><subsection id="H47479A0D6AF9486C8FAA1B5133F29A2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 822 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/383">6 U.S.C. 383</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9AA27FB32816417293E5035841274390"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H8B678C72DA214704B6BA19A167A4462B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">In general; Mission</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3C27EAE172E47A39779AD3526DE46A5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2032</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4344FB5F73B4A4EB54F71A2128C4503"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence and inserting <quote>The Institute’s mission shall be to educate, train, and equip State, local, territorial, and Tribal law enforcement officers, prosecutors, judges, participants in the United States Secret Service’s network of cyber fraud task forces, and other appropriate individuals regarding investigating and preventing cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, and related cybersecurity threats, including through the dissemination of homeland security information, in accordance with relevant Department guidance regarding privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties protections.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CF9368A3654430DAEA1B3EF6AC62691"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) through (f) as subsections (d) through (g), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A64299D9D98428D9DC4D83C26A6398B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block id="H918446669EE942C68FDDA7BD5728FDDE" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7926120D40F94D518E13391CF95062BB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Curriculum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In furtherance of subsection (a), all activities of the Institute shall be conducted in accordance with relevant Federal law and policy regarding privacy, civil rights, and civil liberties protections, including best practices for safeguarding data privacy and fair information practice principles. Activities undertaken pursuant to subsection (a) shall relate to the following:</text><paragraph id="HF122D8B9FF684D8493EDD814212B4216"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Investigating and preventing cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, and related cybersecurity threats, including relating to instances involving illicit use of digital assets and emerging trends in cybersecurity and electronic crime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52A7A82CB8AD462786467FCACBAE4B15" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting forensic examinations of computers, mobile devices, and other information systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H866BAECCBE384C35AF7070394EDA2BC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Prosecutorial and judicial considerations related to cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, related cybersecurity threats, and forensic examinations of computers, mobile devices, and other information systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBF6714BA8C341B8A6A1DF46EAED47AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Methods to obtain, process, store, and admit digital evidence in court.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H680CBFC9EACB4DFA95A0AC27C8BE757F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Research, development, and innovation</header><text>In furtherance of subsection (a), the Institute shall research, develop, and share innovative approaches to investigating cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, and related cybersecurity threats that prioritize best practices for forensic examinations of computers, mobile devices, and other information systems. Such innovative approaches may include training on methods to investigate ransomware and other threats involving the use of digital assets.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F154B98A5614DFDBA36E5C60100F1D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="HB0A65758E2164D9FB692F7F1C107D915"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>cyber and electronic crime and related threats is shared with State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers and prosecutors</quote> and inserting <quote>cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, and related cybersecurity threats is shared with recipients of education and training provided pursuant to subsection (a)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C680697B32C4709BF1E3C5ECDEF538E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Institute shall prioritize providing education and training to individuals from geographically diverse jurisdictions throughout the United States.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3924E0093ECA4BEC849A6EE01EAF0E30"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (e), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="H606E0B4000714F769625DB0A14AD63B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers</quote> and inserting <quote>recipients of education and training provided pursuant to subsection (a)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA80100621DA4384B3F5814DA95AD080"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>necessary to conduct cyber and electronic crime and related threat investigations and computer and mobile device forensic examinations</quote> and inserting <quote>for investigating and preventing cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, related cybersecurity threats, and for forensic examinations of computers, mobile devices, and other information systems</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7066D8059B2410E97847CC1BADA9A53"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (f), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="H64B4A79451E147C6B2D23FB86E4E5778"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending the heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Cyber Fraud Task Forces</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3F7F31B54145469A84328B398A6F793B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Electronic Crime</quote> and inserting <quote>Cyber Fraud</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8228916755E14D6DBD3EDDF48F90A2A8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>State, local, tribal, and territorial law enforcement officers</quote> and inserting <quote>recipients of education and training provided pursuant to subsection (a)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF60257FBFFFA45FE96FF25D76090FDEA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>at</quote> and inserting <quote>by</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A290D1F7F5747D8BA0E0FDEBE9288B3" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g), as redesignated pursuant to paragraph (2), as subsection (j); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADA38B4701F9497698121C09B22D4070"><enum>(8)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f), as so redesignated, the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block id="HF3C2B52016F24A189763AE5C7DC077C0" style="OLC"><subsection id="HABF467682D6A497E8161B3C6402E36A8" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expenses</header><text>The Director of the United States Secret Service may pay for all or a part of the education, training, or equipment provided by the Institute, including relating to the travel, transportation, and subsistence expenses of recipients of education and training provided pursuant to subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H494F128045ED446386DA340C969260F1" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Annual reports to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall include in the annual report required pursuant to section 1116 of title 31, United States Code, information regarding the activities of the Institute, including relating to the following:</text><paragraph id="HFDBF07DEFD664FC5B794BF5D3A970C7C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities of the Institute, including identifying the jurisdictions with recipients of education and training provided pursuant to subsection (a) of this section during such year, the Institute’s operating budget for such year, and projected demands for education and training over the next five years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2972C6145DC84C32AD5D9F4D8DC640EE" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Impacts of the Institute’s activities on jurisdictions’ capability to investigate and prevent cybersecurity incidents, electronic crimes, and related cybersecurity threats.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B0FE03AD44A46A6BAC36B957E452F1D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any other issues determined relevant by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H430F00C52B864922ACDCEEC6AC086D47" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="HCE5AB8B70DB7468ABD10012D10328ABA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cybersecurity threat</header><text>The term <quote>cybersecurity threat</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (enacted as division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H429C5F7EDC69446C8CD86BFDD027AD66" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incident</header><text>The term <quote>incident</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2209(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF158C9BBE251436D9892132974D35CA3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information system</header><text>The term <quote>information system</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 102 of the Cybersecurity Act of 2015 (enacted as division N of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/113">Public Law 114–113</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/1501">6 U.S.C. 1501(9)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C8E225830324A3FB5618D305D8D11F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Guidance from the Privacy Officer and Civil Rights and Civil Liberties Officer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Privacy Officer and the Officer for Civil Rights and Civil Liberties of the Department of Homeland Security shall provide guidance, upon the request of the Director of the United States Secret Service, regarding the functions specified in subsection (b) of section 822 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/383">6 U.S.C. 383</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4ACCC300A90543FE9F2A6F22C6DB9300" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Template for information collection from participating jurisdictions</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Secret Service shall develop and disseminate to jurisdictions that are recipients of education and training provided by the National Computer Forensics Institute pursuant to subsection (a) of section 822 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/383">6 U.S.C. 383</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), a template to permit each such jurisdiction to submit to the Director reports on the impacts on such jurisdiction of such education and training, including information on the number of digital forensics exams conducted annually. The Director shall, as appropriate, revise such template and disseminate to jurisdictions described in this subsection any such revised templates.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3F90DA3C236C41F5A34A09BBD8CCE86A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements analysis</header><paragraph id="H45B9E3D4AF70424FBBDB1ED9E1D39424"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the United States Secret Service shall carry out a requirements analysis of approaches to expand capacity of the National Computer Forensics Institute to carry out the Institute’s mission as set forth in subsection (a) of section 822 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/383">6 U.S.C. 383</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF95789A56A74D67B86B4BAC717544FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after completing the requirements analysis under paragraph (1), the Director of the United States Secret Service shall submit to Congress such analysis, together with a plan to expand the capacity of the National Computer Forensics Institute to provide education and training described in such subsection. Such analysis and plan shall consider the following:</text><subparagraph id="HFE25F6704555490B857B9CAFF5ED65C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Expanding the physical operations of the Institute.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9C4D139F04D24DD386B4980F959118E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Expanding the availability of virtual education and training to all or a subset of potential recipients of education and training from the Institute.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5993ADA557874393BD1EFCE9B5E99472" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Some combination of the considerations set forth in subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H89BBDE17985043AC8E0DEB65D50670DA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Research and development</header><text>The Director of the United States Secret Service, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology of the Department of Homeland Security, shall carry out research and development of systems and procedures to enhance the National Computer Forensics Institute’s capabilities and capacity to educate, train, equip, and disseminate information consistent with the Institute’s mission as set forth in subsection (a) of section 822 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/383">6 U.S.C. 383</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

