<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBDB428412EB543F3B6AE30A2A948E2E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7191 IH: Homes for All Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7191</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220321">March 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish new units of public housing and private market affordable housing, to provide grants to combat gentrification and neighborhood destabilization, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H301CE1E577954DEA9E7403324673C5E8" style="OLC"><section id="HAE636DE7F7694C8A8DA63C6F62D2AC56" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homes for All Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBA89F2EE7E9940F3B386D44E7E11A1E9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HC2F15C4B9B8640348B1B948F07618CE6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Every State and large metropolitan area in the United States is facing a shortage of affordable housing options for people who are very or extremely low-income.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3846EC8515FF43AA9226CED54F863CFE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>More than 18 million households—1 in 6—are paying more than half of their income on housing and are considered severely cost-burdened.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D2EA1C79984417B9F84CC8D4D2D9993"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The current affordable housing shortage facing the United States cannot be addressed solely by the private market, necessitating significant Federal intervention and investment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFE5D464DB2F4A888D5CE8A6A44E51F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Federal Government must adopt a policy that guarantees the right to housing for all individuals, strengthen neighborhoods, and address the failures of the free market in housing by building new public housing and investing in private affordable housing.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB61CD5175B1F41248ECFBCF7F4B5FCAA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Construction of new public housing</header><subsection id="HA0D25A1CC02E4B26B5E52A58C15721DB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this section to fund the construction of 9,500,000 publicly owned dwelling units over 10 years.</text></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBBD2D0FFE6A6447BB5BAB7EBB2420769"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Repeal of Faircloth amendment</header><text>Section 9(g) of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g(g)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (3) (relating to limitation on new construction).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3902038F44424262815B796BF70C550E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Full funding of public housing operating and capital expenses under mandatory spending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (c) of section 9 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437g">42 U.S.C. 1437g(c)</external-xref>) is amended by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H325F6B4B6AAA45599B8382DB2A91F27F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H84B5508008854A7C9A266F4AB11BE98A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2022 and each fiscal year thereafter, each public housing agency shall be entitled to assistance in the following amounts:</text><subparagraph id="H39CD57D31D984057B08BFE3915A18B24"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Capital fund</header><text>From the Capital Fund under subsection (d), such amount as may be necessary to fully fund the capital needs of the agency for such fiscal year, as determined in accordance with such subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DB2AC0E76004037B402A27F229CEAE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Operating fund</header><text>From the Operating Fund under subsection (e), such amount as may be necessary to fully fund the operating needs of the agency for such fiscal year, as determined in accordance with such subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF17A1F270849C486818B660067A435"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Permanent appropriations</header><text>For fiscal year 2022 and each fiscal year thereafter, there is appropriated—</text><subparagraph id="HFDF1E866FA1A4E508BF27B7D6BC7070E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the Capital Fund, an amount equivalent to the aggregate of the amounts to which each public housing agency is entitled under paragraph (2)(A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC30BF0D112BD4221A5CBC0B59915FEAF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the Operating Fund, an amount equivalent to the aggregate of the amounts to which each public housing agency is entitled under paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HCFDD55D368AA45669FCF419F93FE202E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Homes for All new construction program</header><paragraph id="H95FEEAA3C45D4C6A846057E1F9F40D52"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437f">42 U.S.C. 1437f</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF9D2C83193A142C9BA47B931181863AE" style="OLC"><subsection id="H44E6D287027A448383A474AC4F3E75F0"><enum>(ee)</enum><header>Homes for All</header><paragraph id="H0B6EB4D30E3244A090F3B8FF59168965"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be appropriated $80,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2032 for annual contribution contracts for assistance under section 5(a)(2) to cover the development costs for new public housing dwelling units that meet the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7732485AE32146ABA9110A818FAD2B57"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="H4CAE3640210A400598F7E41AED2128BF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Public housing</header><text>All dwelling units funded with amounts made available pursuant to this subsection shall comply with and be operated in compliance with all requirements applicable to public housing (as defined in section 3(b)) and the requirements of this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02F82D2091614D6BA06C461EFDD3F52B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall issue regulations to ensure, to the extent practicable, that dwelling units funded with amounts made available pursuant to this subsection comply with the following:</text><clause id="HA347D88E50FA40CAAA8B17692BE8E0A6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Use</header><text>Notwithstanding any provision of this Act, such units shall be operated as public housing during the entire useful life of such dwelling units and may not be sold or otherwise alienated by the public housing agency receiving such amounts during such useful life.</text></clause><clause id="H8D079A0CC69D419EA3E187810275F31A"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Location and accessibility</header><text>Such units shall be located in a manner that complies with such standards as the Secretary, in conjunction with the Secretary of the Department of Transportation, shall establish to ensure proper integration of housing and public transit and ensure that residents of such units have access to sufficient transportation options. Standards should ensure that such units should be integrated with public transit and vehicle alternatives such as walking and biking and should accommodate differences between a transit hub in a town or reservation compared with a large city.</text></clause><clause id="HB9BA24E7756C41CEBECC7DFA9B34F15B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Environmental standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such units shall comply with such standards as the Secretary shall establish to ensure such units are designed, built, and operated according to the highest possible environmental standard, with a focus on minimizing energy costs and achieving carbon neutrality.</text></clause><clause id="HA62B3163C7AF4CA9BF71278021D27CC2"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Tenancy restrictions</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this subsection shall not refuse to rent a dwelling unit developed with such assistance or otherwise discriminate in the rental of such a dwelling unit based on an individual’s criminal record or immigration status.</text></clause><clause id="H0D38FB235CA240B0955B9D1F2F96DB01"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Anti-discrimination</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this subsection shall not refuse to rent a dwelling unit developed with such assistance or otherwise discriminate in the rental of such a dwelling unit because of the sexual orientation or gender identity of any person.</text></clause><clause id="H9AEA0ACE3A4A421594FD293CDD0C55B1"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Affirmatively furthering fair housing</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this subsection shall comply with the final rule entitled <quote>Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 42272 (July 16, 2015)).</text></clause><clause id="H42B7802EA0BD4F11B577B7FEC5670C0E"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Supportive services</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this subsection shall develop a supportive services plan to ensure that residents have access to free, voluntary programs that address the needs of people experiencing chronic homelessness and housing instability. Services provided should include assistance with accessing healthcare, employment, education, childcare, financial literacy and other community-based supportive services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H08FBB88251954E67B0ADCE23351F786C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Construction of private market affordable housing</header><subsection id="H573C64292F6643EBB25E9CD0A9241583"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the purpose of this section to fund the construction of 2,500,000 private market affordable housing dwelling units over 10 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE205FB2756840539D70C06BD1444F76"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $20,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2032 for crediting to the Housing Trust Fund under section 1338 of the Housing and Community Development Act of 1992 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4568">12 U.S.C. 4568</external-xref>), which amounts shall be available only for assistance for production of new dwelling units that comply with the requirements of such section 1338 and this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H22A65B8B01134FE7A3031ACA91DEBA5F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437">42 U.S.C. 1437 et seq.</external-xref>), all units developed using amounts made available pursuant to this section shall remain affordable housing units for the entire useful life of such dwelling units.</text></subsection><subsection id="H31153733792048B799604F0CCBBCD9D2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Location and accessibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All dwelling units developed using amounts made available pursuant to this section shall be located in a manner that complies with such standards as the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), in conjunction with the Secretary of the Department of Transportation, shall establish to ensure proper integration of housing and public transit and ensure that residents of such units have access to sufficient transportation options. Standards should ensure that such units should be integrated with public transit and vehicle alternatives such as walking and biking and should accommodate differences between a transit hub in a town or reservation compared with a large city.</text></subsection><subsection id="H20B9B93446C945549D1C4D545FC3BE8A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Environmental standards</header><text>All dwelling units developed using amounts made available pursuant to this section shall comply with such standards as the Secretary shall establish to ensure units are designed, built, and operated according to the highest possible environmental standard, with a focus on minimizing energy costs and achieving carbon neutrality.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9BAD88AE95CB413FB357FDBC38DD3990"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Tenancy restrictions</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this section shall not refuse to rent a dwelling unit developed with such assistance or otherwise discriminate in the rental of such a dwelling unit based on an individual’s criminal record or immigration status.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE4BAFC2BA354AAB9F7C42208C639CB7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Anti-Discrimination</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this section shall not refuse to rent a dwelling unit developed with such assistance or otherwise discriminate in the rental of such a dwelling unit because of the sexual orientation or gender identity of any person.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9947AF59D7B54F709D14B52A814F903D"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Affirmatively furthering fair housing</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this section shall comply with the final rule entitled <quote>Affirmatively Furthering Fair Housing</quote> (80 Fed. Reg. 42272 (July 16, 2015)).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9EAEDF2181F9490992020BEA66FD19A9"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Supportive services</header><text>A public housing agency receiving assistance made available pursuant to this section shall develop a supportive services plan to ensure that residents have access to free, voluntary programs that address the needs of people experiencing chronic homelessness and housing instability. Services provided should include assistance with accessing healthcare, employment, education, childcare, financial literacy and other community-based supportive services.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7497C849BC2744609D7549045DDDF717"><enum>5.</enum><header>Community Control and Anti-Displacement Fund</header><subsection id="HD7C166F606BC4BBFBD4208D3A0DD1EB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish a program to be known as the <quote>Community Control and Anti-Displacement Fund</quote> to provide grants to local governments for the purposes of combating gentrification and neighborhood destabilization.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD7C071A65916485AA88D62419785EFE5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>The Secretary shall prioritize awards to local governments that propose projects or programs that encourage alternative ownership housing models that give renters agency over how the housing is operated and that protect housing affordability.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9ECFD5E3D9D149C08E72A0DCD6434AE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development $200,000,000,000 for fiscal years 2022 through 2032 to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

