<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE03C8A96A22D4A3795D33D23F6392AC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7879 IH: To require the Comptroller General of the United States to study radiological contamination in Coldwater Creek, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7879</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to study radiological contamination in Coldwater Creek, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H310E0C23B9E349F98576E0596D953E6C" style="OLC"><section id="H4DC5BEC7FA5A45DC8E6646B17BE72768" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Study on contamination of Coldwater Creek, Missouri</header><subsection id="H373B7F8D89E5460DB32224FE4D16BE41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States, in coordination with the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of Energy, the Administrator of the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry, and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall—</text><paragraph id="H2F25116727004591BDB19168D9540745"><enum>(1)</enum><text>undertake a review of prior and ongoing efforts to remediate radiological contamination in the vicinity of Coldwater Creek in North St. Louis County, Missouri, associated with historic radiological waste storage near the St. Louis Airport;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF192BAEFA93428D97E6EFC2001FD422"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with State and local agencies, and representatives of the Coldwater Creek community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC672409E14394E9FA564569C5450ABB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>take into consideration the Public Health Assessment for the Evaluation of Community Exposure Related to Coldwater Creek, dated April 30, 2019, and prepared by the Agency for Toxic Substances and Disease Registry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83500E8A6EE345DF98CDEFBB06ACDF9F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, submit to Congress a report on the status of efforts to reduce or eliminate the potential human health impacts from potential exposure to such contamination, including any recommendations for further action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC7003BFFFC0A45AF8C42557ABC42D4FC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Installation of signage To prevent potential exposure risks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date on which the report is submitted pursuant to subsection (a)(4) and in accordance with the recommendations of the Public Health Assessment for the Evaluation of Community Exposure Related to Coldwater Creek, the Comptroller General, in coordination with the Secretary of the Army, shall install signage to inform residents and visitors of potential exposure risks in areas around Coldwater Creek where remediation efforts have not been undertaken or completed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

