<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H878DBB67F4364E06AB6B0F68A2FE5409"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8710 IH: Terrorist Reporting Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8710</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220812">August 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001071">Mr. Hice of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit to Congress quarterly reports relating to the total numbers of aliens apprehended by the U.S. Border Patrol unlawfully crossing the border whose identifying information is within the terrorist screening database, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="id9747C762194C461CB39CA4B3BEAD29BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terrorist Reporting Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="idBEB705F12CC0420A92FA0AF4F81C7B09"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports on aliens included in terrorist screening database apprehended unlawfully entering the United States</header><subsection id="id2E58E6771A844C9DA2AE15B6F2A1588E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and every 90 days thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report, subject to subsection (b), that contains the following with respect to each immediately preceding 90-day period: </text><paragraph id="idA50769DD87A64ED6976067BCB0790E4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Information relating to the total numbers of aliens apprehended by the U.S. Border Patrol after unlawfully crossing the border whose identifying information is included within the terrorist screening database (as such term is defined in section 2101(10) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/621">6 U.S.C. 621(10)</external-xref>)) upon processing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id67C3C9C880D747A6B3EB1DE1F62C3032"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information relating to the reason each such alien is included in such database.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idAFCF52E9D27F42B181521D26BB5BC381"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An identification of the country of national origin and citizenship of each such alien.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id3DEFB819FCD243B5AF731EDD8696003D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The current status of each such alien’s detention, including, if applicable, information relating to the reason why any such alien has not, as of the time of the applicable report, been placed in removal proceedings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id295C988B4904455A9B8D04B5E95ECDA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Classification</header><text>Each report required under subsection (a) shall, with respect to the matters considered pursuant to paragraphs (2), (3), and (4) of such subsection, be submitted in classified form.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

