<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0AAB5364422B4AB288E57D56929602AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7892 IH: Prohibition of Agricultural Land for the People’s Republic of China Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7892</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000189">Mr. Newhouse</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain persons from purchasing agricultural real estate in the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5806BC77BF5946C8AA62AAA5A344BEE2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H223ACBE248CC4CAD85847FD2CD6E9DB9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prohibition of Agricultural Land for the People’s Republic of China Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H1A766714151D4D4EAC783E042AD6EECB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on the purchase of public or private agricultural real estate located in the United States by nationals of the People’s Republic of China</header> <subsection id="HE47AA08C8C164161AAC135372D1C35C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall take such actions as may be necessary to prohibit the purchase of public or private agricultural (including ranching) real estate located in the United States by nonresident aliens, foreign businesses, an agent, trustee, or fiduciary associated with the Government of the People’s Republic of China.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H782E2D11ABED46FF8CCE549EA478D952"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President shall take such actions as may be necessary to prohibit participation in programs administered by the Secretary of Agriculture by nonresident aliens, foreign businesses, an agent, trustee, or fiduciary associated with the Government of the People’s Republic of China, with the exception for food inspection or other food and safety regulatory requirements.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5A87C295F4FD46FFA9754C660A64410C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United States Defined</header><text>The term <quote>United States</quote> means the several States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, American Samoa, Guam, the United States Virgin Islands, and any other territory or possession of the United States.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

