<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA14749C6A8C546C6B602F7A7F04F43CD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6434 IH: Japanese American World War II History Network Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6434</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Interior to establish, within the National Park Service, the Japanese American World War II History Network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE32DEB87773D4226A07DD8C175915891" style="OLC"><section id="HBD0EDD9B4103484E9E338F74E1E525B3" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Japanese American World War II History Network Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCECB272EF4A146A4982AF510D24A8504"><enum>2.</enum><header>Japanese American World War II History Network</header><subsection id="H294E4DA072DE47DCAD28F35ACA5F651D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall establish, within the National Park Service, a program to be known as the <quote>Japanese American World War II History Network</quote> (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Network</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCDD38D16E33F4FEB8D8BB8CBBF5DDD0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of Secretary</header><text>In carrying out the Network, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H1AF9320B96FA4DFCB3AD443D4913D072"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review studies and reports to complement and not duplicate studies of Japanese American World War II history and Japanese American experiences during World War II, including studies related to relocation centers and confinement sites, that are underway or completed;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C6669E44804B5FA656B64E3B9841CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>produce and disseminate appropriate educational materials, such as handbooks, maps, interpretive guides, or electronic information relating to Japanese American World War II history and Japanese American experiences during the war, including relocation centers and confinement sites;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04D0E748DF0E40A8BF9C389859FDE562"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enter into appropriate cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding to provide technical assistance under subsection (c); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A895DBA762645F78527A5821C06E1EC"><enum>(4)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE980B554D1A04F868958F6AF7B854A39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create and adopt an official, uniform symbol or device for the Network; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0027778B84574B67BB3E4CAFCB3C4573" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>issue regulations for the use of the symbol or device adopted under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB7E83383AF04245909EAA2933ADA775"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The Network shall encompass the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H72C580AD21454E6D8440CECA547BD122"><enum>(1)</enum><text>All units and programs of the National Park Service that are determined by the Secretary to relate to Japanese American World War II history and Japanese American experiences during the war, including relocation centers and confinement sites.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68032C93E77D4639BB7A89EBA0E6A41F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With the consent of the property owner, other Federal, State, local, Tribal, and privately owned properties that—</text><subparagraph id="H7154511AB9C147E1BAAB57EB3353860B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relate to Japanese American World War II history and Japanese experiences during the war, including relocation centers and confinement sites;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEA2672C34924E0E9F2E40011A0B02F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have a verifiable connection to Japanese American World War II history and Japanese experiences during the war, including relocation and confinement sites; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58952DE33BF54908B814D219C0F4E174"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are included in, or determined by the Secretary to be eligible for inclusion in, the National Register of Historic Places.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D5AFF07A6804170B371A071B2327A55"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other governmental and nongovernmental facilities and programs of an educational, research, or interpretive nature that are directly related to Japanese American World War II history and the experiences of Japanese Americans during the war, including relocation centers and confinement sites.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE654F5EC62154C04B6263FBCE3BA8074"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To achieve the purposes of this Act and to ensure effective coordination of the Federal and non-Federal elements of the Network described in section 2(c) with units of the National Park System and programs of the National Park Service, including the Japanese American Confinement Sites Program, the Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements and memoranda of understanding with, and provide technical assistance to the heads of other Federal agencies, States, units of local government, Tribes, regional governmental bodies, and private entities.</text></section><section id="H722FB6630225458AB7DA00032C7FA9CC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority of the Secretary under this Act shall expire 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

