<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H98FE0DC40BDB49F4989BD33CF34442BA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 6604 ENR: Veterans Eligible to Transfer School (VETS) Credit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6604</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the method by which the Secretary of Veterans Affairs determines the effects of a closure or disapproval of an educational institution on individuals who do not transfer credits from such institution.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H6A7DF749EEF149A9BB130C22E6CFFD91" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D9AAEDF651E43C4B115FA5BDF8E2E6C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veterans Eligible to Transfer School (VETS) Credit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H938E944FDDBC4DD79D532C4F046C2B29" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Charge to entitlement to educational assistance for individuals who do not transfer credits from certain closed or disapproved programs of education</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3699(c)(2)(A) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBF403D77483B4D1880D6206BC3E0B4F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>An individual</quote> and inserting <quote>(i) An individual</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7F67F296F884ADA9492A17D03B3B1C2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by designating the second sentence as clause (iv) and indenting appropriately; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EB76CF91AB14ADDB44C32433C486387"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after clause (i), as designated by paragraph (1), the following new clauses: </text> <quoted-block style="USC" id="H6B9001BF7EA6421182463BB59929C303" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <clause id="HD0C2DB001E5B4EBCBEA1180EFD1C75B8" indent="up3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out clause (i), the Secretary shall—</text> 
<subclause id="H240DBF55D86F4C45B4FFF5562338ED2D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>require an individual to certify in writing that the individual has transferred fewer than 12 credits as described in such clause;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE55ED1664B3547AF825700776539C825"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">require an individual who makes a certification under subclause (I) to acknowledge in writing that if the individual transfers 12 or more credits as described in such clause (i)—</text> 
<item id="H5C11B5E04AC6464C8BAD59ACB426D289"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the individual may not be deemed under such clause to be an individual who did not receive such credits; and</text></item> <item id="HD591DEC1899040E599828A9063A87BC4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Secretary shall rescind the certificate of eligibility provided under subclause (IV);</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD5E3699658CF447096E09EBAC0A7BA59"><enum>(III)</enum><text>accept a certification under subclause (I) as proof of the individual transferring fewer than 12 credits; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H271BF6559F784961AB463BCE7DA65119"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to the individual who makes a certification under subclause (I) and makes the acknowledgment under subclause (II) a certificate of eligibility that the individual may provide to an educational institution as proof of the individual being covered by this paragraph.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H04E227A0C1F746448C8DD1F7E040E4DE" indent="up3"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Secretary shall notify individuals described in subparagraph (B) of being eligible to be covered by this paragraph.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H4ECDEB9755114719A95B9170FFD49A6A" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Elimination of requirement to specify an effective period of a transfer of Post-9/11 educational assistance to a dependent</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3319(e) of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB666FA3823D143E79740A37D81C8257F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (1), by adding <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFE315AFAA19347DFBC23F23DE43B0689"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a period; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDF00F86A05834F2582D8CDC05971FF16"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3).</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H43B4455151E94BC98FC1F086C93A1B78" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


