<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H118B899F40044FCB9BB8089700872ED0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7520 IH: To direct the Corps of Engineers to develop a comprehensive plan for Lake Okeechobee and northern estuaries ecosystem restoration, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7520</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220414">April 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Corps of Engineers to develop a comprehensive plan for Lake Okeechobee and northern estuaries ecosystem restoration, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H05A3CFF7E1734742BF351AA4D11E1AC1" style="OLC"><section id="H7996BDFE703548A2869F2B48CF4459D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Lake Okeechobee and northern estuaries ecosystem restoration, Florida</header><subsection id="H990BBD1BAC074E29A74453D56EA30840"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HAD56671158F04E0094D141F8E452124C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Central and Southern Florida project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Central and Southern Florida Project</term> has the meaning given that term in section 601 of the Water Resources Development Act of 2000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8BECBBAE91B4BC18F68835FFE888B66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Northern estuaries</header><text>The term <term>northern estuaries</term> means the Caloosahatchee Estuary, Charlotte Harbor, Indian River Lagoon, Lake Worth Lagoon, and St. Lucie River Estuary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC193F9DC3654194B3880DDB3F3A37F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9A33089DC2642C3A22079F71B46B36D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>South Florida ecosystem</header><subparagraph id="HC644807E1F934D37A271FCCDD8F5AB70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>South Florida ecosystem</term> means the area consisting of the land and water within the boundary of the South Florida Water Management District in effect on July 1, 1999.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C02F873300F43F8900143AA34823A11"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>South Florida ecosystem</term> includes—</text><clause id="H24805D0B0FC4465FB554C46A285EA90E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Everglades; </text></clause><clause id="HED249649815E40869F347F942B17A1BF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Florida Keys;</text></clause><clause id="H0F29EA3FA0884B63BF9813ADF569CEAD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the contiguous near-shore coastal water of South Florida; and</text></clause><clause id="H608098F1A8BB4C56953AC4BBE098391B" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Florida’s Coral Reef.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H909FFA75B4744AE7A707E1B501FFC72B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Study area</header><text>The term <term>study area</term> means Lake Okeechobee and the northern estuaries, including all lands and waters in the upstream watershed of those receiving bodies within—</text><subparagraph id="HF060CF34C19144E3A78B631AC37DA3F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the South Florida ecosystem; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H489BEA6D4611482EA6DE78B7747D114F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the study area boundaries of the Indian River Lagoon National Estuary Program and the Coastal and Heartland Estuary Partnership, authorized pursuant to section 320 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20AF46332F9145CFA6E05EE5524572F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Comprehensive plan</header><paragraph id="H48E83655E993405589DCE1D8007CAE42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HDA83BAE75FAE47A2AA6FC2D53A2E2121"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Development</header><text>The Secretary shall develop, in cooperation with the non-Federal sponsors of the Central and Southern Florida project and any relevant Federal, State, and Tribal agencies, a comprehensive plan for the purpose of restoring, preserving, and protecting Lake Okeechobee and the northern estuaries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D4FAB6863884992A38A900ED799F2CC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretary shall ensure that the comprehensive plan provides for the protection and improvement of water quality within the study area through activities that include—</text><clause id="H23A7DEA4181E4E269D875EFFC285250E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the elimination of harmful discharges from Lake Okeechobee;</text></clause><clause id="H4BAF0319AFC14D3A97A9259285A164B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the reduction and elimination of harmful algal blooms;</text></clause><clause id="H67E9CAFEFBD44DA291C5C378593A5BC7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the restoration of hydrological connections and conditions;</text></clause><clause id="H53B89600B3C240F79BD49FEF224CF07C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the enhancement of habitat, emergent and submerged aquatic vegetation, and keystone species populations; and</text></clause><clause id="H47CBEF654FD44F3998C9A5262892C328"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the dredging and beneficial reuse of harmful silt and muck deposits in Lake Okeechobee and the northern estuaries.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE06086BFF684C1A998585081D7C5E6A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to Congress—</text><clause id="H1ADEDC1E92A34026A207E9E00590B310"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the comprehensive plan developed under this paragraph; and</text></clause><clause id="H60675156167C4F50AF3CFF24E375A390"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a feasibility report and a programmatic environmental impact statement for any proposed Federal actions set forth in such plan.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9387AA123F1F4DE8BE903F55F33CD0F0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Interim reports</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the submission of the comprehensive plan under subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall submit to Congress an interim report on the development of the comprehensive plan.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C24C9E129EA414EB9D3165356F4FC7E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Additional studies and analyses</header><text>Notwithstanding the submission of a feasibility report under subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall continue to conduct such studies and analyses after the date of such submission as are necessary for the purpose of restoring, preserving, and protecting Lake Okeechobee and the northern estuaries.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7B84A4D87343B8BA12EB24782DFADB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Water quality</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall take into account the protection of water quality, in consultation with the State of Florida and by considering applicable State water quality standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2EE8A2180F49DEA4E73F19F6D5D22E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Integration of other activities</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Secretary shall integrate the activities included in the comprehensive plan with ongoing Federal, State, and Tribal projects and activities, including—</text><subparagraph id="HC99D0535FA4C48A7AFA4C78D50E95E71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Lake Okeechobee System Operating Manual and any subsequent water control plan for Lake Okeechobee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7202D9FBA7F74F058991B73337E7CEA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the projects authorized under the Central and Southern Florida project and the Comprehensive Everglades Restoration Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H757541732AA04A4F9244AD5756F7E538"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Justification</header><text>Notwithstanding section 209 of the Flood Control Act of 1970 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1962-2">42 U.S.C. 1962–2</external-xref>) or any other provision of law, in carrying out any activity included in the comprehensive plan developed under subsection (b), the Secretary may determine that—</text><paragraph id="H305BDF71AD2B47C08557B1A9AA09974D"><enum>(1)</enum><text> the activity is justified by the environmental benefits derived by Lake Okeechobee and the northern estuaries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9979EFFBC19B42079E0371921985A976"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no further economic justification for the activity is required, if the Secretary determines that the activity is cost-effective.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

