<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2BD77BCCAE814832B20C2873D63A0302" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9240 IH: Concerned Citizens Bill of Rights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9240</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221028">October 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To foster transparent crime data, to discourage no-cash bail, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE1FAD05E3644482994672F7428ACD570" style="OLC"><section id="HBDE81CCB81064CE895A7DF7F44E0BC7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Concerned Citizens Bill of Rights Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H85623BE91CF646ACA23EBDC647723F4E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act—</text><paragraph id="HF3AF21F9BDEF4230AE74A5314AE4D2AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>covered grant</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H783C562EF8F249389D8B720579B0FE86"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the grant program authorized under section 1701 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B27FC2ABD124A61AC9A16ED8F9AF126"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the grant program under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94AC62DCBAB14C11A34D1319EE70009B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>criminal courts</term>— </text><subparagraph id="HCD1AC014295F46279FA6C58E8F9C69FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any court of a State or unit of local government having jurisdiction over criminal matters; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DE713BE7E6A427E829CDC0B32E9DC46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes the judicial officers serving in a court described in subparagraph (A), including judges, magistrate judges, commissioners, justices of the peace, or any other person with decision-making authority; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9456612344BC426D8269C2A09073F53A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>jail</term> means any confinement facility of a State or unit of local government, whether administered by such government or by a private organization on behalf of such government; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC2834C59C19466C8369CCA832E086A1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>money bail</term> means any condition of release from confinement that imposes a financial burden on the person released; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H407E909CABB841FFB6A9830C7F1C7D1F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>prosecution office</term> means any public agency charged with direct responsibility for prosecuting criminal offenders, including any component bureau of such an agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA38F932BD4F242179ED30E35093A59C5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the terms <quote>State</quote> and <quote>unit of local government</quote> have the meanings given such terms in section 901(a) of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10251">34 U.S.C. 10251(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HD9D5DFDB215D42799EDE5F8E6BA02050"><enum>3.</enum><header>Crime wave transparency</header><subsection id="H0F0D5FEAE6E74ADE8FD66E0E9BF7F9AD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each State or unit of local government shall—</text><paragraph id="H95734195A50341FEA374552FF2939064"><enum>(1)</enum><text>fully and accurately report information required by the National Incident-Based Reporting System of the Federal Bureau of Investigation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C73C5F41B3B4EA9B5CD4163D4714D47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and at the end of each fiscal year thereafter, submit to the Attorney General a report describing—</text><subparagraph id="H468B613DEBCF4CF7A85542DCD57D0B43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any law, rule, policy, or practice in effect in the jurisdiction of the State or unit of local government which requires or results in the nonenforcement of any criminal offenses within such jurisdiction; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE400DE042FA04A318B2B7FF30D7754D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any law, rule, policy, or practice in effect in the jurisdiction of the State or unit of local government which requires or results in the nonprosecution of any criminal offenses within such jurisdiction;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05401D77016B4E05A24E45EBD5C4D8EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any law, rule, policy, or practice in effect in the jurisdiction of the State or unit of local government which has the effect of withdrawing law enforcement protection from a geographical area or structure that law enforcement officers are lawfully entitled to access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2018EC803D274EF08DD4A520ADF84E19"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of criminal offenses declined to be prosecuted, disaggregated by each criminal offense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3A9C43563404FAEBDCAAD5D3D12FC72"><enum>(E)</enum><text>average sentences for filed criminal charges which resulted in punishment, disaggregated by length of sentence issued after a plea of guilty or plea of nolo contendere, length of sentence issued after guilt was determined by trial, and obligations placed on a defendant as a result of pretrial diversion; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB82CE65297A343719720A2E3312CA12C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the average sentences imposed for each crime within the jurisdiction of the State or unit of local government, and the average sentences actually served, disaggregated by each criminal offense; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E39B86594274EF9B048AAE1EF4EB9BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and at the end of each fiscal year thereafter, submit to the Attorney General a report describing efforts to reduce crime within the jurisdiction of the State or unit of local government, which shall include a discussion of—</text><subparagraph id="H903B1BEC0B074CF8B037CA853B1202BC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ongoing strategies to reduce the number of criminal offenses committed within the jurisdiction of the State or unit of local government; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC98EA3B17ECE40BB85CF6A6CD34C7691"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ongoing efforts to hire and retain law enforcement officers; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D1FD543B0E249569D4A992BC2CCDA70"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ongoing strategies to combat anti-police sentiment; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46FF427248A7468D93792D3197433075"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ongoing strategies to prevent repeat offenses by violent offenders; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H650F59C18BF349DBA94F9892809B1B10"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ongoing strategies to increase prosecution of crime within its jurisdiction; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F89A3E811C34F768CCED60AB3364941"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and at the end of each fiscal year thereafter, submit to the Attorney General a report describing the criminal offenses committed by persons who have been released from jail on pretrial release, which shall include crime data, in compliance with the requirements of the National Incident-Based Reporting System, for individuals who have been released from jail on pretrial release that have been arrested or charged with a felony or violent misdemeanor committed after pretrial release.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HADB36A37DF974548A4AD966C9CBCE2FF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement through reduction in grant funds</header><text>For any fiscal year beginning on or after the date of enactment of this Act, a State or unit of local government that fails to comply with subsection (a) shall be subject to a 20-percent reduction in the amount that would otherwise be made available to the State or unit of local government under covered grants.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE798405E2E84458DB0C7AE19C77DEEA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><text>Amounts not allocated to a State or unit of local government under a covered grant under subsection (b) for failure to fully comply with subsection (a) shall be reallocated under the applicable covered grant program to States or units of local government that have not failed to comply with subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF0E75B907346468395439D0055E2A9A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and at the end of each fiscal year thereafter, the Attorney General shall publish a report listing each State or unit of local government that is not in compliance with subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H5BBEFC50B2AA4927A93F98FBA8F03BC9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Online information</header><text>The Attorney General shall maintain a public website on which each report required under subsection (a) or (d) may be accessed in an electronically searchable format.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFEC0F7F3AE36424F8518A07E6B389F0C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text>In order to ensure that the reports required under subsection (a) are true and correct, the Attorney General shall monitor and assess the accuracy of the reports required under section (a), which shall include conducting audits.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7D61ECE4C9894EACBA54166FAEB5337A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(b) of the Crime Identification Technology Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/40301">34 U.S.C. 40301(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5E4AF2221EC944BDB04E55259330D439" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (17), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1168DC31C474AF0855C5590FE37106F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (18), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H631BD9EEF8A04E16AB67E97313876501"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFC316D344CC5429383E252581950DFBF"><paragraph id="H415A5F1E1CFE401EB2634D1055C7AFB0"><enum>(19)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to assist units of local government that have a population of less than 150,000 in complying with the report requirements under section 3(a) of the Concerned Citizens Bill of Rights Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H46459AC2F03248F8A2ABC78565EB80FF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Defunding no cash bail</header><subsection id="H84F7D85F179844F78D861F4D8B78943B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In order to be eligible to receive any amounts under a covered grant, a State or unit of local government shall, not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and at the end of each fiscal year thereafter, submit to the Attorney General a certification that—</text><paragraph id="H8594542351A849D98C2E9BAE13CE7473"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the State or unit of local government does not have in effect a law, rule, policy, or practice that prohibits criminal courts from—</text><subparagraph id="H1076B555D5A04F0E838544403ADD856C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>imposing money bail for any felony or any violent misdemeanor offense; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78F1B238A19640618D446E9229286B7A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">taking the criminal history and dangerousness of the defendant into account when setting money bail for any felony or violent misdemeanor offense; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAF191417A784457BE087EEFEC01DD2F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prosecution office of the State or unit of local government does not have in effect a law, rule, policy, or practice of prohibiting the imposition of money bail for any felony or violent misdemeanor offense.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3321E8FBC852431AA1E4B78E42E25499"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of amounts</header><text>Amounts not allocated to a State or unit of local government under a covered grant for failure to fully comply with subsection (a) shall be reallocated under the applicable covered grant program to States or units of local government that have not failed to comply with subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

