<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7DAA2536E0354A6294FCA8077BEED364" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8275 IH: Wholesale Produce Market Review Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8275</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to submit to Congress a report on improving supply chain shortfalls and infrastructure needs at wholesale produce markets, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC042773CE6F043DBADBAB87E7E04D0A6" style="OLC"><section id="HCF2C761509F94CE89C16B7A42A5E1271" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wholesale Produce Market Review Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H5D07883E31794A71941A219813E474BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Secretary of Agriculture report on improving supply chain shortfalls and infrastructure needs at wholesale produce markets</header><subsection id="HC554B2AC768245E9977C17DBA8A97965"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture, in consultation with the entities specified in subsection (c) shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on—</text><paragraph id="HA5DC8D77D5B84E0C855A7198B20AFB4B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the 5 largest wholesale produce markets by annual sales and amount of goods moved for the preceding 4 calendar years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4DB23F11D0D4AE1BE8348DAEC1198AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a representative sample of 8 wholesale produce markets that are not among the largest wholesale produce markets.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D198C4420C94E709F5DA2FDBEBC32F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall contain the following:</text><paragraph id="HC67DD18F20BA4DEAB48F2A3CC0B95765"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An analysis of the supply chain shortfalls in each wholesale produce market identified under subsection (a), which shall include an analysis of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H819F890261C844FB8F0ED62232F2A490"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State of repair of infrastructure, including roads, food storage units, and refueling stations. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31601ACD1D7444938E77494D1F3C555A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Sustainability infrastructure, including the following: </text><clause id="H6F7E579AB6A34265B834FAD315F5E7C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Carbon emission reduction technology.</text></clause><clause id="H0C5BE1642FE24ADA8BBF0EB0D838C93C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>On-site green refueling stations.</text></clause><clause id="H88A4ECAFB3F5411FAA8AF4891F14C1D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Disaster preparedness. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5CE2FF9CDB74A1EBBC89CD5B9D0C7B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Recovery systems, including coordination with State and Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93FCA139C1E24BCB89F9B3D03BA411AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any actions the Secretary recommends be taken as a result of the analysis under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H770454DFBFCC4404A9DFF0BF6D08A6BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations, as appropriate, for wholesale produce market owners and operators, and State and local entities to improve the supply chain shortfalls identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H080FA65EB42F43128AC97B69C949924E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Proposals, as appropriate, for legislative actions and funding needed to improve the supply chain shortfalls.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0BAF669302964A3FA3EE8115A6F9093E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing the report under subsection (a), the Secretary of Agriculture shall consult with the Secretary of Transportation, wholesale produce market owners and operators, State and local entities, and other agencies or stakeholders, as determined appropriate by the Secretary. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC5DC517BC4ED4C0597A8F43C95BC3288"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Agriculture and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

