<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB7BE5A7FD7D14282BF97852640B50656" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6597 IH: Blockchain Solutions for Small Businesses Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6597</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000397">Mrs. Kim of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to conduct a study on the state of blockchain technology and its use in consumer protection, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HE614AAE89E374D6BAD825F17335B40FB" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1ED31855A14A4C63BEA21289425152C9" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Blockchain Solutions for Small Businesses Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H08DE23D6A7834AEB84E1B89410B25F7F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0A7AAD40EED74801AA4FA139520A60E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Blockchain or distributed ledger technology allows computers connected by a peer-to-peer network to reach agreement over a shared ledger of data. Changes to the shared ledger can only be effected if the majority of the computers in the network verify the validity of the change and agree to its inclusion in the ledger.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2C3D40397CE42F697635A2F52CF319D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Connected Commerce Council found that 72 percent of small businesses increased their use of digital tools during the COVID–19 crisis, and 48 percent utilized a new digital tool.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5CC74F7708B44EC4A2A9E497A3EBD83F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As small businesses increasingly move their operations online, it is critical that any and all information relevant to the business is protected and secure. Blockchain technology is an additional tool that small businesses can leverage to ensure that the operation is adequately protected from cyberattack.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H604E833F34BB4A48BF4AD1EC3931CDE6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Blockchains are decentralized and distributed across peer-to-peer networks that are continually updated and kept in sync. Because these networks are not contained in a central location, they do not have a single point of failure and cannot be changed from a single computer operating within the network. These features of blockchain technology make stealing data or engaging in fraud significantly more difficult.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7554DF84E70F4320AB477D52B28975B0"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Blockchain technology has the ability to bolster trust and efficiency. All participants in the blockchain networks have access to the same information, which is not only immutable but also updated in real time, which means that information sharing and verification is streamlined and accessible to all relevant parties. </text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3812016D5E944F58BC4D61E7215029A8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on blockchain technology and its uses at the Small Business Administration</header> <subsection id="H00091018C59547AEAB114A9FFF1FC9D2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration, in consultation with any other Federal agency the Administrator determines appropriate, shall conduct a study on—</text> 
<paragraph id="H25704663AFFB4B3395E91BE74C612332"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the current and potential uses of blockchain technology to carry out the requirements of subsections (a) and (b)(2) of section 7 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E74B532FC0C405D967887E44CD75A7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential uses of blockchain technology to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H670FE87FDD864345BF8E443131E513D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>minimize fraud in the lending programs established under such subsections; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB84F43E81124BF08E72AF292D6A003A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve the provision of services under such lending programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H57E7760CB6AA4D1AB64957B9D37D383B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> <paragraph id="HA9BD459D51B64CDA9ECD594763377116"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of trends in the use of blockchain technology in the financial sector.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H47FBE644FA5B42F3A8B6B9FD14DB1AB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of best practices to facilitate partnerships between private entities and the Administration to use blockchain technology to carry out the requirements of subsections (a) and (b)(2) of section 7 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>), minimize fraud in the lending programs established under such subsections, and improve the provision of services under such lending programs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF661001D97944188C89E5978FC44221"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to carrying out the requirements of subsections (a) and (b)(2) of section 7 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>), a description of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4181CBFECDEC46EEA39BCE35AB03CAC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the potential benefits and risks of using blockchain technology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H126BFC3846714AD188525FF25509273B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how blockchain technology can be used to maximize efficiency of the Administration; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF196325010FF4817995F54A3BEECAEA5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how blockchain technology can be used to reduce fraud and increase the security of the lending programs established under such subsections.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H100E6D6402F14F13A1A29401898C324D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other relevant information or recommendations related to the use of blockchain technology by the Administrator.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H07B837E273E54991936128468245C3C6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report on the results of the study.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE81DAECDFA3449FA88E2B5565E1C1634"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Blockchain defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>blockchain</term> means a digital ledger or database which is chronological, consensus-based, decentralized, and mathematically verified in nature. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


