<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H49F9CFFC753A459E8B51D07082F87580" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9450 IH: Connecting Small Businesses with Capital Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9450</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000474">Mr. Flood</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to develop and disseminate resources on Regulation CF and Rule 504 of Regulation D, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H73BA25CA35AE4EC2ACD16934626D5B0B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF699F77D752B4E8B9C1686CF8E3EEB6D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Connecting Small Businesses with Capital Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC8605CB63BD548B8A500862C4C609520" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H218DCD6F94A14DCA9736CD800F2A87A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/106">Public Law 112–106</external-xref>) was a law that expanded opportunity and access to capital for entrepreneurs.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAEB1009F51714DC487BF2A5E86C169C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the rules of the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act of 2012 have taken time to be finalized, participation by small business concerns in part 227 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly known as <quote>Regulation CF</quote>) and Rule 504 of Regulation D (section 230.504 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations) is still maturing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37E3D92776FC4E87A3338BC60E5829E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Small Business Administration serves as a resource for thousands of small business concerns and entrepreneurs across the United States seeking financing, aid, counsel, and assistance in starting or growing their business.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H1B7F1101245445E2AD4FA17E43F9E45B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Resources on Regulation CF and Rule 504 of Regulation D</header> <subsection id="HCE9B7CF278544743AAF77874BF6D403F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration, in coordination with the Office of Advocacy of the Administration and the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation of the Securities Exchange Commission, shall develop and disseminate, and make publicly available on a website of the Administration, resources related to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H70691222AAFE45D79B43A135E1CB8F5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>part 227 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations (commonly known as <quote>Regulation CF</quote>) implementing title III of the Jumpstart Our Business Startups Act of 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/112/106">Public Law 112–106</external-xref>) (commonly known as the <quote>CROWDFUND Act</quote>); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H15E02E65DDF64DE6877E4756E64909CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rule 504 of Regulation D (section 230.504 of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H448FFF352AC444B7BA3DBE7FA4D45F2C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content</header><text>The resources described in subsection (a) should include the following:</text> <paragraph id="H4AA3A8EFF2BC4D6881F6B5B1F2D35F7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of Regulation CF and Rule 504 of Regulation D.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7F4F5D3905943ECA692C45BF9F587D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An explanation of how a small business concern (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)) may be affected by Regulation CF and Rule 504 of Regulation D.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2E5BC27CD69A4FEABCE3873D3A77BF9A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How Regulation CF and Rule 504 of Regulation D may be helpful in assisting small business concerns with raising capital from investors.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H36E4037814004B9BAFA8B72201B0C201" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Provide points of contact to the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation of the Securities Exchange Commission to a small business concern.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9B1961542A3343E986BCDC9B50CD1DF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than once a year, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration, in coordination with the Office of Advocacy of the Administration and the Office of the Advocate for Small Business Capital Formation of the Securities Exchange Commission, shall update the resources described in subsection (a) in accordance with any modifications made to Regulation CF and Rule 504 of Regulation D.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HC403B1E3AF1449CC9179640E01730070"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Resource partners</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall disseminate the resources described in subsection (a) to—</text> <paragraph id="H5BA0149E2A7D49CF958E1BC0DB706907"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">small business development centers (as defined in section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>));</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE713E00022CD4F4BBC07374328B4CC60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>women’s business centers (described under section 29 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/656">15 U.S.C. 656</external-xref>));</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB08A2F5C03804FADA3DA056C769C967B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>chapters of the Service Corps of Retired Executives (established under section 8(b)(1)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(b)(1)(B)</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H430D2FF577474C919B2F5B68CF8818AF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Veteran Business Outreach Centers (described under section 32 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657b">15 U.S.C. 657b</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7A619299726241AEA26B74FA5BA46CAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall submit to Congress a report on compliance with the requirements of this Act. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

