<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H680A3CB95623463BBEE72D4152A04778" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8300 IH: Empowering Resilient Local Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8300</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to issue guidance on extreme temperature events and resilience goals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6116DEE6085E4E28907E46A67DA09553" style="OLC"><section id="H56F4246AECA449D7B426DBD3A8A667A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering Resilient Local Communities Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB19C388AD6AA4FD9AB5BF90138366C64" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 203 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD7657E629D684C65920E761FEF6F9ECD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3142A15531664D90B52C1F28450FF5E8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HA97F285354E745BEA945A0334AC81C67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of underserved community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>underserved community</quote> means a community, or a neighborhood within a community, that—</text><paragraph id="H4C775F7167184CAB9BAF81028C4806AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is classified as high risk according to census tract risk ratings derived from a product that—</text><subparagraph id="H97E1087E4F6F417B9C519CFAD667A6D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is maintained under a natural hazard assessment program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3CFA517975141179CA1D77FB8C835F1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is available to the public;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB730A97B12C14A83800D625D6C261CE1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>defines natural hazard risk across the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6E72E1CD7BE4BCDA931108CF47C5C4E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reflects high levels of individual hazard risk ratings;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F6912AAD5FD4DE58A04F77D5F2C2C13"><enum>(E)</enum><text>reflects high social vulnerability ratings and low community resilience ratings; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H514D8DE841E54D6392A283B02736E64A"><enum>(F)</enum><text>reflects the principal natural hazard risks identified for the respective census tracts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H43DB5667C09044CB8235D88294160D61"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any other elements determined by the President;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H092B855E314C452CBDB2D63377360F03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is comprised of 50,000 or fewer individuals and is economically disadvantaged, as determined by the State in which the community is located and based on criteria established by the President; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3D4DA8707DB4F8EAEC676364956E87C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is otherwise determined by the President based on factors including, high housing cost burden and substandard housing, percentage of homeless population, limited water and sanitation access, demographic information such as race, age, and disability, language composition, transportation access or type, disproportionate environmental stressor burden, and disproportionate impacts from climate change.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A2F0C0E7DE84D3AA0A4A29FF6FE2B5F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g)(9) by striking <quote>small impoverished communities</quote> and inserting <quote>underserved communities</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC22355A3B64F6F8CCF7029174E63DC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H1C2C5FBD27034FE29B6469B836A7CCED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the heading by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Small impoverished communities</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Underserved communities</header-in-text></quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3D3DBCFCF77446FAF88EC04C4A5A075"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>small impoverished community</quote> and inserting <quote>underserved community</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H1CF852D283014F08A9BACDA561769E31"><enum>3.</enum><header>Guidance on extreme temperature events</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Administration shall issue guidance related to extreme temperature events, including heat waves and freezes, and publish such guidance in the Federal Emergency Management Administration Public Assistance Program and Policy Guide.</text></section><section id="HCCFDEBC5DC824CD4B81A0A8E9BCA549E"><enum>4.</enum><header>Hazard mitigation plans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 322 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165">42 U.S.C. 5165</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H19291461B5734220934A1233E5CF927B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) by striking the period at the end and inserting </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB05EE9F60BD141D9A76FEB3012118A08" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>, including—</text><paragraph id="HC529104C84194F2EB8724ADE2CF6ACC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying the extent to which resilience is or will be incorporated into other planning processes, including community land use, economic development, capital improvement budgets and transportation planning processes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC637ACF90624604B2DBCDBC748EE387"><enum>(2)</enum><text>goals and objectives related to increasing resilience over a 5-year period, including benchmarks for future work and an assessment of past progress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B88E7193F0A4991BB8D71687AADDFBE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the building codes in existence at the time the plan is submitted and standards that are in use by the State for all manner of planning or development purposes and how the State has or will comply with the standards set forth in section 406(e)(1)(A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDAE566FF7E1412C95591F739F9B6AF3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the use of nature-based solutions or other mitigation activities that conserve or restore natural features that can serve to abate or lessen the impacts of future disasters;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5248588644FC4E14BC29C8D63906A9E3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>integration of each local mitigation plan with the State, Indian Tribe, or territory plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H047354920A5B4F909FDFD93A02D05762"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the disparate impacts on underserved communities (as such term is defined in section 203(a)) and plans to address any disparities.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0B86725DEFA45C5AF42D3CA3455F565"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE7AF04E7CC2E4342AE54CDFEF8381C8C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H1D62E7646EB54E519C57D6C32D77058C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue specific guidance on resilience goals and provide technical assistance for States, Indian Tribes, territories, and local governments to meet such goals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H681423532DF74C6D90FB70FA6DF22B51"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Adequate staffing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall ensure that ample staff are available to develop the guidance and technical assistance under section 322, including hazard mitigation planning staff and personnel with expertise in community planning, land use development, and consensus based codes and hazard resistant designs at each regional office that specifically focus on providing financial and non-financial direct technical assistance to States, Indian Tribes, and territories.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDF0353E6EA684C91A0D43FBB11E20A60"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not less frequently than every 5 years, the Administrator shall submit to Congress a report on the progress of meeting the goals under this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HA00B78B584CA422689AD80780E2565CC"><enum>5.</enum><header>Additional uses of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFB55BED2DD3A45F8941FEC298E989A0D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H04FEB443E34442F9A7F92E4F3C13AEB3"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Additional uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For State and local governments that have exceeded, adopted, or are implementing the latest two published editions of relevant consensus-based codes, specifications, and standards that incorporate the latest hazard-resistant designs and establish minimum acceptable criteria for the design, construction, and maintenance of residential structures and facilities, a recipient of assistance provided under this paragraph may use such assistance in a manner consistent with the standards set forth in clauses (ii) and (iii) of section 406(e)(1)(A).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3617E2F1941C4666A4FA5FA08349EFC6"><enum>6.</enum><header>Collaboration with other agencies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In awarding grants under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency may coordinate with other relevant agencies, including the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of Energy, the Department of Transportation, the Corps of Engineers, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Housing and Urban Development, as necessary, to improve collaboration for eligible activities under the Act.</text></section><section id="H162BDECA3EFF4BCAACA109E327BA7C1E"><enum>7.</enum><header>GAO reports</header><subsection id="HB806289D04DE4AB0AB7F0EE0E8CF9E05"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extreme temperature events</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Comptroller General of the United States shall evaluate and issue to Congress and the Federal Emergency Management Agency a report regarding the impacts of extreme temperatures events on communities, the challenges posed to the Federal Emergency Management Agency in addressing extreme temperature events, and recommendations for the Federal Emergency Management Agency to better provide assistance to communities experiencing extreme temperature events. The report may also include examples of specific mitigation and resilience projects that communities may undertake, and the Federal Emergency Management Agency may consider, to reduce the impacts of extreme temperatures on and within building structures, participatory processes that allow for public engagement in determining and addressing local risks and vulnerabilities related to extreme temperatures events, and community infrastructure, including heating or cooling shelters.</text></subsection><subsection id="H90469D443A204B7E9364F7CDEA2D7A38"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Smoke and indoor air quality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 5 years thereafter, the Comptroller General shall evaluate and issue to Congress and the Federal Emergency Management Agency a report regarding the impacts of wildfire smoke and poor indoor air quality, the challenges posed to Federal Emergency Management Agency in addressing wildfire smoke and indoor air quality, and recommendations for the Federal Emergency Management Agency to better provide assistance to communities and individuals in dealing with wildfire smoke and indoor air quality.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6451B5750E27419F96134170B6A3806F"><enum>8.</enum><header>Report Congress and update of cost effectiveness determinations and declarations</header><subsection id="H8F8C985DA6484BC99B23EE22F2491BF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall submit to Congress a report regarding the challenges posed by the Agency’s requirements for declaring an incident or determining the cost effectiveness of mitigation activities and specifically how such requirements may disproportionately burden small impoverished communities, or specific vulnerable populations within communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H95D55FBAB247432392207C0932C76C0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Update of cost effectiveness determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, to the extent practicable, shall update the requirements for determining cost effectiveness and declaring incidents, including selection of appropriate interest rates, based on the findings made under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

