<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC86F805855D04199BBA7402D5E4B53F4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8563 IH: Sunset Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8563</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000294">Mr. Emmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001115">Mr. Cloud</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, to provide for Congressional oversight of agency rulemaking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB1689DE61F1F4206B6D7E25A15DE2AF0" style="OLC"><section id="HB91C193F115B4B6C9FB642DC93AFECE4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sunset Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H88126A14EEF549C7A0DBFA2A70114168"><enum>2.</enum><header>Congressional review of agency rulemaking</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/8">Chapter 8</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H46923CFCAE244D2EBD855AA96E288BA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the table of sections, by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H9356009D9A2A4D7F9F3D23A58942C882" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">809. Sunset for rules.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">810. Review of rules in effect.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">and </continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA8E7FEF46FE4C00BF87FADF68652FA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HD5DCADF15D1B42919DD4EDA1FDBBEBCB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section commented="no" id="HEF6D5749A7C84D4A9AAE3A63A51BD5B7"><enum>809.</enum><header>Sunset for rules</header><subsection commented="no" id="HE1913533A86E41768FCA7C26D0EBD8FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Expiration of rule</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H7182F49728024FB5A6B063EC7BDACAFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in this section, each major rule made by an agency shall cease to have effect—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H86405018A10A498AAAABC36A0B8F5336"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of a joint resolution described in subsection (d) with regard to the rule; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3F03EEAE81ED4A7F9B4B731C5BF681ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if a joint resolution of extension described in subsection (d) has been enacted with regard to the rule, beginning on the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of the most recently enacted such joint resolution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF84CAFA4F269454B982A6EF3C3B93C92"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reissuance of the rule prohibited</header><text>The rule may not be reissued in substantially the same form, and a new rule that is substantially the same as such a rule may not be issued, unless the reissued or new rule is specifically authorized by a law enacted after the date described in this subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H9951520E9D8146EF9B273ED25027ED74"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report by agency</header><text>Not later than 180 days before the date described in subsection (a), the agency shall submit a report similar to the report described in 801(a)(1)(A) to each House of Congress and to the Comptroller General, except that instead of the proposed effective date, such report shall contain the date described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H4CEC33AFF6FB41E08CF2E3612BC7FD9D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption by President</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may by Executive order exempt not more than one rule during each Congress from the application of subsection (a) for a period of not more than 30 days if the President determines, and submits to Congress written notice of such determination, that such rule is—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE82FF0CE2B76407694E4A66C43D39A65"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">necessary because of an imminent threat to health or safety or other emergency;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3705858462E14EA89B5BC5A0529A7708"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">necessary for the enforcement of criminal laws;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF1884F935FE45AD862C0CF8F2F26B6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">necessary for national security; or</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5261CFF8E2C84464A7D3DF86F236648E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issued pursuant to any statute implementing an international trade agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H03260A626EF54295BBF1E1FE9C3FD51A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Joint resolution of extension</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H085B41A609E74CEDB629FEB15C3BD523"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Joint resolution described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>joint resolution</term> means only a joint resolution introduced on or after the date on which the report referred to subsection (b) is received by Congress (excluding days either House of Congress is adjourned for more than 3 days during a session of Congress), the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress extends the rule submitted by the _ _ relating to _ _.</quote> (The blank spaces being appropriately filled in). The following shall apply to such a joint resolution:</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0C9DF194AC84C9BAE94BA0EA2DECC4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the House, the majority leader of the House of Representatives (or his designee) and the minority leader of the House of Representatives (or his designee) shall introduce such joint resolution (by request), within 3 legislative days after Congress receives the report submitted under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF5F348A526EE4B6591502F721B924E1C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the Senate, the majority leader of the Senate (or his designee) and the minority leader of the Senate (or his designee) shall introduce such joint resolution described in subsection (a) (by request), within 3 session days after Congress receives the report submitted under subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H143156FF8C6F40318C8FC36A9F8D0552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of joint resolution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b) through (g) of section 802 shall apply to a joint resolution described in paragraph (1) of this subsection in the same manner as a joint resolution described in subsection (a) of section 802, except that for purposes of that subsection, the term <quote>submission date</quote> means the date on which the Congress receives the report submitted under subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBF5BF1006F6D44C69129EDF50CE0E179"><enum>810.</enum><header>Review of rules in effect</header><subsection id="HAF7F804004114D18AF033FEEE711B0A1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual review</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this section and annually thereafter for the 9 years following, each agency shall designate not less than 10 percent of eligible rules made by that agency for review, and shall submit a report including each such eligible rule in the same manner as a report under section 801(a)(1). Section 801 and section 802 shall apply to each such rule, subject to subsection (c) of this section. No eligible rule previously designated may be designated again.</text></subsection><subsection id="H85403D99C025402B93143ED898AD557B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset for eligible rules not extended</header><text>Beginning after the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this section, if Congress has not enacted a joint resolution of approval for that eligible rule, that eligible rule shall not continue in effect.</text></subsection><subsection id="H88DB33C67BA140119CFA8A1BC0301808"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consolidation; severability</header><text>In applying sections 801 and 802 to eligible rules under this section, the following shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H6BFAB9A2914D4930A41F954B80EA92E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The words <quote>take effect</quote> shall be read as <quote>continue in effect</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC93A86E13AE9442EBC7E71DF528A675B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), a single joint resolution of approval shall apply to all eligible rules in a report designated for a year, and the matter after the resolving clause of that joint resolution is as follows: <quote>That Congress approves the rules submitted by the __ for the year __.</quote> (The blank spaces being appropriately filled in).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80A6F7C977104C6F8740B3586EE5B275"><enum>(3)</enum><text>It shall be in order to consider any amendment that provides for specific conditions on which the approval of a particular eligible rule included in the joint resolution is contingent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41D89A5A5B4A4A72A53EA761AB6DB3BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A Member of either House may move that a separate joint resolution be required for a specified rule.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC28E53580E25415B8A24E974DB61F8EA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible rule</quote> means a major rule that is in effect as of the date of enactment of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H040D155CF8CD4500A30F133EBBBB03DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date that is 10 years after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="HF27A8D392C5B48348ACFD84BE5A53082"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 810 of title 5, United States Code, is repealed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D2F27A476AB470CA6C89D875F77F46C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the table of sections for chapter 8 of such title is amended by striking the item pertaining to section 810.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

