<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H855CBD09175F41C185ED37B917C7839A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9651 IH: To promote long-term economic recovery and job creation in underserved communities by providing for investment in catalytic local predevelopment projects for resilient climate infrastructure innovation and to provide assistance to support State and local project development, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9651</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221221">December 21, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To promote long-term economic recovery and job creation in underserved communities by providing for investment in catalytic local predevelopment projects for resilient climate infrastructure innovation and to provide assistance to support State and local project development, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H36EA28E7228E4028B30A937E2595A7AF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD3D84AE24F16495AA8D609534CEA3996" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Infrastructure Funding &amp; Technical assistance Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LIFT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7A4D4BAE42104377BF941E3A17204091"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header> <subsection id="HA0E5EB11E28D4FF1A2F2718D3CA0E583"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD9E7C96468FD484FB5D2DEEFF9D71665"><enum>(1)</enum><text>infrastructure systems in the United States are in a period of significant disrepair and are increasingly vulnerable;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48E281C935DC4A9592C3105E4775A09E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aging infrastructure, new technologies, increasing complexity, and increasing incidents of severe weather pose new challenges to the resilience of those infrastructure systems;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC17598FD36324F68B70BFF159AB70417"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the climate resilience challenge is most acute in underserved communities in the United States, which face a chronic underinvestment in infrastructure systems and require restorative investments to rebuild with equity;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC0342686622240FB8A4865C3C9B5140E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in purchasing infrastructure, the Federal Government typically accepts a low-cost capital bid without a plan for maintaining an asset that is designed to last 30 to 40 years, such that investing in local best practices and capacity for better procurement, asset management, design, lifecycle finance, and innovative data and sensor systems will partially address the resilient infrastructure funding crisis in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFBDF09A446314D0D8CF8E2AE639FB3C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>experts have determined that pre­de­vel­op­ment funding at the local and project levels is the critical gap in accelerating efforts of the Federal Government—</text> <subparagraph id="H5EEE8F328D4A40159001150EDEB03061"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support climate-resilient infrastructure systems and regional economies; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H28D5505CEC494B0287E6782265BF4096"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to create a steady stream of <quote>shovel-worthy</quote> and well-maintained community projects; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27880883E4A9491E83FD4565CBA15629"><enum>(6)</enum><text>economic analyses have determined that existing Federal and State predevelopment programs generate as much as $16 to $20 in economic activity for every $1 of public funds expended;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H295B99234D5D451C9A92FB3807BA5E60"><enum>(7)</enum><text>studies demonstrate that the development of stronger lifecycle infrastructure methods by State and local project sponsors will likely help local governments better leverage current and future Federal taxpayer investment in public infrastructure through partnerships with impact investors;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H158AFEF15C8548ACAEECCC6BA2AD7B33"><enum>(8)</enum><text>well-managed and resilient regional, State, and local infrastructure assets will lower future Federal taxpayer costs for recovery and restoration efforts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9EAD3CE7E1F64D38AFC2CE0F03E2B2F8"><enum>(9)</enum><text>States and regions have unique infrastructure systems and challenges, such as—</text> <subparagraph id="HCBCEA38A5F96454BBEE11FEFCBC0A7E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>hurricanes and flooding along the coasts; </text> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H44135D9A216045899F89CB21F3F00BC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>wildfires and droughts in the West;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC0C4410C4FFA4002AC3AD5A6EB7BB553"><enum>(C)</enum><text>failing dams and levees in the Midwest and Mississippi regions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE905FC40FB37498EBFBD042994FBEC4C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>stormwater management issues in the East; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C13227BF00649A5B9A8E012D0D30EF7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>broadband connectivity in the Intermountain region;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1522FE2E4124FFF8225CEA56695D0A6"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the interconnected nature of energy, water, building stock, transportation, and communication systems demands new investments and innovations—</text> <subparagraph id="HE9A705CC48AE4ACF87C1B9F276C7C00A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to prepare for mitigating risks and cyberattacks; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFE58110CA83743D4B2E0689B05DD3A66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out integrated deployment strategies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE25DE28F72B7463C88E743527D18C85E"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the basic infrastructure needs of many communities are changing during the COVID–19 era to emphasize distance learning and public health, while much of the infrastructure stock of the United States created in the 1950s, 1960s, and 1970s is aging;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD725F17FFEA04812A7E8E97D32FA4640"><enum>(12)</enum><text><fraction>2/3</fraction> of United States infrastructure is funded at the State and local levels; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E27D58848694F95A1F02B5E7C8B227B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the Federal Government, in the role of a long-term strategic infrastructure partner, should focus on making catalytic investments that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAF62F2F0989E4E0CA8297B56A114C118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promote local best practices in resilient infrastructure through performance-based investments in States and communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H15D214BC1E0C4EA3B6F1BD4F4EAEF973"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage regional innovation, innovative partnerships, and economic resilience strategies and outcomes that fund long-term capacity building and economic recovery; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HADBF006F25524CB9A71464142A03261B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide strategic capacity building resources, technical assistance, and flexible predevelopment support for resilient infrastructure project development that allows States and communities to accelerate the most critical State and community infrastructure needs; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H374F8C622A7F49A38E8D991C243CD31C"><enum>(14)</enum><text>grantees and applicants of the Assistance for Coal Communities program of the Economic Development Administration have expressed financial hardship with meeting all project predevelopment costs needed to be eligible for that program and to transition away from fossil fuel infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0F7A9B5F67CB4D87BEDABC321416474E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>Recognizing that pressing climate infrastructure needs differ by State and region, and that Federal program support for project predevelopment is limited or inflexible due to programmatic silos, the purpose of this Act is to establish new, flexible funding streams and expedited processes—</text> <paragraph id="HBDB32F13F39C414C9F90507939CDFBDE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to accelerate timely, resilient infrastructure deployment, specifically in underserved communities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1315003018F438688544E29192FAF23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to reduce taxpayer costs in response to disasters involving infrastructure; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE40860BBD6314F5DAD3EFB79177E96DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to preserve existing jobs and to create new jobs.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HA3D2EAE67CE7493E872B16DFF66D5B83"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H44739048A7BD47FEB32DFF1CE996177B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Capacity building</header><text>The term <term>capacity building</term> includes all activities associated with early stage community-based project formation and conceptualization, prior to project predevelopment activity, including stipends to local community organizations for planning participation, community outreach and engagement activities, grant writing, research, and mentorship support to move projects from formation and conceptualization to project predevelopment. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AB7AE010AA647F09E2EFE05FF792314"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><text>The term <term>eligible recipient</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H3E9C891D6FC74566B650F41F45454C28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an eligible recipient (as defined in section 3 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3122">42 U.S.C. 3122</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2F5A115341D84160B5AF2CAB1E2673AE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a private individual, a nonprofit organization, or a for-profit organization. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFC7E2A8510345E69EEC7F279F96F256"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB48783F502FB4042B8BB9894B9A49764" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Lead applicant</header><text>The term <term>lead applicant</term> means the eligible recipient that is primarily responsible for the preparation, conduct, and administration of the project for which a grant is provided under section 4(b)(2). </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9085B2A9F23479CAD503829738ABAC9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minority or woman-led entity</header><text>The term <term>minority or woman-led entity</term> means an organization, as determined by the Secretary—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8B24690BF9EE4ABDBB2EA1B483AD8565"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for which a majority of the governing board of directors and executive leadership of the organization are women or minority persons;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2A5F856FA3174F6AA3E0E15573435230"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is not dependent on or influenced by another non-eligible person or organization; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H85831F59C6C94E9094F2B0A8B138BC97"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that has not been established for the purpose of this Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB3A169A5F5141F9B5D74B63B201FED0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Project predevelopment</header><text>The term <term>project predevelopment</term> means a measure required to be completed before construction of a project may occur, such as—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0B4BBC76B884460689EF8AE1B6FCB159"><enum>(A)</enum><text>architectural or engineering work;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91A07EA4E4E74202B9247F656A286388"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a market assessment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE68658C3F14471B83972CDCE1B7B16E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>community outreach and engagement;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACA50C1BA548458BBE821E96512E15C2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an economic feasibility study;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4F6141947C274021A1560480BEF21260"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the acquisition of a site or lease;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC90153ADF9994C15A2E1D9546A904392"><enum>(F)</enum><text>preparation of a business plan; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H324C3DD5CCFE47559E54C46CA7408830"><enum>(G)</enum><text>any activity relating to permitting;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DC33EC691364DFAA9205C188547031C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any activity relating to the writing of grant applications;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H763B9F76807B4E36B4C9C513A6D8FA7F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>capacity building in local governments, community institutions, and nonprofit organizations; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD531E029DDD485DACD654D70D0A21DF"><enum>(J)</enum><text>training for unionized labor to execute on such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDB1A22552D5047D6A4CED67058831F3A"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB743A484A8734CB3B7C9B49E774A21C8"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Underserved community</header><text>The term <term>underserved community</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H916CBC4D6EFD4029B0E5E60D0AF029EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community—</text> <clause id="HC24BBB9BBF754C0F9C9FC0C0A7EC6F4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or indigenous communities; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD28D9254EBF145228748F5A76A13DF3A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects, as compared to other communities;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H313B15A0D81341ED971F937269B2A392"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Tribal communities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BE64720AF0C43CA8E8A886425B85FFB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a community facing economic transition, deindustrialization, and historic under-investment; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D86C1A5EF994042B81508DB22B38D09" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a community with a high rate of poverty or unemployment. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H4C21FAF3337C4631BC2E2F800574D2C7" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="H6B51CBCD3FA24E92B7E3646C4629E622" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2022 $15,000,000,000 to remain available until September 30, 2027, to the Secretary of Commerce for economic adjustment assistance under section 209 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3149">42 U.S.C. 3149</external-xref>) to provide grants for project predevelopment and technical assistance.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H60D4242C8F4C42C5937B9F90ABE00302" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is authorized to be appropriated for fiscal year 2022 $300,000,000 to remain available until September 30, 2027, to the Secretary of Commerce for the administrative costs of carrying out this section, including the costs of utilizing temporary Federal personnel as may be necessary. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A7B45EDA2DC42AE8CB0E3F19C243DC4" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Type of grants</header><text>Of the amounts made available under subsection (a)—</text> <paragraph id="H8FF9945BFFFC46B6AF6CB9281302AC0B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$5,000,000,000 shall be for technical assistance and grants to eligible recipients to perform capacity building; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0C85F62DA2AC4A0EBA4290E6680706F3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$10,000,000,000 shall be for grants to eligible recipients to perform project predevelopment activities to assist States and communities that need support with climate infrastructure investments, subject to the requirements of section 5. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H69E703254A114ECD89D75D520B6F8823" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Underserved communities</header><text>Of the amounts made available under subsection (a), not less than 50 percent shall be used for activities described in subsection (c) that are carried out in underserved communities.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H23B17653A5054E7D9B3A1E909C19D9D9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Local infrastructure funding &amp; technical assistance grant requirements</header> 
<subsection id="H321D3F1649814B389D323277D8C60827"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>In making grants with amounts made available under section 4(c)(2), the Secretary may not—</text> <paragraph id="H65AD92C0406C42059F85D1DC6F2D2CE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide to an eligible recipient more than 1 grant for which the eligible recipient is the lead applicant; or </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD938403860C940C696665ED50B5D4E7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make a grant in an amount of more than $500,000.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF1FB512DD7E14C8F8CDAEB167926D253"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text>An eligible recipient seeking to receive a grant under section 4(c)(2) may partner with 1 or more—</text> 
<paragraph id="H3D80277DCA96464D87EE6B7608D13948"><enum>(1)</enum><text>eligible recipient; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F4E118115934473A081D6F5C51CF432"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other entity, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1508087D49494D11920E9223ADFE64C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of grant</header><text>An eligible recipient may use a grant under section 4(c)(2) for project predevelopment including—</text> <paragraph id="HA212D3B7FC7540A597103E70257E5E88"><enum>(1)</enum><text>project planning, community outreach and engagement, and feasibility studies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A86AAE0A8FF47C59E18D94DF56C9A49"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrations of innovative activities or strategic economic development investments;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31A6E5B4CF704CFB8952430DB7CF8BE3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>management and operational assistance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57026DF6F028421DBAD568F3E32E17D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishment of university centers;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H657AB7D70B344684B9FFF6EA3EF86DD4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establishment of business outreach centers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H514E55C4CB084953B73F1746C6D99200"><enum>(6)</enum><text>studies evaluating the needs of, and development potential for, economic growth of areas that the Secretary determines have substantial need for the assistance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD27716A1E1334BB3AF95D230098F12EA"><enum>(7)</enum><text>studies that evaluate the effectiveness of coordinating projects funded under the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3121">42 U.S.C. 3121 et seq.</external-xref>) with projects funded under other Acts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63812C3AC8FE47649969FDAE3D81FF68"><enum>(8)</enum><text>assessment, marketing, and establishment of business clusters; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF01C113B2CCB4C9B8C9FED6B0E7FB29F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>other activities determined by the Secretary to be appropriate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0F6CCF69AF14E838C822B67C24AC19C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>making a grant to an organization to carry out any of the activities described in paragraphs (1) through (9). </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H920B72C85BF14987842DE3A063965FF0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection</header> <paragraph id="H7C9839A08CF4414EB0B497DBDDC15DBE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may award a grant under section 4(c)(2) only after an evaluation of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA4964EE8E0C441B0B48DCAB6BF453EEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the merits of the application;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9609AADDC2DB4A488D5EED1F0A64F5A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the likely low- to no-carbon opportunities described in the application that align with any Federal climate and resiliency goals; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H54FEA87669A44EE0BFFA66DA40047530"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the extent to which the proposed activities would create efficiency of operations across services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H01D9916E89CA4CDAAB53623BDC99EAD4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the extent to which the proposed activities would promote resources to invest in community infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9E397559BA7B43C9BA6DD6DF0746891E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible recipients that—</text> <subparagraph id="H2946A105CCA04FC98EBB3AD12909E859"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are minority or women-led entities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA712CE9B616140C7B3ADE9473853E011"><enum>(B)</enum><text>are partnerships between an institution of higher education and a labor organization; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1265EC58A4CC4B1B91C167508106AFF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>are located in an underserved community; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19448EAB722A4EF78202E357F8CCE37A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>propose to carry out activities that would—</text> <clause id="H5820C656A3A9445EB2978FF8FC1F526C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>result in predicted large greenhouse gas reductions; or </text></clause> 
<clause id="HC5415E8209F34EF896D6837521AA1585"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce air pollution; </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F473423EA004724A3B1CCAB75F9E53E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>propose to carry out activities that would result in large improvements to public health; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4B55388F879947A7AD67871E1F293E95"><enum>(F)</enum><text>propose to carry out activities that would improve community adaptation and resiliency; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H136A6615B4AB43DFB1C84403119FC45B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>propose to carry out activities that would modernize communities and community connectivity. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 


