<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7942007083E143E19A52BB859445F8ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8834 IH: Enhancing Questions to Understand Intentions for Pregnancy Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8834</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220915">September 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for a demonstration program to facilitate the clinical adoption of pregnancy intention screening initiatives by health care and social service providers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFB4D7185D3F741D3AD36A53FD0FC4D96" style="OLC"><section id="H9E2BBFC2A98E4D07899AEE14E05C3C7C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Questions to Understand Intentions for Pregnancy Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>EQUIP Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6244F78C82374374ADB5151044027A91"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pregnancy intention screening initiative demonstration program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2199B82E88294EEFBFB2EFFF0B37C7C4" style="OLC"><section id="H2AF3947E38334E47A9E22570C8377062"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Pregnancy intention screening initiative demonstration program</header><subsection id="H7CDD543B5D45414D82B1F543E024C928"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall establish a demonstration program to facilitate the clinical adoption of pregnancy intention screening initiatives by health care and social service providers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H311160586EF5430D98BEE2344B0CBF13"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The Secretary shall carry out the demonstration program through awarding grants to eligible entities to implement pregnancy intention screening initiatives, collect data, and evaluate such initiatives.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC21488B742C64D9384D5CD3559E18ABA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible Entities</header><paragraph id="H40A236A4A99F4A44B3BBBE5DE3EFCC9A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity under this section is an entity described in paragraph (2) that provides non-directive, comprehensive, medically accurate information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBA1BAE48F0B406987E550C2CAB9B356"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Entities described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), an entity described in this paragraph—</text><subparagraph id="HBD8FBABE2AE64646AB5D42E56484C708"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a community-based organization, voluntary health organization, public health department, community health center, or other interested public or private primary, behavioral, or other health care or social service provider or organization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99A81044151F440AA9C917EED80679CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any crisis pregnancy center or other anti-abortion organization that presents itself as a comprehensive reproductive health care provider but has the intent of discouraging pregnant people from accessing abortion care.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H78D0D78F97DD47459620657D7386CA00"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pregnancy intention screening initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>pregnancy intention screening initiative</term> means any initiative by an eligible entity to routinely screen people with respect to their pregnancy and reproductive health desires and goals to either prevent unintended pregnancies or improve the likelihood of healthy pregnancies, in order to better provide health care that meets the contraceptive or pre-pregnancy needs and goals of such people.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0991535E82D14F108C538AF410E28905"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><paragraph id="H21BC272E85D1473FA72AC478D4279FE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall, by grant or contract, and after consultation as described in paragraph (2), conduct an evaluation of the demonstration program, with respect to pregnancy intention screening initiatives, conducted under this section. Such an evaluation shall include:</text><subparagraph id="H6FC66013C44B4812B973031553FBAC0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessment of the implementation of pregnancy intention screening protocols among a diverse group of patients and providers, including collecting data on the experiences and outcomes for diverse patient populations in a variety of clinical and social service settings.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H995ECCFB851146B1AE3E7E18C6AF21BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Analysis of outcome measures that will facilitate effective and widespread adoption of such protocols by health care providers for inquiring about and responding to pregnancy and reproductive health goals of people with both contraceptive and pre-pregnancy care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DA6FBA8328E4B488F748165E069C2BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Consideration of health disparities among the populations served.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD89B517623A45A8A644A1C238BF1B71"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessment of the equitable and voluntary implementation of such initiatives to Black, Indigenous, and people of color, and other medically underserved communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF44DB7095BE94FCE89F2079DE3436E56"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Assessment of the training, capacity, and ongoing technical assistance needed for providers to effectively implement such pregnancy intention screening protocols.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H078E239A2CBB4076B1FE0E5695A91A48"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessment of whether referral systems for selected protocols follow evidence-based standards that ensure access to comprehensive culturally competent and gender affirming health services and appropriate follow-up care.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27F94D91FB094758A6F279A9BE00B850"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Measuring through rigorous methods the effect of such initiatives on key health outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H019C620E218B4E6E89C709786DD55EE0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost study</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall, by grant or contract, conduct a study assessing the time and cost for providers to administer pregnancy intention screening tools and provide related counseling in a diverse array of settings.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H24BD3B9D08A34711AF60A5B8BD32E64A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation with independent experts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting any evaluation under paragraphs (1) and (2), the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall consult with physicians, physician assistants, advanced practice registered nurses, registered nurses, nurse midwives, behavioral health providers, other health care providers who specialize in reproductive and sexual health, human services providers, and other experts in public health, clinical practice, program evaluation, and research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H751A4722DE8F4562B658E89DD6B3C230"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the last day of the demonstration program under this section, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall submit to Congress a report on the results of the evaluation and study conducted under paragraphs (1) and (2) and shall make the report publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7013A204C994AE8901181ED1F62E108"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="H5A63BAAEE8D14A2D99BB0C4ED2FBD4DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B4ECDEB23AE42BEA92ECB0D584B12E2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Not more than 20 percent of funds appropriated to carry out this section pursuant to paragraph (1) for a fiscal year may be used for purposes of the evaluation under subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

