<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDC828ED186CB404D8D582550B3E50BCD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6897 IH: Preventing Usurpation of Power and Privileges by Extralegal Territories’ Sedition Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6897</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220302">March 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate certain unelected entities claiming to be governments as foreign terrorist organizations, to impose certain measures with respect to countries that support such entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA0D8664DCFCA427FAD741279C7C7C196" style="OLC"><section id="HA558D9658E8A4E0CA8C938B969D7E13E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preventing Usurpation of Power and Privileges by Extralegal Territories’ Sedition Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PUPPETS Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HA13BF71ADCB244E7B8511C42F722E0CD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation as foreign terrorist organizations of unelected entities claiming to be governments</header><subsection id="HB073B279E316404EB12710712095492F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each entity described in subsection (b) is designated as—</text><paragraph id="HFD77072D38BF465A99852F46468941D2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a foreign terrorist organization pursuant to section 219 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1189">8 U.S.C. 1189</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DE114366E4F48DD997A1C3454BCA9C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a specially designated global terrorist organization under Executive Order 13224 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note; relating to blocking property and prohibiting transactions with persons who commit, threaten to commit, or support terrorism), as amended before, on, or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5E539E0749B1477EAAE1A9CBBA081E08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Entities described</header><text>An entity described in this subsection is an entity holding itself out to be the Government of—</text><paragraph id="H8D4EB007D7654F18AC9BEEF278F6E755"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Donetsk People's Republic, the Luhansk People’s Republic, or any other region of Ukraine, that was not elected through the presidential or parliamentary elections in 2019 or local elections in 2020; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCCA2DEE4469347E89BFADFE4721E781C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Pridnestrovian Moldovian Republic;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01BDF280EDF24A85B9008C22AE5976BB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Republic of South Ossetia; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AA01681E06D4302BC4AB5627803C131"><enum>(4)</enum><text> the Republic of Abkhazia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB143257D06244A889F14EF5CD75E8883"><enum>3.</enum><header>Non-recognition of sovereignty by unelected entities claiming to be governments</header><subsection id="H46DABBF7F6984D35BC0DBECFBE98F583"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United states armed forces</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may not take any action, including any movement of aircraft or vessels that implies recognition of the sovereignty of any entity described in section 2(b) over territory or airspace claimed by the Government of Ukraine, Moldova, or Georgia.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB4A0B2CAAAB145E3A260BC4AF2250834"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United states flagged vessels</header><text>No vessel that is issued a certificate of documentation under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/121">chapter 121</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, may take any action that implies recognition of the sovereignty of any entity described in section 2(b) over territory or airspace claimed by the Government of Ukraine, Moldova, or Georgia.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF11C10BFC3044E87BA04681C2EBD3B4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>United states aircraft</header><text>No aircraft operated by an air carrier that holds an air carrier certificate issued under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/411">chapter 411</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, may take any action that implies recognition of the sovereignty of any entity described in section 2(b) over territory or airspace claimed by the Government of Ukraine, Moldova, or Georgia.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2A6511FA1AF244DDA400249F466CAFAE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Measures with respect to countries that support unelected entities claiming to be governments</header><subsection id="HF30D1B13FE234232BC618E836095F9C0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification of countries that assist unelected entities claiming To be governments</header><paragraph id="H3CCA875044984658AA349DAC75B22F70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every 180 days thereafter, the Secretary of State shall submit to Congress a report identifying each country the government of which the Secretary determines, after February 23, 2022—</text><subparagraph id="HD92C0A66CE3D42DBB1371E15F3F94468"><enum>(A)</enum><text> recognizes the sovereignty of an entity described in section 2(b) over territory or airspace claimed by the Government of Ukraine, Moldova, or Georgia; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H90C7BBD41C1C4FF8A306B6CEB1FA3F89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides material assistance or support to such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBA5AC2A87E44A5C9CFCA27BCE081B12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if the Secretary determines it is necessary for the national security interests of the United States to do so.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABBDD99ACDE54FF5ACAAB04A102605F5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall publish the unclassified part of the report required by paragraph (1) on a publicly available website of the Department of State.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E25BCDB9B47449295C5758714CD2410"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on foreign assistance</header><paragraph id="HD6D959A65EBA42E3AAFC8ED2E5904FE2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided by paragraph (2) or (3), no amounts may be obligated or expended to provide foreign assistance to the government of any country identified in a report required by subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99CF9BB8D8FF445FBFB8AB95006761B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>This subsection shall not apply with respect to Ukraine, Taiwan, humanitarian assistance, disaster assistance, emergency food assistance, or the Peace Corps.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA78D742DCDA447019CEA66564D95157D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of paragraph (1) with respect to the government of a country if the President determines that the waiver is in the national interests of the United States. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6E3ECDDED00C470198E7CB6A21E42535"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Designation as state sponsors of terrorism</header><paragraph id="HB6870EA2DF5540938047EE580EAF004F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The government of each country identified in a report required by subsection (a) shall be designated as a state sponsor of terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38AC2A7DE68E43C28F978BC318C3588B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State sponsor of terrorism defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State has determined has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism, for purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="HE88F655298D2433E8DE522166D00F7E6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A)(i) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4813">50 U.S.C. 4813(c)(1)(A)(i)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B0CB36CC2DE48C2B288B7C90D909199"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D3CD5F757F74CB9B15180ADA0B5B89A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40(d) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780(d)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FB8DD2C1CA248818B82C53135B6E60C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HE91A1F8C846C4255B37C19C84CF6FB46"><enum>5.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements of this Act terminate on December 31, 2023. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

