<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4C58A842F4124867A61CA4244C1E4ABB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9581 IH: Short Line Railroad Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9581</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide emergency relief for American short line railroads, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H548B563118F34B97A1E2A070EBF5A0AE" style="OLC"><section id="H86F4DCD6FD0C448EAEDBCE71846BAFE6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Short Line Railroad Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H12703C8B4E2B47389DFC127DFB56AAA8" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Short line railroad emergency relief program</header><subsection id="H7818A455C00A44D088C0CF922B4AC0B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>General authority</header><text>The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration, may make grants or enter into contracts and other agreements (including agreements with departments, agencies, and instrumentalities of the Federal, State, or local government) for capital projects to protect, repair, reconstruct, or replace short line railroad equipment and facilities that the Secretary determines is in danger of suffering catastrophic damage, or has suffered catastrophic damage, as a result of an emergency.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8BA405DEAAAC48E18E47911EE2A7F85F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>In making grants under subsection (a), the Secretary may make grants on a reimbursable basis or advance funding basis.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE525A3137774113B3F7D6FFAFF0CC0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination of emergency funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds appropriated to carry out this section shall be in addition to any other funds available and shall not affect the ability of any other agency of the Government, a State agency, a local governmental entity or organization, or person to provide any other funds otherwise authorized by law, except that no person, business concern, or other entity shall receive assistance with respect to any part of a loss as to which such person, business concern, or other entity has received financial assistance under any other program or from insurance or any other source.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEB77BCC81F0D4C4881A93A9ECA7CA23B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grant requirements</header><paragraph id="H337262719B9940F786A833CC3B100226"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant awarded under this section that is made to address an emergency shall be subject to the terms and conditions the Secretary determines are necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H700E3F21461A47C390BB09E886C626E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight funds</header><text>The Secretary may retain up to one-half of 1 percent of the funds appropriated under this section to fund the costs of project management oversight by the Administrator of the Federal Railroad Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2567B2F366C347DE96E3FBA4D2591CDE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application of law</header><text>The provisions of section 24312 of title 49, United States Code, shall apply to entities receiving a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H216F03AF79764C6C8CDD72EF8EEEAAA6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Government share of costs</header><paragraph id="HC12D37351EE943199BA0A64CF7CC5DCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A grant, contract, or other agreement for a capital project under this section shall be for not more than 80 percent of the project cost, as determined by the Secretary. The non-Federal share of the project cost shall be provided in cash, equipment, or supplies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D2296BEF9294B2EBEA625A4CF59CEAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary may waive, in whole or in part, the non-Federal share.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A9F1068377B4CD9956135E9911062ED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><paragraph id="H30A1ECD833104F38A41809AD61DFF647"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Project costs under this section shall be limited to the scope of damage caused by the respective emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12D36E27F3254F01BCBAF32A9F3E6973"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>In the case of a project that included damage preexisting the respective emergency, the Administrator shall make a determination on the amount or percentage of the damages preexisting such emergency. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D271E70C7C84A71B272D50F4BC8F6AA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section the following definitions shall apply:</text><paragraph id="HFD29C2E6BF464AF0993FFD9005BA617E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Emergency</header><text>The term <quote>emergency</quote> means a natural disaster affecting a wide area (such as a flood, wildfire, hurricane, derecho, tidal wave, earthquake, severe storm, landslide, or avalanche) or a failure due to a disaster as a result of—</text><subparagraph id="H84ADC0871AFB443D906E10C6FA28E13C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>natural causes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DAD40778EFF4520B526E8D57BBA02D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>man-made causes beyond the control of a short line railroad operator, including regulatory restrictions (including those imposed as a result of judicial action) imposed to protect human health or the environment; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA38526A619824C88BF8D1855666B8235"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">undetermined causes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF67EC060D0624430BF05C5D690DEE717"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Short line railroad</header><text>The term <quote>short line railroad</quote> means a Class II railroad or a Class III railroad as such terms are defined by the Surface Transportation Board.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

