<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H62A2D3C031EC498591086CC04F1B98ED" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9556 IH: Financial Services Innovation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9556</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001156">Mr. McHenry</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote innovation in financial services, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94F158536AD248648F730EE6FA60586A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HED1DD43157B24895815DE5C09A88195E" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H67E1E105E96C490A97B72A8F83788BDC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Services Innovation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE803520C744E400AB19484782B5838AB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="yes-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="HED1DD43157B24895815DE5C09A88195E" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H557CEDE3C97A4BBB978DC2A92236E367" level="section">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H188670400DAC46C59EC2D77977886A6A" level="section">Sec. 3. Agency identification of regulatory areas.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3CDC8F067D7F435A8AD5220197D49888" level="section">Sec. 4. Establishment of FSIO at agencies.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H2F2210DEF2474637A045E6B7008DD5DB" level="section">Sec. 5. FSIO Liaison Committee and chair.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBBEB574C49BD4BC2A5CDD2F71093CA8E" level="section">Sec. 6. Petition to agency.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF1FEE4CAAB8D463C940E5A1A582050B2" level="section">Sec. 7. Agency determination of petition.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H452B4A54774D445A90B8524F75960BD8" level="section">Sec. 8. Enforceable compliance agreement.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC60C633B7631463E99133EB7FCCBEDD3" level="section">Sec. 9. Report to Congress.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBD836AB96B7242D29DB4C1DC8E17B9CF" level="section">Sec. 10. Funding.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H557CEDE3C97A4BBB978DC2A92236E367"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <paragraph id="H407AE07E5572415498F2036FB5E34088"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency regulation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency regulation</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H39D8C64D849E482C989F73718002A90C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a rule (as defined in section 551 of title 5, United States Code) issued by an agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H687E1D8CBCE1449ABAAC7A016C86037E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>guidance issued by an agency; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC54B4AFAC08340A2AA35EDB54380BED8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a published proposed or interim rule, policy statement, directive, adjudication, or interpretation of an agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0607B92821374FB1B23DD50EC279C7A7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agency</term> means each of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Commodity Futures Trading Commission, the Department of the Treasury, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the National Credit Union Administration Board, the Office of the Comptroller of the Currency, and the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD83C2195FCE84DBA881CB7C63160E97F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered person</term> means a person that offers or intends to offer a financial innovation by submitting a petition to a Financial Services Innovation Office at one or more agencies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF829CDDE09B747EA9E70FD4E7D57A9EA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Enforceable compliance agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>enforceable compliance agreement</term> means a contractual agreement described under section 8.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B54F9CD4D3B4562BE4493A9AD41AC2E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Financial innovation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>financial innovation</term> means an innovative financial service or product, the delivery of which is enabled by technology, that is or may be subject to an agency regulation or Federal statute.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B6B708334D741BA9E730D4579623AC6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Financial Services Innovation Office or FSIO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Financial Services Innovative Office</term> or <term>FSIO</term> means an office established in an agency pursuant to section 5.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H188670400DAC46C59EC2D77977886A6A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Agency identification of regulatory areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and biannually thereafter, each agency shall publish in the Federal Register a nonexclusive list that identifies 3 or more areas of existing regulation—</text> <paragraph id="HA70B1F8B206B482CA1696F1F2BF76AF1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that apply or may apply to a financial innovation; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85D5A2CEA6154A3C82F5A25C8D46929C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that the agency would consider modifying or waiving if the agency were to receive a petition under section 6 relating to that regulation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3CDC8F067D7F435A8AD5220197D49888"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of FSIO at agencies</header> <subsection id="HBAB29F267B9D4ABE8A2D7EE16FB8604E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency shall establish a Financial Services Innovation Office (known as <quote>FSIO</quote>) to promote financial innovations and to assist a covered person whose petition has been approved under section 7.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCAC0D34ABAFE445DBD9741482C8054F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Director</header><text>Each agency shall appoint an individual to serve as the Director of the agency’s FSIO.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9101A500798C48F0A219124356AC40B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header> <paragraph id="H884F10940A4F42FEA24246F45A016DE1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency, acting through the agency’s FSIO, shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H380AC98260D64734919380C941500C02"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support the development of financial innovations;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C500653020E4138B1B3B4F3195FBE36"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with FSIOs at other agencies to share information and data; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0C5AB66DA85D42EC9AC54C6E806AA758"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establish procedures to reduce the time and cost of offering a financial innovation to the public and enable greater access to financial innovations.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A580C6B4C2A4C1083984E8160ACB811"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties for petitions</header><text>With respect to a covered person whose petition has been approved under section 7, each FSIO shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H472A67D5FEBA48B5BA437F50ADDCB545"><enum>(A)</enum><text>work with the covered person to address issues of how existing regulatory frameworks apply to the financial innovation that is the subject of the petition;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3596701EE2224AD3B8F5CDC95B4544A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assist the covered person in complying with the requirements of Federal regulators of the financial innovation; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFB1170F90FAC4498B6C57120968FB3BB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>assist the covered person in responding to any challenges to a modification or a waiver granted under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H10904BB2DBCD469FB86937BB8495E38A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a covered person whose petition has been approved under section 7, if an agency has a rational basis for doing so and if the agency determines that a provision of a Federal statute under which the agency has rulemaking authority or an agency regulation is unduly burdensome to the covered person, the agency shall, acting through the agency’s FSIO, modify or waive the application of the Federal statute or the agency regulation.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H30E0D744353F4570943A51698F2C6C1B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination of other programs; transfer of authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the establishment of a FSIO at an agency, the agency shall modify any offices or programs at the agency that promote financial innovations or assist covered persons in developing financial innovations to operate within the FSIO. Any legal action or proceeding commenced by or against such office or program of the agency, including no-action letters and staff advisory opinions, shall be transferred to the FSIO of that agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H787472AB01984DB7A5C647457C1213F1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, each agency shall submit a report to Congress and to the Financial Stability Oversight Council, and shall present testimony to Congress, on the activities of the FSIO, including a description of the petitions considered, the rationale for acceptance or rejection of petitions, and the efforts of the FSIO to encourage financial innovations.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H311C5E759B504743925D40EC113FCA81"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>If an agency has not received a petition described in section 6 within 5 years of the date of the establishment of the agency’s FSIO, the agency shall eliminate the FSIO, while continuing to honor any enforceable compliance agreement of another agency.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="H2F2210DEF2474637A045E6B7008DD5DB"><enum>5.</enum><header>FSIO Liaison Committee and chair</header> <subsection id="HE6A6B69C85714D8382A08925108722DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the agencies shall establish a committee to be known as the <quote>FSIO Liaison Committee</quote>.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9C540CD25217472FB3A42A0E0444C930"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The FSIO Liaison Committee shall be composed of the Director of each FSIO office and a State banking supervisor selected by the Conference of State Bank Supervisors (or a successor organization).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC9321DC1A4B343C1A804F956B8FD6D5A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The FSIO Liaison Committee shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB5E7466D47F64B399EE66240A4F019A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult on the administration, coordination, and oversight of each agency’s FSIO;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB11821BC7A0449C9911D68D7C4E5EB15" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>facilitate the cooperation of each FSIO to ensure that agencies share information and data on petitions submitted under section 6;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H759100F2D5934687AA65A49C02A7ECFB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor regulatory proposals and developments related to financial innovations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DF05A38285344F1B7EBA3F9218BDECB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage the application of uniform principles and standards at each FSIO; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86B86AA9F0274257A210841E1D6CDF47"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hold public field hearings 4 times a year to informally provide—</text> <subparagraph id="H0BE462DEA4A945B89A91E5C38A596BEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information and advice to the public and covered persons; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H76FE88E46D504917B1EEFAB48206E89B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a forum to gather information from the public and covered persons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H5F24CD9306324556ADB8706DCEB50639" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The FSIO Liaison Committee shall meet at least twice a year.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H511300039D674F0DA955FC148F0833CD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Chair</header> 
<paragraph id="HEC2B9B5132ED4341B654E3696E28A156"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The first Chair of the FSIO Liaison Committee shall be elected by the members. The Chair shall serve for a term of 2 years and thereafter the chairmanship shall rotate among the members of the committee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H033FEDE1CA5C41459DC7BECCAEC6AB24"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of the Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair is authorized to carry out the internal administration of the FSIO Liaison Committee, including the appointment and supervision of employees and the distribution of tasks among members, employees, and administrative units.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF9130218CD59437098C86DBD51D81499"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Testimony</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Chair of the FSIO Liaison Committee shall present testimony to Congress on the activities of the FSIO Liaison Committee.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H64275D9EB3714A0BB872C90B54E9F764"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="HF36F567B68D049179367E2C309BB6EB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each member of the FSIO Liaison Committee shall serve without additional compensation but shall be entitled to reasonable expenses incurred in carrying out official duties as such a member.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H875FB8F046944F399212EF11A47B9ECA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>General expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The costs and expenses of the FSIO Liaison Committee, including the salaries of employees, shall be split equally between, and paid by, each agency other than an agency that has eliminated the agency’s FSIO pursuant to section 4(g).</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <section id="HBBEB574C49BD4BC2A5CDD2F71093CA8E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Petition to agency</header> <subsection id="H5D756FF51E6549D18FC6A0763AE93971"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered person may submit a petition to an agency, through the agency’s FSIO, in such form and in such manner as the agency’s FSIO may require, to request to enter into an enforceable compliance agreement containing a modification or waiver of an agency regulation or Federal statutory requirement under which the agency has supervisory or rulemaking authority with respect to the covered person or a financial innovation the covered person offers or intends to offer.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C27349FAAD548B387CB13CFB371FF4C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In a petition submitted under this section, the covered person shall—</text> <paragraph id="H838D3F3BF604470AAEC702E45524E400"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit an alternative compliance strategy that proposes a method to comply with the agency regulation or Federal statutory requirement; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0C44A41259A4BDBABEA145A396AB59E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">demonstrate that under the alternative compliance strategy, the financial innovation—</text> <subparagraph id="H261D255FFCCD47D09F3B2B4BE2E04EB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">would serve the public interest;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF7CEA0DC14BB489AB0F4D4DC65BDB202"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improves access to financial products or services; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5E15F996883D4D42920902C5F61EB87E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not present systemic risk to the United States financial system and promotes consumer protection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE3E693C56C744424B897A224C4893E50"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Multiparty petitions</header><text>One or more covered persons that offer or intend to offer similar financial innovations may jointly submit a petition under this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H747EDC4145B24929A769A897B85D52CC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Safe harbor</header> <paragraph id="H9E7CB79F057144848475E232B0D69608"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the period after a covered person submits a petition under this section and before the agency receiving the petition makes a determination on the petition pursuant to section 7, an agency may not take an enforcement action against a covered person relating to the financial innovation that was the subject of the petition.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB514DF0BC0EB430097B9ADF44A226C95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an agency determines that a financial innovation described under paragraph (1) presents an immediate danger to consumers or presents systemic risk to the United States financial system, the agency may apply to a court of competent jurisdiction for injunction to prohibit a covered person from offering such financial innovation during the period described in paragraph (1).</text> </paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF4717400DD9E4C77BBA5C0712D1E7FAD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notice and comment</header> <paragraph id="HCFECCD3FBE584B37AE47341908E7E543"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a petition, the agency that receives the petition shall publish the petition in the Federal Register and provide a 60-day period for public notice and comment.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD4B2968D2D7943AA9A4CFD0D5793667F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for notice and comment period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agency that receives the petition may waive the notice and comment period described in paragraph (1) if such agency determines that the covered person submitting the petition is similarly situated to another covered person that has been granted approval of a petition pursuant to section 7.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4237178F81EC4932A141B32A8A74A45E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agency shall maintain the confidentiality of any nonpublicly available data or information in any petition submitted under this section. The agency shall give reasonable consideration to maintaining the confidentiality of data or information identified by the covered person in the petition submitting under this section as nonpublicly available data or information.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
<section id="HF1FEE4CAAB8D463C940E5A1A582050B2"><enum>7.</enum><header>Agency determination of petition</header> 
<subsection id="HC2B33CD4B2F6451AAC36A340E6545FD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the end of the comment period described under section 6, or if the comment period was waived, not later than 60 days after receipt of a petition under section 6, the head of the agency receiving the petition shall complete a review of the petition and notify the covered person, in writing, of the agency’s determination of the petition.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H56826D0BAC004D66944E9379852C741C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Approval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the covered person submitting the petition shows that it is more likely than not that the covered person meets the requirements for establishing an alternative compliance strategy, the agency shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H538F025ED011451CB5ECE099C4191028"><enum>(1)</enum><text>approve the petition; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F51BD35666341689501505EBF2B7ED5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enter into an enforceable compliance agreement with the covered person in accordance with the requirements of section 8.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H179C88C49B9546BCA2262ABFCB673B5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disapproval</header> 
<paragraph id="HBEC408631BDD4EFEB75F6BD032BB2A24"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Explanation</header><text>If the agency rejects a petition, the agency head shall provide the covered person with a written notice explaining the reason for rejecting the petition, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HE81BA1598CCF42FD8CFD14C6C5D1BE00"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence that the covered person did not satisfy the requirements for establishing an alternative compliance strategy;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F85B87DA86E4826A1D42B55E8F80D56"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of the rules or regulations of the agency applicable to the covered person with respect to the financial innovation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1DC376F0091A40809E37B5592A3C7B85"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of—</text> 
<clause id="HA1A1ECC837934B81A473F43F06E0CEDA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any beneficial effects, including an identification of persons likely to benefit, from rejecting the petition;</text></clause> <clause id="H9590C2A137A242C5948A271C2626A17F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any potential costs, including an identification of persons likely to bear the costs, of rejecting the petition; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7CADC66ED65048359833C4A2596F3324"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the baseline used by the agency to measure the likely economic consequences of rejecting the petition.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H116B2646B8C6446A969C6F1F6449DCF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Resubmittal</header><text>Not later than 90 days after receiving a notice of disapproval, a covered person may revise and resubmit a petition to the agency under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB7E13FFA6A86456DA0111E157BDAB1F9" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Moratorium</header><text>If an agency disapproves a petition submitted in good faith under this section, the agency shall provide the covered person notice and a reasonable amount of time before the agency takes an enforcement action against the covered person relating to the financial innovation that was the subject of the petition.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3007EB0238A84C39A542C60F320B27AE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered person may seek judicial review of an agency’s determination on a petition in accordance with subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H452B4A54774D445A90B8524F75960BD8"><enum>8.</enum><header>Enforceable compliance agreement</header> 
<subsection id="HF0528A1A082846D48A2B476643CC90DC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an agency approves a petition under section 7, the covered person may enter into an enforceable compliance agreement with the agency, which shall include the terms under which the covered person may develop or offer the approved financial innovation to the public and any requirements of the covered person and any agency with respect to the financial innovation.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HC284C8E592DF48B3A74E5AF3859B111A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each agency, by rule, shall establish requirements relating to enforceable compliance agreements that include—</text> 
<paragraph id="HDB74D2E69D5A45C998A199089A049E50"><enum>(1)</enum><text>procedures for modifying the terms of the agreement;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31D3A7AF80854831BCD1C926ED97CCD2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consequences for failure to comply with the terms of the agreement;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F32812C86344D4ABBAED5BE4402A5EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a compliance examination process that—</text> <subparagraph id="HA1EDC7A4C92E41789ED96DE361E81410"><enum>(A)</enum><text>solicits feedback from other agencies on the agreement; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1B8FA154AFB453DA68CF6529CBA366C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>occurs not less frequently than annually;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFEF79F82D35E4462BA93241789C82EBC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a termination date for the agreement that is at least 1 year after the date on which the agreement is entered into;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H05A7DCD5A63C4B81BD93095DA273CBE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>procedures for extending the termination date;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E19D16D7CD64FA8B3E07FF9A9C38CE5"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures for judicial review of another agency’s or State’s challenge to the agreement in accordance with subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, and <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/7">chapter 7</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H23376A8BE47146DC9FFA2A1CDEC49DF0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>procedures for maintaining the confidentiality of any information disclosed to the agency in making the agreement.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0352E819CEA145669A13D16E80B51289"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Multiparty agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a financial innovation that is the subject of an enforceable compliance agreement entered into under this section, an agency that did not enter into such enforceable compliance agreement may join as a party to the enforceable compliance agreement entered into pursuant to this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF47498A2E782445FB7A96C19902E7BA2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on enforcement actions</header> 
<paragraph id="H2E9ECED996F84A09B715A478F430A012"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a covered person and an agency enter into an enforceable compliance agreement—</text> <subparagraph id="H05F6DDECA6FB47D3ACDC5F077398C74A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>another agency may not commence an enforcement action against the covered person with respect to the financial innovation that is the subject of the enforceable compliance agreement; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDBDF713A1A4D4C90A2B39023450853ED"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State may not commence an enforcement action against the covered person with respect to the financial innovation that is the subject of the enforceable compliance agreement, if the covered person provides the State with—</text> <clause id="HFECD533A0DA34AC2B248A34277C4A279"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the enforcement compliance agreement; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD4E374FF6B364C7EB0B85F5E49C6ECFA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a statement of policies and procedures the covered person has in place to comply with State laws that are applicable to the financial innovation.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7E9B89AA0C9441A4AC8005D97AB9CD18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State exception for consumer harm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B), a State may commence an enforcement action against a covered person with respect to a financial innovation that is the subject of an enforceable compliance agreement if, in an action brought by the State in a court of competent jurisdiction, the court determines that the agency’s action was arbitrary and capricious and the financial innovation has substantially harmed consumers within such State.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="HD00B47523153446A8FC150CA0C0AC256" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Arbitration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered person may elect to arbitrate any action initiated by another person relating to a financial innovation that is the subject of the enforceable compliance agreement.</text></subsection> </section> <section id="HC60C633B7631463E99133EB7FCCBEDD3"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Financial Stability Oversight Council shall submit to Congress a report on the aggregate impact of enforceable compliance agreements entered into under this Act, which shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H121A913D760E47CC9DCD03AEDA325110"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and characteristics of the agreements;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7627883E9A5141BC895EEB03775F8472"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the most innovative and least burdensome tools that the agency’s FSIO has implemented for achieving regulatory ends;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE7704BCD6FD6414B9299466D9C084806"><enum>(3)</enum><text>strategies implemented to coordinate and facilitate interagency cooperation among agency FSIOs;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H86E8DC789A784EA4BCB679178F753D05"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the existing Federal and State laws, regulations, or practices (including guidance materials, examinations, and enforcement proceedings and settlements) that the Financial Stability Oversight Council identifies as the most burdensome to innovation in developing or providing financial products and services, that adversely affect competition in the financial services industry, or that restrict improvements for consumers of financial products or services; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H62FE5A88A3D84A469040EF497A5E8FB3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an identification of the overlap or fragmentation of regulation of financial products or services and recommendations for reducing, consolidating, or eliminating such overlap or fragmentation.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HBD836AB96B7242D29DB4C1DC8E17B9CF"><enum>10.</enum><header>Funding</header> <text display-inline="no-display-inline">The costs of carrying out the requirements of this Act (except as specified in section 5(g)) shall be split equally between, and paid by, each agency for fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

