<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2842AA6D3F9B41F0888E8FB5A1793F11" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6610 IH: Border Czar Accountability Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6610</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220204">February 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001126">Mr. Carey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000616">Mr. DesJarlais</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a visit to the United States land border with Mexico and a report thereon by any Cabinet member appointed by the President to lead efforts related to immigration or securing such border, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H58E00D8E68C843778A870A8CE91F1CDC" style="OLC"><section id="H50C638454F664FB580E348AE757D6DF8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Border Czar Accountability Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE1D46094BFCB4842BB32F5D91AD2E7C5" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report relating to visit to United States land border with Mexico</header><subsection id="H0D35B974553C4B588BCAAFC0ECC24774" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any Cabinet member appointed by the President to lead efforts related to immigration or securing the United States land border with Mexico shall visit such border at least once every 60 days.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF2A18E9F11B44EAF991660B8ECEE42E1" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H95A3D0E07D42476CA2CDB2731130AA35"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, any Cabinet member appointed by the President to lead efforts related to immigration or securing the United States land border with Mexico shall submit to the President and Congress a report describing how policy changes that went into effect during the period beginning on or after January 20, 2021, and ending on the date of enactment of this Act, including—</text><subparagraph id="HA8FE4F27A1154AE69440504149539D6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the effect of such policies on agents in the Department of Homeland Security and local law enforcement and government officials in States, units of local governments, Indian tribes, and territories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6DED23EA5BC84C5E9025E2DA27DE588F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the difference in the amount of funds expended in fiscal year 2021 in comparison to fiscal year 2020 to address the unlawful presence of aliens in the United States, including expenditures with respect to border security and education, healthcare, and shelter for aliens unlawfully present in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60CDAE5906F540198CA34BCFBB4A7A25"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether funds have been transferred from any executive department or agency to the Department of Homeland Security for the purpose of supporting efforts to secure the southern border and preventing unlawful entry into the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB49FB4532A64B868D7F2202BA902934"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visit reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 15 days after each visit referred to in subsection (a), any Cabinet member appointed by the President to lead efforts related to immigration or securing the United States land border with Mexico shall submit to the President and Congress a report that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H19E23993DFE34C069327772DD41F3623" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>information relating to any issues either observed or informed of during such visit, including—</text><clause id="HFDE8389749834294BEA55C1B32A9F1DC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a detailed list of the Federal agents and local supporting law enforcement officers the Cabinet member met in person while on location at a facility operated by U.S. Customs and Border Protection, or at a Border Patrol Duty location, at the United States land border with Mexico;</text></clause><clause id="HBDDDBB4C009C4E0880C3A1289F5E4B11"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>trends at the border with respect to demographics and group size that could contribute to overcrowding of U.S. Customs and Border Protection facilities;</text></clause><clause id="HB8B0E28CB1734DD09E904368607C4F67"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the negative impact unlawful immigration has had on farmers and ranchers near the United States land border with Mexico;</text></clause><clause id="HDFDE05B021F14450BC9D55AE9B75099C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of aliens unlawfully present in the United States who are housed in the U.S. Customs and Border Protection facilities, including how the number has changed since the previous report;</text></clause><clause id="H84E67AFA5529459FA9390BE1BCA119ED"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the number and description of illicit drugs, weapons, and other contraband obtained from aliens unlawfully present in the United States by agents of the Department of Homeland Security and local law enforcement officers;</text></clause><clause id="H2DF1CAF020AA4D42B322AE4118D1F72F"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the number of unlawful points of entry from which such aliens entered into the United States, including how the number has changed since the previous report; and</text></clause><clause id="H7385C3173DE2445EBA335D4FD37CA67C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the number of aliens unlawfully present in the United States who are released into the local community without a notice to appear;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C407102B9E446DA6CF2D988F2C0CF5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>suggestions for improvement of the security and situation at such border, including proposals for legislation relating to—</text><clause id="H332C09AE753B477CB12BF9F65A1C75BA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>preventing unlawful immigration;</text></clause><clause id="H4A08FD52975E46F0AF98500C5707DD33" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjusting Federal resources, including staffing and equipment;</text></clause><clause id="HF0C61726F3D745FA96DEA76E65CF2D30" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enhancing interoperability between Federal, State, Tribal, territorial, and local governments;</text></clause><clause id="HD554EC6C6840426DAABBFA7F5B9D0812" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>enhancing the processing of traffic and commerce; </text></clause><clause id="HDE94AAA230B340C0AFAE34D453F99177" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>developing procedures to more effectively seize and dispose of drugs, weapons, or other contraband;</text></clause><clause id="HF7087414F34A4EB8A7B663581C1DAC63"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developing procedures to combat human trafficking; and</text></clause><clause id="HA54BAB7E84404C749452960B8507F4B2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>developing procedures to address any negative impact unlawful immigration has on farmers and ranchers near the United States land border with Mexico; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19BF2FA6DE85445EB724FF7FC5DEFC21" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other information such head determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H52C05C8613354B6F832B13C304FC0619"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal funds may be obligated or expended by any Cabinet member appointed by the President to lead efforts related to immigration or securing the United States land border with Mexico if the report under subsection (b) was not submitted, until such time as the report is delivered.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

