<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF08FABE999C4483985CDC2F483D774BC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8904 IH: To require the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy for further collaborating with allies and partners of the United States regarding access to strategic and critical minerals, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8904</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Defense to develop a strategy for further collaborating with allies and partners of the United States regarding access to strategic and critical minerals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H280D90D0FE48450EB0BD63A41E1A0B4D" style="OLC"><section id="H2AF35244C02E4C56B8EB2FEEE7F6D4B8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Strategy on further collaborating with allies and partners for access to strategic and critical minerals</header><subsection id="HCC700C8636A248BB9FCD4E207EF0EEB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Feasibility briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary of Defense for Acquisition and Sustainment shall brief the appropriate congressional committees on the feasibility of expanding the cooperation of the Department of Defense with the allies and partners of the United States regarding critical minerals, including shared access to sources of such minerals, facilities for processing such minerals, and stockpiles of such minerals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H66D0D3AA40624FF1A3EC29F4AAFB034C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collaboration strategy</header><paragraph id="H0BC0C52905E64C4EA0BCF64217C82B80"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, in line with section 3(b)(iii) of Executive Order 14017 (86 Fed. Reg. 11849; relating to America’s supply chain), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for expanding the collaboration of the Department of Defense with the allies and partners of the United States to strengthen the supply chains for critical minerals and address the risks to such supply chains.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41E6DE5EB1E148E0838DCA65675533F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7FBAA1F1E4CD4A8185F8CBCE1420847F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify key allies and partners of the United States with which the Department of Defense may seek to enter into bilateral and multilateral agreements on access to critical minerals to strengthen defense industrial supply chains;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBDF25DD11E14DBD8246944115CF2B70"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prioritize strategic and critical minerals that are essential for national defense and of which such allies and partners maintain large stocks;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDB8F1A4D1814486ABEF18FED1CA2CE5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess opportunities for regional and multilateral agreements regarding access to strategic and critical minerals, including prioritizing mining, processing, and refining of strategic and critical minerals for national defense purposes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BE2761348964CF0B982054A7A9B8E74"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review the authorities under which the Department of Defense may enter into strategic and critical mineral sharing agreements; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H798A3045B4D04679BA8A41AEF5DC27DA"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide recommendations for adjustments to existing authorities to facilitate strategic and critical mineral sharing agreements with such allies and partners.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFEEAAFCC53452DABBC1652ECC370E1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collaboration agreement requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The agreements described in subparagraphs (A) and (C) of paragraph (2) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2A76B072D84B4C1D9070A21A554C08E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify the terms of potential bilateral and multilateral agreements, including processes for information sharing during peacetime and mechanisms for expediting the sharing of strategic and critical minerals during crisis and conflict scenarios; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9B91E5E34DD4A87B91D8E26A47A5864"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in a crisis or conflict scenario, prioritize the access of the domestic defense industrial base to strategic and critical materials.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77FD5E9DCD8D465C823995C5413EBB88"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section may be construed as authorizing the Secretary of Defense to transfer or otherwise dispose of any strategic and critical mineral contained in the National Defense Stockpile that is necessary for the defense industrial base.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA998C4746A03457D99CE34C44C69FC63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H957CA27C415A48D69E8597DF1703E5EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEDAF795E982439CB8A98D1DD85F5930"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Strategic and critical minerals</header><text>The term <term>strategic and critical minerals</term> means any mineral, element, substance, or material designated as critical by the Secretary of the Interior under section 7002(c) of the Energy Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/30/1606">30 U.S.C. 1606(c)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

