<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H8C770EBC1ED6478A9B3D8A5B36D2B6FA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 441 EH: Don Young Alaska Native Health Care Land Transfers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 441</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To provide for the conveyance of certain property to the Tanana Tribal Council located in Tanana, Alaska, the conveyance of certain property to the Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium located in Sitka, Alaska, and the conveyance of certain property to the Alaska Native Tribal Health Consortium located in Anchorage, Alaska, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H5C748D9781314864A64EDB4359FF3D70" style="OLC"><pagebreak/>
<section id="H3B8BF691F0CB48B4843621341F46F1D1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Don Young Alaska Native Health Care Land Transfers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H58C25FC0D79946E982EB937A731C1872"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H6520D249CB1C4586AA413517F4B9225A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consortia</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Consortia</term> means the Alaska Native Tribal Health Consortium and Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5A352EA824C46B4922323E2B7E64983"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the Tanana Tribal Council located in Tanana, Alaska.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA88F1CBEE07F49AD9CA29AB43EBBFAA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H3B1B6D802EDF4CF092AE88ADE7EF40AE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Conveyances of property</header> <subsection id="H505E2CECCE2249B1B688EA2D7BB41215"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance of property to the Tanana Tribal Council</header> <paragraph id="H2F0E989076BD45CCB93DDEF7BE50490C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 180 days, after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey to the Council all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in paragraph (2) for use in connection with health and social services programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F4DA552BF084ABCB55B846DCA60088C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property described</header><text>The property referred to in paragraph (1), including all land, improvements, and appurtenances, described in this paragraph is the property included in U.S. Survey No. 5958 in the village of Tanana, Alaska, within surveyed lot 12, T. 4 N., R. 22 W., Fairbanks Meridian, Alaska, containing approximately 11.25 acres.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF468894D9AA442A8AED2443D7B35ED07"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conveyance of property to the Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium</header> <paragraph id="H275EAB1F9DA040F181963C7AA842E830"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 2 years, after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey to the Southeast Alaska Regional Health Consortium located in Sitka, Alaska, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in paragraph (2) for use in connection with health and social services programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60B364F757644BDAAEE5666E59774990"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property described</header><text>The property referred to in paragraph (1), including all land and appurtenances, described in this paragraph is the property included in U.S. Survey 1496, lots 4 and 7, partially surveyed T. 55 S., R. 63 E., Copper River Meridian, containing approximately 10.87 acres in Sitka, Alaska.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H62000A711AA04E17B366761DBA8AA4AF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conveyance of property to the Alaska native tribal health consortium</header> <paragraph id="H397A6BDC31844169A732D20A83C3B789"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As soon as practicable, but not later than 1 year, after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall convey to the Alaska Native Tribal Health Consortium located in Anchorage, Alaska, all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to the property described in paragraph (2) for use in connection with health programs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4A6301565BF54F12857DEAB5F65F7F73"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Property described</header><text>The property referred to in paragraph (1), including all land, improvements, and appurtenances, is the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H4F996B6D9BA94E7BB9CB02B4396BAE89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Lot 1A in Block 31A, East Addition, Anchorage Townsite, United States Survey No. 408, Plat No. 96–117, recorded on November 22, 1996, in the Anchorage Recording District.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB66B8F36ABBB4E2EA8338FDC7787CF0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Block 32C, East Addition, Anchorage Townsite, United States Survey No. 408, Plat No. 96–118, recorded on November 22, 1996, in the Anchorage Recording District.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H38929787847447ED842C456742FDB1D6"><enum>4.</enum><header>Conditions of the conveyance of the properties</header> <subsection id="HFEB8EDDADD1347BE9A598525D217E881"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text>The conveyance of the properties under section 3—</text> 
<paragraph id="H34CB4B63B1594F69A86BE25C3241009E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be made by warranty deed; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H137D51147C404AC6B425BF08699EACB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall not—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E4F40B348AE478FB7472EDA499E9E42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>require any consideration from the Consortia or the Council for the property;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE358F2E78FF54EE79A779357C6B60B33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">impose any obligation, term, or condition on the Consortia or the Council regarding the property; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA3F714512AC44198AE02CE343144DA8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>allow for any reversionary interest of the United States in the property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H387B40967D17498398E08896C491F46B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effect on any quitclaim deed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The conveyance by the Secretary of title by warranty deed under subsection (a)(1) shall, on the effective date of the conveyance, supersede and render of no future effect any quitclaim deed to the properties described in section 3 executed by the Secretary and the Consortia or the Council.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HCFFB11867E634154A585FE7F67FBB476"><enum>5.</enum><header>Environmental liability</header> 
<subsection id="H00CBD5C90C6941DA99AB03A0F99D3B63"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Liability</header> 
<paragraph id="HEFB6736B8A914B218601D0F5A0ECBC07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, neither the Consortia nor the Council shall be liable for any soil, surface water, groundwater, or other contamination resulting from the disposal, release, or presence of any environmental contamination on any portion of the property described in section 3 that occurred on or before the date on which the Consortia or the Council controlled, occupied, and used the properties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF594DFE698A4FA296D3D8FCA8656DF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Environmental contamination</header><text>An environmental contamination described in paragraph (1) includes any oil or petroleum products, hazardous substances, hazardous materials, hazardous waste, pollutants, toxic substances, solid waste, or any other environmental contamination or hazard as defined in any Federal or State of Alaska law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6DD76F8B476E41329B90C6A1F15CE0ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Easement</header><text>The Secretary shall be accorded any easement or access to the property conveyed under this Act as may be reasonably necessary to satisfy any retained obligation or liability of the Secretary.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H79B91B19573540BA931CEA18584BED04"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice of hazardous substance activity and warranty</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall comply with section 120(h) of the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF13FDE3909FD4013966CB6799E310F80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on applicability</header><text>The provisions in this section apply only to the property conveyances specifically required by this Act. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220426" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 26, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

