<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HECE84043568148D696D2934B21372A09" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7280 IH: Prison to Proprietorship Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7280</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220329">March 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Small Business Act to provide re-entry entrepreneurship counseling and training services for incarcerated individuals, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F01B0BCDEAA4C82A53FC58EAEA855FE" style="OLC"><section id="HBBAE00008C1245F0BEC547CD0F5BB1EE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prison to Proprietorship Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDE05D31F3A4143FBA3E75EF6C05B95F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Re-entry entrepreneurship counseling and training for incarcerated individuals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE12A49C29B9845089B4B868CB1D3C558"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 49 as section 50; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB97FC3D178841B2AA2A0312942D01D1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 48 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H206F67D7BE0F4053B7282F195A5B476E"><section id="HE292914262504E128946A44969BFE5A4"><enum>49.</enum><header>Re-entry entrepreneurship counseling and training for incarcerated individuals</header><subsection id="HD950A893795549F9A10BA163FC6DEB26"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Services required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator, in coordination with the Director of the Bureau of Prisons, shall require women’s business centers and small business development centers identified under the plan described in subsection (b) to provide entrepreneurship counseling and training services to covered individuals.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9AB4D5680C204DF5BCF48E86CDA15B47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Plan</header><paragraph id="HDED9B32482844B35B6906905D0B75C6F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="H243B19C159B249A8B155355F0A6D788C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a plan, which shall be updated annually, to match women’s business centers and small business development centers with covered individuals in Federal prisons who are eligible to receive services under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D3944C1A95A46E1AB4C98B50E7AB8CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>seek to consult with both an association formed to pursue matters of common concern to women’s business centers and an association of small business development centers formed pursuant to section 21(a)(3)(A) to develop and update such plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H185B28B559C744569CC13EF8F0715457"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matching</header><text>In determining matches under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall prioritize matching the women’s business center or small business development center in closest proximity to the applicable Federal prison to provide such services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51714A89F7D64EDBA5A48750587FF4FE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Association responsibilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the women’s business center or small business development center identified under the plan in paragraph (1) is unable to provide such services to covered individuals in such Federal prison, another women’s business center or small business development center, an association of women’s business centers, or an association of small business development centers shall provide such services in accordance with the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D34A29A8E2C4D7FBB2958C76A4FF5A3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goal of the services provided under this section is to provide covered individuals with the following:</text><paragraph id="H073A16EE13264BBC85F7E729F61FBA6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assistance and in-depth training on how to start or expand a small business concern.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47D407975D9F4661A891A8D4E696ECF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tools, skills, and knowledge necessary to identify a business opportunity, including how to—</text><subparagraph id="H2797620D5D5246A2B3A31F0EEA64EF08"><enum>(A)</enum><text>draft a resume, business plan, and transition plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H122D575843D5447EA2CC33F220220AA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify sources of capital; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9C61FD4755548B2913F4CBFD5A0D87F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>connect with local resources for small business concerns.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1366996496A5492CBA51FCEC6D083F32"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The services provided under this section shall include—</text><paragraph id="HC13B4D7824E542CEBE57B8A0A3491D73"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a presentation providing exposure to the opportunities involved in self-employment and ownership of a small business concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB9823200B6149118D2A2C936C98ED4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a self-study course manual focused on the basic skills of entrepreneurship, financial literacy, the language of business, and the considerations and life skills relevant to self-employment and ownership of a small business concern;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H781FA2A66E674F71A4A1CC8A32966BC7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">five two-day sessions of in-depth classroom instruction introducing the foundations of self-employment and ownership of small business concerns, including guided discussions to explore personal entrepreneurial development interests;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF7390F9380443B9916938DF3F71D892"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in-depth training delivered through one-on-one mentorship, including individual support in the development of a business plan, entrepreneurial skills, and strategies for starting up a small business concern; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AB9474AD9074AAAB37DE66D63265DBC" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon completion of the counseling and training, a presentation of a certificate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H96D91E8FAECA4AFA8D65AA81F0C4B59D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall, to the extent practicable, ensure that women’s business centers and small business development centers prioritize providing entrepreneurship counseling and training services to covered individuals who will be released from Federal custody not later than 18 months after the date on which such a covered individual begins to receive such services.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9822024799041F7943D56F204B40345" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Continuation of services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered individual receiving services under this section may continue to receive such services after release from Federal custody.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E18F7AA08F946E6B5E43C10DCBBE0B4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Administrator may, subject to appropriation, award a grant to an association formed to pursue matters of common concern to women’s business centers or small business development centers to coordinate the services described under this section, including to develop curriculum, train mentors and instructors, and establish public-private partnerships to support covered individuals and identify opportunities to access capital.</text></subsection><subsection id="H50AC75EF61CB45ACB7C7A9C43952F0CE"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Curriculum</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administration shall print and make available to women’s business centers, small business development centers, an association of women’s business centers, or an association of small business development centers any curriculum or course materials developed pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H058AC6BA153E465E8B07710651501D3C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each women’s business center or small business development center that provided services under this section shall survey covered individuals who received such services to assess the satisfaction of such covered individuals with such services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7E9D52A81E884149A799592C8B8164C6"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate a report on the performance and effectiveness of the services provided under this section, which may be included as part of another report submitted to such committees by the Administrator, and which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H64AD3184D0EE470CA9594EC8A0C80CCB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered individuals counseled or trained under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E285A4EF9DA47E5B18E072A4095A847"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of hours of counseling provided by each women’s business center and each small business development center under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8DC2C58385E489A8311EEB82BE47BF0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of certificates presented under subsection (d)(5);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H346406AAE37B4B87BB4FB657E86A5EC6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the demographics of covered individuals who received services, including age, gender, race, and ethnicity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB5549F1718A4E3CA2360F4E64B5659E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the level of understanding of business concepts of covered individuals upon completion of the counseling and training described under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H599B62D88CC94DE5AA3F26256CFA79CF"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary and analysis of surveys conducted under subsection (i); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F24EF22F60145DBBB7D96903EF86E89"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any additional information the Administrator may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3EF1ED51BF85456C991FBED57A4538CA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Covered individual defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered individual</term> means an individual incarcerated in a Federal prison that the Director of the Bureau of Prisons has designated as a minimum, low, or medium security prison.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEA02259A1A2A4240830988FD8659CEE1"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the availability of appropriations, the Administrator shall reimburse women’s business centers, small business development centers, an association of women’s business centers, or an association of small business development centers for the costs relating to the services provided under the section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

