<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H374934F0263D4ED493011D3E27A20319" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 7727 IH: Accountability in Student Loan Data Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7727</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220511">May 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require that institutions of higher education maintain certain adjusted cohort default rates to participate in programs under title IV of such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6FFAB468E8C408F930541F0A948D1E2" style="OLC"><section commented="no" id="H92161E18B1974AAE87AA982DF72CBB10" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Accountability in Student Loan Data Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6CDBA8D383F24963B802485BF0B44FF8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Progress period status</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H02611B451DFB443EB96924B45BD8AE77"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (14) through (24) as paragraphs (15) through (25), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BD33969BF0648BD9E84FDA566988F62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (13) the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1F0A8B4DEA664C24B9110FFA1879C234" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H20B6BAB360E44A9CA3642DEC0788B863"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Progress period status</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>progress period status</term> means the status of an institution of higher education that is determined by the Secretary to be in danger of failing to meet title IV eligibility criteria relating to student debt because the institution has an adjusted cohort default rate of not less than 10 percent and not more than 15 percent.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HCB73841A3C15498DB46AB023E478B7C5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Consumer information</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 132 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015a">20 U.S.C. 1015a</external-xref>) is amended in subsection (i)(1)(T), by striking <quote>rate,</quote> and inserting <quote>rate and adjusted cohort default rate,</quote>.</text></section><section id="H3877F2A4175B43CB90FFEA91896610B4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal Pell Grants</header><subsection id="H8AE829F9B77A49BC8D295FD92E539BA0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Higher Education Act</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401(j) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a(j)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1B58246E8EC24249B4DFE1DACA09BC32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, or if such institution of higher education is subject to an ineligibility determination under section 435(a)(9)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC5228C387BC440888E24A6D7FA9B5E3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, final adjusted cohort default rate, or on-time repayment rate,</quote> before <quote>determination</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1386233FC7084854B9375D30CE6D2EE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FAFSA Simplification Act</header><paragraph id="H9198556FEB354BF0B79341E602633482"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401(j) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a">20 U.S.C. 1070a(j)</external-xref>), as amended by section 703 of the FAFSA Simplification Act (title VII of division FF of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>), is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H19D1BC2581F54095A6431A5B358DE8BE" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>, or if such institution of higher education is subject to an ineligibility determination under section 435(a)(9)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83AE62787CCD48D2966D763FB75B702F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by inserting <quote>, final adjusted cohort default rate, or on-time repayment rate,</quote> before <quote>determination</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB53CB89B898431C8E601C3E768297E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by <internal-xref idref="H9198556FEB354BF0B79341E602633482" legis-path="4.(b)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> shall take effect as if included in section 703 of the FAFSA Simplification Act (title VII of division FF of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/260">Public Law 116–260</external-xref>) on the date of enactment of such Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9DCEE39943124203AF8FDC24F6BC4067"><enum>5.</enum><header>Disbursement of student loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 428G of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-7">20 U.S.C. 1078–7(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H29C3D27A06B9476A945620E6307D76AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H76C75012D6BB4CC2AB9F2D2790A6D1A7" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2EB9FB6E7EE146A8A3E9562935A69C5F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Adjusted cohort default rate</header><text>Beginning on the date on which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published by the Secretary for not less than 3 fiscal years under section 435(m), an institution whose adjusted cohort default rate (as determined under section 435(m)) for each of the 3 most recent fiscal years for which data are available is less than 5 percent may disburse any loan made, insured, or guaranteed under this part in a single installment for any period of enrollment that is not more than 1 semester, 1 trimester, 1 quarter, or 4 months.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H62E4C47718EB473BA7D87E177A2181A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by inserting before the period the following: <quote>or, beginning on the date on which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published by the Secretary for fiscal year 2021 under section 435(m), an adjusted cohort default rate (as determined under section 435(m)) of less than 2 percent</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7481CEE908DB4A11BEF72993E697B351"><enum>6.</enum><header>Cohort default rates</header><subsection id="HE19FDF7E06B04E41A5A2139DB84BFFEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ineligibility based on high default rates</header><paragraph id="H782909CE6B194A29A6DB20C50F20E3D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 435(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HA5936C0B59B74474BB0867FAFE0857B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (7)(A), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF61FF0127F104CEF85ED66DEA86D92D2" style="OLC"><clause id="H4572E070BE654A4AB5FFF5C9BB2CD3BE"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Default management plan</header><text>The default management plan required under clause (i) may not include placing students in forbearance as a means of reducing the cohort default rate or the adjusted cohort default rate of the institution.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H474665E5F4204D0094AEEB84F6077CBB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA22A87595909488794D402A8C4C6E671" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF68F3D5C60454E27BFBD32EF3E808347"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Ineligibility based on high adjusted cohort default rates</header><subparagraph id="HEEDFF1B059904C26B683C11D44DCC333"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraphs (B) and (D), beginning on the date that is one year after the date on which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published by the Secretary for not less than 3 fiscal years, in a case in which one of the following determinations is made with respect to an institution, such institution shall be ineligible to participate in a program under this title for the fiscal year for which the determination is made and for the two succeeding fiscal years:</text><clause id="HBF5AD4ACB8A54EBDBCFBBB0A81C0D8F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The institution’s adjusted cohort default rate is greater than 20 percent for each of the three most recent fiscal years for which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published.</text></clause><clause id="H921500A1D7244ECC8E8F2883C5F95500"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the six most recent fiscal years for which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published—</text><subclause id="H4C178A30C8B0447C8C84E7ED0F59B3E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the institution’s adjusted cohort default rate is greater than 15 percent for each such fiscal year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H53D8E65FA6684C38976A3E13E89A326F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Secretary determines that, during such 6-year period, the institution has not made adequate progress in meeting standards for student achievement established by the relevant accrediting agency or association pursuant to section 496(a)(5)(A).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBE94542E80D94B019A190A9A6D1DC478"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the eight most recent fiscal years for which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published—</text><subclause id="H6F58FF18E2EF4CE4AFF58D0A2BB98CC3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the institution’s adjusted cohort default rate is greater than 10 percent for each such fiscal year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3DA46030AAB6487E9D644BD83C6E7656"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary determines that, during such 8-year period, the institution has not made adequate progress in meeting standards for student achievement established by the relevant accrediting agency or association pursuant to section 496(a)(5)(A).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H439337E0AB724ACA9DAFF1E989A4FDCF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exceptions for certain categories of educational programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an institution that loses eligibility to participate in a program under this title in accordance with subparagraph (A)(ii), such institution may request and be granted an exception to such loss of eligibility for a category of educational programs at such institution by demonstrating to the Secretary that the adjusted cohort default rate for the category of educational programs is 15 percent or less for each fiscal year of the 6-year period on which such loss of eligibility for the institution is based.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83C284C179C04BB1ACA4A504F5894166"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of the adjusted cohort rate for a category of educational programs</header><text>In determining the adjusted cohort default rate for a category of educational programs for purposes of this paragraph—</text><clause id="HD5A43E5F6DAC4995B2319F86C595BF9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subsection (m) shall be applied—</text><subclause id="H7DEC782AE191413B874B34C3D9BF4A10"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><item id="HCAF7FA558BA944609B5AA73D44EF69E5"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by substituting <quote>received for enrollment in the category of educational programs for which such rate is being determined</quote> for <quote>received for attendance at the institution</quote>; and</text></item><item id="H9EAF9310BFA546CCBFC6B85868CE71BC"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E)(i)(II), by substituting, <quote>percentage of students enrolled in the category of educational programs for which such rate is being determined</quote> for <quote>percentage of students enrolled at the institution</quote>; and</text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H616672DEF74F46198933D39B9BA9F3B3"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as if the following were added at the end of paragraph (2):</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3BFE3363502D4068AF52EB998B6F6042" style="OLC"><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8B4BB4309C03482D9B6E6E93D636FE41"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a student who has received a loan for enrollment in more than one category of educational programs, the student (and such student’s subsequent repayment or default) is attributed to the last category of educational programs in which such student was enrolled.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE01DA3B085B5420DA1360CBB052C1379"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Transition exception</header><clause id="HEA560E683D6D4AF78F3CE2D01538E5E3"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered institution with an adjusted cohort default rate that is greater than 20 percent for the first fiscal year for which such rates are published by the Secretary may request that any determination of such covered institution’s ineligibility under subparagraph (A) not be based on the adjusted cohort default rate of such covered institution for any or all of the first 3 fiscal years for which such rates are published by the Secretary.</text></clause><clause id="HF901D43656184F39BEB77F16A9194698"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>To be granted a request under clause (i), a covered institution shall submit to the Secretary a default management plan as specified in paragraph (7).</text></clause><clause id="H4A526954F2F6423BA492D9D1646BBA8E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Definition of covered institution</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>covered institution</term> means—</text><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4735FD143230449A9E2A9A14B903A96C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a public institution of higher education;</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1AE0383CF1684537B09A68C7EFC93BEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a part B institution (as defined in section 322); or</text></subclause><subclause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAF82063069A44F2FAA96AFFA7429F248"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a private, nonprofit institution of higher education at which not less than 45 percent of the total student enrollment consists of low-income students (as such term is defined in section 419N(b)(7)).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2AA3CCBE07AC4D3F825D35E63318205B"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Category of educational programs defined</header><text>The term <term>category of educational programs</term>, when used with respect to an institution, means one of the following:</text><clause id="H7E7481334CEB4857A8ABC01012A0FEB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The educational programs at the institution leading to an undergraduate, non-degree credential.</text></clause><clause id="HEC595A8E2BBF48CFA9230BDEBB933B25"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The educational programs at the institution leading to an associate’s degree.</text></clause><clause id="H2EB96CF1835249F3867AEFC9B77EE3EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The educational programs at the institution leading to a bachelor’s degree.</text></clause><clause id="HA8AA376533704C2B9E38FF1AE7AF9117"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The educational programs at the institution leading to a graduate, non-degree credential.</text></clause><clause id="HE65FCB278E3D4D6F948975C66BC41693"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The educational program at the institution leading to a graduate degree.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E7C76041FE7443B8FF35F338EABF091"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Application of adjusted cohort default rate</header><text>Beginning on the date on which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published by the Secretary for not less than 3 fiscal years—</text><subparagraph id="H14477F060E9848EF977B886B0AD53AE6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>paragraph (1) shall be applied by substituting <quote>paragraph (9)</quote> for <quote>paragraph (2)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D059CDA1CE14C45BD8C858564F6BB25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>paragraph (3) shall be applied by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate, calculated in accordance with subsection (m)(1)(D), is greater than 20 percent for any 3 consecutive fiscal years</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate, calculated in accordance with subsection (m), is equal to or greater than the threshold percentage specified in paragraph (2)(B)(iv) for any two consecutive fiscal years</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H770AAB4235C648B680B14DED1AB44D6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>paragraph (4) shall be applied—</text><clause commented="no" id="HA38A2ABE70684E708ED33224AE763820"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate is greater than 15 percent</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate equals or exceeds 20 percent</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HFDCF2A39A2CC42E8A2824F52F6BC3C19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the matter following subparagraph (C), by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate to reflect the percentage of defaulted loans in the representative sample that are required to be excluded pursuant to subsection (m)(1)(B)</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate to reflect the percentage of defaulted loans in the representative sample that are required to be excluded pursuant to subsection (m)(1)(B)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28FE2D9BB9604D938EE85C3B214E609A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>paragraph (5)(A) shall be applied by substituting <quote>paragraph (9)</quote> for <quote>paragraph (2)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H321333693C934AB8A01341B26E335155"><enum>(E)</enum><text>paragraph (7) shall be applied—</text><clause id="HBFDD034BA5B54017AEC4D78D0E11ED1B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(i)—</text><subclause id="H37FE7AA8990C4AD9B98FCC049689DD80"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I), by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate is greater than 20 percent</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate is equal to or greater than the threshold percentage specified in paragraph (2)(B)(iv)</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H3B1DFB96364B4087A147FC77D5768690"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclauses (I) and (II), by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H9AEE655A542640E988EB7E617097873D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(i), by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate is greater than 20 percent</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate is equal to or greater than the threshold percentage specified in paragraph (2)(B)(iv)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H121A92F04A3D4265B50FB5CEA44D3D02"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>Section 435(a)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HEFE40446A29147C4A9849AA676060CA1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading, by adding at the end the following: <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">before fiscal year 2021</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H270AC275CEDE43359FEAC8BF5F9828F7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(iv), by striking <quote>and any succeeding fiscal year</quote> and inserting <quote>through fiscal year 2020</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A4A899418264EAFA65FFA68FEB0532E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Adjusted cohort default rate defined</header><text>Section 435(m)(1) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(m)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB50CB329224644DE8CDB469DD8C17613" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HC6759CAA1A174538836523DB04C5B80D" indent="up1"><enum>(D)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAA77DF7E6FF74C16A9327162EE8F4AF5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>With respect to a cohort default rate calculated for an institution under this paragraph for fiscal year 2021 and for each succeeding fiscal year, such cohort default rate shall be adjusted as follows:</text><subclause id="H6676C9D13AD14E27ADAAD5EA6A8A1750" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>In determining the number of current and former students at an institution who enter repayment for such fiscal year—</text><item id="HCF2BE9F5CB4A4247A58D62CD15F1643C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>any such student who is in nonmandatory forbearance for such fiscal year for a period of greater than 18 months but less than 36 months shall not be counted as entering repayment for such fiscal year;</text></item><item id="H11D88A584C194C1CB8B5099C817DC98E"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>such a student shall be counted as entering repayment for the first fiscal year for which the student ceases to be in a period of forbearance and otherwise meets the requirements for being in repayment; and</text></item><item id="H61D79C40BD964A7DB5A64905D89F23D7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>any such student who is in a period of forbearance for three or more years shall be counted as in default and included in the institution’s total number of students in default.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H5E17938103D347C8A8C675D28B16341F" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Such rate shall be multiplied by the percentage of students enrolled at the institution for such fiscal year who are borrowing a loan under part D of this title.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HBCA8A50168A74C1BA37E6DDAF2A93B2D" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The result obtained under this subparagraph for an institution shall be referred to in this Act as the <quote>adjusted cohort default rate</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0BAFA43F745447B28805CBA58341AABF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Publication of adjusted cohort default rate</header><text>Section 435(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1085">20 U.S.C. 1085(m)</external-xref>) is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE37EAA8095F0455C94F425F574F3F665" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H070D2D175EE8463D9D4B48BB61337AE6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Beginning on the date on which the final adjusted cohort default rates for fiscal year 2021 are made available for publication by the Secretary, paragraph (4) shall be applied by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default</quote> for <quote>cohort default</quote> each place it appears.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H7D7EE9C9281D4E758A8A977AC309DE29"><enum>7.</enum><header>Adjusted cohort default rate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 487(a)(14) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE5060941ADA5421C94B1011362AEB0CF" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HF49CBBB741CB40CFA74911FE40119743"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Beginning on the date on which the final adjusted cohort default rates are published by the Secretary for fiscal year 2021 under section 435(m), subparagraph (C) shall be applied by substituting <quote>adjusted cohort default rate in excess of 5 percent</quote> for <quote>cohort default rate in excess of 10 percent</quote> each place it appears.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE8C1B2A4336D46F898F9802913AA5038"><enum>8.</enum><header>Program review and data</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 498A of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099c-1">20 U.S.C. 1099c–1</external-xref>) is amended in subsection (a)(2), by striking subparagraph (A) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6DA06466777249CDB3F91197C1F7C3DC" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H7C8F49722BEA4D0FB8FE5C9F68BA75F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutions with an adjusted cohort default rate for loans under part D of this title in excess of 18 percent or which places such institutions in the highest 25 percent of such institutions;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H11120FA276714447BBA6F641205968D0"><enum>9.</enum><header>Assistance to progress period institutions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part H of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099a">20 U.S.C. 1099a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7E48D632708A496FB0EF00179B2306F7"><section id="HFA1459CEC57E48B7886E65B8C1C1B7A3"><enum>498C.</enum><header>Assistance to progress period institutions</header><subsection id="H545B4587F41747C89980D70F03A8A26E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall provide grants and technical assistance to covered progress period institutions in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD94054B1D13A4840B843481080E71EDE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorized activities</header><text>Grants and assistance provided under this section shall be used to improve student achievement (as described in section 496(a)(5)(A)) at covered progress period institutions.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC43849FFDA334E44871E59887E3842DF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants and assistance may be provided under this section for a period of not less than one year and not more than three years.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFED8029513EC41DABE21B5E1BFAF84FA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions</header><paragraph id="HD32320FEEB2F433DA75F28C0120EC85F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Benchmarks</header><subparagraph id="HB4BE5606D3A3444485A759641D834C7C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To continue to receive support under this section after the first year in which such support is provided, an institution must show progress, as determined by the Secretary, toward meeting the standards for student achievement established by the relevant accrediting agency or association pursuant to section 496(a)(5)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3919B6B736084B48B3E6FA614E9DE009"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining the progress of an institution under subparagraph (A), the Secretary may take into consideration extenuating circumstances that may have contributed to the poor performance of the institution in the first year of the review period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD46E341D3C4713B8FED9703B086CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deadline for compliance</header><text>An institution that does not achieve an adjusted cohort default rate of less than 10 percent after receiving support under this section for three consecutive years shall be ineligible to receive further support under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71586F1370044EC3A01B5495424B296A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>An institution shall be ineligible to receive further support under this section if, while the institution was receiving such support, the total enrollment of low-income students (as such term is defined in section 419N(b)(7)) at the institution decreased by 10 percent or more.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H322FA1DC5488498B9169837A2D6A9504"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Covered progress period institution</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered progress period institution</term> means—</text><paragraph id="H1F08E62DBE5A412B940928233F5963F4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a public institution of higher education that is determined to be in progress period status;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59D7204F26724E4986FFC0DF7E8062B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a part B institution (as defined in section 322) that is determined to be in progress period status; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B3845ADF1D144D49755BA380C3C2785"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a private, nonprofit institution of higher education—</text><subparagraph id="HB564992F50324F3C8E78CF40B64F9729"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is determined to be in progress period status; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6CF54F1D57A4C948963158BA2CB7478"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at which not less than 45 percent of the total student enrollment consists of low-income students (as such term is defined in section 419N(b)(7)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB61413EC6509452881D279661CC2C605"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HACE33975AA864B5FB69519F7082D5089"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are appropriated such funds as the Secretary, using the formula described in paragraph (2), determines necessary to meet the needs of all eligible institutions under this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB85691D7BDC7497A8A1DDB55B4228356"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary shall establish through negotiated rulemaking a formula to determine the—</text><subparagraph id="HE344D31918A04950B924BBFF3D67D547"><enum>(A)</enum><text>proportional amount of institutional need under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF3BEB42DF448659DCA7C86BAA2DD2F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>total amount of institutional need under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9EA6FC0DB3642C6AAF3306FE26EA90F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text>Such formula must at minimum take into consideration the severity of the problem, size of the institution, institutional resources, historical underfunding, and the number of low-income students (as such term is defined in section 419N(b)(7)) being served.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

