<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD6DF7DDACD78418ABF8C472E5E610D2A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6594 IH: Protecting Federal Agencies and Employees from Political Interference Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6594</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require that the headquarters for any entity of the Federal Government located in the National Capital region shall remain in the National Capital region unless relocation legislation is enacted, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17B06F14AAE540478B58D0DC826AF58F" style="OLC"><section id="H7B88BD196C2344BD93F4DE26A546655F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Federal Agencies and Employees from Political Interference Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H55A1C7AEB7AB4ED6A7007DA3AE7B8ED9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Agency and department headquarters located in the National Capital region</header><subsection id="H871A35EB158F486B94A44E2559962B35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Headquarters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The headquarters for any entity of the Federal Government located in the National Capital region on the date of introduction in the House of Representatives of this Act shall remain in the National Capital region unless legislation is enacted into law approving or otherwise providing for relocation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H35F6B548F518494C9B3E35EDFBBA1937"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee Stations</header><text>Any employee position with a duty station in the National Capital region on the date of introduction in the House of Representatives of this Act shall remain stationed in the National Capital region unless legislation is enacted into law approving or otherwise providing for relocation.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

