<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0584DEFA7E164A0E9337DA4759712333" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8075 IH: Internet Freedom Rapid Response Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8075</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Open Technology Fund of the United States Agency for Global Media to make grants to surge and sustain support for internet freedom technologies to counter acute escalations in censorship in closed countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F575F8930A74CCBBF584C808991D05F" style="OLC"><section id="HE376FA2477D849FDA31F0964BAAF18FF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Internet Freedom Rapid Response Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H94504BC9604B43C38955BC6D608D67E8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Open Technology Fund grants</header><subsection id="HCC9D4F39A5C84835884FBEDA8FDE4AF4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to grants made to the Open Technology Fund of the United States Agency for Global Media pursuant to section 305 of the United States International Broadcasting Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6204">22 U.S.C. 6204</external-xref>) to make grants for the purposes specified in section 309A of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/6208a">22 U.S.C. 6208a</external-xref>), the Open Technology Fund may make grants to eligible entities to surge and sustain support for internet freedom technologies to counter acute escalations in censorship in closed countries.</text></subsection><subsection id="H33824506DB9645B5BEC19197A93D0CCA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Methodology</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants under this section shall be made competitively, and shall be subject to audits by the Open Technology Fund to ensure that technologies described in subsection (a) are secure and have not been compromised in a manner detrimental to the interests of the United States or to individuals or organizations benefitting from programs supported by such grants.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3339DD78E2314372B022BABD3E305294"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Open Technology Fund shall annually submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Appropriations, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate a report on grants made and activities carried out pursuant to such grants during the immediately preceding fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3371AE845C9545B58B23DF5B999BE779"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H66CE356DFFBC48C9AA6130DE4334D9F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $5,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026 to carry out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14CDF2F13215450F969916A6FC512380"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to this subsection are authorized to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H631EC140454043779D03B7FE9CACFF33"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H03152BE6EF1344B5A7A93F0065F8553E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Closed countries</header><text>The term <quote>closed countries</quote> means countries in which democratic participation, free expression, freedom of movement, or access to information is suppressed or explicitly prohibited through political, judicial, social, or technical means, or as otherwise determined by the Secretary of State, the Chief Executive Officer for the United States Agency for Global Media, or the President of the Open Technology Fund.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA2E43E6E830443A87415FB3B530D010"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>eligible entities</quote> means public or private sector entities with proven and already-deployed technology relating to surging and sustaining support for internet freedom technologies to counter acute escalations in censorship in closed countries.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

