<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H216788C21D884B24BEC41B272BBF48FD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9563 IH: To direct the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration to provide its firm electric service customers with credits from shortfalls in generation from certain Bureau of Reclamation hydroelectric facilities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9563</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration to provide its firm electric service customers with credits from shortfalls in generation from certain Bureau of Reclamation hydroelectric facilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6D9FB41D42E04023AACB0E774477072A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HD5995DCDC25C4B0E89923338769EC34B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Hydropower drought mitigation</header> 
<subsection id="H79ED0C98F0CB43CD9E0FA7BF0C228DB9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification of power available</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall notify existing firm electric service customers of certain Bureau of Reclamation Projects of the amount of energy expected to be available for delivery during the 12-month period after such notification, based on the Bureau of Reclamation’s most recent 24-month study that is issued each month, from the following:</text> <paragraph id="H9EABCBEC8D954AB1BD8D3396D1FA4C58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Salt Lake City Area Integrated Projects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H14BD327B16BA494098DAE980BDA5935E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Boulder Canyon Project.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63A7BE93417949588616BBCA4A915C43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Parker-Davis Project.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9B7F33815A824BDBA1AA5D0538B91D0E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pro rata reduction</header> 
<paragraph id="HBA63998DC2DB4C2994DF54EB48D14AD1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Salt lake city area integrated projects</header><text>If the annual amount of energy from the Salt Lake City Area Integrated Projects is expected to be less than 4,900,000 MWh, the Administrator shall apply a pro rata credit from the general fund of the Treasury for each firm electric service customer of the Salt Lake City Area Integrated Projects on each monthly invoice for firm electric service until such time as the energy production returns to levels equal to or greater than 4,900,000 MWh.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B8AB386C0D44299B518B14AE0219F62"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Boulder canyon project</header><text>If the annual amount of energy from the Boulder Canyon Project is expected to be less than 3,600,000 MWh, the Administrator shall apply a pro rata credit from the general fund of the Treasury for each firm electric service customer of the Boulder Canyon Project on each monthly invoice for firm electric service until such time as the energy production returns to levels equal to or greater than 3,600,000 MWh.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H976D789FA786419F993BFC89C1F836FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parker-davis project</header><text>If the annual amount of energy from the Parker-Davis Project is expected to be less than 1,400,000 MWh, the Administrator shall apply a pro rata credit from the general fund of the Treasury for each firm electric service customer of the Parker-Davis Project on each monthly invoice for firm electric service until such time as the energy production returns to levels equal to or greater than 1,400,000 MWh.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HAA69E3894D27472AA9C7C87C1D462D1E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Credit composition</header> <paragraph id="H92D61C69D14042A48A669F8F40021386"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of calculating a pro rata credit required under subsection (b), the Administrator shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE0549830C64F4CDA95FFD084D9981127"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determine costs for each Project set forth in invoices for firm electric service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6DA226DF9FAD41CAA92CE6289D138EE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>calculate a credit based on levels set forth under subsection (b) as compared to the available energy anticipated in the notice set forth under subsection (a); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0259F8B9DEA1413C8DD3CB38D3917ABE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>apply such credit to each firm electric service customer’s monthly firm electric service invoice total to reflect decreased hydropower output.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA08CEADF1F2488E90D3285C2728C2E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other obligations</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall preempt obligations of the Administrator to set rates to recover such costs unrelated to hydropower production as may be required by law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE7B33A5F3AEB490599F4C1BB500FB1E5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs nonreimbursable</header><text>Any costs incurred by the United States in carrying out the requirements of this section shall be nonreimbursable and nonreturnable to the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H959C2C86B280416EAEAF296C33440444"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No retroactive rates</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Administrator shall not recover credits provided pursuant to this section in future rates.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8302EE5FFEC746D0ABEEA06AF9BE8709"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this section shall—</text> <paragraph id="H959C90FEB71B4FC1BA5EACE577F9B2C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>alter or affect any water rights held by—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEA1A7125629D4ADD9520C8B8D761D799"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the United States;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB947FF3B40E34782967F9891271A2C6C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any Indian Tribe, band, or community;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H86591D500D4B4AE383D59BC276CE382B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any State or political subdivision of a State; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCD6639397814422893C546D8426AB947"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any person;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CEE7501183D4AE38288C7F54CF91E08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be construed or interpreted as authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to change or otherwise modify existing operations at Bureau of Reclamation facilities in the Colorado River basin; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8104F893AADD43D6A43AD231ED2800EA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be construed or interpreted to authorize a change in the existing terms of the Second Memorandum of Agreement Concerning the Upper Colorado River Basin Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2AC5AB0E9CCE4ED4868FFB5DD4347AA1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Administrator defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Western Area Power Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7E2ABF6AC8334412885D4520AAE9D04C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>All authorities provided under this section shall terminate on December 31, 2026.</text></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

