<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7D99582BF243453E82737E33708AC94B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9279 IH: Strengthening the Force and Fleet Through Enlisted Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9279</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221107">November 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize more enlisted members of the Armed Forces to attend the Naval Postgraduate School.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8D5B868F47494D78B8A0553D14BEE528" style="OLC"><section id="H0455E9303E7145609853AACB0ECFD940" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthening the Force and Fleet Through Enlisted Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Smart Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2AC842A199B84C6DB36306190AFCAB03"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that:</text><paragraph id="HB19FD10DC66F4E9F9342A29C37EBE118"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The demands of the future operating environment need to be met by the most professional, intelligent, innovative, and capable servicemembers our Nation has ever produced.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB55DBFF2FF174B5983B0AA420AE83C66"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Though officers comprise roughly 18 percent of the Armed Forces, they receive significantly higher investments into their education up to the PhD level than that of their enlisted counterparts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCED5E1B62762491E9522547B27223157"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Investing in enlisted advanced education will strengthen the lethality of the Armed Forces by producing higher quantities of noncommissioned officers able to operate through the intellectual demands of complex contingencies, producing military leaders at rates higher than is otherwise feasible with the pool of eligible officers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ECACFDB2D09459EA39694DF91E635C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Conducting research and analysis on the impact of advanced education on enlisted servicemembers performance, promotion rate, misconduct, and retention is critical to propelling the Department of Defense’s initiatives for a modern, state-of-the art approach to education and research to create and sustain an intellectual overmatch in today’s warfighting domains.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50EB7DFC7AE247438B65B50A4C6720A8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Naval Postgraduate School serves as a converging point for all branches of the United States military while simultaneously offering innovative learning environments that, combined, offers an ideal testing ground to evaluate the potential benefits of expanding enlisted higher education across the Joint Force.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HED6BA4C8B5AB4FD8A46855E6FF1F2CB4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Naval Postgraduate School: attendance by enlisted members</header><subsection id="HDFE4260B236740538C8B3A0B2512DC38"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a)(2)(D)(iii) of section 8545 of title 10, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>only on a space-available basis</quote> and inserting <quote>at a rate of acceptance not to be conditioned by the number of officer applications</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCAD1166122464DC6B3DF3F87695E84F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Six years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall brief the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives on the effects of increasing enrollment of enlisted members at the Naval Postgraduate School pursuant to the amendment made by subsection (a). Such briefing shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H5EE74C533E384988BDFEE29A4CB331E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any increase to the lethality of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD479A6B056C14498BC07CAE2110F6A6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Effects on rates of recruitment, promotion (including compensation to members), and retention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB50C3695AA81408E9A9FA1FD558C7DAE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Effects on malign behavior by members of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

