<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H856EC0A3B01048B3A1B1377AA3290427" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8097 IH: Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8097</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 51, United States Code, to direct the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to establish an initiative to conduct research, development, and demonstration on technologies capable of reducing both greenhouse gas emissions and noise emissions from aircraft, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H644E5B7766A4412BBE669F7E5BC8F498" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1D6A725F49914BD8803B9C873EF64D7B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cleaner, Quieter Airplanes Act</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H99C96FC0E3924C59A77F1C212774B74B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H462E2B3A28F64E6C89CE31E04734C982"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Air travel currently contributes approximately 3 percent to global carbon emissions, but emissions from this sector are expected to triple by 2050.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3186234EED98404188C74E20DE8E955F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A healthy, thriving aviation sector contributes to the quality of life and economic well-being of the United States. In 2016, the Federal Aviation Administration found that civil aviation accounted for 5.2 percent of the United States gross domestic product, generated $1.8 trillion, and supported 10,900,000 jobs.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3904594792C3472598F4513CB6EE5726"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Existing aircraft technologies contribute to noise pollution that has adverse impacts on the quality of life in affected communities. As air traffic volumes increase and the adoption of performance-based navigation technology proceeds, the problem of noise pollution is becoming more severe in some areas.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17C2B2702FE344AA932B6507C0D8DAAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The United States has adopted a goal of net-zero greenhouse gas emissions from the United States aviation sector by 2050.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58E92B43D8C8431EAE014FE4EC2CE6C3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Research on technologies to lessen the environmental and noise impacts of aviation is ongoing, but should accelerate, and should include work on the further maturation and integration of multiple enabling technologies on production aircraft, including novel integrated systems at the aircraft level.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HCB04C0530C434E93AF073312E08B636E"><enum>3.</enum><header>National Aeronautics and Space Administration Initiative on Reduction of Greenhouse Gas and Noise Emissions from Aircraft</header> <subsection id="H2C8A8B1DD55443928B27369CF7DDB6E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initiative required</header><text>Section 40112 of title 51, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5BB36B9C48F94862AF54E63C5777A000"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) through (f) as subsections (c) through (g), respectively; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H61241484D388404EAF5E1F65F40A3CB3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H983726BAD4A04813AC106F6D8E829F9E" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H51CFEEA02496432F977E87345A77D687"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research and development initiative on reduction of greenhouse gas and noise emissions from aircraft</header> 
<paragraph id="H1AB6439A85554846A7F7B2BAD91DBC13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall establish an initiative to research, develop, and demonstrate new technologies and concepts for the purposes of reducing greenhouse gas emissions from aviation, including carbon dioxide, (CO2), nitrogen oxides (NOx), other greenhouse gases, water vapor, black carbon and sulfate aerosols, increased cloudiness due to contrail formation, noise emissions from aircraft, and to enable associated aircraft performance characteristics.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D57DF3BAD9C427A925C49377BB9C25B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Goals</header><text>The goals of the initiative shall be to—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H982B45EBCA50462385DF7C894CF240FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure United States leadership in research and technology innovation leading to substantial reductions in aviation noise and greenhouse gas emissions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73AF036FC00D4F6AA4AEAE7B834F31C7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhance and expand basic research, and the translation of basic research into applications, that may lead to transformational advances in reducing aviation noise and greenhouse gas emissions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82F90EDBE3064098A33577FE1060593D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>accelerate research and development that contributes to maturing new technologies for reducing aircraft noise and greenhouse gas emissions; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C73B1D9FC6D4321898445197EFDB978"><enum>(D)</enum><text>obtain and disseminate associated testing and performance data that facilitates the incorporation of new technologies into commercial aircraft development as soon as practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB461A0CD19FF45E5B0292B2D8FBA9D1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Objectives</header><text>The objectives of the initiative and goals in paragraph (1) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H2499A49E2FF747D292204F8197D16BB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as soon as practicable, a reduction of greenhouse gas emissions from new aircraft by at least 50 percent compared to the highest-performing aircraft technologies in service as of December 31, 2021;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19CBEE3B48A24BA7AA0602A39356A090"><enum>(B)</enum><text>noise levels from aircraft throughout all phases of flight that do not exceed ambient noise levels in the absence of flight operations in the vicinity of the flight route;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD899485FE125490F92B50CB74C2B4527"><enum>(C)</enum><text>net-zero greenhouse gas emissions from aircraft by 2050; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H168BBE9D92B44F4C995802D080F8B525"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrating new technologies developed pursuant to the initiative established under paragraph (1) on regional aircraft intended to enter into service by 2030 and single-aisle aircraft designed to accommodate more than 125 passengers intended to enter into service by 2040.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HB83757185F9440089A39F5766B8D63D1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technology focus areas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the research and development initiative established under subsection (b) of section 40112 of title 51, United States Code, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall advance research, development, and demonstration projects on promising technologies such as—</text> 
<paragraph id="HF92034E1AC68458FA18AFA1536A79493"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advanced subsonic propulsion technology, design, and integration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4F1CE571565B490FAEC0B1495A44505C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>electric and hybrid-electric propulsion, including battery electric and hydrogen fuel cell electric systems;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAAF7AE00873542DF9B5BC9895E087A26"><enum>(3)</enum><text>airframe concepts and configurations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2EDF61B0480D4062B1CB1BAED7C0370C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>analysis of technology options, including cost-benefit analysis of greenhouse gas and noise emissions reduction technologies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H96BB1A2ED1724F369A0C2A654A790ECB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>analytical tools for system- and system-of-systems-level modeling and integration;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC894CCAB6F2A48CE9E765EB49A1046A0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>airspace operations improvements;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B38197AF41F4011BF845BFFB6F63FEE"><enum>(7)</enum><text>noise emission reduction; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD342F63F66024418AC0C0B0B9DD1F5DB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>other efforts, as determined by the Administration, that contribute to a sustainable future for aviation.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0DB407687D554B2EA023CB49D4A3AEB6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In implementing the initiative established under subsection (b) of section 40112 of title 51, United States Code, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall, to the extent practicable—</text> <paragraph id="H7A8CC0C2652847EE859F73855ACE1D92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that testing and performance data integrates the results of community acceptance surveys conducted by the Federal Aviation Administration and other relevant studies, including studies on the impacts of new noise effects from novel propulsion systems and from airspace operations changes;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5B0C6D149CC44CF4AFA7916685E66FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide testing and performance data on the technologies described in subsection (b) to the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to facilitate the work of the Federal Aviation Administration in identifying new requirements for policy, infrastructure, and administrative capacity necessary to enable the safe integration of such technologies on aircraft;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFD07B6F0F6824991A7099CEC23CAC772"><enum>(3)</enum><text>pursue partnerships with organizations, current commercial production aircraft providers, academic institutions, small businesses and new entrants, including partnerships to advance research and development activities related to both regional aircraft and aircraft designed to accommodate more than 125 passengers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7E3D3F2CE7A419EAA27B15C850EE210"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include universities, academic institutions, and other research organizations in the partnerships under paragraph (3);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA07237C417704442840CC0E5795BD620"><enum>(5)</enum><text>expand basic research;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H63CC675B37FF4EC7B8CC47323773922B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>ensure equity in research sponsorship and partnership opportunities with underrepresented students, faculty, and minority-serving-institutions;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H474B5514893A4C778C12B0930580B7F1"><enum>(7)</enum><text>continue to coordinate with the Department of Energy on battery technology research;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA379291596B546E88243A5D6DE13FDD0"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">make available the research and development carried out under the initiative established under subsection (b) of section 40112 of title 51, United States Code, to help enable an industry-wide shift toward aircraft concepts that reduce greenhouse gas emissions and aircraft noise to achieve the goals and objectives under paragraphs (2) and (3) of such subsection; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H68D018AD59E24179A2549B3E8AA0FDC6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>continue to support research, development, and demonstration of aircraft concepts, including systems architecture, materials and components, integration of systems and airframe structures, human factors, airspace planning and operations, and the integration of related advanced technologies and concepts, with the goal of carrying out test flights with integrated subsystems by 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H846EC890E9314819A12555863D7800DD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration shall submit a report to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate on the progress of the work under the initiative established under subsection (b) of section 40112 of title 51, United States Code, including—</text> <paragraph id="H97EE7CBE2ECD46E08A31BDB0FE1DBAA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the status of progress on the initiative under such subsection;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H68EAEF70B218444891EE3F4DC98306CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an updated, anticipated timeframe for readiness of technologies and aircraft to be adopted by industry with the emissions reduction levels directed under such subsection; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB8C04B9F773E47C3ADBE530BFA8A84C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of fundamental aeronautics research activities contributing to achieving the initiative under such subsection, as well as a description of any obstacles to achieving such goals and objectives under paragraphs (2) and (3) of such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

