<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31C9644CDD084A4998348F80BF294349" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9400 IH: Assessing Health Evaluations to Advance Decision-making Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9400</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221201">December 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a study by the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine on the potential benefits on population health outcomes of incorporating into the Federal legislative process tools that measure the impacts of proposed legislation (including in areas outside of health care) on health and health disparities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H243E3A0A242C43A19580F423CCD174DB" style="OLC"><section id="H8C6BD7C04BC94C149173E2A5D4889D91" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Assessing Health Evaluations to Advance Decision-making Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AHEAD Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H02E2EFC59B064B13961916A8B83F0DDB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study to assess the value of using tools to measure the impacts of proposed Federal legislation on health and health disparities</header><subsection id="H0AD0808289154D05AA9976A0F220272C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall enter into an arrangement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (referred to in this section as the <quote>National Academies</quote>) (or, if the National Academies decline to enter into such arrangement, with another appropriate entity such as the National Academy of Public Administration) under which the National Academies (or other appropriate entity) will complete a study to—</text><paragraph id="HDE604985F9844F71BA39959D958A050C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>examine the potential benefits on population health outcomes of incorporating into the Federal legislative process tools that measure the impacts of proposed legislation (including in areas outside of health care) on health and health disparities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H900316FC35AA466AB910DA0812EF773C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>formulate recommendations on integrating such tools into the Federal legislative process to achieve better population health outcomes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE603BDC9AEF94B3492A8C0DC357BD03B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>formulate recommendations on how behavioral and nudge research on the effects of health disparities may translate into evaluative tools for policymakers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD19A2EF91F9C4DC5B2075FCD1A16660C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>consider, with input from the Comptroller General of the United States, the Director of the Congressional Budget Office, and the Director of the Congressional Research Service, how such tools could be incorporated into the Federal legislative process.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3953DE99C29A4FB38BFFCD6DA1C8384B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tools To be considered</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The tools considered under the study under subsection (a) shall include health impact assessments, and may include any other tools of analysis, particularly such tools related to impacts on health and health disparities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9769227C432E489DBCC529F04DEED11A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specific populations To be considered</header><text>The study under subsection (a) shall consider the impacts described in such subsection on health and health disparities within specific populations, including racial and ethnic minority groups (as defined in section 1707(g) of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300u-6">42 U.S.C. 300u–6(g)</external-xref>)), youth, women, older adults, sexual and gender minorities, individuals living in rural communities, individuals living in rural Tribal or urban Indian communities, individuals living in regions with persistent poverty, individuals with co-morbid conditions, individuals with disabilities, individuals who are homeless, and individuals involved with the criminal justice system, among others.</text></subsection><subsection id="H02FECB08BD304CA097497F2B9199A24A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional and regulatory process options</header><text>The study under subsection (a) shall consider how assessments of potential population health outcomes could be incorporated into Federal legislative and regulatory processes, including by evaluating options with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HEE37284B2A1D4C2EBDB02301084D46B0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>methodological tools for evaluating evidentiary standards across multiple disciplines and the potential benefits and negative effects of a proposed policy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA2FB32220684786B40C5041F9E3A954"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the processes and considerations for preparing a population health outcomes report, including time, resources, community consultation, and competencies required to review relevant scientific literature;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29E99132206645BB85B637DBEED6DBFC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>entities that conduct population health outcomes reports by comparing the experiences of State and local jurisdictions that have incorporated health impacts assessments in legislative or regulatory processes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H41EFC704C5244822A9A1E1FC38D37FD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>potential uses of a population health outcomes report in the Federal legislative and regulatory processes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H030721538D2E497692A3BE3030E93A7B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The arrangement under subsection (a) shall provide for the submission of a report on the results of the study under such subsection, not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, to the Secretary, the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

