<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9271CD61FB347958468CD0BD0D4CDB7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7566 IH: Stop Human Trafficking in School Zones Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7566</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220425">April 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 18, United States Code, to increase the punishment for human trafficking in a school zone, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H08E72ED90DA84A0594C13399DCB6F6EA" style="OLC"><section id="HC0B7878D26C14E688D117E7BC898F416" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Human Trafficking in School Zones Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF0653AD455074D1DA993CEE5186CA0C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph id="H3E0E018E887649C3A28B259B659B9A2A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Child sex trafficking can have devastating immediate and long-term consequences, including health impacts, psychological and physical trauma, and even death.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EFED002DD0D4FC28AA1E42E39E94034"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While any child can be targeted by a trafficker, research, data, survivors’ lived experiences, and expertise have revealed that traffickers often target vulnerable youth who lack strong support networks, supervision, care, or basic necessities, have low self-esteem, have experienced violence in the past, are experiencing homelessness, are experiencing academic difficulties, or are marginalized by society, and lure them into forced labor and prostitution and other forms of sexual exploitation. Traffickers are masters of manipulation and prey upon vulnerabilities using psychological pressure, intimidation, and drugs to control and sexually exploit the child for their benefit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44FF3D7D123844FA8D11C8B0974F6DE0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The National Center for Missing and Exploited Children (NCMEC) has received reports of child sex trafficking in all 50 States, the District of Columbia, and Puerto Rico. These reports include incidents occurring in every type of community, including suburban, rural, urban, and Tribal lands. In 2021, NCMEC received more than 17,200 reports of possible child sex trafficking.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB29ED9231BF34C8DA002AF5B4B0BA7A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Of 22,326 trafficking victims and survivors identified through contacts with the National Human Trafficking Hotline in 2019, at least 5,359 were under age 18.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0443FCB9EF04FC5BEAA2C140C1F1FE3"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Many underage victims of sex trafficking are students in the United States school system. No community, school, socioeconomic group, or student demographic is immune.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80AA3569BC5E4EB9808C43C29F1C2542"><enum>(6)</enum><text>While the internet and social media make up the majority of first encounters, traffickers regularly find young people in shopping malls, through friends, at bus stops, and at schools. Specifically, traffickers systematically target vulnerable children and youth by frequenting locations where young people congregate, including schools. They also use peers or classmates, who befriend the target and slowly groom them for the trafficker by bringing the young person along to parties and other activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFC742B4C80B4AC9B53F641C09C9E461"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A 2018 survey reported that 55 percent of young sex trafficking survivors in Texas were trafficked while at school or school activities and 60 percent of trafficked adults say they were first groomed and solicited for trafficking on school campuses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H714848E199594318AC304B49311A9A3C"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Schools can and should be safe havens for students. Schools are best positioned to identify and report suspected trafficking and connect affected students to critical services. Students are more likely to report instances of sex trafficking, attempted sex trafficking, or grooming for the purposes of sex trafficking where they feel most safe from harm and threats.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFAD1DAC04C644BA1B42F6D80BACA0179"><enum>3.</enum><header>Increased punishment for human trafficking in school zones</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1591 of title 18, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H46D3D08C34E4408DAA89F97C3C9C60A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (e) as subsection (f); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H650A2C70CD4348289BAD5EE1D820798B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (d) the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE1F11F32083F4B189648C429165BF390" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8491D3A559F243F788F6AEA9C591F6EF"><enum>(e)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H8BC2519B2DA94E8185F8961437B63E34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Whoever violates subsection (a) in a school zone (as such term is defined in section 921), or on, or within 1,000 feet of, a premises on which a school-sponsored activity is taking place, shall, in addition the punishment otherwise provided under this section, be imprisoned for not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E6B276F1ED4D938F9D434E6E32FD52" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <quote>school-sponsored activity</quote> means any activity that is produced, financed, arranged, supervised or coordinated by a school, district personnel, or State or local educational agency or is under the jurisdiction of a State or local educational agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

