<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE086A3D16D214E7BBD615B24750B169E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6873 IH: Bombing Prevention Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6873</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220228">February 28, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish the Office for Bombing Prevention to address terrorist explosive threats, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H15E6A33902704B5390E539D7FFB54FE3" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1E267E7FCC06492BB493A6F175D89FCE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bombing Prevention Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEED94DEA21FF45DDA1D316D577ED95AC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Office for Bombing Prevention</header> <subsection id="HA75AEBBE20E749CA90C67C4F54A19EC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/651">6 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subtitle:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H509044D98B194C259668B73D6D249B08" style="OLC"> 
<subtitle id="HD84F3AE65306456995D8DF87455B0D2C"><enum>D</enum><header>Bombing Prevention</header></subtitle> 
<section id="HFF54FB2626994A539F56CADE8FE2CD11"><enum>2241.</enum><header>Office for Bombing Prevention</header> 
<subsection id="H1842E221D7904E779B004C277A5827F0" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Department an Office for Bombing Prevention (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H565A3CB6DB944784BB1AAE46F9955A1F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The Office shall have the primary responsibility within the Department for enhancing the ability and coordinating the efforts of the United States to deter, detect, prevent, protect against, mitigate, and respond to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States, including by carrying out the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H33C7354DAA7F4A23A4FA65DD326E6F23" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Advising the Secretary on matters related to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FDA1400B4D942CEAB90FF21D54190A3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coordinating the efforts of the Department to counter terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States, including by carrying out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H54999F7C2966467097E0D04EA32B0F48" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Strategy, Policy, and Plans, the Department’s strategy against terrorist explosives threats and attacks, including efforts to support the security and preparedness of critical infrastructure and the public sector and private sector.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBE629A99C9364ED4871DD208E21865A9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Leading the prioritization of the Department’s efforts against terrorist explosive threats and attacks, including preparedness and operational requirements.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDE846F4EBAC5483182B838C28D0AAB01" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Ensuring, in coordination with the Under Secretary for Science and Technology and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, the identification, evaluation, and availability of effective technology applications through field pilot testing and acquisition of such technology applications by the public sector to deter, detect, prevent, protect against, mitigate, and respond to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FE16F1D3D854D2F990369C2B8DE937A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Providing advice and recommendations to the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency regarding the effective use of grants authorized under section 2002.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45584027951E4CF08612E88AA1502DCE" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In coordination with the Assistant Secretary for Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction, aligning Department efforts related to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States and weapons of mass destruction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0AE9094297414D99A86D62EEB96A5762" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engaging other Federal departments and agencies, including Sector Risk Management Agencies, regarding terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H373608AD826F4BDA86C07A0C82D38C85" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilitating information sharing and decision support of the public and private sector involved in deterrence, detection, prevention, protection against, mitigation of, and response to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States. Such sharing and support may include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H1AD00209B8894ED2BDE4E07A0773B007"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Operating and maintaining a secure information sharing system that allows the sharing of critical information and data relating to terrorist explosive attack tactics, techniques, procedures, and security capabilities, including information and data described in paragraph (6) and section 2242.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBEAEFA12E354463FBCC75580B4ADE6B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Working with international partners, in coordination with the Office for International Affairs of the Department, to develop and share effective practices to deter, prevent, detect, protect against, mitigate, and respond to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAC4E2D7DF43545268E04946CC37AB17D" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promoting security awareness among the public and private sector and the general public regarding the risks posed by the misuse of explosive precursor chemicals and other bomb-making materials.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCBB2AEDDBC1E4F249FD28ABF3B953D90" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Providing training, guidance, assessments, and planning assistance to the public and private sector, as appropriate, to help counter the risk of terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA7C6F095D39B4E75BDB819EC9A52AD64" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting analysis and planning for the capabilities and requirements necessary for the public and private sector, as appropriate, to deter, detect, prevent, protect against, mitigate, and respond to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States by carrying out the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEE725D0955D24B9993DB371EB734AA44" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Maintaining a database on capabilities and requirements, including capabilities and requirements of public safety bomb squads, explosive detection canine teams, special tactics teams, public safety dive teams, and recipients of services described in section 2242.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F69BCFF5A8E497EB6F7764813DC5AB3" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Applying the analysis derived from the database described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the following:</text> 
<clause id="HAC50D3783D76461D9842EE9D68A3540A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Evaluating progress toward closing identified gaps relating to national strategic goals and standards related to deterring, detecting, preventing, protecting against, mitigating, and responding to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></clause> <clause id="H3F07F8F2078F4BF6B4B89953A01CEE6B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Informing decisions relating to homeland security policy, assistance, training, research, development efforts, testing and evaluation, and related requirements regarding deterring, detecting, preventing, protecting against, mitigating, and responding to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFDF4DEF1A6FF4D8DA2370C0612948E86"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Promoting secure information sharing of sensitive material and promoting security awareness, including by carrying out the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAB3038A1F55F43CA93D1D1E1EA7D227F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Operating and maintaining a secure information sharing system that allows the sharing among and between the public and private sector of critical information relating to explosive attack tactics, techniques, and procedures.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCE6B19E38D2445748D437EBAD647F36E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Educating the public and private sectors about explosive precursor chemicals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98022FCE91294D96A1695039FB65A689" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Working with international partners, in coordination with the Office for International Affairs of the Department, to develop and share effective practices to deter, detect, prevent, protect against, mitigate, and respond to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H33C2283908A64FC282E5AB4405F3DF15" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executing national public awareness and vigilance campaigns relating to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States, preventing explosive attacks, and activities and measures underway to safeguard the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA96DE73B285544B6B9CA62F269382ABE"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Working with relevant stakeholder organizations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC27AF63059DA4A76897E685B172B9064"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Providing any other assistance the Secretary determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HD5A4DF4055B14456801663460533C90C"><enum>2242.</enum><header>Countering explosive devices technical assistance</header> <subsection id="H4EA63AAE5D6B4E3090F744C61653C67F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon request, the Secretary shall, to the extent practicable, provide to the public and private sector technical assistance services to support the security and preparedness of such sectors, as appropriate, to counter terrorist explosive threats and attacks that pose a risk in certain jurisdictions, including vulnerable and disadvantaged communities, to critical infrastructure facilities, or to special events, as appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C0A060B1E004AC69F7A191EC7AE4078"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Technical assistance services provided pursuant to subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H97E6CB99D468432B8979591CCD6E75DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support the planning and implementation of effective measures to deter, detect, prevent, protect against, mitigate, and respond to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States, including effective strategic risk management and emergency operations plans;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD1727036A2734B69BA89934AEA32E00D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support the security of explosive precursor chemicals and other bomb-making materials outside of regulatory control;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC64320E193774A8C97A8FFF61EC1CAA1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support efforts to prepare for and respond to bomb threats or other acts involving the malicious conveyance of false information concerning terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26CF5F0437D747F385A0FE59283C1498"><enum>(4)</enum><text>make available resources to enhance deterrence, prevention, detection, protection, mitigation, and response capabilities for terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States, including coordination and communication, to better integrate State, local, Tribal, and territorial and private sector capabilities and assets, as appropriate, with Federal operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B6D8E3493D548098558C185FCC88B7E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>make available augmenting resources, as appropriate, to enable State, local, Tribal, and territorial governments to sustain and refresh their capabilities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFC5881E065D8499AB0E20069619D7E9A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>track performance in meeting the goals and associated plans of the provision of such technical assistance; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAB30FF63543744459AE586EFA95DEFF3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>include any other assistance the Secretary determines necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H1AEA8F9AE5E7423699D1025943275684"><enum>2243.</enum><header>Relationship to other Department components and Federal agencies</header> 
<subsection id="H890DFC0477574BC5823A4655825D3993" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The authority of the Secretary under this subtitle shall not affect or diminish the authority or the responsibility of any officer of any other Federal agency with respect to the command, control, or direction of the functions, personnel, funds, assets, or liabilities of any other such Federal agency.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H757D1BD4AF584FC48CD9902D572DABAF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department components</header><text>Nothing in this subtitle or any other provision of law may be construed to affect or reduce the responsibilities of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HADFF9A7EE47141DC9A09DC4629BBD501"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office or the Assistant Secretary of the Office, including with respect to any asset, function, or mission of the Office or the Assistant Secretary, as the case may be;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H494FDF5D3BE9485F9FA4D828F9912316"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Federal Emergency Management Agency or the Administrator of the Agency, including the diversion of any asset, function, or mission of the Agency or the Administrator as the case may be; or </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5E1B3F40084742EE803A0E6DCD0DFC7B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Transportation Security Administration or the Administrator of the Administration, including the diversion of any asset, function, or mission of the Administration or the Administrator, as the case may be.</text></paragraph></subsection> </section> <after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC66FBB952FE0448FB18B675951234D45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2238 the following new items:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0EFBC49551824A7DB7A608FE13B78C26" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="subtitle">Subtitle D—Bombing Prevention</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2241. Office for Bombing Prevention.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2242. Countering explosive devices technical assistance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2243. Relationship to other Department components and Federal agencies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3CA3A877B73544868E15F22E2666B8D9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Explosives technology development</header> 
<subsection id="HBC8A6F1BE589470592024E06AF84005F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title III of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/181">6 U.S.C. 181 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="HDEB7811453C6439DB7D39955BC56FE32" style="OLC"> <section id="H1E53B6E0642E43E483279FA1D2E737BC"><enum>323.</enum><header>Explosives research and development</header> <subsection id="H4BD72D7426FB4572915D9B2FB97A1AE3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and in coordination with the head of the Office for Bombing Prevention and the Assistant Secretary for the Countering Weapons of Mass Destruction Office, and in consultation with the Attorney General, the Secretary of Defense, and the head of any other relevant Federal department or agency, including Sector Risk Management Agencies, shall ensure coordination and information sharing regarding nonmilitary research, development, testing, and evaluation activities of the Federal Government relating to the deterrence, detection, prevention, protection against, mitigation of, and response to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1776F23FF74D4778A02DDAB125DDD958" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Leveraging military research</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Under Secretary for Science and Technology, and in coordination with the head of the Office for Bombing Prevention and the Assistant Secretary for the Countering of Weapons of Mass Destruction Office, shall consult with the Secretary of Defense and the head of any other relevant Federal department or agency, including Sector Risk Management Agencies, to ensure that, to the maximum extent possible, military policies and procedures, and research, development, testing, and evaluation activities relating to the deterrence, detection, prevention, protection against, mitigation of, and response to terrorist explosive threats and attacks in the United States are adapted to nonmilitary uses.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H1CAAFFBF4CD642739937E8D4A2B016DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 322 the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H74CF9D8CF4014F4B9FD77D3FA34D5E2D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 323. Explosives research and development.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> </section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 

