<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2C0430FC58634236BEFE3142017E168D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 6455 IH: Prosper Africa Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6455</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote, facilitate, and increase two-way trade and investment between the United States and Africa.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDBCE83C5716F4EC8B6FE866175B8BAF4" style="OLC"><section id="H15CDAFD6B145437DBC4B5D51BEED5833" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Prosper Africa Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H46E7032E2413488F95AF7F3D4BB4400B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to promote, facilitate, and increase two-way trade and investment between the United States and African countries to strengthen commercial ties, promote economic growth and job creation, and advance strategic partnerships.</text></section><section id="HB7228CDCA0EB415F8F1CEF934924CE1C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prosper Africa Initiative</header><subsection id="H181F39074C22409FB1844EAFAE01A1D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish an initiative to be known as the <quote>Prosper Africa Initiative</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Initiative</quote>). </text></subsection><subsection id="H65547BCE4AD14B2E8A8F0305BD69AEFC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of the Initiative shall be to prioritize and coordinate United States Government programs, activities, and diplomatic efforts aimed at increasing two-way trade and investment between the United States and Africa, including to—</text><paragraph id="H57C382DE4C7749059F206EB9E5AE84DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify, promote, and increase trade and investment opportunities, facilitate business and investor engagement, and support dissemination of data and market information to better inform United States businesses and investors of trade and investment opportunities across Africa;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD97A1338A94CAF9994EAA9E92910BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support efforts of the United States and African private sectors to access, navigate, deepen, and compete in African and global capital markets using a private sector-led and sector-specific approach that includes energy, agriculture, information and communications technology, healthcare, financial services, arts and entertainment, and infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E1C1EF52CF4C708853BD18A6795E1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modernize, streamline, and improve access to resources and services designed to promote increased trade and investment opportunities for United States and African businesses and investors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE85FED68C93E4920BDD855AC5C3280F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>promote economic growth and job creation in the United States and Africa, while advancing strategic partnerships; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2EFCD6E3F084B299551F7817E5C47F5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>identify policy, regulatory, and legal reforms needed to reduce trade and investment barriers between the United States and Africa and improve the business and investment climate in the United States and Africa, including through the reduction of the cost of accessing capital.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H5C5E997923D445699E2894D8FD0D0C5C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Leadership and coordination of Initiative</header><subsection id="HB6B69EC425644182A26B369776C4FBA1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Directorate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish a directorate to be known as the <quote>Prosper Africa Directorate</quote> (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Directorate</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5757C22E0CE4FDCBEA0B16E23EEA54B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Executive Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall appoint an Executive Director of the Directorate who shall be responsible for the management, coordination, and information sharing functions of the Prosper Africa Initiative established pursuant to section 3(a) and other duties that support the purposes of the Initiative described in section 3(b) as appropriate. </text></subsection><subsection id="H9142A24C169C4F449BC55BA55B3A5FEC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Director shall be responsible for—</text><paragraph id="HBEDA99BA32014B6D90653C63768A4063"><enum>(1)</enum><text>convening relevant Federal departments and agencies to coordinate programs, assistance, communications, and stakeholder engagement, and consulting with such departments and agencies on the appropriate levels and allocation of resources in support of achieving the strategic objectives of the Initiative; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51DFEDD85127420C99F14E2F3AAE6CCD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>planning and implementing information sharing and other collaboration efforts among relevant Federal departments and agencies, and the private sector as appropriate, related to trade and investment opportunities, African capital markets, and relevant transactions in Africa and support for monitoring, evaluation, and transaction facilitation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9F84F4BAD674B9F9546F21B372511FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>engaging with United States and African private sector partners, civil society organizations, nongovernmental organizations and the African diaspora community, as appropriate, to solicit input and feedback on the Initiative’s activities, as well as any technical, policy, financial, and political obstacles private sector partners encounter in accessing or expanding in African markets or gaining access to capital for those purposes; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47B7E4EC35AA4F0F9B9E241D0E4AE942"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing measurable goals and objectives for the purposes of carrying out the Initiative.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H59F59D0950234B618406A90611924C90"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Leadership committee</header><paragraph id="H0AB9432B2D2146878416BD4F9DF3D90F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall establish an interagency leadership committee (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>committee</quote>) to provide strategic guidance for administering the objectives of the Initiative and serve as the United States interagency strategic development and coordination body for efforts of relevant Federal departments and agencies. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02D88B067AD04D7C8145B02F240C7EE9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The committee shall include representatives from relevant Federal departments and agencies, as determined appropriate by the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73BACCABA5C04EB789E8DC200A93E738"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Executive Director of the Directorate shall serve as chairperson of the committee. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H140BF801E6E04872B8F3ED5C2D946AC0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The committee shall meet not less than four times each year at the call of the Executive Director of the Directorate (or the Director’s designee).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E3FB85BA5284AE2847784C60A77DDC6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Staffing and field presence</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations—</text><paragraph id="H5611ACFC55694B649586B6A70A99A173"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Directorate shall be supported by at least 6 full-time employees of the Federal Government, which should include personnel detailed to the Directorate from relevant Federal departments and agencies, who are stationed in Africa and whose sole duties are to support the purposes of—</text><subparagraph id="HDDD6248D40FC4BEAADD5A20BF1B7A19C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Initiative described in section 3(b); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6133626B887343508DF4DEC90D146314"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the provisions of the Better Utilization of Investments Leading to Development Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>) with respect to Africa and in compliance with the requirements of the Championing American Business Through Diplomacy Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9901">22 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H939A8D48CEB64317A014AF4EC2AA8BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>relevant Federal departments and agencies should detail personnel to the Directorate at the Directorate’s offices in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC8BFEE99A34844C88940F7418306D6E6" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Deal teams</header><paragraph id="H6FF72E1289A04461B6BBD7F6B1FA7CAB" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Prosper Africa Initiative established pursuant to section 3(a) shall be supported by designated embassy staff holding positions related to United States commercial and economic interests at United States embassies located in Africa, to the extent practicable. Such designated embassy staff at a United States embassy located in Africa shall be referred to as a <quote>deal team</quote> for purposes of this subsection. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DE9AF1BE2F94FC1A0D4F03A59F0BD4E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each deal team shall prioritize efforts to identify commercial opportunities, advocate for improvements in the business and investment climate, engage and consult with private sector partners, and report on such activities, in compliance with the applicable requirements of the Championing American Business Through Diplomacy Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9901">22 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDDD14CFC2143463893A2237A92818340"><enum>5.</enum><header>Investment promotion and trade capacity building assistance</header><subsection id="HA15EC2A0CB734051A8FF47581F70C044"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President, acting through the Executive Director of the Directorate, shall develop and implement policies that promote, facilitate, and increase two-way trade and investment between the United States and Africa, including by providing support for—</text><paragraph id="HAC680482B5B44CDD8C0BE7F5EEF0A74A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>activities to advance trade capacity building assistance, as authorized by the African Growth and Opportunity Act and Millennium Challenge Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/167">Public Law 115–167</external-xref>) and the amendments made by that Act, and other applicable statutes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1F2F885192B4ECEA1D34DEB8A812CA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identification and development of investment opportunities for the United States private sector in partner countries and efforts to facilitate and promote trade and investment opportunities in the United States and Africa;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3541F92FBBB14F4EAE5CA436459F96E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>analysis of market systems, trends, prospects and opportunities for value-addition, including risk assessments and constraints analyses of key sectors and United States strategic competitiveness, and other reporting on commercial opportunities and investment climate in Africa;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13DFEFB5B5DD4874A583FA12BC4C52EB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>outreach and engagement with small and medium-sized enterprises in Africa or doing business with African partners, including women-led and diaspora-owned businesses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H690E67C1E4FD49F89EF8AC8639230244"><enum>(5)</enum><text>efforts to leverage resources and expertise to lower non-tariff barriers to trade and investment in Africa, such as African enterprise access to capital, and to generally promote a conducive business climate for private sector investment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCBE2C9DAC524B98BAEADCA434FF1E7F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>technical assistance to the African Union and regional economic communities to implement the African Continental Free Trade Area and support regional economic integration; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90C3540C09D744C4B71F554BE50AEFE4" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">development of local African capital markets and Africa’s access to lower cost, longer-term capital on global capital markets, including improving African investment readiness, increasing the availability of market-based risk mitigation tools and improving the reliability and availability of investment data, to promote the larger-scale, standardized, transparent investment flows asked for by investors. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FFB95BA7494492481F1E430AE9512DD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In providing assistance to carry out the activities described in subsection (a), the President should consider United States strategic interests when allocating such assistance and give priority for activities in countries that—</text><paragraph id="H8D7D9031429841F7AA9AE446E18E11AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>have demonstrated support for economic policies that promote the development of private enterprise, including foreign direct investment, and taken steps to improve a business enabling environment that could benefit the United States private sector and economy if such assistance is provided; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B57624C5AB9433796FB3CD834AE7503"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are designated by the President—</text><subparagraph id="H8ADEB0016BB54CAF8FC8A04F2FD84C4B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an eligible sub-Saharan African country under the African Growth and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/19/3703">19 U.S.C. 3703</external-xref>); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF474BC1B7C0E49499332006F5B396F01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as meeting the threshold requirements to enter into an agreement with the United States under section 609 of the Millennium Challenge Act of 2003 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7708">22 U.S.C. 7708</external-xref>; relating to Millennium Challenge Compact); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H257763A91DE049CE86EF3886FAF735CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>as a beneficiary developing country under section 502 or 506A of the Trade Act of 1974 (19 U.S.C. 2462 or 2466a) and has ratified and taken steps to implement the African Continental Free Trade Area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDE92036D5B994BB2AF5FD6FD5D411305"><enum>6.</enum><header>Advisory council</header><subsection id="HB9564EE7B84647C7970BC3A7E9597959" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall establish an advisory council—</text><paragraph id="H713848D643ED401395CE1FD2402C72B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to advise the President, and others as appropriate, on the extent to which the Directorate and relevant Federal departments and agencies are meeting their objectives under this Act, and provide suggestions for improvements with respect to meeting those objectives, including implementation challenges and opportunities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AD05A3B4BB048A6B6A2C24AF782A1F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support efforts to identify, promote, and facilitate opportunities to expand commercial ties between the United States and Africa.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7E89C66097FA47398AF8747F6BFC81AF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H624661C4A9A840708FB183E4F546E071"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The advisory council shall be composed of—</text><subparagraph id="H625FF59DB43B41888BB5919E47C25BAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not less than 12 members appointed by the President, in consultation with the Executive Director of the Directorate and Congress, from among individuals with significant experience investing and operating in Africa, including representatives of United States and African diaspora-owned, women-owned, and small and medium-sized enterprises; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB02D1E5A6160403FAA091652608FFA4E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the co-chairs or two appropriate designees of the President’s Advisory Council on Doing Business in Africa, as established by Executive Order 13734. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2242A49EF534C099BCA89152814C19D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms; reappointment</header><text>Each of the members of the advisory council—</text><subparagraph id="HE8AE57CEF11A4CCBBE0364C4D131B6F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall serve a term of 2 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7DEAC6C3DAD4B9DAC6AC7B5D69002DE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be reappointed for one additional term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DDBB53C09B24D088ECDC4B4F357BC32"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline for appointment</header><text>Each of the members of the advisory council shall be appointed under paragraph (1) not later than 90 days after the date on which the President establishes the Advisory Committee under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC611B153410D4A6694CD6205D55ACA2F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Advisory Council shall be filled in the manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36B2FD3E93924C6A973C1099BC5DC6F3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><paragraph id="H6DAF5DD76B7A42ED8F25CE36A4282D54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Executive Director of the Directorate shall appoint a chairperson of the advisory committee from among the members of the advisory committee appointed under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49C22014651048FE90D5BF83823A8390"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Terms; reappointment</header><text>The chairperson of the advisory committee—</text><subparagraph id="H2076A04D080B48F690514C7011265549"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall serve a term of 2 years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE03D3F76F25A4A3F9A45236EC0018381"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not be reappointed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABA9329C45BC477DA7D880096B9E8A42"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation</header><text>Members of the advisory council may not receive pay, allowances, or benefits by reason of their service on the advisory committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE3F8962D7D144BAB71F803FF194475D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The advisory council shall meet at the call of the Executive Director.</text></subsection></section><section id="HEF5884C8D11F443CB3CFA0548005B18A"><enum>7.</enum><header>United States-African Leaders Summit</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The President shall seek to convene on a biennial basis a meeting between the United States Government and heads of state of countries of Africa, to be known as the <quote>United States-African Leaders Summit</quote>, for purposes of advancing shared priorities and strengthening diplomatic, economic, and security partnerships in Africa. </text></section><section id="HE1475E4334B3454685C9444F7C603741"><enum>8.</enum><header>United States strategy to promote trade and investment in Africa</header><subsection id="H8192125061524C55A61CDEE9E5B1BB68"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President, in consultation with the heads of the relevant Federal departments and agencies, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees and make publicly available a single government-wide strategy, to be known as the <quote>Prosper Africa Strategy</quote>, that provides a detailed description of how the United States intends to fulfill the policy objectives of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6EBCBDE29A8342ABA64FEDDE7E6D5D52"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H51CB32213BF84456AFF53410EE03CD22"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support and be aligned with other relevant strategies of the United States Government; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAD86866495B42E389ED2A6297733ED3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>outline a plan to enhance coordination and information sharing among relevant Federal departments and agencies on investment climate and opportunities and provide support to pending transactions, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22355516EFB9420E98B3820D63CA610E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>include specific and measurable goals, benchmarks, performance metrics, and timetables to carry out the purposes of this Act, and training, monitoring, and evaluation plans to ensure the accountability and effectiveness of all policies and initiatives carried out under the strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE87C1640F9F848758F7D548550C300EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specific implementation plan</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall include a specific implementation plan, in coordination with the recommendations and activities of the Economic Diplomacy Action Group as required by section 708(c) of the Championing American Business Through Diplomacy Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9904">22 U.S.C. 9904</external-xref>) from each of the relevant Federal departments and agencies that describes—</text><paragraph id="HFE659BC6B1304FDCA6027C8A9EDFA6E6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the anticipated contributions of the department or agency, including technical, financial, and in-kind contributions, to implement the strategy; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD86A2B0A7386482E9F699B4B1D11407B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the efforts of the department or agency to ensure that the policies and initiatives carried out pursuant to the strategy are designed to achieve maximum impact and effectiveness and progress made toward achieving the goals, benchmarks, performance metrics, and timetables outlined in subsection (b)(3); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88BBC2492FB14342A9DE77F20DD99E62"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on necessary resources, including staffing, to expand efforts to promote trade and investment between the United States and Africa.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA96C470F7B854391A2DEAD0CEDC515B0"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the submission of the strategy required by section 8(a), and annually thereafter until 2026, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report, in coordination with the report required by the Championing American Business Through Diplomacy Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/94">Public Law 116–94</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9901">22 U.S.C. 9901 et seq.</external-xref>), that—</text><paragraph id="H2ED7916FB97F4D548E04DD08D90935AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes and evaluates the implementation of United States diplomatic efforts and foreign assistance programs, projects, and activities to advance the policy objectives set forth in section 2;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B25CB11C19A4547B93D43EDCEFC3BFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the nature and extent of coordination among relevant Federal departments and agencies, including a summary of activities and engagements of the Directorate and the interagency leadership committee established pursuant to section 4(d);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB607CD743FD14AE98CDE27C8414BBD1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provides data on goals identified for financial commitments under the Initiative and any private capital mobilized to support and finalize transactions, opportunities identified by relevant Federal departments and agencies, and transactions determined to be ineligible for United States support or not being pursued for other reasons under the Initiative; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDF44A74A971B4413B7DAC126306BED4B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describes the monitoring and evaluation tools, mechanisms, and indicators to assess progress made on the policy objectives set forth in section 2.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC4BBB53D8CA14D9A9FF2948EFE79A781"><enum>10.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HDB5337E8582046E3989B42A7D7AE2F6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H66051CE4C2534DB699584AE8E521CCE2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F1158401954415698F76C62A388FE04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H411A566150AE40FAB69E541CA912C18A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private sector</header><text>The term <quote>private sector</quote> means for-profit businesses and not-for-profit entities. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H2A1113073D3049C49556C6C95443493C"><enum>11.</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements of this Act shall terminate on the date that is 7 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

