<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HECEDEC3611FE4FFA82BD3C779A5040D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7678 IH: American Small Business Competition Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7678</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220506">May 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000471">Mr. Fitzgerald</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase the loan limits under the business loan program and the 504 loan program of the Small Business Administration for businesses principally engaged in the research, development, manufacturing, or production of critical and emerging technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0010336A87A54B9AA94A92BC44BE75B8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2F4D760AC2754CE083759D6AE8D2CF3F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Small Business Competition Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H12AA90F4003C4AE6851DB915EF6AE50B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Loan limits</header> <subsection id="H0E90B17A8AD54E99B2327A8BDEABAC11"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Business loan program</header><text>Section 7(a)(3) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H420D59D5AD554395894A2D3A4884E69F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraphs (B) and (C)</quote>; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0890CAF0BE614467870D2F0C839DD6BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H002871A4CFB74493BDBA4E21C5DDFDF7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (D); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F6E815216EE4C6DA9FF35D665633FDC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B) the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2F05D996E36E4A3997C2A3E26005D09F"> 
<subparagraph id="H4CF25F9087D245F19C103D38F415893B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if the gross amount outstanding and committed (by participation or otherwise) to the borrower from the business loan and investment fund established by this Act would exceed $7,500,000, for a small business concern— </text> <clause id="H546AF0982CF74E52AA411520A636BCF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is principally engaged in the research, development, manufacturing, or production of a technology listed on the Critical and Emerging Technologies List issued by the National Science and Technology Council in coordination with the National Security Council, or any successor to such list; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H4DA00BB975294FF99978535EC7B21083"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which the headquarters of the small business concern is located in the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="HDAB1F461CB8F4134A7B7473A80AEE51D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that includes in the application of the small business concern for the loan under this subsection information regarding any foreign individual or entity that owns not less than 5 percent of the small business concern; and</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1C7390A31C2847BF913C17B28A0392DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>504 loan program</header><text>Section 502(2)(A) of the Small Business Investment Act of 1958 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/696">15 U.S.C. 696(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H78636B6F946D412AB81974D3310241B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in clause (i), by striking <quote>or (v)</quote> and inserting <quote>(v), or (vi)</quote>; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA995F5B041FB4D83A6812489ECE7635F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB16EF46843944879A1ABD7724356273D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (v), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBC583D00C7554BEC9BB2F9C31FF7BDFD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8A072093519546AD993F72BD32661498"> <clause id="H8E58073506F945F8B8476C59891B07F5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$7,500,000 for each project of a small business concern principally engaged in the research, development, manufacturing, or production of a technology listed on the Critical and Emerging Technologies List issued by the National Science and Technology Council in coordination with the National Security Council, or any successor to such list.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HBDA32C069A3B41D78CD4ADBB693D1A27"><enum>3.</enum><header>Report regarding access to capital for small businesses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="HEA05F6982CF54A68AF77A808177AAA35"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provides a description of the effect of inflation and supply chain disruption during the 3-year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act on the cost to small business concerns (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636</external-xref>)) of obtaining access to capital, disaggregated by industry; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H946618FCD88C4E00BBC5B306C7423168"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes recommendations, in partnership with the Office of Advocacy of the Small Business Administration, on how to support access to capital for small business concerns involved in the domestic research, development, manufacturing, and production of technologies listed on the Critical and Emerging Technologies List issued by the National Science and Technology Council in coordination with the National Security Council, or any successor to such list.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

