<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H936983C19F3C4F07A06CBD76AAC75DD4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9043 IH: Respect for Child Survivors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9043</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, to require appropriate use of multidisciplinary teams for investigations of child sexual exploitation or abuse, the production of child sexual abuse material, or child trafficking conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H32813A02162F487FA08E0B9291C90D2C" style="OLC"><section id="HF13C6CEA721242A3A9B8BF10DD8BBE1C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Respect for Child Survivors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HD3B17EEDE68D4D6F8AE54F89F1AC8F45"><enum>2.</enum><header>Multidisciplinary teams</header><subsection id="H6FAE24FC14444098A81157FD27EF0CE9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/33">Chapter 33</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3CE0A8E7A3524A5983E7446C15106F24"><section id="H453FBA1CED6D42BD8A4BD392FB37A46C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>540D.</enum><header>Multidisciplinary teams </header><subsection id="H918AD4122F9A4B0D98095E5121024378"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H77473D1207604AEC9980C6D53B1D5F6F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>child sexual abuse material</term> means a visual depiction described in section 2256(8)(A) of title 18; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA3B97F156E74B7898E4B726CFE7A9E7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>covered investigation</term> means any investigation of child sexual exploitation or abuse, the production of child sexual abuse material, or child trafficking conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA454B1C843B34D69825E87404CD2664D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92273783FF8D4D6A8DAA1F0B7A0618D2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <term>multidisciplinary team</term> means a multidisciplinary team established or used under subsection (b)(2); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1FADD833832C47BE839B9C554665E22A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the term <term>relevant children’s advocacy center personnel</term> means children's advocacy center staff that regularly participate in multidisciplinary child support settings, including the director of the children’s advocacy center, the coordinator of a multidisciplinary team, forensic interviewers, victim advocates, forensic medical evaluators, physicians, sexual assault nurse examiners, and mental health clinicians; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H568F672C78BD4A44B2F0D1E683B4E68C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the term <term>victim advocate</term> means a person, whether paid or serving as a volunteer, who provides services to victims under the auspices or supervision of a victim services program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB445364ABFE847C689BBAA8D7BB1D12C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>FBI victim support requirements</header><paragraph id="HFA3D2FFEA48A49EF8C3F6325FA89397E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To carry out the functions described in subsection (c) in connection with each covered investigation conducted by the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director shall— </text><subparagraph id="H2C2F6AC1F455449CB863D4798BF4881D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>use a multidisciplinary approach; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1536DB8F5B0F44FDBE51A3009C62728C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>unless impracticable or otherwise inconsistent with applicable Federal law, in accordance with paragraph (3), use— </text><clause id="HFEAD384391FD41DB987C38441F965E62"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a trained Federal Bureau of Investigation child adolescent forensic interviewer; or </text></clause><clause id="H3C81C1C8FD194759A5675490400CF75C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the absence of a trained Federal Bureau of Investigation child adolescent forensic interviewer, a trained forensic interviewer at a children’s advocacy center.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8F74854D8C54DAB9660E41F5F82FF30"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use and coordination</header><text>The Director shall use and coordinate with children’s advocacy center-based multidisciplinary teams as necessary to carry out paragraph (1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA7D57ECDA864AE18159AB07F3A02E0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Children’s advocacy centers</header><text>The Director—</text><subparagraph id="HFCE58A2F85AA497DA3BCFCDDF2EBFB34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may work with children’s advocacy centers to implement a multidisciplinary team approaches for purposes of covered investigations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H709E4423809748B8B22DCC8103A148C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall allow, facilitate, and encourage multidisciplinary teams to collaborate with a children’s advocacy center with regard to availability, provision, and use of services to and by victims and families that are participants in or affected by the actions at issue in a covered investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H08C1546C75A24ECA8D56239C64973F88"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Director shall submit to the Attorney General an annual report identifying any interview of a victim reporting child sexual abuse material or child trafficking that took place—</text><subparagraph id="H56F87D26C57E4DDFBC62ACED0E0CB5E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>without the use of—</text><clause id="H3234B79DD8904A9382EA595835601E69"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a multidisciplinary approach; </text></clause><clause id="H38A60D346D52413C98D20C4F6FC2C538"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a trained forensic interviewer; or</text></clause><clause id="HEEA34994A6A24D5387A5F66C5A8C9055"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>either the use of a multidisciplinary approach or a trained forensic interviewer; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB91BD07993F24597800E93E92AF5F7CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each interview identified under subparagraph (A), describing the exigent circumstances that existed with respect to the interview, in accordance with paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H223F8954187B44CCA2707C8B14AB0E21"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Memoranda of understanding</header><text>The Director shall seek to enter into a memorandum of understanding with a reputable national accrediting organization for children's advocacy centers— </text><subparagraph id="H1ADC1D2991D74CDF8D1F8E9CBD3FA09E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under which—</text><clause id="HCB2F1BEDC9AE425183B33A1B61AF75CC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the children’s advocacy services of the national organization are made available to field offices of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HCEB69DCBBE0148FD92AD564299C30E5B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>special agents and other employees of the Federal Bureau of Investigation are made aware of the existence of such memoranda and its purposes; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB27EF09C06740BB8BA68794AF2FBD9C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which shall reflect a trauma-informed, victim-centered approach and provide for case review.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0676CC4DCF54861A9DB92BC086E5082"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The functions described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="HF85B49E77C9A4B9F9B2789571D3AC783"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To provide for the sharing of information among the members of a multidisciplinary team, when such a team is used, and with other appropriate personnel regarding the progress of a covered investigation by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE685A81087604CF7AF5EF8D678FABD99"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To provide for and enhance collaborative efforts among the members of a multidisciplinary team, when such a team is used, and other appropriate personnel regarding a covered investigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3DAB70ADCF5435E9A6A88198065EC71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To enhance the social services available to victims in connection with a covered investigation, including through the enhancement of cooperation among specialists and other personnel providing such services in connection with a covered investigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F2C757BBD75417C86952C17B7D1E75D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>To carry out other duties regarding the response to investigations of child sexual abuse or trafficking. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7A8A38C9E3C4602B4C3EB539A683280"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Personnel</header><paragraph id="H3F152351130D4EF1A2EEABB4444DE78F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each multidisciplinary team shall be composed of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H19B488D3D96740189493D20CC7FBE479"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Appropriate investigative personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99D4C71CB7E04336A5B0AABFD66D81D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Appropriate mental health professionals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H043FE9BF7C7F48F18091B9BB53796F24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Appropriate medical personnel.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF87473CDAAE4B93874854A94B256130"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Victim advocates or victim specialists.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86144DCDA2448699D794AEDB4F11852"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Relevant children’s advocacy center personnel, with respect to covered investigations in which the children’s advocacy center or personnel of the children’s advocacy center were used in the course of the covered investigation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFCE194F48E042A892B1FF2209474DBD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Prosecutors, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25C3883EFAFD40ABADD7329A37BA9E23"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expertise and training</header><subparagraph id="H6EA37C2E12AE40F1B915767187A2D4C0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any individual assigned to a multidisciplinary team shall possess such expertise, and shall undertake such training as is required to maintain such expertise, in order to ensure that members of the team remain appropriately qualified to carry out the functions of the team under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47A403E79EBD40C0A4D005158292649F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The training and expertise required under subparagraph (A) shall include training and expertise on special victims’ crimes, including child sexual abuse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H344FB1D8B0EF48CAA015D8D0232655E8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sharing of information</header><paragraph id="HE241BEACDA224A8BB887F9D44D8E995E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Access to information</header><subparagraph id="H7AE1107AF0F34EE4BE12FF6858F8AE4D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), relevant children’s advocacy center personnel who are assigned to work on a covered investigation under this section shall be granted access to the case information necessary to perform their role conducting forensic interviews and providing mental health treatment, medical care, and victim advocacy for Federal Bureau of Investigation cases. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EE10418249C4E9A9C6AB9B95918C91C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Included information</header><text>The case information described in subparagraph (A) to which relevant children's advocacy center personnel shall be granted access includes—</text><clause id="HBD0F20AFEC0B435FA0892BA3CD594503"><enum>(i)</enum><text>case outcome of forensic interviews;</text></clause><clause id="HFD4110D0689442128F148B37C0858CE6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>medical evaluation outcomes;</text></clause><clause id="H3D313A41F3CB403D80918DC7ADEB0254"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>mental health treatment referrals and treatment completion;</text></clause><clause id="H4321EECDB7B8408697EC36020B7F2FEA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>safety planning and child protection issues;</text></clause><clause id="H8540C57AE3FF40C69D638AC8D952A40F"><enum>(v)</enum><text>victim service needs and referrals addressed by the victim advocate; </text></clause><clause id="HE4A5F1646DD04D32B30676C3D33CD876"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>case disposition;</text></clause><clause id="H8896FF5B6A06414BBFAB9D45EE7A7CC5"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>case outcomes; and</text></clause><clause id="HBB3A51F3EF16423394A24D439C784ECC"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any other information required for a children’s advocacy centers as a part of the standards of practice of the children's advocacy center.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1BCD44FFAF846B3A919EFD7C8DD0E1F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exempt information</header><text>The case information described in subparagraph (A) does not include—</text><clause id="H5668ABE017654076AD4F0D31994D69D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>classified information;</text></clause><clause id="H2B882AA7C7914190ABB915AE3482B3FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the identity of confidential informants; or</text></clause><clause id="H305ECCBF3B584492ACA5FDAC5847A8C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other investigative information not included as a part of the standards of practice of the children's advocacy center.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40DB761A384C442FAF6D3F1751002C5F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sharing information with FBI</header><text>Children’s advocacy centers shall provide the Federal Bureau of Investigation with forensic interview recordings and documentation, medical reports, and other case information on Federal Bureau of Investigation-related cases. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6ADBBB8F442E48C4A1AEAFB30AD8C9B1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Security clearances</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB40C082EF2E346188AF01B2B5C33C1C7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Bureau of Investigation shall provide security clearances to relevant children's advocacy center personnel for purposes of case review by multidisciplinary teams, if it is determined that those personnel are eligible and possess a need-to-know specific classified information to perform or assist in a lawful and authorized government function. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H4CB0514A2C1F4B6C98F52BD54A5AB506"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4169A429A153469582EB94A47120D3BA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of teams</header><text>Multidisciplinary teams used under this section shall be made available to victims reporting child sexual abuse or child trafficking in covered investigations, regardless of the age of the victim making the report. </text></subsection><subsection id="HB6D0AC7903BE4D009231A0420E31D68E"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Case review by multidisciplinary team</header><text>Throughout a covered investigation, a multidisciplinary team supporting an investigation under this section shall, at regularly scheduled times, convene to—</text><paragraph id="H095DC590A60D4E2B98ED579A12F31334"><enum>(1)</enum><text>share information about case progress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9250BDDBF968404AA4F39CEC7F0A14F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>address any investigative or prosecutorial barriers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE85372223D0C4D269A2BCBE87BC8ADC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that victims receive support and needed treatment. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4037252AB0C94436BA03A19B52739716" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Availability of advocates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall make advocates available to each victim who reports child sexual abuse or child trafficking in connection with an investigation by the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H655342F07B5A4C908C223E31100D628F"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD0D2484A76004F1B90042A43A2EE7393"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Investigative authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to augment any existing investigative authority of the Federal Bureau of Investigation or to expand the jurisdiction of any Federal law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H73B5D89BAF6A4E82AC93C1218340CA2A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Protecting investigations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to limit the legal obligations of the Director under any other provision of law, including section 552a of title 5 (commonly known as the <quote>Privacy Act of 1974</quote>), or require the sharing of classified information with unauthorized persons.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H65CCC500460A455D86DAEB6D8D3FE4F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/28/540C">section 540C</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC849B43A75E041B89F57EA831C84A345"><toc><toc-entry level="section">540D. Multidisciplinary teams.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

