<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A15CBB9E4FF4623AE58D0D6CE1579B6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7515 IH: Infectious Disease Therapies Research and Innovation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7515</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220414">April 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide an exception from the passive loss rules for investments in specified medical research small business pass-thru entities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H50E23701D2B94E71929EB9FB823E8B11" style="OLC"><section id="H934E246CEFEB47A6A8E18E68E77549DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Infectious Disease Therapies Research and Innovation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF8B3D93B6F0840AAA267D2F4AE756015" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Exception from passive loss rules for investments in specified medical research small business pass-thru entities</header><subsection id="H51B68356A9C64AA9B63F79EC7960D1F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (c) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/469">section 469</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating paragraphs (4) through (7) as paragraphs (5) through (8), respectively, and by inserting after paragraph (3) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H42994F9072244C179BC03D3E0F240E04" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE8A10A79156D40DAB7AB7CAD4DB090E0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Specified medical research activities</header><subparagraph id="H0A849731B32346CE8552DCD55C1F31F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>passive activity</term> shall not include any qualified medical research activity of the taxpayer carried on by a specified medical research small business pass-thru entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7217DFF511C840279D0F0B8B3FAB1233"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of losses and deductions</header><clause id="H86AA0F2111894308832A8F773EC63380"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Losses or deductions of a taxpayer in connection with qualified medical research activities carried on by a specified medical research small business pass-thru entity shall not be treated as losses or deductions, respectively, from a passive activity except as provided in clause (ii) and subparagraph (C).</text></clause><clause id="H5C732134FF4745D0A822FEE44FC2B7F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) shall apply to losses and deductions of a taxpayer in connection with a specified medical small business pass-thru entity for a taxable year only to the extent that the aggregate losses and deductions of the taxpayer in connection with qualified medical research activities of such entity for such taxable year do not exceed the portion of the taxpayer’s adjusted basis in the taxpayer’s ownership interest in such entity that is attributable to money or other property contributed—</text><subclause id="H0A571C04271A4BF9AFB48B436023BEF4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in exchange for such ownership interest, and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE74DB605D6B54324BDEB666C2AC6B87B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>specifically for use in connection with qualified medical research activities.</text></subclause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="clause">For purposes of the preceding sentence, the taxpayer’s basis shall not include any portion of such basis which is attributable to an increase in a partner’s share of the liabilities of a partnership that is considered under section 752(a) as a contribution of money. </continuation-text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36CA66062E3C4D01B7C060BB344ECB00"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of carryovers</header><text>Subparagraph (B)(i) shall not apply to the portion of any loss or deduction that is carried over under subsection (b) into a taxable year other than the taxable year in which such loss or deduction arose.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE59DE63F946D4CD18942F45B323C7637"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Qualified medical research activity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>qualified medical research activity</term> means any qualified research (within the meaning of section 41(d)) with respect to qualified countermeasures (as defined in section 319F–1(a)(2) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 247d–6a(a)(2)). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FE785867D094B51BB0789B34422FEBB"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Specified medical research small business pass-thru entity</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>specified medical research small business pass-thru entity</term> means any domestic pass-thru entity for any taxable year if—</text><clause id="H01C9849093A944318601FC2FB9F3B833"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 80 percent of such entity’s expenditures on qualified research for such taxable year are paid or incurred in connection with qualified medical research activities, and</text></clause><clause id="H6DC21A336AAB4F8082359CC0986DB091"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the gross receipts (as determined under the rules of section 41(h)(3)) of such entity for the taxable year (and each preceding taxable year) is less than $1,000,000. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE32A43389E5E4341BBA848639F9D203B"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Capital expenditures taken into account for expenditures test</header><text>An expenditure shall not fail to be taken into account under subparagraph (E)(i) merely because such expenditure is chargeable to capital account.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94098A97FBAB4BDEA2A92757D24A1C6B"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Pass-thru entity</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>pass-thru entity</term> means any partnership, S corporation, or other entity identified by the Secretary as a pass-thru entity for purposes of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD93350F395B14DB2B8E502FBC90DE1F4"><enum>(H)</enum><header>Aggregation rules</header><clause id="HAF09E45A21B240B8BB68DF5FD76DD779"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of section 52, or subsection (m) or (o) of section 414, shall be treated as a single entity for purposes of subparagraphs (E) and (F)(iii).</text></clause><clause id="H3BB2D3B77843451485BE33238EFD4616"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation where entity would not qualify</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No entity shall be treated as a specified medical research small business pass-thru entity unless such entity qualifies as such both with and without the application of clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD38A0BD009D74E299B0C9EAFE4207829"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Material participation not required</header><text>Paragraph (5) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/469">section 469(c)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986, as redesignated by subsection (a), is amended by striking <quote>and (3)</quote> in the heading and text and inserting <quote>, (3), and (4)</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBEED6873DC74417BB2FA4DE05A55BCB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain research-Related deductions and credits of specified medical research small business pass-Thru entities allowed for purposes of determining alternative minimum tax</header><paragraph id="HCBDEBC80D2704E7EB86A781194B6D276"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deduction for research and experimental expenditures</header><text>Paragraph (2) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/56">section 56(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H2BFA9F8C43E44B3AA31F862734C6C558" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HAAC0EDCF2E0D43C68A3C07CD89037EB5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Exception for specified medical research small business pass-thru entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a specified medical research small business pass-thru entity (as defined in section 469(c)(4)), this paragraph shall not apply to any amount allowable as a deduction under section 174(a).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4209F2080D644EE49F71483813E57693"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allowance of certain research-related credits</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 38(c)(4) of such Code is amended by redesignating clauses (ii) through (xii) as clauses (iii) through (xiii), respectively, and by inserting after clause (i) the following new clause:</text><quoted-block id="H71F2E22E4193488580C20FCA12D1A5DC" style="OLC"><clause id="HF63F7F1D774F47C08CBE96C94E1B33C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the credit of an individual taxpayer determined under section 41 to the extent attributable to a specified medical research small business pass-thru entity (as defined in section 469(c)(4)),</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H718D268E7E9B45D9B7E289CC6720D04A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exception to limitation on pass-Thru of research credit</header><text>Subsection (g) of section 41 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>Paragraphs (2) and (4) shall not apply with respect to any specified medical research small business pass-thru entity (as defined in section 469(c)(4)).</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H686C04EEFB564EF2BAC3A5F33C93DFE5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to losses and credits arising in taxable years beginning after December 31, 2022.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

