<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H99EE7C841E78475A887EBF651201DF68" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9477 IH: Science-based Equitable Aquaculture Food Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9477</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221208">December 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize studies and pilot programs related to the development and production of aquaculture in the exclusive economic zone of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB1482F64E77843E5842E7A543D27A68C" style="OLC"><section id="HE78E8968B5724D76859886FDD7A35DF4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Science-based Equitable Aquaculture Food Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SEAfood Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0C6F4549BA5048A2B6E5901BCA71A6D5"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H00F7FC2ED3AB43AC9B27019824217792" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adjacent coastal jurisdiction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>adjacent coastal jurisdiction</term> means with respect to any activity proposed, conducted, or approved by the Administrator under section 5(a), any coastal State land—</text><subparagraph id="H7C7FA852CB054653922EF1E6F0145B92"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is used, or is scheduled to be used, as a support base for such activity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D52EF2E40F64EB19F737FD2AFF806A0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in which there is a reasonable probability of significant effect on land or water uses from such activity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46212EE03AC24938B84C94AABDAF07B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96B48F752DE242BCB494126AA8399A9E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means the Committees on—</text><subparagraph id="HE49CD9E5223447C1B845A48FEEE9F0ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Natural Resources of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61475882137A4724829CFA5B14D91986"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Agriculture of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6BC44097DFB4A9A9CD1BC2B6B2C9E87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2C2A417EB9F487199F975AC52FD0361"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF8F0FBFDE7724E2CB048C1BB1DD4CE3E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Environment and Public Works of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE579F2EB6C844B5BB176C9D6FFA141B6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DA3CAE23DFE469DA130F4C584640F85" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB3E3C0A5814B46E9A5D333EAD47414A9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Individuals who reside in a census block group in which 30-percent or more of the population are individuals with an annual household income that does not exceed the greater of—</text><clause id="H3EAC497DF14B4C87BCF4A851D44994A9" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount equal to 80-percent of the median income of the area in which the household is located, as reported by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development; or</text></clause><clause id="H96A6FE517DF749A5B715983C623ADC3D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>200-percent of the Federal poverty line.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18A536DB9EE24AD89232E71DFBAEB3A7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Individuals who reside in a geographically distinct area in which the population of any of the following categories of individuals is higher than the average population of that category for the State in which the community is located:</text><clause id="H87246355BFF942E2B8FA67810BDE0FB1" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Black.</text></clause><clause id="HDB108E58773E4ED6BA00B8A9F3CA392F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>African American.</text></clause><clause id="H160FEC969BE241368FBCA0C8D383FCEB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Asian.</text></clause><clause id="HA5D3E67432C247788F6F3EA0907C99E0" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Pacific Islander.</text></clause><clause id="H43384E9BD0034832BA235FE5EF738306" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Other non-White race.</text></clause><clause id="H6652FA04993E49EAAA8DD6D96C7A2CAD" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Hispanic.</text></clause><clause id="H2BCA1ECD35144491BBBEF115BBC12EAE" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Latino.</text></clause><clause id="H9D39A3BC05854E4585C562A7F9A3905C" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Linguistically isolated.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8CAF0BA1FAF4CEAB0C32BD985C0A371" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Tribal or Indigenous communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD9E3127AC7648D8BE359DB020D8794F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Escape</header><text>The term <term>escape</term> means the escape of juvenile- or adult-farmed organisms, viable gametes, or fertilized eggs spawned by farmed organisms from aquaculture facilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CCA586F4142471CB9352928491B1026"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Exclusive economic zone</header><text>The term <term>exclusive economic zone</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3(11) of the Magnuson Stevens Fishery Conservation and Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1802">16 U.S.C. 1802(11)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE97DB51C2E194DB38C5D93DE775C14DD" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB52DE2458A641DBB0FBA8E3E9EF9D48"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Offshore aquaculture</header><text>The term <term>offshore aquaculture</term> means aquaculture conducted in the exclusive economic zone. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90ECC77C62A2468AA7A5AD48551B29C6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Pilot project</header><text>The term <term>pilot project</term> means an aquaculture project approved under section 5.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA11C73A141664075952EB6F043AD4357"><enum>(10)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each commonwealth, territory, or possession of the United States, and each Indian Tribe. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H134EB9067E10480B8C19DDCD37AD1F3B" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Tribal or Indigenous community</header><text>The term <term>Tribal or Indigenous community</term> means a population of people who are—</text><subparagraph id="H024E79380BCE49C19AD0910BD77BD828" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enrolled members of an Indian Tribe;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE546FF1CDA084B729518602E3AD5E469" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members of an Alaska Native or Native Hawaiian community or organization; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53B38C4B5BA749D9A42822ABF429BD1D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>members of any other community of Indigenous people located in a State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H919A1CC25C8F49A1BF91C4C3BD78ECE3" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Underserved communities</header><subparagraph id="H0825694782004513890468DA9C8292ED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>underserved communities</term> means women and individuals belonging to communities that have been denied consistent and systematic fair, just, and impartial treatment and have been systematically denied a full opportunity to participate in all aspects of economic, social, and civic life, including Black, Latino, Indigenous and Native American persons, Asian Americans and Pacific Islanders and other persons of color.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE433A25E036444B89FA6744E3068C9B0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>In the context of the aquaculture industry, the term <term>underserved communities</term>, within fishing communities, may include—</text><clause id="HDE7A9B91D1CE483681C0440236207246"><enum>(i)</enum><text>subsistence fishery participants and their dependents;</text></clause><clause id="HDCAFA01C40B54D93BC390FECAA4D9821"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>fishing vessel crews, and fish processor and distribution workers; and</text></clause><clause id="H503D8BD73B11413088581C8D6ABF7191"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>territorial fishing communities (including those in American Samoa, Guam, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, and the United States Virgin Islands). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8C8F4FDF57C41EABA89FCBE2D5A3B24"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text>The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H9450EC19047544D6B90A94E3CABB4C9F"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO study</header><subsection id="H811181279D384F71B3CD97D00F11ACF1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section, the Comptroller General shall submit a report to the appropriate committees of Congress examining aquaculture permitting, monitoring, and regulation during the 15-year period ending on the date of enactment of this section based on the available literature, case studies, and stakeholder input.</text></subsection><subsection id="H924F33B41C854BD79101FECE99B0F762"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents of study</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H8D710372FD0B4DB0B4839CEAB49918AD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider the feasibility and potential positive and negative implications of designating a lead agency to issue aquaculture permits in a timely manner;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H197823278DE84FB8872AEED6D64C7CF8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify lessons learned during such period with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H461693C5CFE94161B541D7C91F1183D3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the implications of aquaculture type, location, and regulatory framework on project success;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35E3EFBD2AAF402D914E2C806BD70B2F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the degree of involvement of coastal or adjacent States, Tribal groups, underserved communities, or environmental justice communities in consultation, planning, or operations of such aquaculture operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H56C55E972A944D42A4CE3EB21F2F0F8C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>safety protocols and risk mitigation measures for the permit and oversight processes, including—</text><clause id="H380357A8BB0A40BABAEF831152569531"><enum>(i)</enum><text>escape prevention measures;</text></clause><clause id="HAA2E54E7CA6C404A881DC06BE55CFD26"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>emergency event response planning;</text></clause><clause id="H3330C49D617141B6BFB7CAE3BC3E5DAB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>compliance monitoring, particularly in remote locations;</text></clause><clause id="H143B5700F7804DD0B3905C29F84469E7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>compliance with Federal laws;</text></clause><clause id="H54307D592D7641979D38F125E39C7FDB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>reporting mechanisms to appropriate Federal authorities, and</text></clause><clause id="H9580ABC01C9C44769F3FC0E1FC2D09C8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>vessel navigation aids to ensure navigational safety;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H193D0958A5DC4A1AB880F97E78131C71" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the effect of incentives to reduce adverse effects or disparate impacts from aquaculture operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC88411FED292463A82A2D60AB801D530" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>building and optimizing synergies between aquaculture and wild-caught fishing activities, or offshore, nearshore, and onshore aquaculture activities, including market development, increasing seafood consumption, and shared infrastructure;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C0817E89AEC487DB42F2D532AC59D70"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the environmental effects of marine aquaculture operations, including mechanisms to prevent harm to the environment, wildlife, or human well-being;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4480AF58ED749ECBF5E7F2FCA46A8D2" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>net economic and social benefits of the aquaculture projects, particularly for nearby communities (including underserved and environmental justice communities), based on project size, regulatory structures, and financing structures;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93A827BBDAEE4EC3B330EEA94EB0BF6E" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the impact of introducing aquaculture products to the marketplace on supply and demand for wild-capture fisheries products and methods for ensuring resiliency and growth for both aquaculture and wild-capture fisheries products;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A02737E74424572AA79A6D47EF003F4" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>mechanisms to enhance capital investment, workforce development, and equitable opportunity requirements or assistance programs in the permit process, or to diversify permit applicants; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4987D145A40A4855BD073D5944226D50" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>outstanding needs for continued research, development, education activities, programs, and funding regarding offshore aquaculture projects and development of the domestic workforce and entrepreneurship related to offshore aquaculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD418819524AB446D88389926A3ECF6A9" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the economic potential for both large- and small-scale aquaculture operations to generate a positive return on investment under various regulatory and financing structures; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H949DD228613D402E9B5791E709413067" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make recommendations with respect to future offshore aquaculture operations, including—</text><subparagraph id="HD940AE815699472C994A5CA307278E58" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regulatory processes necessary for permitting, monitoring, and oversight, including processes and techniques related to siting, deployment, operations, and decommissioning;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3EDC10F9CAA24B749EB1BFAA6DBA7C39" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>potential safeguards, data collection, or monitoring required to minimize disparate impacts on environmental justice communities, local economies, marine environments, and existing domestic economic sectors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9753BAB65BB4FD39B9555C6F7A8148C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>mechanisms for optimizing the efficiency and coordination among Federal agencies with a role in permitting aquaculture in offshore waters without compromising the goals of such permitting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3AE9280CB8404D88BFC7747AF656B8F0" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>methods for effectively involving stakeholders, including—</text><clause id="H564B47F891B44848A4855D46BDA6D9AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>adjacent jurisdictions;</text></clause><clause id="HDDBB917376D04B23AA11206A7B06121C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>local communities;</text></clause><clause id="HA4F75E26268D43B6B8ADE43DDE1D6F16"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>regional offshore waters users and management groups (including regional fishery management councils); and</text></clause><clause id="H8FA157345CF7411FB57D8442394CD17D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>users of local, State, and Federal waters and coastal resources, including underserved communities, and environmental justice communities;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC3FA08149D344D8A171ABBF009EB600"><enum>(E)</enum><text>best practices for incorporating local knowledge, including from Tribal or Indigenous communities; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBE1DEAECF2E4941850327DEF723590B" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Federal agency capabilities that are necessary for effective regulation of the sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9AB8F2D1B6E4CA795715948883C48CE" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">how creating private rights of action or waiving sovereign immunity would facilitate or hinder the development of offshore aquaculture projects and their acceptance by nearshore and offshore waters user groups and coastal communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H240AAD2CA521415995051C373EEB6F88"><enum>4.</enum><header>Study of aquaculture permitting standards</header><subsection id="H9D9BEB0CBD6D4753BEFD1D0818EE94DC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Ocean Studies Board of the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine shall complete a study to develop the scientific basis for efficient and effective regulation of offshore aquaculture.</text></subsection><subsection id="H132C9037CA1F47D4AF6F3B5C00625305"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The study required by subsection (a) shall, with respect to offshore aquaculture—</text><paragraph id="HD137A70008414396AEACDD985BC23D53"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identify—</text><subparagraph id="H69B8CAD013574EA0B979FC1F0E76821F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>optimal methods of operation of aquaculture facilities to promote high yields and limit adverse effects on the environment, wildlife, and human well-being, including—</text><clause id="H57ADBB003DC44A298831C8326182F036"><enum>(i)</enum><text>considerations to guide siting decisions of such facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="HC954E38BE27C446AA1C79EBB4954C5F6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>appropriate stocking densities; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6308EDE08A624360B02BB29FB80CB16D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a science-based definition of sustainable aquaculture feed or other inputs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1DAAB17644544A309D2CDBB4C7B2A866"><enum>(C)</enum><text>potential adverse effects on the environment, wildlife, and human well-being, including from—</text><clause id="H3B8F2DDA92FD496BBA550C9B5BE1FB92"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the use of antibiotics and other pharmaceuticals by aquaculture facilities, including analyses necessary to establish acceptable rates, impact levels, and risk thresholds, such as organism antibiotic consumption or metabolization versus excretion to the surrounding environment;</text></clause><clause id="HA0117D6DD4744D4ABCF74BD3DE0ED4FF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assimilation of pollution originating from such facilities on marine organisms;</text></clause><clause id="H50411281033849F69E30EAB247379325"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the risk posed by misplaced or damaged equipment;</text></clause><clause id="H9DA87FC534294FBABE215DD3196E1EB5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the risk of wildlife entanglements;</text></clause><clause id="HF4D75E19BC954D7595B29181C4E82566"><enum>(v)</enum><text>interbreeding or the spread of disease;</text></clause><clause id="H6BDBBD6C2A5C4DDEB8183F30F1DD1696"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the source and sustainability of brood stock for offshore aquaculture operations and impacts of hatcheries and prestocking rearing operations that are specific to offshore aquaculture;</text></clause><clause id="HF99CA721F4F6466D81165A7D9BF787F6"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>large-scale cultivation of filter-feed bivalve organisms and seaweed on the marine food webs;</text></clause><clause id="H7F934521596C4DCCBF45AB69A3EF1A26"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>aquaculture facilities acting as aggregating devices and increasing the vulnerability of wild fisheries and wildlife populations to fishing or other sources of mortality; and</text></clause><clause id="HBCDF51B1A560466F95DA10CFBE05E1AA"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the use of nonsustainable sources of feed or other inputs;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H465C24F109F84FAEBBC3E2B0B15D38F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>potential methods and technologies to mitigate adverse effects, including those identified under subparagraph (C);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0856DC14312D4BDAA9CC2BFF7F6BD606"><enum>(E)</enum><text>potential conflicts and solutions to mitigate such conflicts between offshore aquaculture facilities and other users of the offshore environment;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77B0B47C16E14AA499ABDF1421F000E9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the types of data and qualitative information necessary for the optimal operation of such facilities and appropriate methods of procuring such data information, including from citizen science (as defined in section 402 of the Crowdsourcing and Citizen Science Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3724">15 U.S.C. 3724</external-xref>) and the traditional aquaculture knowledge of Tribal and Indigenous communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4618A4B949A4B22BAAFAFB295597455"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the applicability and sufficiency of existing regulatory systems on offshore aquaculture;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0C2514E4737416785B2979DE7858269"><enum>(H)</enum><text>existing local, State, Federal, and foreign regulatory standards that may serve as models for efficient and effective regulation of offshore aquaculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17E4998F7A9F4F50840BDB9CE720EE9C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the considerations necessary to account for the effects of climate change predictive assessments on the siting and operation of offshore aquaculture facilities; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46A0332EBC0A44E2B20CD02052D45371"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide legislative and regulatory recommendations with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H8472CC0ADEFA426BB2AAF93336486804"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting the methods of operation identified under paragraph (1)(A); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H937CEA6A90004C93BC26918BF35017C9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mitigating adverse effects identified under paragraph (2)(B);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H654F7D7A06EF47C8830F4780FDA65292"><enum>(C)</enum><text>environmental standards, control rules, or reference points that build upon the existing public and private standards for aquaculture sustainability; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5E9F06EC1854BAF8CD4C4333F46400E"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring that operators of offshore aquaculture facilities adhere to international standards for social responsibility, public health, and equitable labor practices, including with respect to sourcing inputs for such facilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8C56B5496B4544FDA6879F4329D96487"><enum>5.</enum><header>Assessment program for offshore aquaculture</header><subsection id="HFFE14D0E58224FB2A5FDE5FF29AADAFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish an assessment program to evaluate the following with respect to offshore aquaculture:</text><paragraph id="HA0DD60CA1AAE4E8CB77D96991981D029"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The ability of different commercial-scale facility designs and operational methods to—</text><subparagraph id="H468458E332A44DC5BD4805E7B576B85B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>survive various atmospheric and ocean conditions, including high wind speeds or high-energy ocean conditions associated with severe weather, without—</text><clause id="H37D0875E90C3433C81A23FC8F784480D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>allowing escapes of cultivated organisms;</text></clause><clause id="HB221D7D15B6E4E9894698FC1BE8D275C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>loss of infrastructure; or</text></clause><clause id="H268C9BE5C3374CA59FABEA3B96906C57"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">wildlife entanglement resulting from loss or damaged infrastructure;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7FCB9F8CE9841E081238B018176666A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prevent adverse wildlife impacts, including entanglements of large whales, sea turtles, and other species protected under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9108D77EB00941EF8BCDBB631F49A14F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">prevent adverse impacts on the marine environment, including impacts to habitat, water chemistry, and wildlife; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEA2B7038A0CB42A79F3C4F1C10FA1F21"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">avoid adverse impacts on navigation and safety to existing ocean users due to aquaculture facilities, including requirements for operations, navigation, and transit associated with such facilities. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H45607498C468483F92FD5D52965586F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The ability for different technologies to provide reliable and timely data on offshore aquaculture facilities (including visual data and other relevant data types) to enable the Administrator to monitor—</text><subparagraph id="H9AA17A6FEDD24181B26DC37DF075F031"><enum>(A)</enum><text>project compliance with the requirements of subsection (b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DD5F687AF554007B9A5444E8A3DBE59"><enum>(B)</enum><text>impacts on the marine environment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4EB7CFDE31FA4C88A91915727EA9B995"><enum>(C)</enum><text>interference with existing uses of the water body in which the project is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H17B64D8229E745669D87A4C8017DE691"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The relative risks, benefits, and cost of various types of aquaculture, including different species of finfish in different geographies and under varying climactic and ecological conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A34F026F7814C2489506BD3F59A454B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The development of performance standards for offshore aquaculture operations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB083A67086834583B0E568544FAE6745"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pilot project selection</header><paragraph id="H79411F7D8168412BA6D3553512A9A0F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Solicitation</header><text>The Administrator shall solicit and accept applications for participation in the assessment program from projects that would advance the objectives of subsection (a), including—</text><subparagraph id="H4062F2AD777147C48EC541FA690C2143"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">objective analyses of data from commercial-scale and other demonstration projects existing or carried out in offshore waters of the United States or other countries within the past 15 years; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17730119B8614BE6A4B2450E7C456EB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">pilot projects proposed to be operated in the exclusive economic zone. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H48EF8AB8A58C465DB35586FCCAC5C0B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall publish in the Federal Register a notice summarizing each application received under this section and invite and consider public comments regarding the pilot projects proposed under those applications for their inclusion in the assessment program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H411ED0B2CCDC4A42BCFBBDCF9BFB13C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation of adjacent coastal jurisdictions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall promulgate a mechanism for identifying and designating, with respect to each pilot project application received under paragraph (1), the nearest adjacent coastal jurisdiction or jurisdictions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H429B348123274652A989304A2F9BCFD4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The Administrator shall provide a copy of each pilot project application to each adjacent coastal jurisdiction designated under paragraph (3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5926FAE295F54064871B2838179197DA"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Denial at the request of adjacent coastal jurisdiction</header><text>If, in the 60-day period after receiving notice of a pilot project application under paragraph (4), an adjacent coastal jurisdiction requests that the Secretary rejects such application, the Secretary shall reject such application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0059975E57174E2B9B1D9A5E34271124"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Pilot project approval</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall approve not less than 1 and not more than 4 applications for aquaculture pilot projects that—</text><subparagraph id="H0F0455CC50994AFFAB98645C8AFF4040"><enum>(A)</enum><text>cultivate species that pose minimal threat of harm to wildlife and the ecosystem in which the project is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A3A43B12837443D9EA2E6978E029862"><enum>(B)</enum><text>incorporate design and operational characteristics that minimize the risk of escape, wildlife entanglement, and adverse pollution impacts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9C6D60EEABE448B86227798686D475B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have developed and are able to implement an escape response and infrastructure loss or damage plan that minimizes the impact of any escapes or infrastructure loss or damage on the marine environment and on other uses of the water body in which the project is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H28842141A64E42769F8C0A045B10C934"><enum>(D)</enum><text>comply with all applicable requirements of the Clean Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1851">33 U.S.C. 1851 et seq.</external-xref>), the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>), and the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC4B19F892A244849A9298B90DCF4CAF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>are compatible with, and prevent or minimize displacement of, existing uses and users of the marine environment in which it is located;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BBEC832235C4ACCB55B51ACCE289F4D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>will conform to best practices to avoid or minimize the use of antibiotics and other pharmaceuticals and minimize the release of such pharmaceuticals into the environment; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D849C364A61481189705AEB2862FB5A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>will be conducted over a period of 5 years. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F833D5EFEB148518FD0F515DEFDFCCE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Aquaculture Opportunity Area</header><text>The Administrator may elect to site a project approved under this section in an Aquaculture Opportunity Area. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA363B0C4746E4A6FAE443D234B6C4A4C"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Permit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall issue the appropriate permits to allow each pilot project approved under paragraph (6) to conduct offshore aquaculture activities in the exclusive economic zone in accordance with this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H76BE863C66E14F6D812493ED99C3CC3D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority consideration</header><text>In considering pilot project applications, the Administrator shall give priority consideration to pilot projects owned or operated by—</text><paragraph id="HC31227B6BF2D4B999852ED07368F2DBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>veterans, or entities in which a veteran or veterans have a majority ownership interest;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9588556CB434295B42B001A5F77A706"><enum>(2)</enum><text>members of an environmental justice community or underserved community, or entities in which a member or members of an environmental justice community or underserved community have a majority ownership interest; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD7EBC3CD3A44CA90F88FC12E6036EC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>entities that primarily serve or employ members of an environmental justice community or underserved community; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA510A75FF3040D9BE6E28CA4952C795"><enum>(4)</enum><text>applicants who can demonstrate that the pilot project will directly benefit individuals who are already participating in the agricultural, wild-caught fishery, and aquaculture industries who have been negatively impacted by the COVID–19 pandemic, natural disasters, or disaster declarations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4539C0F5B75C4A248CF8F80C99FF84F1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interim final rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may make an interim final rule to implement the requirements under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H039494A49DAC46BE917A10F0EDB4C984"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Assessment program participant reporting</header><paragraph id="HC06910FA038044BF82D22E5DDE4DF9B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Data and monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner or operator of each commercial-scale demonstration project or pilot project approved for inclusion in the assessment program under this section shall submit such documentation, in such time, place, and manner as the Administrator determines appropriate, including—</text><subparagraph id="H81DC7CABEA754780B74547231BA3B982"><enum>(A)</enum><text>production data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE4274DD19764BD392B9670C7C0BFB90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interactions with wild species, mitigation measures taken, and the result;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H100B5581A50B4148824C31AD784AC7CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>technology and operational practices used to measure and monitor effluent, integrity of cage materials and other gear, and health of the cultivated species;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82F6B6C843E24C438CC8B0F5893AF74E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>environmental and ecosystem impacts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB42E4F85A79428691CB268E2532AF8E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>data necessary to assess the considerations described in section 4(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79F123896E134331B683514815DAE4B9" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>information necessary for the Secretary to make a revocation or modification determination under subsection (f);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AC6314E162E402196C1FDFEA8B2D02F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>owner, operator, and employee demographic data and other relevant data as determined by the Administrator for purposes of assessing the pilot project’s direct benefits to environmental justice communities and the economic and social benefits for nearby coastal communities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC42D36F5F4BF438DB03C45CB5DB50F6B"><enum>(H)</enum><text>navigation and safety impacts to existing ocean users; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H622930EA0EAF4F3F86CA8CD0E517E726"><enum>(I)</enum><text>such additional information as the Administrator requires to fulfill the goals and objectives of the assessment program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE7818A75074E749A4AEE2E39973F8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Administrator shall, upon request, provide technical assistance to owners and operators of commercial-scale demonstration projects and pilot projects to comply with the reporting requirements of this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55382E8E10284A73ABC61942DAF9EEAA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Emergency reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall establish an emergency reporting process for each owner or operator of an aquaculture pilot project approved under this section to immediately report suspected or known interactions between pilot project facilities or vessels and protected wild species.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE16B7B20AA9149B080B27AE87D56D83A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authority To revoke or modify pilot project participation</header><text>The Administrator may require modifications to, or terminate pilot project participation under this section, and order the removal of an offshore aquaculture facility authorized to operate under this section if—</text><paragraph id="H8DF7503D7DE042CFB4A5A6AACF621CCC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the project incurs an incident involving a death or serious personal injury, and the Administrator determines that project operator negligence was the cause or a contributing factor to such incident;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H458445933C034C5FAE1DFAC63D0B1173"><enum>(2)</enum><text>operation of the project results in a violation of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Marine Mammal Protection Act of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1361">16 U.S.C. 1361 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43363C7B1F9047F68E47AA35387BF398"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the pilot project owner or operator fails to comply with all of the terms and conditions of the pilot program approval or modifications required by the Administrator under this subsection; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68748B8E27C04F08B4DDBF40BA130F09" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Administrator determines that continued participation in the pilot program by the project would be unsafe or result in unacceptable negative impacts to the marine environment or nearby communities, or other users of the water body in which the project is located.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6653B29FCD9942EC8A08A4D8F3883B8C"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H329152D570224BC5870F2162CCC13A44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for the duration of the assessment program, the Administrator shall publish, make available to the public, and submit to aquaculture stakeholders (including each adjacent coastal jurisdiction and each affected Tribal or Indigenous community, regional fishery management council, interstate fisheries commission, conservation organization, and fisheries association) a report that includes the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H48558BD83C6149F1B7576F9E939E8028"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of each approved pilot project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H601040D5586C4521AC1A855C65ABA8DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the first report, documentation supporting selection of each approved pilot project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F9A979C938E471ABF05A1F80A9195D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A summary of the information reported to the Administrator under subsection (e) for each approved pilot project.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E4BEB70CE754AC49646AE47EE56BBB0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a description of the progress made toward meeting the goals described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB424FBA95D1D48BB95C9BE91E7EA4F6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the completion of the assessment program, the Administrator shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report describing the results of the pilot program that includes the following information:</text><subparagraph id="H3CF045C9795C484BA6A2D5BF9ACA0364"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An evaluation based on data from the assessment program of the opportunities and risks of offshore aquaculture regarding—</text><clause id="H710FA1EBCBD7496DB1BF9EAC3485A80B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>marine ecosystems;</text></clause><clause id="H935A440308654554805A7E1DED7E0347"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other users of the exclusive economic zone;</text></clause><clause id="H8398D250077E4D729E591A2B7034407F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>other ecosystems goods and services;</text></clause><clause id="H54BA4564EB914A4A80E61785C4DC8C7B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>social and economic impacts to nearby communities, including cumulative impacts and impacts on environmental justice communities, low-income communities, and communities of color;</text></clause><clause id="H98908BB262E740DD972D8D0F1FEC8066"><enum>(v)</enum><text>best practices to mitigate risks; and</text></clause><clause id="H5841BD76586E4215929A5B754667CBDC"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>best practices to prevent disparate impacts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD8BC7520FBE43E5A6D62ED42B19A912"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any recommendations of the Administrator for amendments to statutes or regulations and the establishment of performance standards for offshore aquaculture siting and operations, that—</text><clause id="HEFFACA42D81C478B8B38894B713F0F71"><enum>(i)</enum><text>would minimize risks posed by aquaculture operations to marine ecosystems;</text></clause><clause id="H28A4E3A07B794D238CDA506922557C48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>would enhance the safe operation of aquaculture facilities, service vessels, and associated activities;</text></clause><clause id="H352D6A16034C4A09AA2010B0C7B4F68F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>prevent displacement of existing uses and users; and</text></clause><clause id="HB828393574CB4E928024D3F7D11ED3FD"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>are technically, operationally, and economically feasible.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HBAD5616C4ED94322A17F231D57718741"><enum>6.</enum><header>Aquaculture centers of excellence</header><subsection id="H3A51125494604A8991378F97117A5368"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minority aquaculture research and entrepreneurship grants</header><paragraph id="HB9C84CE38A3F46FCB0A8F223AAD4BD79"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Administrator shall establish the <quote>Aquaculture Centers of Excellence</quote> program to award grants to covered institutions to assist in establishing or enhancing an aquaculture curriculum for undergraduate or graduate courses of study at such covered institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF951DF965BE8403CA1A086D7ABDCDD55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, a covered institution shall submit to the Administrator an application in such form, at such time, and containing such information as the Administrator determines appropriate, including any plans to partner with other institutions of higher education pursuant to paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA123C3D11B534282921A82504850976E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant uses</header><text>A covered institution receiving a grant under this section—</text><subparagraph id="HF6202FD28098407FBA6FFC739DCA51F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall use such grant funds to establish or enhance an aquaculture curriculum for undergraduate or graduate studies that includes—</text><clause id="H3264A6521BB84292960B9E90A09A266C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>training in various skill sets needed by successful aquaculture entrepreneurs, including—</text><subclause id="H1F57E92576AB4B0B875730DAFA63AA5C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>business management, strategic planning, business plan development, capital financing and fundraising, financial management and accounting, market analysis and competitive analysis, and market entry and strategy execution; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H67AD892502E84667BC88C82BEDC7987F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any other skill sets specific to the needs of the student population and the surrounding community, including social and environmental sustainability, as determined by the institution;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H045858AAA34343E585C9B2A29BB510AF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>natural and social science research programs in aquaculture and natural fisheries, including offshore aquaculture;</text></clause><clause id="HE0CD2C4C67B140CD840FCEF459F96CF8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>development of extension programs (or cooperation with existing extension programs) that educate and engage community members, including elementary and secondary school students, on aquaculture and aquaculture career pathways that transfer newly developed techniques and research information developed or collated at the covered institution to aquaculture practitioners; and</text></clause><clause id="H7DB6A7FEEC604ACBACB65DDD6AEB6A24"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>career development, such as the establishment of cooperatives, apprenticeships, mentorships, accelerators, or grant competitions; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2732E27CCD8E4D55ADEC894B2691582F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may only use such grant funds for expenses directly related to the implementation of the curriculum or activities authorized by this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAFA607304514AA09ADC49227F36ABB9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying for and carrying out activities with grants under this section, a covered institution may partner with other institutions of higher education with established aquaculture programs, including institutions of higher education not otherwise eligible for grants under this section, to facilitate the sharing of resources and knowledge necessary for aquaculture curriculum development or enhancement at the covered institution. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF384FF88108B4C3F9182B117C2059171"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Grant limitations</header><text>A grant awarded under this section may only be used for expenses directly related to the implementation of the curriculum or activities authorized by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1A197F86239499D86BE852FBFFEF401"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 to remain available until expended, for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26478177C19049A381A0576E05AA2642"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H04AB60A816BF404E896779A381D55EE5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered institution</header><text>The term <term>covered institution</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H628DE173BD4D47D2A2E58DA5CD650B92"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a minority-serving institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB9E48148F5F14A8492A1A4A408979833"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a historically Black college or university; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41EC2921E25F4450B5567F02C0F92FD8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Tribal College or University. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DBFDD94494A4146872AFC78C1BED587"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historically Black college or university</header><text>The term <term>historically Black college or university</term> has the meaning given the term <term>part B institution</term> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF624E41C43407DA6CF46E8BA64007C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9085910FFA1641E2B282CEB38203F55D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an eligible institution described in paragraphs (2), (4), (5), (6), and (7) of section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H811D352C56F143C1A638CFDA2D2F5BAB" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Tribal College or University</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Tribal College or University</term> means and institution described in section 316(b)(3) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>) that is chartered under the sovereign authority of its respective Tribal Nation or by the Federal Government. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H71DE1F04A4AD4B24BD50E49AD747F78B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any requirement in this Act to identify or consider an impact or effect on human health, the environment, or the climate shall include a requirement to make such identification or consideration while taking into account—</text><paragraph id="HCDD7D45C492645A7A0F4AFD53362E905"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the cumulative impact of such impact or effect in the context of all sources of emissions, discharges, or releases from any source, past, present, or in the reasonably foreseeable future, on the affected environment and population;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFE184F0DB364A0488E72E7539717E16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any characteristics of such environment and population that may heighten vulnerability to environmental pollution and related health risks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19B84B99C5724778B18453ECEB3EA4CF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any action or practice that, even if appearing neutral, has the effect of subjecting individuals to discrimination on the basis of race, color, or national origin.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

