<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6A0934059184C94A7A8E9F3262B6F2C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8574 IH: Global Catastrophic Risk Management Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8574</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001157">Mr. McCaul</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish an interagency committee on global catastrophic risk, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6F9F4033CDD54D9FBEF1E37306F108E2" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HD8C50F916BE2436AA26AF46F6BDFE020"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Catastrophic Risk Management Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1150EB98E74E40BE98CAB8E8AB718FFA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H5575086352D44B478862887CA4822C1F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic need</header><text>The term <term>basic need</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H1D44B08815FD4CF99A43680AE2BAE42C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any good, service, or activity necessary to protect the health, safety, and general welfare of the civilian population of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB32E1AF5BD054031BD8855D7C7221C2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="H954CB354C3184F589296F0433A3DB494"><enum>(i)</enum><text>food;</text></clause><clause id="HCC0682CE5E454B94BC36399A68B7579A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>water;</text></clause><clause id="HFF4F6B1C76054B54B0CE7BE4C49A854A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shelter;</text></clause><clause id="HB3ACBF18DB3F4C668CBBD69DC2E7DD80"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>basic communication services; and</text></clause><clause id="H0DE163BB6262455287A3619B81D2697B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(v)</enum><text>public safety. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB30D266CA051483B99A098B57AA57671"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Catastrophic incident</header><text>The term <term>catastrophic incident</term> means an incident, whether caused by human or natural events, in which multiple levels of United States critical infrastructure are destroyed, damaged or interrupted in sufficient magnitude to threaten the health, safety, or general welfare of the civilian population of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C039D298836463D8557B16246FC69F6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Committee</header><text>The term <term>committee</term> means the interagency committee on global catastrophic risk established under section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2982126DA40C41FAB59D0C77B2DFDEA2" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Critical infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>critical infrastructure</term> has the meaning given the term in section 1016(e) of the Critical Infrastructure Protection Act of 2001 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5195c">42 U.S.C. 5195c(e)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6640B18A5E83488288A757E6E5F844C1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Existential risk</header><text>The term <term>existential risk</term> means the risk of human extinction.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65B55CFE68574D358460524C7EAA060B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Global catastrophic risk</header><text>The term <term>global catastrophic risk</term> means the risk of events or incidents consequential enough to significantly harm, set back, or destroy human civilization at the global scale. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7015EE89E18848988A9F83C883ECFBFF"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Global catastrophic and existential threats</header><text>The term <term>global catastrophic and existential threats</term> means those threats that with varying likelihood can produce consequences severe enough to result in significant harm or destruction of human civilization at the global scale, or lead to human extinction. Examples of global catastrophic and existential threats include severe global pandemics, nuclear war, asteroid and comet impacts, supervolcanoes, sudden and severe changes to the climate, and intentional or accidental threats arising from the use and development of emerging technologies. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FC6E2D3BB52453A86D84BF42CE299A0"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National exercise</header><text>The term <term>national exercise</term> means a national exercise described in section 648(b) of the Post-Katrina Emergency Management Reform Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/748">6 U.S.C. 748(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H914C01D16A854F12A0997979BF8873DC"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, that is individually identified (including parenthetically) in the most recent list published pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>). </text></paragraph></section><section id="H9C57D61041EF4DF29FA3154830147A34"><enum>3.</enum><header>Interagency committee on global catastrophic risk</header><subsection id="HFFC73811456B4A6A8F165AFFCE951FD2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall establish an interagency committee on global catastrophic risk.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBA185076B7854FE89B0A93020AFF6150"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The committee shall include senior representatives of—</text><paragraph id="H00D1E8A2B5EC48E78D5A0913E3F0259D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06E7087AFABF49BD88F8214BAEF7B621"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33E8E4A812CF479A86635A9904F8340F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Director of National Intelligence and the Director of the National Intelligence Council;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE437256933CA4DEA8CB64662E6590941"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4794FCED26B8456686BAF039465C6638"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Secretary of State and the Under Secretary of State for Arms Control and International Security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ADBC10DC3434B65958C7A8AFDC96717"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Attorney General and the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A81DCE2DFFB4CB4A36A52BEAA3D5377"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy, the Under Secretary of Energy for Nuclear Security, and the Director of Science;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72E760D4F7774FC4B814B6E2D492CE53"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Assistant Secretary for Preparedness and Response;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0AF04C3C0244BBC88BEF2AC4F8A96C6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere, and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Standards and Technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE52C8AE0CF3643868268B840017F1F49"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior and the Director of the United States Geological Survey;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H283322973AF34CC9824FD41890CE0208"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DD0094EEDA94043968F5E483A0231E8"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2728B1C1CBAD4D57B0058C70BFA6948B"><enum>(13)</enum><text>the Director of the National Science Foundation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45BB3DA94F904943AD00618DEDA444BD"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Treasury;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H039DBB88F9D143FFAA1072EA3B2F17BE"><enum>(15)</enum><text>the Chair of the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A32CE1065064E0F85E8EEF3E8CB3D1C"><enum>(16)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EB4DD144CAF40188F82FDE31876A722"><enum>(17)</enum><text>other stakeholders the President determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6FD298152EA749A6A6DA27CDF04CBF68"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chairmanship</header><text>The committee shall be co-chaired by a senior representative of the President and the Deputy Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency for Resilience.</text></subsection></section><section id="H54CE082610014517B1A0C68EF4CFC0FD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report required</header><subsection id="HB7FFB957C485427D9E3C802B07F1CA7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the President, with support from the committee, shall conduct and submit to Congress a detailed assessment of global catastrophic and existential risk.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E127A5C609842AE991AD5D645474B55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters covered</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H91E9D14E219F453C99E8F16326788B70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expert estimates of cumulative global catastrophic and existential risk in the next 30 years, including separate estimates for the likelihood of occurrence and potential consequences;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D0B700AD7324A479B5AD086E87AB26C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expert-informed analyses of the risk of the most concerning specific global catastrophic and existential threats, including separate estimates, where reasonably feasible and credible, of each threat for its likelihood of occurrence and its potential consequences, as well as associated uncertainties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H829D27DE2AA84605A47CBC953A1858EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a comprehensive list of potential catastrophic or existential threats, including even those that may have very low likelihood;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H104E74EAA19945E48AF60782044AA66C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>technical assessments and lay explanations of the analyzed global catastrophic and existential risks, including their qualitative character and key factors affecting their likelihood of occurrence and potential consequences;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0C56DB04C1C4D3E991389A22A744D00"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an explanation of any factors that limit the ability of the President to assess the risk both cumulatively and for particular threats, and how those limitations may be overcome through future research or with additional resources, programs, or authorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24F6FC9AD6E746C8B4C7C52EA92CB309"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a review of the effectiveness of intelligence collection, early warning and detection systems, or other functions and programs necessary to evaluate the risk of particular global catastrophic and existential threats, if any exist and as applicable for particular threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC542147C9CA84322BD9CC393B0450A63"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a forecast of if and why global catastrophic and existential risk is likely to increase or decrease significantly in the next 30 years, both qualitatively and quantitatively, as well as a description of associated uncertainties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H420F71B8F7C04827BED7AB860215ED53"><enum>(8)</enum><text>proposals for how the Federal Government may more adequately assess global catastrophic and existential risk on an ongoing basis in future years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H671E57D7B1854A92BA0A846D1D40713E"><enum>(9)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative actions, as appropriate, to support the evaluation and assessment of global catastrophic and existential risk; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60F7185615454E1FBDE645B27ED8DC3D"><enum>(10)</enum><text>other matters deemed appropriate by the President.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H412AB06D35A04D9BBD292D3214976E6D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation requirement</header><text>In producing the report required under subsection (a), the President shall regularly consult with experts on global catastrophic and existential risks, including from non-governmental, academic, and private sector institutions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C294BC7ACFC48488B3D04CB401E375F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. </text></subsection></section><section id="H24812EE50D224ADE9448698B0D6D319C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report on continuity of operations and continuity of government planning</header><subsection id="H8D7BDB044754492AAFF024A3EF5EEC8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the submission of the report required under section 4, the President shall produce a report on the adequacy of continuity of operations and continuity of government plans based on the assessed global catastrophic and existential risk.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D992F824345455DB7775D5CD0EEEF7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters covered</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H09BE4C65C77E4FA9A1CDBE9D4A24CA96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed assessment of the ability of continuity of government and continuity of operations plans and programs, as defined by Executive Order 13961, Presidential Policy Directive–40, or successor policies, to maintain national essential functions following global catastrophes, both cumulatively and for particular threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3430A247093445B7A71F966EA9089CF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the need to revise Executive Order 13961, Presidential Policy Directive–40, or successor policies to account for global catastrophic and existential risk cumulatively or for particular threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34720E881DC745BA9D2707F4C1DF48D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a budget proposal for continuity of government and continuity of operations programs necessary to adequately maintain national essential functions during global catastrophes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77C80DCA316244B2B3B700F462E4B4DA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative actions necessary to improve continuity of government and continuity of operations plans and programs; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H569326B8058E46C5AAB7D5F0CEE78792"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other matters deemed appropriate by the co-chairs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13E03AF850A342219B9D929FB594DC8B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H66BBD42F271B4A27BEF39BB291138D6F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Strategy to ensure the health, safety, and general welfare of the civilian population of the United States</header><subsection id="H60128DB7697C43A892EFECA09992CFB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the President, with support from the committee, shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a strategy to—</text><paragraph id="H11C77BBC25134D53B6B28A309D321200"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide for the basic needs of the civilian population of the United States that is impacted by catastrophic incidents in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D6F544570454391BC4E5A36FA88665B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>coordinate response efforts with State and local governments, the private sector, and nonprofit relief organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAFE4EC64E0F4897A53D9AA19198E9CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>promote personal and local readiness and non-reliance on government relief during periods of heightened tension or after catastrophic incidents; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90A5790FDF234BA098493196BEADD975"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop international partnerships with allied nations for the provision of relief services and goods.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA4E29A4D3E424378A0254476BBAFC3B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements of the strategy</header><text>The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall include a description of—</text><paragraph id="H6B01F84A72934184A503F49657423B7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actions the President will take to ensure the basic needs of the civilian population of the United States in a catastrophic incident are met;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02065AA569EC4C96AF4E4AFE1707C081"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how the President will coordinate with non-Federal entities to multiply resources and enhance relief capabilities, including—</text><subparagraph id="H34878D0332B5454FA30F4CB5CEE36038"><enum>(A)</enum><text>State and local governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEC7C46702374DBB903224044461EF3A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Tribal governments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9FC2A59903A64AF6B2633DAA30F9A304"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State disaster relief agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EEB132DA79D4831985607F34E55A836"><enum>(D)</enum><text>State and local disaster relief managers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06DD186576D423496BC76A659479A97"><enum>(E)</enum><text>State National Guards;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35A6C91F708C42BD9B9C2144AEFF801B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>law enforcement and first response entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2284C25E07634985AD572DC873629D7D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>nonprofit relief services;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H297A3E7F1EE24684AA6C2FE11698595C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>actions the President will take to enhance individual resiliency to the effects of a catastrophic incident, which actions shall include—</text><subparagraph id="H5AB8F8F96B594F978CF0F8FE4DB9F8A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>readiness alerts to the public during periods of elevated threat;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H348ED725C9A847198854A72BF14AA456"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to enhance domestic supply and availability of critical goods and basic necessities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98168B4244C84EB5B09845ED54BD6BDD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>information campaigns to ensure the public is aware of response plans and services that will be activated when necessary;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H435E68E198B04DD9B2A9FDDDC4A64CC8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>efforts the President will undertake and agreements the President will seek with international allies to enhance the readiness of the United States to provide for the general welfare;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H61869A74174C4CD79829A616BA215120"><enum>(5)</enum><text>how the strategic plan will be implemented should multiple levels of critical infrastructure be destroyed or taken offline entirely for an extended period of time;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6295C4E4656C47519BCC4F0B887F792E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>how the strategic plan will be made operational within the larger response strategy of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C3BAC1C5E994BFAA556AE7BC913783A"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the authorities the President would implicate in responding to a catastrophic incident.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8BFFA734DCD3497689A5BC00B438ABBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assumptions</header><text>In designing the strategy under subsection (a), the President shall account for certain factors to make the strategy operationally viable, including the assumption that—</text><paragraph id="H1E8C0B3237A54C369A623A81B58CC932"><enum>(1)</enum><text>multiple levels of critical infrastructure have been taken offline or destroyed by catastrophic incidents or the effects of catastrophic incidents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75FFB7CE4FCF4AA4BB897A5E1DE8B4B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impacted sectors include—</text><subparagraph id="H583A9E13062E4600B6F13685A34129CC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the transportation sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D25990B8FF845B6B58A50868D65E2CE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the communication sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8271F79A41274F8EB28D369EC31705EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the energy sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9178689310AD444581BECDB84C6C18CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the healthcare and public health sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3B798D479084E4B93B3F2D4B8C2475E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the water and wastewater sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H808EFEBA0E4E4011BA2DBB4D151F6646"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the financial sector;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8320299EA5FF41F8ACD2E74E37EF2AD5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State and local governments have been equally affected or made largely inoperable by catastrophic incidents or the effects of catastrophic incidents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47359E10CBF249FDB64AB94E9F3C47BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the emergency has exceeded the response capabilities of State and local governments under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5121">42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq.</external-xref>) and other relevant disaster response laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B8C5FBA01E840BC981E46BFCE2598A6"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States military is sufficiently engaged in armed or cyber conflict with State or non-State adversaries, or is otherwise unable to augment domestic response capabilities in a significant manner due to a catastrophic incident.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5C74DB324B54DA1AF65CA58A9BC3D30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Existing plans</header><text>The President may incorporate existing contingency plans in the strategy developed under subsection (a) so long as those contingency plans are amended to be operational in accordance with the requirements under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE529C7910EA4CC8858AD45407459775"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The strategy developed under subsection (a) shall be available to the public but may include a classified, or other restricted, annex to be made available to the appropriate committees of Congress and appropriate government entities.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCE479DF0917A45B485B6D7A9B3454DCC"><enum>7.</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the issuance of the strategy required under section 6, the President shall issue a plan to implement and operationalize the strategy, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HFF86726F8A8D42F289DBC6089F9B7390"><enum>(1)</enum><text>steps the President will take to prepare implicated entities for mobilization under the strategy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE360A9E6996A4A5684DC63EA8DFA904E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specific actions the President will take to—</text><subparagraph id="H5F1AEFB9CFB049BE944960618C321F1E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure the continued readiness of the United States to implement the strategy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD2156A8E72C413EA627418E11C41C8D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>educate the public on the strategy and the role individual citizens should play to ensure the objectives of the strategy are met;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD0D187ECE6A4487ADC5073E3C0ECF46"><enum>(C)</enum><text>ensure the objectives of the strategy are met; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF0EF9B75B340E1B2531523CD4B307D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure foreign adversaries are not able to undermine the operationalization of the strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H9CD03DD889AB4F58A5B962A20360E89C"><enum>8.</enum><header>National response exercise</header><subsection id="H72646C6573B24AEC852B52A8C7929A6F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the issuance of the implementation plan required under section 7, the Department of Homeland Security shall lead a national exercise, in coordination with the committee, to test and enhance the operationalization of the implementation plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3CBE3FA380F64389B4F77986E23DB560"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A national exercise conducted under this section shall include participation from most or all entities implicated by the strategy required under section 4, including:</text><paragraph id="H277B5D553750451593C38E15DDBD40A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>State, local, and Tribal governments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88FAFA010F314850A5EC9AE47B4BB2CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Information sharing and analysis centers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7ACD5EAF9A3B492F8194E09628C9BE3D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Owners and operators of critical infrastructure.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H173C84855F7F4018BE617BF87AF97612"><enum>9.</enum><header>Recommendations</header><subsection id="H83EE74244FB442268372A81EDC9F8E13"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall provide recommendations to Congress for—</text><paragraph id="HF766B45477774E479AD815A4AA68D937"><enum>(1)</enum><text>actions that should be taken to prepare the United States to implement the strategy required under section 6, increase readiness, and address preparedness gaps for responding to the impacts of catastrophic incidents on citizens of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7934C9DFF7C045B1B35339BF3F76A46D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>additional authorities that should be considered for Federal agencies and the President to more effectively implement the strategy required under section 6.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06B592DCF5B542638ABD1BE723E31A54"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion in reports</header><text>The President may include the recommendations required under subsection (a) in a report submitted under section 10.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD146F46722D5490C9813E5F99194AB74"><enum>10.</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date on which Department of Homeland Security leads the national exercise under section 8, the President shall submit to Congress a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H030140A1E74E438BA2DCF8D8CA5591C3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the efforts of the President to develop and update the strategy required under section 6;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EBDDF905ED441EF88B450C841567D2E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the efforts of the President to develop and update the implementation plan required under section 7; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44143A5643074CCD96B4EADDF69EFBFA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of the effectiveness and benefit of the national exercise conducted under section 8. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

