<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1031ADC513A54D10970974E632078A3A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9696 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to provide certain resources to implement the Department of Defense policy on civilian harm in connection with United States military operations, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9696</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221227">December 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to provide certain resources to implement the Department of Defense policy on civilian harm in connection with United States military operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H46ADDF3080174969A7EC0721BCDD564C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0A5769E1D7EB4D2E9E3BF9F5D056E944" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Resources to implement Department of Defense policy on civilian harm in connection with United States military operations</header>
<subsection id="HDFF5EFA2D0574EC1A464C67E7F048097"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to facilitate fulfillment of the requirements in section 936 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/232">Public Law 115–232</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/134">10 U.S.C. 134</external-xref> note).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H041BE53192874BECB183D4EFB6B21F6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Personnel</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall do the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA5FD01789211433D81EF38974E019C91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Assign within each of the United States Central Command, the United States Africa Command, the United States Special Operations Command, the United States European Command, the United States Southern Command, the United States Indo-Pacific Command, and the United States Northern Command not fewer than two personnel who shall have primary responsibility for the following in connection with military operations undertaken by such command:</text> <subparagraph id="H541EB60002D445818E846931C3289628"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Providing guidance and oversight relating to prevention of and response to harm to civilians, promotion of observance of human rights, and the protection of civilians and civilian infrastructure, including ensuring implementation of the policy of the Department of Defense on harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8FC7061676C849DF9205C89B216AA8AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Overseeing civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response functions on behalf of the commander of such command.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91016AD59DC84A3090004DCB00449D7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Receiving reports of harm to civilians and conducting assessments and investigations relating to such harm.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFB5964D964B8458E9F3C73D5C35CA613"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Analyzing incidents and trends with respect to harm to civilians, identifying lessons learned, and ensuring that lessons learned are incorporated into updated command guidance and practices.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F8BB76FA5124FEDA0802D98B63101AC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Offering condolences and amends for harm to civilians, including ex gratia payments.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2A44F4735E2C4C17963C53E0E1B9FEE6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Ensuring the integration of activities relating to civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response, the protection of civilians, and promotion of observance of human rights in security cooperation activities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B945840B3D1404CB7AB08E95B6E65BC"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Working with the Center for Excellence established under section 184 of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5375BDFADEAA4B5FB53ED2A18F30A370"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Consulting with non-governmental organizations on civilian harm and human rights matters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66AA4D79E87B48049FCDD96DEACA940D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Assign within the Office of the Under Secretary of Defense for Policy not fewer than two personnel who shall have primary responsibility for implementing and overseeing implementation by the components of the Department of Defense of Department policy on harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H37AFB983504A4C578B74758FAC09A9FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Assign within the Joint Staff not fewer than two personnel who shall have primary responsibility for the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H78F66BB9B080444C8033525BE3645B60"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Overseeing implementation by the components of the Department of Defense of Department policy on harm to civilians resulting from United States military operations.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H47AE7E7DBAAF417383F898AB20497B4A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Developing and sharing in the implementation of such policy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAFA3048F29064D858F07E89E00B1E09D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Communicating operational guidance on such policy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H5C2E5E64103D4CEF82320453B2254134"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training, software, and other requirements</header>
<paragraph id="H2D0208E0D7D04A5E903E6BC24F90AD44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025, the Secretary of Defense and each Secretary of a military department may obligate and expend, from amounts specified in paragraph (2), not more than $5,000,000 for the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF84B5833166F454081099AB450F9DF64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Training related to civilian harm prevention, mitigation, and response.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCF3ED514DD39477C82676A348D0BD071"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information technology equipment, support and maintenance, and data storage, in order to implement the policy of the Department relating to harms to civilians resulting from United States military operations as required by section 936 of the John S. McCain National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2019.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9A70124A7F884860BE284173368F7BEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funds</header><text>The funds for a fiscal year specified in this subparagraph are funds as follows:</text>
<subparagraph id="HBAE299152208439CA9551C04A294BB79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In the case of the Secretary of Defense, amounts authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for operation and maintenance, Defense-wide.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBD2200D90A9A412692B05E3284E501C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the case of a Secretary of a military department, amounts authorized to be appropriated for such fiscal year for operation and maintenance for the components of the Armed Forces under the jurisdiction of such Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

