<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF30FF83B565748A78A102875A859DA2A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8449 IH: Fire Ready Nation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8449</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220720">July 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish and maintain a coordinated program within the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration that improves wildfire, fire weather, fire risk, and smoke related forecasting, detection, modeling, observations, and service delivery, and to address growing needs in the wildland-urban interface, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H35154F2F34404040A48DB28D5F92DE8B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H2600C9F146D741D197B37D86F8DA84D0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H984C7E2EDACB4432B07E233DC1EBA4B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fire Ready Nation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H15FA5E8F64964FC4949BC271623466A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H2600C9F146D741D197B37D86F8DA84D0">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H72AF6C065A4A4F4AB36D6265D9036EA0">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HBE42DF479FC449808C75D06075B24C94">Sec. 3. Establishment of fire weather services program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H87F00E8971F043128454F73D6CAECD86">Sec. 4. National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration data management.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HCAB3F25A8EB34DC4A7A8DB28057A3656">Sec. 5. Digital fire weather services and data management.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HF452C23AA9F04EF6B9CE7EEE7AC96014">Sec. 6. High-performance computing.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H47A78514063D4CAC952E702117B671E6">Sec. 7. Government Accountability Office report on fire weather services program.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H4DCB1B5A7795430BAEDEA7DDEF84F992">Sec. 8. Fire weather testbed.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H7B6F5221FA444AD9B8DDFBBBD5D3E29B">Sec. 9. Fire weather surveys and assessments.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HF4C038CDA8834743801C892715F9CAD9">Sec. 10. Incident Meteorologist Service.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H7B1B1ADBBE0C4DEC83BDC80203E2F2F9">Sec. 11. Automated surface observing system.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H2ACA70A6AFDB47A7824A3EC161B96DA5">Sec. 12. Emergency response activities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HE2D15E8B8A6E4D959BE6E345F84FE6BD">Sec. 13. Government Accountability Office report on interagency wildfire forecasting, prevention, planning, and management bodies.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H261C7477CAC64E2FA7DA0C08F5E59677">Sec. 14. Amendments to Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act relating to wildfire mitigation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H5F21A73BD2814F57AC830388462869DA">Sec. 15. Wildfire technology modernization amendments.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HD3573F7332C04310B3FAFFBDF5D35A73">Sec. 16. Cooperation; coordination; support to non-Federal entities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HB900E69EAFEB4B37A267A7D244BCD3CE">Sec. 17. International coordination.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="HE85B3D96C9E84825A7507261FD1EDDD0">Sec. 18. Submissions to Congress regarding the fire weather services program, incident meteorologist workforce needs, and National Weather Service workforce support.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section" idref="H8F667BC5E0124D3487523071BA80FE78">Sec. 19. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H72AF6C065A4A4F4AB36D6265D9036EA0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HA90A2623926840F7BDE80D086BE55509"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The term <term>Administration</term> means the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCFDA419D39EE4A1DA0BEB2429009A8DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H65B0A8AA44C0493EB1F28A1BAC716FF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H721F13EC0A584026924C731D6FB6A1BA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5EE4FDB86CF344079293810940A35109"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decadal</header><text>The term <term>decadal</term> means a time range from multiple years to multiple decades.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA33990FCAD854BB6881687A7A08C5914"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Earth system model</header><text>The term <term>Earth system model</term> means a mathematical model containing all components of the Earth, namely the atmosphere, oceans, land, cryosphere, and biosphere. The Earth system model represents the critical physical, chemical, and biological processes and the interactions among those processes in hydrological and biogeochemical cycles that affect weather and climate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB7D7D5A7D91488FBC0D5E29FDC38731"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Fire environment</header><text>The term <term>fire environment</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6C962154A816467C8A39BD28E5B09E4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the environmental conditions, such as soil moisture, vegetation, topography, snowpack, atmospheric temperature, moisture, and wind, that influence—</text> <clause id="H26F4373401D948BFA651DC002343F32D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>fuel and fire behavior; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F76560A54624B62BCDA1483B1F11514"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>smoke dispersion and transport; and </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4CDF1ACA36024943810B2C185850E60A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the associated environmental impacts occurring during and after fire events.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H102B1F9626594EB5A87C004DEFF8B03B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Fire weather</header><text>The term <term>fire weather</term> means any type of weather conditions that influence the start, spread, character, or behavior of wildfire or fires at the wildland-urban interface and all associated meteorological and chemical phenomena, including air quality, smoke, and meteorological parameters such as relative humidity, air temperature, wind speed and direction, and atmospheric composition and chemistry, including emissions and mixing heights.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BA149D4D1B44786B70731949777A59E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Impact-based decision support services</header><text>The term <term>impact-based decision support services</term> means forecast advice and interpretative services the Administration provides to help core partners, such as emergency personnel and public safety officials, make decisions when weather, water, and climate impact the lives and livelihoods of the people of the United States. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H194606C896404EEABA64CCAB9173BCB6"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Seasonal</header><text>The term <term>seasonal</term> means a time range between 3 months and 2 years.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC546D56FB9B5435B82EB689B573774DA"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H60DD4553E4D34367A549858882FADC71"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Smoke</header><text>The term <term>smoke</term> means emissions, including the gases and particles released into the air as a result of combustion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF0D5BC9C11E54AAE95D88A7BC5555237"><enum>(11)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means a State, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, the United State Virgin Islands, the Federated States of Micronesia, the Republic of the Marshall Islands, or the Republic of Palau.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF8710E3DDDE64CFA9D60CE5EFFA186CD"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Subseasonal</header><text>The term <term>subseasonal</term> means a time range between 2 weeks and 3 months.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BCA55FF0CF6410B9297784FDDCEF059"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Tribal government</header><text>The term <term>Tribal government</term> means the recognized governing body of any Indian or Alaska Native tribe, band, nation, pueblo, village, community, component band, or component reservation, individually identified (including parenthetically) in the list published most recently as of the date of enactment of this Act pursuant to section 104 of the Federally Recognized Indian Tribe List Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5131">25 U.S.C. 5131</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD2554C6F97B54F2A9919A3E71C4F0AA7"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Under Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Under Secretary</term> means the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H013EFB78978A4F18B86F7E27C06ECB02"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Weather enterprise</header><text>The term <term>weather enterprise</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEFFC79615E664BF5A934E88330732B75"><enum>(A)</enum><text>individuals, organizations, offices, programs, or any other form of entity from public, private, and academic sectors that contribute to the research, development, and production of weather forecast products; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFE8C8FE8DE64F738828084A46FFFAE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>primary consumers of those weather forecast products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55A156C5A69A4049BF76860D95DD0684"><enum>(16)</enum><header>Wildfire</header><text>The term <term>wildfire</term> means any nonstructure fire that occurs in vegetation or natural fuels, originating from an unplanned ignition.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H75687E4C9E24443FA00A4BED0D53F93D"><enum>(17)</enum><header>Wildland-urban interface</header><text>The term <term>wildland-urban interface</term> means the area, zone, or region of transition between unoccupied or undeveloped land and human development where structures and other human development meet or intermingle with undeveloped wildland or vegetative fuels.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HBE42DF479FC449808C75D06075B24C94"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of fire weather services program</header> 
<subsection id="HF0D92DD1753F4F58AC52CAEFAD0F446E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish and maintain a coordinated fire weather services program within the Administration.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HEBB2778CE5174BCD95B7FE71888B0167"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program functions</header><text>The functions of the program established under subsection (a), consistent with the priorities described in section 101 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8511">15 U.S.C. 8511</external-xref>), shall be—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC935C8B579D947C9BA2290D306CC767A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support readiness, responsiveness, understanding, and overall resilience of the United States to wildfires, fire weather, smoke, and other associated conditions, hazards, and impacts in built and natural environments and at the wildland-urban interface;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35D4CD4900A3440F9A928E7A9DB37B23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to collaboratively disseminate accurate, precise, effective, and timely risk communications, forecasts, watches, and warnings relating to wildfires, fire weather, air quality, smoke, and other associated conditions, hazards, and impacts, as applicable, in collaboration with Federal land management agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H66F3D89A35034A6DAAA29040560DE81E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to partner with and support the public, Federal, State, and Tribal governments, and academic and local partners through the development of capabilities, impact-based decision support services, and overall service delivery and utility;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB02DEF4DEEF54BADBC121D721B4CC9FF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to conduct and support research and development of new and innovative models, technologies, techniques, products, systems, processes, and procedures to improve understanding of wildfires, fire weather, air quality, the fire environment, including impacts of climate variability and changing climate conditions, smoke, and associated conditions, hazards, and impacts, and to transition such research into effective operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H312FFE9F367C4E92951832CD1AB9A3E1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to develop strong research-to-operations and operations-to-research transitions, in order to facilitate delivery of products, services, and tools to operational users and platforms; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F04663FC9914305892666E3159D6C0A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to develop, in coordination with Federal land management agencies, impact-based decision support services that operationalize and integrate the functions described in paragraphs (1) through (5) in order to provide comprehensive impact-based decision support services that encompass the fire environment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H069AD0051ADF409AA6E0B810291CFBC7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program priorities</header><text>In developing and implementing the program established under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall prioritize—</text> <paragraph id="H8752170B43BA480DAEF51E30422EC99B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>development of a fire weather-enabled Earth system model and data assimilation systems that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H36E544D5E2714973898C1A48FCB42BD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are capable of prediction and forecasting across all timescales;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDC91F996C83040DF83D2821A27C64054"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include variables associated with fire weather, air quality from smoke, and the fire environment, and other variables, as determined by the Under Secretary;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H039B1A5AD2D54A7FBE1839561B95FB1B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improve understanding of the connections between fire weather and modes of climate variability; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF7D230BBBD1A452C816FD7AEA7F406D6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>incorporate emerging techniques such as artificial intelligence, machine learning, and cloud computing; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7D823FF1A77F4FF7999655EB0758C731"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advancement of observational capabilities, including satellite-, airborne-, air-, and ground-based systems and technologies that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB2968587D9514DFE955FBE37270459D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify—</text> 
<clause id="H80D775BDFBC2435E87A0A8F7C9E6AC1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>high-risk pre-ignition conditions;</text></clause> <clause id="H023EFDE9D6124050A48F3C12A4163A3D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>conditions that influence fire behavior and spread including those conditions that suppress active fire events; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4D1F1CE28C6C4D4CB61DE630E41B7C28"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>fire risk values;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H96BA621927594F31AE4949C9E4B4CF1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support real-time notification of ignitions;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD4133E43D64442DBB826F8926CD7C564"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support observations and data collection of fire weather and fire environment variables for development of the model and systems under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H824E94808A134177BB2D16790A9254F8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>support forecasts and advancing understanding and research of the impacts of wildfires on human health, ecosystems, climate, transportation, and economies; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8A5B6522E0D041E5B1C2A4AC99A39B9C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>development and implementation of advanced and user-oriented impact-based decision tools, science, and technologies that—</text> <subparagraph id="HB7C6037647EA4B8E9DB58571B0724878"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure real-time and retrospective data, products, and services are findable, accessible, interoperable, usable, inform further research, and are analysis- and decision-ready;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F1FD520D80F44DEB172A4D17B589D7B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide targeted information throughout the fire lifecycle including pre-ignition, detection, forecasting, post-fire, and monitoring phases; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD2FD4A6BA3B945D6B6605D4300AC24AD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>support early assessment of post-fire hazards, such as air quality, debris flows, mudslides, and flooding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD0AB71EF923C4E06B2CF3C84B442B657"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program activities</header><text>In developing and implementing the program established under subsection (a), the Under Secretary may—</text> <paragraph id="H63FEAC4606694380BD35A293947FD039"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct relevant physical and social science research activities in support of the functions described in subsection (b) and the priorities described in subsection (c);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H386E75EEC4A741AD83A601A225C491C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>conduct relevant activities, in coordination with Federal land management agencies, to assess fuel characteristics, including moisture, loading, and other parameters used to determine fire risk levels and outlooks;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD5E41B88D2D14C6CBC31A400C08722BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>support and conduct research that assesses impacts to marine, riverine, and other relevant ecosystems, which may include forest and rangeland ecosystems, resulting from activities associated with mitigation of and response to wildfires; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC57AEBE113124ADE8C28D13718F989D0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support and conduct attribution science research relating to wildfires, fire weather, fire risk, smoke, and associated conditions, risks, and impacts;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H63DDBD4482C14FDDB395383C813A8072"><enum>(5)</enum><text>develop smoke and air quality forecasts, forecast guidance, and prescribed burn weather forecasts, and conduct research on the impact of such forecasts on response behavior that minimizes health-related impacts from smoke exposure;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD09B30123A07486F8AEC13A56BBF7587"><enum>(6)</enum><text>use, in coordination with Federal land management agencies, wildland fire resource intelligence to inform fire environment impact-based decision support products and services for safety; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1F7355D12EB547A6AB310B905984C309"><enum>(7)</enum><text>evaluate and provide data, tools, and services to support determinations for the implementation of mitigation measures such as prescribed burns and selective thinning; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA87EE0496B5F433A931349CFBF50E3E5"><enum>(8)</enum><text>provide comprehensive training to ensure staff of the program established under subsection (a) is properly equipped to deliver the impact-based decision support products and services described in paragraphs (1) through (6); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3FA06C5ECA8F4C75A12EFC4D93844B81"><enum>(9)</enum><text>acquire through contracted purchase private sector-produced observational data to fill identified gaps, as needed.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H88AF0C957C664EDEA0FE9CE1A2699098"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Collaboration; agreements</header> 
<paragraph id="H2EC7A8CB5168492596C4195E8789B3C0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>The Under Secretary shall, as the Under Secretary considers appropriate, collaborate and consult with partners in the weather and climate enterprises, academic institutions, States, Tribal governments, local partners, and Federal agencies, including land and fire management agencies, in the development and implementation of the program established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDB71D815D68448B92FD21031185D1EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Agreements</header><text>The Under Secretary may enter into agreements in support of the functions described in subsection (b), the priorities described in subsection (c), the activities described in subsection (d), and activities carried out under section 8.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H87F00E8971F043128454F73D6CAECD86"><enum>4.</enum><header>National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration data management</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301 of the Weather Research and Forecasting Innovation Act of 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/8531">15 U.S.C. 8531</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H83F83E75D5B74032BDB69989592973A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (f) and (g) as subsections (g) and (h), respectively; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2CF246364FEF4324BC0F68DD5851C60D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (e) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A165C6F50B24E358E430408A2103F7B"> <subsection id="H193963602ECB4CC49654140FD6ABBDAD"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Data availability and management</header> <paragraph id="H6E5295034A1041CCA04A110E7EBCB21F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBBBD18519AFA437786AED11527D0E0E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>make data and metadata generated or collected by the National Oceanic and Administration that the Under Secretary has the legal right to redistribute fully and openly available, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code and the Foundations for Evidence-Based Policymaking Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/435">Public Law 115–435</external-xref>; 132 Stat. 5529) and the amendments made by that Act, and preserve and curate such data and metadata, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Federal Records Act of 1950</quote>), in order to maximize use of such data and metadata; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD4D60088C8F241A38B44775B47C91922"><enum>(B)</enum><text>manage and steward the access, archival, and retrieval activities for the data and metadata described in subparagraph (A) by—</text> 
<clause id="HF313C8F5955849298BC46FD27D4382C4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>using—</text> <subclause id="HDB05C9C7CC1A428E96A6D080B8676FFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>enterprise-wide infrastructure, emerging technologies, commercial partnerships, and the skilled workforce needed to provide appropriate data management from collection to broad access; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB42F32EC771C42C6976E55AD163A69D3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>associated information services; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9A186711C36A4B51BD81786823C05FC1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>pursuing the maximum interoperability of data and information by—</text> 
<subclause id="H07F6B26DE8E7468B8145122315B629E9"><enum>(I)</enum><text>leveraging data, information, knowledge, and tools from across the Federal Government to support equitable access, cross-sectoral collaboration and innovation, and local planning and decision-making; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H15D0A2717F0A423DA490E5697D3D6235"><enum>(II)</enum><text>developing standards and practices for the adoption and citation of digital object identifiers for datasets, models, and analytical tools.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD01CAD6B50A54D248EC41C96407DFA3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Under Secretary shall collaborate with such Federal partners and stakeholders as the Under Secretary considers relevant—</text> <subparagraph id="H706FE82C30AB4E588616407D84F403A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to develop standards to pursue maximum interoperability of data, information, knowledge, and tools across the Federal Government, convert historical records into common digital formats, and improve access and usability of data by partners and stakeholders;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7B901497304E485AA5E04BA5A4FD9820"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to identify and solicit relevant data from Federal and international partners and other relevant stakeholders, as the Under Secretary considers appropriate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9C279BB4446434DA0ABFFFF7B94D4D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to develop standards and practices for the adoption and citation of digital object identifiers for datasets, models, and analytical tools.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HCAB3F25A8EB34DC4A7A8DB28057A3656"><enum>5.</enum><header>Digital fire weather services and data management</header> 
<subsection id="H12199BCE68E546FD867E4CEBDFC535D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="HF90FA172EB874E2684C42E1F97F62465"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Digital presence</header><text>The Under Secretary shall develop and maintain a comprehensive, centralized, and publicly accessible digital presence designed to promote findability, accessibility, interoperability, usability, and utility of the services, tools, data, and information produced by the program established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A2F81D887834CE48865B0AAD6C7884F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Digital platform and tools</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB9F3C453CFED438F8CF2A6FBF26977AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek to ensure the digital platform and tools of the Administration integrate geospatial data, decision support tools, training, and best practices to provide real-time fire weather forecasts and address fire-related issues and needs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C3C34345F4B426880CF907B0459CF26"><enum>(B)</enum><text>strive to enhance community resilience, ecosystem values, and economic growth and development by helping communities and other users of the digital platform and tools address their issues, needs, and challenges through maximum usability and utility.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB4F769EFF60E42D5900267C4E92BC6BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Under Secretary shall make all data, research, reports, findings, surveys, and assessments relevant to the program established under section 3(a), as determined by the Under Secretary, available in a publicly accessible digital format.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H15485FE29FCF42FD98E3B9B37BCB7C5B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Internet-Based tools</header><text>In carrying out subsections (a) and (b), the Under Secretary shall develop and implement internet-based tools, such as webpages and smartphone and other mobile applications, to increase utility and access to services and products for the benefit of users.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44551FD0E8B44C67AA502CE0FF3C353D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Data management</header><text>The Under Secretary shall develop and maintain services that provide public access to digital fire weather data and information—</text> <paragraph id="H0BC562922CA04CD8A973C893CCFA2F6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to improve understanding and historical analysis of wildfire and fire weather science, including inventories of fire emissions required for multi-decadal model runs;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B705E6122BD46CBB0B210D046784FFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to support—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C134A05043446DB8AA9DD647F4E87A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the archiving, stewardship, utility, and preservation of wildfire and fire weather data including satellite-, ground-, airborne-, and air-based observations; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1AE314C638F4917BD609EEDECDA76B5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>real-time and retrospective model forecasts;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F071753B71947F598CB43020065EC43"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to promote findability, interoperability, analysis- and decision-readiness, and reusability of historical and near real-time data across Federal, State, Tribal, and local users, including ensuring digital access and machine-readability of historical fire weather records; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5B6E1F544BB480B92F68D8ADDEA430E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to support equitable access, cross-sectoral collaboration and innovation, and local planning and decision making.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF452C23AA9F04EF6B9CE7EEE7AC96014"><enum>6.</enum><header>High-performance computing</header> <subsection id="H049D7870825C40B8A475102128CCC4B3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall seek to acquire sufficient high-performance computing resources and capacity for research, operations, and data storage in support of the program established under section 3(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72791DF62D3047D1815E80DA5F0514A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In acquiring high-performance computing capacity under subsection (a), the Under Secretary shall consider requirements needed for—</text> <paragraph id="HCC3B71012DBC4BFBAE7C271403CAA560"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the transition of research and testbed developments into operations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB9AA1B0C2CAC442ABF62AFE1C42944EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>skilled workforce development.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H47A78514063D4CAC952E702117B671E6"><enum>7.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report on fire weather services program</header> <subsection id="H519AD36DD90C42ECB592A9CA09AEDB41"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report on the program established under section 3(a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFD2BD73A61C14F418E0150AD3A409484"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H6447F54B29D04935B63EF884CD271362"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate the performance of the program by establishing initial baseline capabilities and tracking progress made toward fully operationalizing the functions described in section 3(b);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E7247636B68400FA870B89C5752F00D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess the efficacy of cross-agency collaboration and stakeholder engagement in carrying out the program and provide recommendations to improve such activities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H03A9973C538B4D06AC41E1FB16BBEFDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assess the program for inefficiencies, identify duplicative efforts across Federal efforts, and provide relevant recommendations; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6AE9C183C16C43F3937DDB741CAB107E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include such other recommendations as the Comptroller General determines are appropriate to improve the program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H4DCB1B5A7795430BAEDEA7DDEF84F992"><enum>8.</enum><header>Fire weather testbed</header> <subsection id="H03B412F2719F443296C159642C4C3B5E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of fire weather testbed</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish a fire weather testbed that enables engagement across the Federal Government, State and local governments, academia, private and federally funded research laboratories, the private sector, and end-users in order to evaluate the accuracy and usability of technology, models, fire weather products and services, and other research to accelerate the implementation, transition to operations, and use of new capabilities by the Administration, Federal and land management agencies, and other relevant stakeholders.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H573683D68E8343FFA0F6FB4F2A0BE2B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uncrewed aircraft systems</header> 
<paragraph id="H519B38151BB24FD0BF51A821D23535B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA4DA8BD48B44F5899E9470ADD8DF2A3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>research and assess the role and potential of uncrewed aircraft systems to improve data collection in support of modeling, observations, predictions, forecasts, and impact-based decision support services; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB043257808AD400A99BF66A5536BEA01"><enum>(B)</enum><text>transition uncrewed aircraft systems technologies from research to operations as the Under Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H341B7C6F1ED248DEA9C82228DF01DECF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pilot required</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall conduct at least 1 pilot of uncrewed aircraft systems for fire weather and fire environment observations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FDFCFB0C3D847D5A22ED3CC666FD414"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Savings clause</header> 
<subparagraph id="HEE9D8CE7DCAB4FCA8260880ED9DBBFDC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out activities under this subsection, the Under Secretary shall ensure that any testing or deployment of uncrewed aircraft systems follow procedures, restrictions, and protocols established by the heads of the Federal agencies with statutory or regulatory jurisdiction over any airspace in which wildfire response activities are conducted during an active wildfire event. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF17C9246ECA24B27822A734D361986F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>The Under Secretary shall consult and coordinate with relevant Federal land management agencies and the Federal Aviation Administration to develop processes for the appropriate deployment of the systems described in subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7B6F5221FA444AD9B8DDFBBBD5D3E29B"><enum>9.</enum><header>Fire weather surveys and assessments</header> 
<subsection id="H61A565F4050E4CC391069C40D79E6FD6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual post-Fire-Weather season survey and assessment</header> 
<paragraph id="H2EB262D0D672489DA08077AFCF9BB786"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During the second winter following the enactment of this Act, and each year thereafter, the Under Secretary shall conduct a post-fire-weather season survey and assessment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H85D7C79C0577421481906933CB8787E5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>After conducting a post-fire-weather season survey and assessment under paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEEDFCAC21BFC4FFBA84CB9DA905DB314"><enum>(A)</enum><text>investigate any gaps in data collected during the assessment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H862A32383AC84E34939E8DC89F8C7F93"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify and implement strategies and procedures to improve program services and information dissemination;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD96B09BBB5C4E76A98C1BD2C5F290EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>update systems, processes, strategies, and procedures to enhance the efficiency and reliability of data obtained from the assessment;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA76BF2AE66894C61B049B3A0A6B653C5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>evaluate the accuracy and efficacy of physical fire weather forecasting information for each incident included in the survey and assessment; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC3378268265E406C8DE9DE8C00C37688"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assess and refine performance measures, as needed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H0FA7CC10BEAA43A686B96B1070AA65F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Surveys and assessments following individual wildfire events</header><text>The Under Secretary may conduct surveys and assessments following individual wildfire events as the Under Secretary determines necessary.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB8073BECF8444849B7F15DE7B02B5AED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Goal</header><text>In carrying out activities under this section, the Under Secretary shall seek to increase the number of post-wildfire community impact studies, including by surveying individual and collective responses and incorporating other applicable topics of social science research.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA5F005D73E424C7186DE959EC6CE36CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual briefing</header><text>Not less frequently than once each year, the Under Secretary shall provide a briefing to the appropriate committees of Congress that provides—</text> 
<paragraph id="H640395C54EB94432B50D038C48745979"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an overview of the fire season; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0703B4E6C1B49AD848290FEF7F94AC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an outlook for the fire season for the coming year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCDACDEDE136948CB8CB05D813A32376E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>In conducting any survey or assessment under this section, the Under Secretary shall coordinate with Federal, State, and local partners, Tribal governments, private entities, and such institutions of higher education as the Under Secretary considers relevant in order to—</text> <paragraph id="H650D3D4B76104779AB66950F69E1A759"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improve operations and collaboration; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2593DB3DDFA44CD5B515B179076C3E13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>optimize data collection, sharing, integration, assimilation, and dissemination.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEA074D6C7D2041E4ABF7F18764E90E04"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Data availability</header><text>The Under Secretary shall make the data and findings obtained from each assessment conducted under this section available to the public in an accessible digital format as soon as practicable after conducting the assessment.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H2CEEDED61AC546618B91BF054F1313D8"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Service improvements</header><text>The Under Secretary shall make best efforts to incorporate the results and recommendations of each assessment conducted under this section into the research and development plan and operations of the Administration.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HF4C038CDA8834743801C892715F9CAD9"><enum>10.</enum><header>Incident Meteorologist Service</header> <subsection id="H574F1BD8CA14432481CAEC1FB7D1ED54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Under Secretary shall establish and maintain an Incident Meteorologist Service within the National Weather Service (in this section referred to as the <quote>Service</quote>).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC346F773B6948E287768E87C4ADA6EF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion of existing incident meteorologists</header><text>The Service shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HA542DAD742474F70AA87BFA799746F59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the incident meteorologists of the Administration as of the date of this enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC671B5F3F72F45E4B053BD1927DF60B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such incident meteorologists of the Administration as may be appointed after such date.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3B8E19D57FC847E58DD4744288022883"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Service shall provide—</text> 
<paragraph id="H5D79DCF23B074025BAB9EF23996553C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on-site impact-based decision support services to Federal, State, Tribal government, and local government emergency response agencies preceding, during, and following wildland fires or other events that threaten life or property, including high-impact and extreme weather events; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5669F2EBD2314979A023DE855335B246"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support to Federal, State, Tribal government, and local government decision makers, partners, and stakeholders for seasonal planning.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE640BCAE2EAF439C92A6F143C5049A6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deployment</header><text>The Service shall be deployed—</text> <paragraph id="H37EE294AABF74DFFAA5F938333FB8200"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as determined by the Under Secretary; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7A97E60AB3D74296985E618E155F34C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at the request of the head of another Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCAA0F2CA74104917ACDDDAD2D42B04DF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Staffing and resources</header><text>In establishing and maintaining the Service, the Under Secretary shall identify, acquire, and maintain adequate levels of staffing and resources to meet user needs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54422C5E03C54277805B2352368236FF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Symbol</header> 
<paragraph id="H9FE86C477EC24EA3A5C300ADE8B85ACB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary may—</text> <subparagraph id="H35928BA484D04764AD9F1A324305C04D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>create, adopt, and publish in the Federal Register a symbol for the Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H288C67E705F94D6482EA588BA4BDF270"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restrict the use of such symbol as appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4AECABD1993942F48235D8917DA60482"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of symbol</header><text>The Under Secretary may authorize the use of a symbol adopted under this subsection by any individual or entity as the Under Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H315D482A4B4C402C96D27367F4EF5815"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><text>The Under Secretary may award contracts for the creation of symbols under this subsection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0FC1CE9D94FA49788EA0412F54AC3F79"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Offense</header><text>It shall be unlawful for any person—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA952323BCE004CCC98E7078DAA160020"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to represent themselves as an official of the Service absent the designation or approval of the Under Secretary;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6587FB344D884D879CE1D3159457DD25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to manufacture, reproduce, or otherwise use any symbol adopted by the Under Secretary under this subsection, including to sell any item bearing such a symbol, unless authorized by the Under Secretary; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H80361BC7F6E7454CA8C52C8C1FF1B9D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to violate any regulation promulgated by the Secretary under this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC8A574BF545641D4B5F8DB490D9D2F40"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Support for incident meteorologists</header><text>The Under Secretary shall provide resources, access to real-time fire weather forecasts, training, administrative and logistical support, and access to professional counseling or other forms of support as the Under Secretary considers appropriate for the betterment of the emotional and mental health and well-being of incident meteorologists and other employees of the Administration involved with response to high-impact and extreme fire weather events. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H7B1B1ADBBE0C4DEC83BDC80203E2F2F9"><enum>11.</enum><header>Automated surface observing system</header> 
<subsection id="HFF34FF6DDA1642FCB540C402936C795D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Joint assessment and plan</header> 
<paragraph id="HC543661216BC42D1B7FA43DD156F79B7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary, in collaboration with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretary of Defense, shall— </text> <subparagraph id="H02BEA82F282244F9BC0ED2760D902136"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct an assessment of resources, personnel, procedures, and activities necessary to maximize the functionality and utility of the automated surface observing system of the United States that identifies—</text> 
<clause id="H9771739D66AE436F8D7A48039BA218CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>key system upgrades needed to improve observation quality and utility for weather forecasting, aviation safety, and other users;</text></clause> <clause id="HB1CC73175EA442BF8EFFA0E006F6F350"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements needed in observations within the planetary boundary layer, including mixing height;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H010CC237653C481B9FB5103AEF45E255"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>improvements needed in public accessibility of observational data;</text></clause> <clause id="HF1F69AEDFC1044EDB1F231A3E1529B53"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>improvements needed to reduce latency in reporting of observational data;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4CF779C2E7894B06B2C72E7FD4A85155"><enum>(v)</enum><text>relevant data to be collected for the production of forecasts or forecast guidance relating to atmospheric composition, including particulate and air quality data, and aviation safety;</text></clause> <clause id="HE8F70E37D4FF4050A0531987BBD229E0"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>areas of concern regarding operational continuity and reliability of the system, which may include needs for on-night staff, particularly in remote and rural areas and areas where system failure would have the greatest negative impact to the community;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H56BB7723DF9748B6A9E8DAD5C8D4F388"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>stewardship, data handling, data distribution, and product generation needs arising from upgrading and changing the automated surface observation systems;</text></clause> <clause id="H7235575FFBED4AE0B653EC26C8E1A26D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>possible solutions for areas of concern identified under clause (vi), including with respect to the potential use of backup systems, power and communication system reliability, staffing needs and personnel location, and the acquisition of critical component backups and proper storage location to ensure rapid system repair necessary to ensure system operational continuity; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC5E41F92B9DB40F298D04750892B556F"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>research, development, and transition to operations needed to develop advanced data collection, quality control, and distribution so that the data are provided to models, users, and decision support systems in a timely manner; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C8E741637D24F33B2D6A9C85248209D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop and implement a plan that addresses the findings of the assessment conducted under subparagraph (A), including by seeking and allocating resources necessary to ensure that system upgrades are standardized across the Administration, the Federal Aviation Administration, and the Department of Defense to the extent practicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4C8244393A8A41928C6970801C9CCB3E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Standardization</header><text>Any system standardization implemented under paragraph (1)(B) shall not impede activities to upgrade or improve individual units of the system.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6EFA539D8FFB4574B2324116F83A3A14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Remote automatic weather station coordination</header><text>The Under Secretary, in collaboration with relevant Federal agencies and the National Interagency Fire Center, shall assess and develop cooperative agreements to improve coordination, interoperability standards, operations, and placement of remote automatic weather stations for the purpose of improving utility and coverage of remote automatic weather stations, automated surface observation systems, and other similar stations and systems for weather and climate operations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H08C35CDDEA4F4B768CCD4039830595DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header> 
<paragraph id="H871161902A2F452C8762D0F7918F7597"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary, in collaboration with the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration and the Secretary of Defense, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that— </text> <subparagraph id="H3E49A55D30B343E99AA5F20A78308B52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>details the findings of the assessment required by subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H623D491D45074762B79E30CCEAD04A82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the plan required by subparagraph (B) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1A86C995412141B0975845312026AFC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include a detailed assessment of appropriations required—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0F970B5BD64F4A2C9F6230E07D035C5B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address the findings of the assessment required by subparagraph (A) of subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA6651D172A2B4D5FABE4AB40858BAAA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to implement the plan required by subparagraph (B) of such subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6CFA4FE5AC7B41568BB558376579A4A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> <paragraph id="H2D148E59E2694662879E7001525A3BDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluates the functionality, utility, reliability, and operational status of the automated surface observing system across the Administration, the Federal Aviation Administration, and the Department of Defense;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3AEC68B93DFC4510998D4992D966ECD7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluates the progress, performance, and implementation of the plan required by subsection (a)(1)(B);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF2ED97BBFF75477291533984ADC464EC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the efficacy of cross-agency collaboration and stakeholder engagement in carrying out the plan and provides recommendations to improve such activities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H71E9259F235E4CE49849F95D38F1A219"><enum>(4)</enum><text>evaluates the operational continuity and reliability of the system, particularly in remote and rural areas and areas where system failure would have the greatest negative impact to the community, and provides recommendations to improve such continuity and reliability;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H59BB950E95444B03981DD7EC36EC9827"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assesses Federal coordination regarding the remote automatic weather station network, air resource advisors, and other Federal observing assets used for weather and climate modeling and response activities, and provides recommendations for improvements; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF1D24B71DB14E75B9FFFADAAF6F1933"><enum>(6)</enum><text>includes such other recommendations as the Comptroller General determines are appropriate to improve the system.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2ACA70A6AFDB47A7824A3EC161B96DA5"><enum>12.</enum><header>Emergency response activities</header> <subsection id="HEE9D027DC0054FF18CAEB4B260A2DDC3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDF7211AFAD1B4050B3F5E890D3DC96FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic pay</header><text>The term <term>basic pay</term> includes any applicable locality-based comparability payment under section 5304 of title 5, United States Code, any applicable special rate supplement under section 5305 of such title, or any equivalent payment under a similar provision of law. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA72CF8E4D45A4EF782BAD105FD5DD672"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered employee</header><text>The term <term>covered employee</term> means an employee of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF4B29D4A97E44527986F39C6DC528800"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Department of Commerce; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H73DC8580ABBE41779280DEE16E3B674D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior; or </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6FB320641E3440108F88812A7383FB4E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2AC58A71B344F488DC4830FB7D32383"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered services</header><text>The term <term>covered services</term> means services performed by a covered employee while—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0414670D176F403796FBF42D6A6C7F93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serving—</text> <clause id="HD6738A1C09284FAAB2A9BCE43C7E9F56"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as an incident meteorologist accompanying a wildland firefighter crew; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H171D88AA11264CDCBC3095670A76B4CE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a role that is determined by the Secretary concerned to be primarily relating to emergency wildland fire suppression activities;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7609A61A2F494CE79F8A504ACA3D1153"><enum>(B)</enum><text>serving—</text> 
<clause id="H34123BB7D63C4BC49C8A5052AC05AD00"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on an incident management team;</text></clause> <clause id="HD178FF5E6A3B45449BADA150D641ABF0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>as an emergency response specialist;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF7BC35711C2D46529C11460AA80C9E6A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>at the National Interagency Fire Center;</text></clause> <clause id="H75DBD86F015740F0805370C1F0DD90BA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>at a Geographic Area Coordination Center; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3258F9CD6E9B41AB9675CBE2F91FE242"><enum>(v)</enum><text>at an operations center; or</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE7298FBB4248453394E0B6A0B8266490"><enum>(C)</enum><text>serving in a capacity determined by the Secretary, or the Under Secretary acting on behalf of the Secretary, to be primarily relating to emergency response activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA1BCBD714858443C9BDE0DEBA4AA95BF"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given that term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H58B17E4AC2A54B1398BC6FB899664A98"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Premium pay</header><text>The term <term>premium pay</term> means premium pay for the purposes of section 5547(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA3150B6CCB74BFABEC338A2182D9771"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary concerned</header><text>The term <term>Secretary concerned</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="HFF61FF25055542DEA167A7BC063B5981"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of Commerce, with respect to an employee of the Department of Commerce; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB8D3BF18A99647D2825EA00472EC02F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Agriculture, with respect to an employee of the Department of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C78057D640943C183D0D32D047342F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of the Interior, with respect to an employee of the Department of the Interior. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3A11FD6F25F64AEB8DBCC449756AC78C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header> 
<paragraph id="H0038AB9D18B9494CAB56874D47413A94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any premium pay received by a covered employee for covered services shall be disregarded in calculating the aggregate of the basic pay and premium pay for the covered employee for purposes of applying the limitation on premium pay under section 5547(a) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB938B477B7974F86B9789E7865F2A75D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>A covered employee may be paid premium pay that is disregarded under paragraph (1) only to the extent that the aggregate of the basic pay and premium pay paid to that covered employee in the applicable calendar year, including premium pay that is disregarded under that paragraph, does not exceed the rate of basic pay for a position at level II of the Executive Schedule under section 5313 of title 5, United States Code, as in effect at the end of that calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6DCD218EC7464322886B168D2E8717CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>If the application of subsection (b) results in the payment of additional pay to a covered employee of a type that is normally creditable as basic pay for retirement or any other purpose, that additional pay shall not—</text> <paragraph id="H895EE5FAF82D4256A128A8657B6087FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be considered to be basic pay of the covered employee for any purpose; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD56334D5D89A4A2C8299AEE3551A80B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be used in computing a lump-sum payment to the covered employee for accumulated and accrued annual leave under section 5551 or 5552 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8084990F858D470A83238D3C0AD65747"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Amendment</header><text>Section 5542(a)(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H60B9E2356E0742838FE7382241F1F8AE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, the Department of Commerce,</quote> after <quote>Interior</quote>; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C1EBC7E17284235813AC38FC3A90723"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the United States Forest Service in</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H762626D4A44242F6BD4A8AF52CCAEF8D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>This section and the amendment made by this section shall take effect as if enacted on January 1, 2020.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEEF14856C5F4DBA866F4FC686CD2981" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Derivation of funds</header><text>Any amounts used to pay covered employees for covered services shall not be derived from amounts made available to the Administration or amounts saved by reducing the number of full-time-equivalent employees of the Administration.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA5266FE000324A789A8B7E5E28267899"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Policies and procedures for health, safety, and well-Being</header><text>The Under Secretary shall maintain policies and procedures that ensure that the deployment of a covered employee to perform a covered service will not compromise the health, safety, and well-being of the covered employee.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HE2D15E8B8A6E4D959BE6E345F84FE6BD"><enum>13.</enum><header>Government Accountability Office report on interagency wildfire forecasting, prevention, planning, and management bodies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to Congress a report that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2E7A7593607E463FBECEA5750922A1E7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies all Federal interagency bodies established for the purpose of wildfire forecasting, prevention, planning, and management (such as wildfire councils, commissions, and workgroups), including—</text> <subparagraph id="HFE702F19EA784DEAB3AE6C2B12229BCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Wildland Fire Leadership Council;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7BABFF1B5BD3462BA31D5085A9A280F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Interagency Fire Center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFDD5AFB879394A6BAD2AA43B41DA0C39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Wildland Fire Management Policy Committee;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H634D3E1DCA7848FD936AD7F93A37A6F2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Wildland Fire Mitigation and Management Commission;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3279AC731A44A2A981491128DCC213D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Interagency Fire Center;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H810744FBCCF04CF592A20E65BDA0EF39"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the National Interagency Coordination Center;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9ED7A7E1C84499987756B7BE5A240F4"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the National Predictive Services Oversight Group;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD5320624AEE74AF9971FE0C224FAA149"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Interagency Council for Advancing Meteorological Services;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA06693745DF04996BDDACA89ACAF4505"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the National Wildfire Coordinating Group; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB367FB83B1274DBCAD21457148D34FD6"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the National Multi-Agency Coordinating Group; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C4804A9E267478F8B4CD50BDA7ACEB9"><enum>(K)</enum><text>the Mitigation Framework Leadership Group;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C3EDF4232CC4B21BF21941B65F55CB0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evaluates the roles, functionality, and utility of such interagency bodies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30443DC1C0DE40A685B6C66DA8A1FFBC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluates the progress, performance, and implementation of such interagency bodies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H862ACF33FA8C4FCBA6EF5638FB342007"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assesses efficacy and identifies potential overlap and duplication of such interagency bodies in carrying out interagency collaboration with respect to wildfire prevention, planning, and management; and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F5951A848B84B64A1F528B8A8F1093C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(5)</enum><text>includes such other recommendations as the Comptroller General determines are appropriate to streamline and improve wildfire forecasting, prevention, planning, and management, including recommendations regarding the interagency bodies for which the addition of the Administration is necessary to improve wildfire forecasting, prevention, planning, and management. </text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H261C7477CAC64E2FA7DA0C08F5E59677"><enum>14.</enum><header>Amendments to Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act relating to wildfire mitigation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 429) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HD3972EB8B4D046CEB6166AC567E8A649"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 70202—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6F5BB23F2E6C43349F1AA9CB76AA3542"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="H903158A8DB0040B2AD39954DA54C3B48"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H29E9973BB84C436A90540B57E553705F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (K), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7035EBB18C2B4782AE0EE3A998CB512D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H83CC702C839341AE96E4405C3F65012C"> 
<subparagraph id="H103654BD5F1349509CBDE0B65A1FF5C1"><enum>(L)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H562B5DB933DF4440B01457FFE37B4364"> <subparagraph id="HCC70D26545C44FF29BA2D756C5A3758B"><enum>(M)</enum><text>the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1886E2B5AF5D489BA3125209EB15E7A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (6)—</text> <clause id="H2380A18FD0CB4795B8E6BB07885D810E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC6EE09BCC3994E93B49B9E09874F2C95"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD5FC8B78660143AE9EE80CC3E5EADA5C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H05BF742A891C4B4882A73BAE570EDD61"> 
<subparagraph id="H57B6AAF089044DC68B520AB52E7077CE"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28CE32ACD3914E52AE9C65CCEC539093"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 70203(b)(1)(B)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H074518F404DD46EABCED9F86F27021AD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>9</quote> and inserting <quote>not fewer than 10</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCB6C4E61B9954543BDEF7467DD9A1310"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text> 
<clause id="H97B0C7D82B4F434BB4D02F3071159382"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></clause> <clause id="H984190285DEA4A61B5759258F221506E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC86CF3412A6147AEA30EBEEF5C72EB75"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8691127D8E0E451399F393DCC2D2B74A"> <subclause id="H27B33C6FDE704B5A8D554A36E42312DB"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE5660B490D1D4C91B4EF6CD4F1524C8B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in clause (iv), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4A3B19C4293465281CA8743543B2F1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6D45C1615C484A52A902D20E55E82A52"> 
<clause id="H6CC41FF9A9164E0FB6CB16C4B10DAB46"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>if the Secretaries determine it to be appropriate, 1 or more representatives from the relevant line offices of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H5F21A73BD2814F57AC830388462869DA"><enum>15.</enum><header>Wildfire technology modernization amendments</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1114 of the John D. Dingell, Jr. Conservation, Management, and Recreation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1748b-1">43 U.S.C. 1748b–1</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4CA8F3FA1D584FCCB97AF2718BDB4D99"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(3), by inserting <quote>the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration,</quote> after <quote>Federal Aviation Administration,</quote>; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0211693941544A869D631822B202C9B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(2)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H84CD556BE60B4AC6A72A51529761B821"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (B) as subparagraph (C); and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H61BA0C8D65024F0E9047691377BAB64C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following: </text> 
<quoted-block id="H89DECDB803A846A69F0FD43DB502704F" style="OLC" act-name=""> 
<subparagraph id="H627D0C6F272E414CA3E497A0F5C4475A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consultation</header> 
<clause id="H49757A543DD5495B8127F1C6F38F3BEC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subparagraph (A), the Secretaries shall consult with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere regarding any development of impact-based decision support services that relate to wildlife-related activities of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></clause> <clause id="HC29C3956684547BFAE4F27FC1D221BC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Definition of impact-based decision support services</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>impact-based decision support services</term> means forecast advice and interpretative services the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration provides to help core partners, such as emergency personnel and public safety officials, make decisions when weather, water, and climate impact the lives and livelihoods of the people of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD675B453AD804BC88F5813D0A17D7BD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> <subparagraph id="HD826D96DF9BB4A9592AA9061D6C4E78D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) and (2) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, and moving such subparagraphs, as so redesignated, 2 ems to the right; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5EE8ADD7EDDA4518BA55209704D5E2FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretaries</quote> and inserting the following: </text> <quoted-block id="H75A7C765DB2641A88FE81A64C3DE8B09" style="OLC" act-name=""> <paragraph id="HF00E58AC524A4D479ABFFBA95C4D6261"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretaries</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBE364C72B797475FB671566E4EF637D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text> <quoted-block id="HBDF5A4CC900E447796256BFEB75EEE20" style="OLC" act-name=""> <paragraph id="H7F42DF61A60C4DF5A8BFCB728487FE55"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Collaboration</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretaries shall collaborate with the Under Secretary of Commerce for Oceans and Atmosphere to improve coordination, utility of systems and assets, and interoperability of data for smoke prediction, forecasting, and modeling.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HD3573F7332C04310B3FAFFBDF5D35A73"><enum>16.</enum><header>Cooperation; coordination; support to non-Federal entities</header> 
<subsection id="HE7C54CF08FAD4EBC9BA6158FE7A59962"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cooperation</header><text>Each Federal agency shall cooperate and coordinate with the Under Secretary, as appropriate, in carrying out this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H89CFB6BEFB784B1DA90C68D1B2A8734C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination</header> <paragraph id="H01DAFDF14BCD44FDBB7AAF16D1DD9BFC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In meeting the requirements under this Act and the amendments made by this Act, the Under Secretary shall coordinate, and as appropriate, establish agreements with Federal and external partners to fully use and leverage existing assets, systems, networks, technologies, and sources of data. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A1F06D2BEA64001949E9CCACF18D009"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Coordination carried out under paragraph (1) shall include coordination with—</text> <subparagraph id="HA18DFB78AF97426D8269A238E3FBF627"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Interagency Fire Center, including the Predictive Services Program that provides impact-based decision support services to the wildland fire community at the Geographic Area Coordination Center and the National Interagency Coordination Center; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1129B01C7E33470EB8DCF03517B23019"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Wildfire Coordinating Group; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H598FBE0895874CF5B9C07135DA1DB99A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>relevant interagency bodies identified in the report required by section 13.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7180CE4677744EDD9C96BA5DDF77E7FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out this subsection, the Under Secretary shall consult with Federal partners including—</text> <subparagraph id="H5C35A16BBCA64C35ABB75053859DA54E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Aeronautics and Space Administration;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A6D034F134147C3AC30C08E4888F325"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of the Interior;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H40ECEB3D5F224AEA955E8D5366FCAB96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Federal Emergency Management Agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA87D97F4514847239E289D99480F7ADC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Science Foundation;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C9654C635944A778937147FC03B5034"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States Geological Survey;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEC9BB4EF88894CEFAFB4EE49D41556BD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Department of Agriculture;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAA1EDBDDC79413384CBDE9329489F82"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBD6627C39B9549348A6714181842B972"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Department of Energy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB529C385C1D04F1DAF0406391444B021"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Department of Defense;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBA44FDC6E9724C96A67D5C21CF572D63"><enum>(J)</enum><text>the National Institute of Standards and Technology; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC27B0A17F1C6430CA4294879E4583E97"><enum>(K)</enum><text>such other departments and agencies as the Under Secretary considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3EAB5F1907BF4E45B8CF938DA7A5510B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination with non-Federal entities</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall develop and submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a process for annual coordination with Tribal, State, and local governments to assist the development of improved fire weather products and services.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3235AE1C8DCE47AF97622AFBE4A89E41"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support to non-Federal entities</header><text>In carrying out the activities under this Act and the amendments made by this Act, the Under Secretary may provide support to non-Federal entities by making funds and resources available through—</text> 
<paragraph id="HBC7E483672D348348B9CF01B9510AC70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>competitive grants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4B7B04BC0E440139B7EDD35AFE4CB3B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>contracts under the mobility program under subchapter VI of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Intergovernmental Personnel Act Mobility Program</quote>);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4B42755742634231912583D7DA2CC330"><enum>(3)</enum><text>cooperative agreements; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9C62C6F22A464984852A63709538E657"><enum>(4)</enum><text>colocation agreements as described in section 502 of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Commissioned Officer Corps Amendments Act of 2020 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/851">33 U.S.C. 851</external-xref> note prec.).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB900E69EAFEB4B37A267A7D244BCD3CE"><enum>17.</enum><header>International coordination</header> 
<subsection id="HE840B0F1511446F58FDFF637A61A77D9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary may develop collaborative relationships and agreements with foreign partners and counterparts to address transboundary issues pertaining to wildfires, fire weather, smoke, air quality, and associated conditions and hazards or other relevant meteorological phenomena, as appropriate, to facilitate full and open exchange of data and information.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA47D8214B0954723A442CD6A0D0C824A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out activities under this section, the Under Secretary shall consult with the Department of State and such other Federal partners as the Under Secretary considers relevant.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HE85B3D96C9E84825A7507261FD1EDDD0"><enum>18.</enum><header>Submissions to Congress regarding the fire weather services program, incident meteorologist workforce needs, and National Weather Service workforce support</header> 
<subsection id="HA8FF35F962B64C73AE4A58663E31E169"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 540 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Under Secretary shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress—</text> <paragraph id="H4ED4EB4CC5E648909AD220F72972CF51"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the plan described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EF8F7DC555B496DBC64DC1B8D1B9322"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the assessment described in subsection (c); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAB93615DC2744BE807A574AD3A2ADEE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the assessment described in subsection (d). </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB2E1F29809E44BAC84EE471433142404"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fire weather services program plan</header> 
<paragraph id="H3781E60CC51A4138A168446717942323"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan submitted under subsection (a)(1) shall detail—</text> <subparagraph id="H3905770213894A77B83A2E04AEEBCB8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the observational data, modeling requirements, ongoing computational needs, research, development, and technology transfer activities, data management, skilled-personnel requirements, engagement with relevant Federal emergency and land management agencies and partners, and corresponding resources and timelines necessary to achieve the functions described in subsection (b) of section 3 and the priorities described in subsection (c) of such section; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAA350EA104A94B84A45C990DF60EF699"><enum>(B)</enum><text>plans and needs for all other activities and requirements under this Act and the amendments made by this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8174C607A94A4C3AACB4039E6E28E484"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submittal of annual budget for plan</header><text>Following completion of the plan submitted under subsection (a)(1), the Under Secretary shall, not less frequently than once each year concurrent with the submission of the budget by the President to Congress under section 1105 of title 31, submit to Congress a proposed budget corresponding with the elements detailed in the plan.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H35F6D50DB1F847699D9EA03AE1521C14"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Incident meteorologist workforce needs assessment</header> 
<paragraph id="H5B7306BD982E41C6B9521F5E2E5FEAB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall conduct a workforce needs assessment on the current and future demand for additional incident meteorologists for wildfires and other high-impact fire weather events.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6CBD91253514802BC7EA3CB9A15DED1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5C17C458413248CCB1EE34FC709094E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of staffing levels as of the date on which the assessment is submitted under subsection (a)(2) and projected future staffing levels.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H641C27C5DC014128AE499301AD8DB4C1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of the state of the infrastructure of the National Weather Service as of the date on which the assessment is submitted and future needs of such infrastructure in order to meet current and future demands, including with respect to information technology support and logistical and administrative operations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE1F9E206514F4175A9D2EB169867A0AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In conducting the assessment required by paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall consider factors including projected climate conditions, infrastructure, all hazard meteorological response system equipment, user needs, and feedback from relevant stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE7F339A0FC7841B48C239C05F4EADD78"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Support services assessment</header> <paragraph id="H617B37836CDD4359B50B816AEA5278A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Under Secretary shall conduct a workforce support services assessment with respect to employees of the National Weather Service engaged in emergency response.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37CDC37C04854717AD628F2D67BBA283"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The assessment required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H957E2836865242F08DFA7DAD59501630"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of need for further support of employees of the National Weather Service engaged in emergency response through services provided by the Public Health Service. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCA7546FC45194713AD64F6052393E619"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A detailed assessment of appropriations required to secure the level of support services needed as identified in the assessment described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCCC39ABEF3DC4D12A5B6D557D3D1ED14"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional support services</header><text>Following the completion of the assessment required by paragraph (1), the Under Secretary shall seek to acquire additional support services to meet the needs identified in the assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H8F667BC5E0124D3487523071BA80FE78"><enum>19.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administration to carry out this Act and the amendments made by this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H9D2E927B618C49E9ADD77AE1CD7F4C89"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$55,000,000 for fiscal year 2023; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H898C3CA45D31401F9BBDA901B6E02CD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$125,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H597D193AAFF74A0BBB384D06289024E8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$135,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H906E24C1959D426EBF524241EC941853"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$150,000,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88C8F9CC047949E09170A8910E37CE74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$200,000,000 for fiscal year 2027. </text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

