<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE4EE9CF696894D2D92009EF394904F3F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8659 IH: Animal Violence Exposes Real Threat of Future Violence Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8659</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001101">Ms. Clark of Massachusetts</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001260">Mr. Buchanan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to conduct a study on animal cruelty, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9A4E1A175732475FBD68AF4DA2B8ACB1" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HAEE6CE55BA7A4B1A83E9A74E31967704"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Animal Violence Exposes Real Threat of Future Violence Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>AVERT Future Violence Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H0C5AAE48686244D59EB25B40CD31FADA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H13D20B1B212F47B9B0A821E97671F664"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Animal cruelty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>animal cruelty</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H3BD1E51F5ACD4BB3898BFF67F2EEA279"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means—</text>
<clause id="H6A56F9D21A8A477C980513D58757FEA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intentionally, knowingly, or recklessly harming or killing an animal, including maiming, mutilating, torturing, wounding, poisoning, engaging in animal fighting, and sexually abusing an animal, or attempting to do so; or</text></clause> <clause id="HF36DB8BAB0E94281B34589443A00C3F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>intentionally or knowingly neglecting or depriving an animal of necessary sustenance or shelter, or attempting to do so; and </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3495C777254846AE88CAC15022B1270D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include any conduct that is—</text> <clause id="HEE1E8084915D4049A009AF6F40434388"><enum>(i)</enum><text>customary and normal veterinary, agricultural husbandry, or other animal management practice;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF0E56F3085A84256B5DD55B7B7AE18B9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the slaughter of animals for food;</text></clause> <clause id="H92A60DE8D6D745E38E4F6E51BDFB5D1C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>hunting, trapping, fishing, a sporting activity not otherwise prohibited by Federal law, predator control, or pest control;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA6A1D3613EB8417B92B7D0666554E4E6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>medical or scientific research;</text></clause> <clause id="HBBC59F221F0F48D6A6CD1E320776551E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>necessary to protect the life of a person; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H093BAAA845364A6C9CAC0C07DBB5BC4B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>performed as part of euthanizing an animal. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H49B8155907534BC8A064127DC607705F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H4870CA7A6D214DA7A88B78958F40210C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3E3819A14694CCBA1670FE6E5CEBC3D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a unit of local government;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0B92C653ABE3480B9059382A74AA1C86"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State or local court (including a juvenile court);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAB7C3D258093425094D19ABDF02F6BE0"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an Indian Tribe; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFBC0D2BFB8A94892B3D7FF3972B231A1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any other organization that has a documented history of effective work identifying, intervening in, preventing, reducing, or otherwise responding to animal cruelty, or animal cruelty as related to interpersonal violence (as determined by the Secretary), including—</text> <clause id="HD83DE2D48B76496585E9E64F37AC163F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any organization that works directly with or on behalf of pets, service animals, emotional support animals, or horses and collaborates with any organization referred to in subparagraphs (A) through (D), including—</text>
<subclause id="H780946305FE94B138B7C3FFAFE1C1E5C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an animal shelter; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HD2D1D446803848E6B1DE1B6F3D0D4B43"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an animal welfare organization;</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="H90EAAA17B4424680B750699D2F2C1F6A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any organization that provides mental health services to perpetrators and survivors of crime;</text></clause> <clause id="HE6D8411A115E452C8327C859D7D03061"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any organization that develops and provides training programs for law enforcement, judges, prosecutors, other court personnel, veterinarians, or mental health professionals;</text></clause>
<clause id="H0BE77AF5EA58468D87DC74EE34912825"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a domestic violence and sexual assault victim service provider;</text></clause> <clause id="HA26F547A30134BC19D7F348F4C7C9A55"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a domestic violence and sexual assault coalition;</text></clause>
<clause id="H00251F4CDCCF4721BAC4E667566A1173"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>a child abuse victim service provider;</text></clause> <clause id="HF64BF789849146DCBA98816F06020D53"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>a provider of services to families under the supervision of the courts or departments of child and family services;</text></clause>
<clause id="H3F1A5830CBD740B0ADEAE948A5AD2796"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>an elder abuse victim service provider;</text></clause> <clause id="H3086DF9E817E49B8AD083CEDE12F4574"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>a community-based and culturally specific organization; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HA8700DFFA4E146DEAD4105CA6A6EDB14" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(x)</enum><text>any other nonprofit, nongovernmental organization. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H11E967081E984E26B508CB45E83B1737"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on animal cruelty, underlying factors, and future acts of human violence</header> <subsection id="H45B30CB0B8494508A9C577BA65284E3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, acting through the Director of the National Institute of Justice, shall carry out a study—</text>
<paragraph id="H479F7041C3AD47D1B537DF95A7C44EAA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the underlying factors that contribute to acts of animal cruelty committed by individuals; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6A37C3B68AA4AF0A3D89E3C59F2FB24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that analyzes acts of animal cruelty as a predictor of future violence against humans.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HFC2B43D57B76435FB736D549B5F7167C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Content of study</header><text>In carrying out the study under subsection (a), the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall—</text> <paragraph id="HFF862AEA2F9F454191D1E558C4FF44A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>specifically examine, through a review of scientific literature, original research, and expert input, as appropriate—</text>
<subparagraph id="H0CC39F82861748BF9146CF0A738DB2B4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evidence-informed risk factors associated or correlated with individuals who commit acts of animal cruelty;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCA0DB9F91E9E432F9D4654C052A5E5AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether certain acts of animal cruelty can be correlated with certain evidence-informed risk factors (such as whether the acts of animal torturing, tormenting, mutilation, maiming, poisoning, organized abuse, such as animal fighting, sexual abuse, abandonment, or neglect, are associated with the same or different evidence-informed risk factors);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF37801F6845C441BB1CCBF48B95D6F12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether certain acts of animal cruelty demonstrate a tendency or likelihood to commit a future act of violence against humans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13D07B3EE4614619BA97B51168AD7326"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the types of violence against humans most commonly associated with certain acts of animal cruelty (such as domestic violence and assault); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H16A608F6D11C45EEBD1D7B3F531987CE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations of areas in which future research on animal cruelty is needed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B4841BBDC854222B8B6EA6CF19A416A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop best practices for—</text>
<subparagraph id="H863E2FFEED2746DBBC47EEBD0DB7F89B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>early interventions that prevent acts of animal cruelty; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H37BCBA1E75734C0B94A1BE05E740B4A1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>interventions with individuals who have committed acts of animal cruelty to prevent future acts of violence.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF1701CE47EDF4F66BEC17ABED408C6E6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The Director of the National Institute of Justice shall submit to Congress a report containing the specific policy recommendations, based on the study conducted under this section, for legislative and regulatory action at the Federal, State, and local levels to—</text> <paragraph id="H78CC63D50A3E4758A2176E07641EAC4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>address the evidence-informed risk factors that may contribute to acts of animal cruelty committed by individuals; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAFD4710BBF3D43238D6D4377410DD501"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop effective interventions and diversion strategies for both juvenile and non-juvenile offenders who have been convicted of criminal offenses involving animal cruelty that reduce the likelihood of offenders committing future violent acts against both humans and animals.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H955148A5EC214D9CACFC86440CDA2908"><enum>4.</enum><header>Stop future violence grant program</header> <subsection id="H2F6FCA23E9964A589BB931E40A502279"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General is authorized to establish a grant program to provide assistance to eligible entities to develop and strengthen effective detection strategies, and early intervention or diversion resources, to stop acts of animal cruelty and rehabilitate offenders.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1DF1962CCB3A4214A8C2F5223D367CFA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A grant awarded under this section may be used to provide personnel, training, technical assistance, data collection, and other resources for the apprehension, prosecution, adjudication, and mental and behavioral health treatment of persons committing acts of animal cruelty, for the rehabilitation of perpetrators and the prevention of future acts of animal cruelty or violence against humans, and specifically, for the purposes of—</text> <paragraph id="H98275A8ACF924613BD1BE136146F10A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>training law enforcement officers, judges, other court personnel, prosecutors, and mental health professionals to more effectively identify and respond to acts of animal cruelty;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H37457930A68D4D95B9E8EF2098109F89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developing, training, or expanding units of law enforcement officers, judges, other court personnel, prosecutors, and mental health professionals specifically addressing acts of animal cruelty;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA3626701F18D4B27987071FC349C81EF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>developing and implementing more effective police, court, prosecution, mental health, and early intervention policies, protocols, orders, and services specifically devoted to preventing, identifying, and responding to acts of animal cruelty; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2C328F130825457B9EF652D95309086B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>developing, installing, or expanding data collection and communication systems, including computerized systems, linking police, prosecutors, and courts, or for the purpose of identifying, classifying, and tracking arrests, protection orders, violations of protection orders, prosecutions, and convictions for acts of animal cruelty.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H12B0283D8D2140E0A01D58F330CFA707"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated—</text>
<paragraph id="H2DE7F831DCBB4FEE9AD819EACA673581"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purposes of carrying out section 3, $2,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available until expended; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DAE1CA1819A41C1A8C22CD963689D72"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the purposes of carrying out section 4, $2,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

