<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8A61873CD68D49E0BF48DB42246372DF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8227 IH: Speak Out Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8227</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220624">June 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To limit the judicial enforceability of predispute nondisclosure and nondisparagement contract clauses relating to disputes involving sexual assault and sexual harassment.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H509764ED8B4C44F0881E6F167C056DF0" style="OLC"><section id="H4EA0E64F53784F82B607CA67795EBC84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Speak Out Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8F3AC8F9D17F4521897B17272FA8AFB2"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H006659FBE1DD47FF83155DE0FA16E430"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Sexual harassment and assault remain pervasive in the workplace and throughout civic society, affecting millions of Americans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FC353884ECC49BE8821F118BC3A8BCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Eighty-one percent of women and 43 percent of men have experienced some form of sexual harassment and/or assault throughout their lifetime.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF1E00D6D9354785899EE8BD77B47BC8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>One in 3 women has faced sexual harassment in the workplace during her career, and an estimated 87 to 94 percent of those who experience sexual harassment never file a formal complaint.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6D166A8628D4F70BF9DA78922B68B63"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Sexual harassment in the workplace forces many women to leave their occupation or industry, or pass up opportunities for advancement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC21082F4634458B98A9D4E60D41B45"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In order to combat sexual harassment and assault, it is essential that victims and survivors have the freedom to report and publicly disclose their abuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F43DFA35F3E4301BA6C9F85B222EFF1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Nondisclosure and nondisparagement provisions in agreements between employers and current, former, and prospective employees, and independent contractors, and between providers of goods and services and consumers, can perpetuate illegal conduct by silencing those who are survivors of illegal sexual harassment and assault or illegal retaliation, or have knowledge of such conduct, while shielding perpetrators and enabling them to continue their abuse.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF65D8C31EA84F3FB34F6EDE4895436B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prohibiting predispute nondisclosure and nondisparagement clauses will empower survivors to come forward, hold perpetrators accountable for abuse, improve transparency around illegal conduct, enable the pursuit of justice, and make workplaces safer and more productive for everyone.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF7087F3F3AD94924A30A579337A88DDF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Limitation on judicial enforceability of predispute nondisclosure and nondisparagement contract clauses relating to sexual assault disputes and sexual harassment disputes</header><subsection id="H551FC34E9DF341DB8699F0150ECB4E9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a sexual assault dispute or sexual harassment dispute, no predispute nondisclosure clause or predispute nondisparagement clause shall be judicially enforceable in instances in which conduct is alleged to have violated Federal, Tribal, or State law.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9A60CEA5CBC4C70B47A95113EE8518A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continued applicability of State law</header><text>This Act shall not be construed to supersede a provision of State law that establishes, implements, or continues in effect a requirement or prohibition except to the extent that such requirement or prohibition prevents the application of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1C1905242AC44929623CFA8B07BBB09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Continued Applicability of Federal, State, and Tribal Law</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall not be construed to supersede a provision of Federal, State, or Tribal Law that governs the use of pseudonyms in the filing of claims involving sexual assault or sexual harassment disputes.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBFE33E3F5FFF4EB9B0AFC77F2C908EF2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA0C293823D6E43F4B34090ACB4DFEB70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Predispute nondisclosure clause</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>predispute nondisclosure clause</quote> means a provision in a contract or agreement agreed to before a lawsuit is filed under Federal, State, or Tribal law, that requires the parties to the contract or agreement not to disclose or discuss conduct, the existence of a settlement involving conduct, or information covered by the terms and conditions of the contract or agreement. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25601E1C75594FBEADF57E36F943A254"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Predispute nondisparagement clause</header><text>The term <quote>predispute nondisparagement clause</quote> means a provision in a contract or agreement that requires 1 or more parties to the contract or agreement not to make a negative statement about another party that relates to the contract, agreement, claim, or case.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F3C8D7F227742DA84CE511290FD2578"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Sexual assault dispute</header><text>The term <quote>sexual assault dispute</quote> means a dispute involving a nonconsensual sexual act or sexual contact, as such terms are defined in section 2246 of title 18 of the United States Code, or similar applicable Tribal or State law, including when the victim lacks capacity to consent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H951EDEA3E9C245A5AAE539A896AB19BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sexual harassment dispute</header><text>The term <quote>sexual harassment dispute</quote> means a dispute relating to conduct that is alleged to constitute sexual harassment under applicable Federal, Tribal, or State law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFA3432D5397D4C31B53D7075BE8E2A32" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall apply with respect to a claim that is filed under Federal, State, or Tribal law on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

