<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1DB853A35C2D4D8F80B3671FAFCDFEF8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9108 IH: Endangered Species Transparency and Reasonableness Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9108</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001084">Ms. Herrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001212">Mr. Stauber</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001128">Ms. Conway</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Endangered Species Act of 1973 to require publication on the internet of the basis for determinations that species are endangered species or threatened species, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H72A13506772E40DEBDA049986A802B07" style="OLC"><section id="H473FA1DAB3C04400814C555C7830CF92" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Endangered Species Transparency and Reasonableness Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HAFF2091E83954C339298D3C119CE2249"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement to publish on the internet the basis for listings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 4(b) of the Endangered Species Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HBA8662043C284164BEDDBE29C6428C17" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H17EAD67EA1C94924AA7B0453565A708A" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall make publicly available on the internet the best scientific and commercial data available that are the basis for each regulation, including each proposed regulation, promulgated under subsection (a)(1), except that—</text><subparagraph id="H442A90F77F464090829ADB87AE88E12F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>at the request of a Governor, State agency, or legislature of a State, the Secretary shall not make information available under this paragraph if such State determines that public disclosure of such information is prohibited by a law or regulation of such State, including any law or regulation requiring the protection of personal information; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H359D6D15BDD94CC5AE2122627F210600"><enum>(B)</enum><text>within 30 days after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary shall execute an agreement with the Secretary of Defense that prevents the disclosure of classified information pertaining to Department of Defense personnel, facilities, lands, or waters.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H68D80C1237844F7E8628B941379F747B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Decisional transparency and use of State, tribal, and local information</header><subsection id="HFAA6013C2E0F4CE6A28F7F45356CB677"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requiring decisional transparency with affected States</header><text>Section 6(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1535">16 U.S.C. 1535(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCEC281C40C9143AE87DDA5BC978F3E84"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting <quote>(1)</quote> before the first sentence; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B5EE239519F433EB1911C15F4AC8A17"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>Such cooperation shall include</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H59BD10F01CD94795B706D608B6DC778C" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H1C1FD107D41F4BEDBBE2CA1D8E6E5FAA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such cooperation shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HB23CA3F2B54A4B5493D7099F5468CA84"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">before making a determination under section 4(a), providing to States affected by such determination all data that is the basis of the determination; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DF81769B3B6498693A752F2D04DB71D"><enum>(B)</enum></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H79BD2491787C4F8D9A7041CD4CE07CA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Ensuring use of State, tribal, and local information</header><paragraph id="H747D73EA32564BBD8B54442F9565C2F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H7EA4F16E12FB4D7FBC14EED4F167D01A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) through (21) as paragraphs (3) through (22), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88BC107C07A2459BA39A6C843E7918CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEC1A94175ED54DBC8A5193B06ADE25DB" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H5392D2AE027F47F5AF5A6975D5B8EFBA" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>best scientific and commercial data available</quote> includes all such data submitted by a State, Tribal, or county government.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EB89B2948B84128BC49AB14DC5D3961"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 7(n) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536(n)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 3(13)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 3(14)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1EA3F2FCB1F7487E90B02C9A95605499"><enum>4.</enum><header>Disclosure of expenditures under Endangered Species Act of 1973</header><subsection id="H43C588EFD2CB4CA38E3655A9F957A49A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To disclose</header><text>Section 13 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (87 Stat. 902; relating to conforming amendments which have executed) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HFC7BA5A37B5249E98E1D02527B355F07" style="OLC"><section id="H886CCDEE42944A9B96BBFBFD3B3131F7"><enum>13.</enum><header>Disclosure of expenditures</header><subsection id="H9CBEB370407147DE83C441ECC684079A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>The Secretary of the Interior, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, shall—</text><paragraph id="H2E1FA2CE96AE4053A139BB8CE7C37E9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 90 days after the end of each fiscal year, submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate an annual report detailing Federal Government expenditures for covered suits during the preceding fiscal year (including the information described in subsection (b)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7B2C7DC994E4812AC30FB8D436E7576"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make publicly available through the internet a searchable database, updated monthly, of the information described in subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD11DF6E5DC634C15AC2D4E509BAF1F12"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Included information</header><text>The report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HEA3D82DAE756407A99B9066B1A78A08D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the case name and number of each covered suit, and a hyperlink to the settlement decisions, final decision, consent decrees, stipulations of dismissal, releases, interim decisions, motions to dismiss, partial motions for summary judgement, or related final documents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFC4003415974AE89569B09C3E4B8834"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of each claim or cause of action in each covered suit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFCAFC5B1F70433DB5A6CF6CCFBB7EF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name of each covered agency whose actions give rise to any claim in a covered suit and each plaintiff in such suit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D703ADA23034EFCB1A6107CA8E9EE9F"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funds expended by each covered agency (disaggregated by agency account) to receive and respond to notices referred to in section 11(g)(2) or to prepare for litigation of, litigate, negotiate a settlement agreement or consent decree in, or provide material, technical, or other assistance in relation to, a covered suit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA46353594FF4B08B90896250A89CAA4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the number of full-time equivalent employees that participated in the activities described in paragraph (4);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D88E9079BC646B99BD6BC40DFF75ED1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any information required to be published under section 1304 of title 31, United States Code, with respect to a covered suit;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6E79D973A4C41D99316364C664715D7"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">attorneys fees and other expenses (disaggregated by agency account) awarded in covered suits, including any consent decrees or settlement agreements (regardless of whether a decree or settlement agreement is sealed or otherwise subject to nondisclosure provisions), including the bases for such awards; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68F7D42D06A14E23BCE5C0C34AA44A20"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any Federal funding used by a person or a governmental or nongovernmental entity in bringing a claim in a covered suit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63F56753087448A6BBCB3C407FAA78E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirement To provide information</header><text>The head of each covered agency shall provide to the Secretary in a timely manner all information requested by the Secretary to comply with the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1CD3C3178D0043E986FD2AF94B376EEE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on disclosure</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, this section shall not affect any restriction in a consent decree or settlement agreement on the disclosure of information that is not described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H784F4FD6A4924D6EAF4425B273BECB63"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><paragraph id="HE2A7C7C53C864B809AE362DA7722E170"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered agency</quote> means any agency of the Department of the Interior, the Forest Service, the Environmental Protection Agency, the National Marine Fisheries Service, the Bonneville Power Administration, the Western Area Power Administration, the Southwestern Power Administration, or the Southeastern Power Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H509E1A2519D64CC1896861AAC502CD6F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered suit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered suit</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H599DD9790E90412A980E0AA5462D1E70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any civil action containing any claim arising under this Act against the Federal Government and based on the action of a covered agency; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H079CF701D8C541C6AA3937ECE3BE2C96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any administrative proceeding under which the United States awards fees and other expenses to a third party under section 504 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HD0DB650B25954C17A0ED8DD74FBF8703"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in the first section of such Act is amended by striking the item relating to section 13 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H810D3AE6F86C444B87611F39BB993271" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 13. Disclosure of expenditures.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6A7B67B1B31E40A0B3016B21C0E442CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prior amendments not affected</header><text>This section shall not be construed to affect the amendments made by section 13 of such Act, as in effect before the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA7DB36699E124BC4B8F1EF4A0979FC84"><enum>5.</enum><header>Award of litigation costs to prevailing parties in accordance with existing law</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11(g)(4) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1540">16 U.S.C. 1540(g)(4)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>to any</quote> and all that follows through the end of the sentence and inserting <quote>in accordance with section 2412 of title 28, United States Code and section 504 of title 5, United States Code.</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

