<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA92AB885A3564DEE843B78FE786EFFE5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9217 IH: Halting Of Trafficking and Exploitation in Lodging Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9217</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221021">October 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to establish a priority for accommodation in places with policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H39F137B02F4B45A7BF4536BCE9B82622" style="OLC"><section id="HEB5D460669344E3B82217B14B9B660CF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Halting Of Trafficking and Exploitation in Lodging Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>HOTEL Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H52EB6231B4364224BDCD7A0E611D5987"><enum>2.</enum><header>Priority for accommodation in places with policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking</header><subsection id="H8994373071884ADA8A6A502D85B2E593"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7DE5F85920D549C29225489A072A6158" style="USC"><section id="H161B71FA43DD4E1991189B020562B54B"><enum>5712.</enum><header>Priority for accommodation in places with certain policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking</header><subsection id="H8BD20F9934B94B2486E97A9C308BA5FD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For the purpose of making payments under this chapter for lodging expenses, each agency shall ensure that, to the greatest extent practicable, commercial-lodging room nights in the United States for employees of that agency are booked in a preferred place of accommodation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8701FBBAC63A4D588ADAF0E5527D6271"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility as a preferred place of accommodation</header><text>To be considered a preferred place of accommodation for the purposes of this section, a hotel or motel shall—</text><paragraph id="H282C4C05A4994EAD98F5A3993C40A95D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>enforce a zero-tolerance policy regarding severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 103(11) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7102">22 U.S.C. 7102(11)</external-xref>)) made available by the Administrator of General Services under subsection (c)(1), or a similar zero-tolerance policy developed by the place of accommodation, demonstrated by—</text><subparagraph id="HC25D1EC015F54CFA9F91836560CF71B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>posting such policy in a nonpublic space within the place of accommodation that is accessible by all employees; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC98282D159E34B02B0668317238A18A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>including such policy in the employee handbook;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H78C6E4EB41BF41CFAA16883D87AF1552"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have procedures in place, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, for employees to identify and report any such exploitation according to protocol identified in the employee training based on training materials developed under subsection (c)(3) to the appropriate law enforcement authorities, management of the preferred accommodation, or the National Human Trafficking Hotline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3F172130F0403BBB388123E112F843"><enum>(3)</enum><text>post the informational materials made available under subsection (c)(3) in an appropriate nonpublic space within the place of accommodation that is accessible by all employees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AF1FA42BE584F748FF88CB4D4EF2A1A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>review and update, as necessary, the zero-tolerance policy, procedures, and informational materials at least every two years prior to the due date for self-certifications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90DBE614622740A58A1BC07CAF2F3109"><enum>(5)</enum><text>require each employee who is physically located at the place of accommodation and who is likely to interact with guests, including security, front desk, housekeeping, room service, and bell staff, to complete the training developed under subsection (c)(2), or a training developed pursuant to subsection (d), that shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8ED8912970AC4364AF71EC20C393E90B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>take place not later than 90 days after the starting date of the new employee, or in the case of an employee hired before the effective date of this section, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD678CC62F7C34C2992BDCAFFDC9CD75B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include refresher trainings every two years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H287B11F08FFD4B1F80D6EDD454EEF7ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include training on the identification of possible cases of sexual exploitation of children and procedures to report suspected abuse to the appropriate authorities;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2490F16EDE8C45FCB211CBB1E1436BE3"><enum>(6)</enum><text>include a notice to all independent contractors in any agreement affecting a property in the United States negotiated or renewed on or after the date of enactment of this section that states the following: <quote>Federal law prohibits the trafficking of humans under the Trafficking Victims Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7101">22 U.S.C. 7101 et seq.</external-xref>).</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97A53F07C42A4670A3EF8563CD1C48DC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>ensure that the place of accommodation does not retaliate against employees for reporting suspected cases of such exploitation if reported according to protocol identified in the employee training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3948CE4359BD4A2E8FEED85284691605"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GSA requirements</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall—</text><paragraph id="H76F08B166AF54BDB8EF5CE5E13E67910"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make available on the website of the General Services Administration, an up-to-date model zero tolerance policy for places of accommodation regarding severe forms of trafficking in persons (as defined in section 103(11) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (22 U.S.C. (11))), including informational materials regarding such policy to be posted in places of accommodation in nonpublic spaces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AB5085AAE0247AF89E358A682475BE8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make available on the website of the General Services Administration an up-to-date list of Department of Homeland Security, Department of Justice, and Department of State and privately produced training programs that address the identification of severe forms of human trafficking and reporting to law enforcement authorities or the National Human Trafficking Hotline;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H593240FCA4C4435DAD1E57B6D0FD3CA4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security’s Blue Campaign, make available up-to-date training materials on preventing severe forms of human trafficking and informational materials to be posted in nonpublic spaces in places of accommodation on spotting the signs of severe forms of human trafficking and reporting possible incidences of such exploitation, except that the Administrator shall permit the use of substantially similar training materials or informational materials required by State or local law on identifying the signs of human trafficking and reporting possible incidences of such exploitation in lieu of materials developed under this paragraph; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9592BD65DBC440DEA456E219A034E12E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>maintain a list of each preferred place of accommodation that meets the requirements of subsection (b), beginning by examining places of accommodation that are—</text><subparagraph id="HBDD51CD8A44848DBAC88B014BAE4061F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>participating in government lodging programs such as FedRooms (or successor system);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88C38E9DC66D47329D9C1C18E91EB75B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included on the FEMA Fire Safe List; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF0676B63ABB42FB8BB08DAEBB14BC96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>otherwise known to have received government travel business in the 2 years prior to enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B08ED45DBFD4E00ABB9E45D54D4BFC8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training programs</header><text>A place of accommodation or lodging company may use a training program developed or acquired by such place of accommodation or company to satisfy the requirements of subsection (b)(4) if such training program—</text><paragraph id="HA1D790CDEF774255A973E5BDE1608A4A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>focuses on identifying and reporting suspected cases of severe forms of human trafficking; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC2B7A94A01D45D3A336E99FC19CB48D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>was developed in consultation with State governments, survivor leaders, survivor-led anti-trafficking organization, or a nationally recognized organization with expertise in anti-trafficking initiatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0D95F9F3ED8F40A881FDEC79FD10FC7F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Previously trained employees</header><paragraph id="H22321CCE3D034770BD5D369BD53BC11D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training prior to effective date</header><text>Any employee of a place of accommodation who has been trained to identify and report potential cases of severe forms of human trafficking during the 2-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this section shall be considered to have met the training requirement in subsection (b)(4) with respect to any employment at that place of accommodation or at any other place of accommodation managed by the same entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53561CA3F6884E6896EC92703043E0C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Training prior to a transfer of employment</header><text>Any employee of a place of accommodation who has met the training requirements under subsection (b)(4) shall be considered to have met such requirements with respect to any employment at a place of accommodation managed by the same entity if such training occurred during the 2-year period ending on the date of the enactment of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBBDFD35C7DED4715B66B410470E917C4"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Property-by-Property Implementation</header><paragraph id="H7A1D664A45064470BE4B44281809F8F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each preferred place of accommodation shall self-certify (in writing) to the Administrator of General Services that such place is in compliance with the requirements of this section. Such self-certification shall occur every 2 years beginning on the date of the enactment of this section. The Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="H5AD43D7FD27848D8A7588A2DC2513DEB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide notice to each place of accommodation regarding any self-certification required under this subsection not later than the date that is 90 days before the due date of such self-certification; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C3FEA8CE28423CBD359ED2F2F13C06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>report to the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate, not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this section and every two years thereafter—</text><clause id="H04EF4243A36846D69633D08C9BF804E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each preferred places of accommodation that submitted and did not submit their self-certifications in the preceding 2 years; and</text></clause><clause id="HC9E25966D54C47FE9628297166A419A5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the corresponding total numbers of nights the government paid for Federal employees in self-certified preferred places of accommodation compared to preferred places of accommodation that did not report self-certification to the Administrator of General Services.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF51D7191AEB44FDDB21FCC4E5236D9B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Group certification</header><text>A person or entity that manages or franchises multiple places of accommodation may provide a single notice with respect to self-certification under subsection (a) that each such place is in compliance with this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE7A0E12DC8645B0ABAE8563094C4907"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Statutory construction</header><text>No provision in this section that applies to an employee of a place of accommodation shall be construed to apply to an individual who is an independent contractor or otherwise not directly employed by a place of accommodation, unless the contract is for housekeeping, security, front desk, room service, or bell staff, in which case it shall be the responsibility of the service provider to ensure compliance with the requirements set forth in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BA6A551E03848A9B473241AE6A360F0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations required</header><text>The Administrator of General Services shall issue such regulations as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H78599B393335466C8061E438F911FB57"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Section 5712(a) of title 5, United States Code (as added by subsection (a)), shall take effect 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H49392FD77D5B45188A7254423D53C423"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H4DD06817266D46C484F478807CDC43CD" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">5712. Priority for accommodation in places with certain policies relating to severe forms of human trafficking.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

