<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H99F84E52328147B89B8F0A0DD5E5FEF3" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8453 : Upholding the Dayton Peace Agreement Through Sanctions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8453</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220921">September 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSFR00">Committee on Foreign Relations</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons undermining the Dayton Peace Agreement or threatening the security of Bosnia and Herzegovina, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDF090D915DD049769B5ABA11C0218061" style="OLC"><section id="H5C5AE9351AF04D1D9B7257AF2925FB0C" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Upholding the Dayton Peace Agreement Through Sanctions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H31E9978CF4C94EE6915820876CE6D38E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="HA9909EBB1E4B4D61A772990E7622B7C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support Bosnia and Herzegovina’s sovereignty, territorial integrity, and multi-ethnic character;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48D15EA7F9B0482AA1C5F5BE52714395"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to back and bolster Bosnia and Herzegovina’s progress towards Euro-Atlantic integration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA22ABE8DC89E4E119F5A26F322D505D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to encourage officials in Bosnia and Herzegovina to resume institutional participation at all levels of government to advance functionality and common-sense reforms for greater prosperity and for Bosnia and Herzegovina to obtain European Union candidate status;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BF7200F9415441F8723422DE9F5D99E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to push Bosnia and Herzegovina to implement the rulings of the European Court of Human Rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3C9C514EBB84C5AB5CEFD6AE52FDBEB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to advocate for robust participation in the October 2, 2022, general elections in Bosnia and Herzegovina;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06E0734BAC6C4A48B0F38FB722315D7A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to utilize targeted sanctions against persons who undermine the Dayton Peace Agreement and democratic institutions, including by blocking, boycotting or not recognizing the results of elections, in Bosnia and Herzegovina to support peace and stability in that country;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H417875246F364680843AB77BB0D2D742"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to urge the European Union to join the United States and United Kingdom in sanctioning Milorad Dodik, a member of the Presidency of Bosnia and Herzegovina, for his actions that undermine the stability and territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5B39BA523884CBC80673B0E938467BD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>to expose and condemn the Government of Russia for its role in fueling instability in Bosnia and Herzegovina and undermining the Dayton Peace Agreement, the role of the Office of the High Representative, and the European Union Force in BiH’s Operation Althea;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H459D49DD35CD483E862928D02D63EF72"><enum>(9)</enum><text>to work with other regional States, including Serbia and Croatia, to support the territorial integrity and stability of Bosnia and Herzegovina; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5D63FC5A38043D7A34502793EDEC0B3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>to use its voice and vote at the United Nations, the Peace Implementation Council and its Steering Board, and other relevant international bodies to support the Office of the High Representative.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBBD95E8C89AC44C1A4EE5BC482AA836D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to foreign persons undermining the Dayton Peace Agreement or threatening the security of Bosnia and Herzegovina</header><subsection id="H5DDAD1D9311C480B8EF685BEE6AACDB4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="HBCB7ADEDBB624F039A9691F0444B096C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter for five years, the President shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a list of foreign persons that are determined—</text><subparagraph id="H7E3CC55D6F5D48C397AADBA28D2300E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, any action or policy that threatens the peace, security, stability, or territorial integrity of Bosnia and Herzegovina, including actions that seek to undermine the authority of Bosnia and Herzegovina’s state-level institutions, such as forming illegal parallel institutions or actions that threaten the Office of the High Representative; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF56BE5B7A5D0497FA4418192CF0D3C4B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, any action or policy that undermines democratic processes or institutions in Bosnia and Herzegovina; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1E433824CE7468A82BD2A5DDBD0BFC9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, or to have attempted, a violation of, or an act that has obstructed or threatened the implementation of, the Dayton Peace Agreement or the Conclusions of the Peace Implementation Conference Council held in London in December 1995, including the decisions or conclusions of the Office of the High Representative, the Peace Implementation Council, or its Steering Board; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC50ACFA11E6A405BA406360CCFE383A9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to be a member, official, or senior leader of an illegal parallel institution or any other institution that engages in activities described in subparagraph (A), (B) or (C), as determined by the Secretary of State; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3071934188E4635B6E681F895D715BA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to be responsible for or complicit in, or to have directly or indirectly engaged in, or attempted to engage in, corruption related to Bosnia and Herzegovina, including corruption by, on behalf of, or otherwise related to the government in Bosnia and Herzegovina, or a current or former government official at any level of government in Bosnia and Herzegovina, such as the misappropriation of public assets, expropriation of private assets for personal gain or political purposes, corruption related to government contracts or the extraction of natural resources or bribery; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA47EAF7B6CB428C9DE4E59769285FD6"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be an adult family member of any foreign person described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E) unless they have condemned the sanctionable activity and taken tangible steps to oppose the activity; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E6962FEB15C4100B3BF195260638C22"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to have knowingly facilitated a significant transaction or transactions for or on behalf of a foreign person described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02B8BBA72ED94B8EBD36D3CCF16E5A4B"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to be owned or controlled by, or to have acted or purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, a foreign person described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H66EC1C8B7A604BACAB38E493ECCE2433"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to have knowingly materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of, a foreign person described in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), or (E).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86E6F8C4D2DA42D5BA3628CE27D4ADA1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Upon the submission of each list required by paragraph (1), the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (c) with respect to each foreign person identified on the list. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H707F772191BD4286A628DB1D828E7EDC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional measure relating to facilitation of transactions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury may, in consultation with the Secretary of State, prohibit or impose strict conditions on the opening or maintaining in the United States of a correspondent account or payable-through account by a foreign financial institution that the President determines has, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, knowingly conducted or facilitated a significant transaction or transactions on behalf of a foreign person on the list required by subsection (a)(1). </text></subsection><subsection id="H5F2D364DA5054A3C89DE2F8E6A398E58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following: </text><paragraph id="HFDA7A468A0804801B9AB9DDC23B00282"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property blocking</header><text>Notwithstanding the requirements of section 202 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref>), the President may exercise of all powers granted to the President by that Act to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB2AB1C7F8FC4F58A621285855E343A9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="HA1F94E692E094B12AAA13FCDB1B2165F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien on the list required by subsection (a)(1) is—</text><clause id="H37790E689B374816AEE9CF176EDFE4A5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HEA5FA93F83A84A17B552E0EDFF55EB21"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible for a visa or travel to the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HD79F2E840ABC44F49A1BAB5234C7A5B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F64ABE3B08D4FE1B55280ECEE122857"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="HDD94A5F1561B43B7B9821439331CB07D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien on the list required by subsection (a)(1) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></clause><clause id="H77D95D69396549678AFE7DB4F0E1A8EE"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A visa or other entry documentation revoked under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="H529B3AF12E8F4269B6453407401ECBD5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take effect immediately; and </text></subclause><subclause id="HE345DF39D5E24C48B60016D07DD604F4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1F2441F9A595479B8BBD289344F2763B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H7EF04390E97F4CE989A2415E428AF1EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Sanctions under this section shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3084D9A3DE947B5BECBF8ED091DF3C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception to comply with united nations headquarters agreement</header><text>Sanctions under subsection (c)(2) shall not apply with respect to the admission of an alien to the United States if the admission of the alien is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, the Convention on Consular Relations, done at Vienna April 24, 1963, and entered into force March 19, 1967, or other applicable international obligations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDC7BA78731147748A372859F0D9407C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception relating to the provision of humanitarian assistance</header><text>Sanctions under this section may not be imposed with respect to transactions or the facilitation of transactions for—</text><subparagraph id="HE0B3F16456DA4F1B9C3421DCB37091D7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the sale of agricultural commodities, food, medicine, or medical devices;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9945C86DAE84498BBBCB9F3B9A026FF5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the provision of humanitarian assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H953224E3941844DAA5ECB832AC3EF97E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>financial transactions relating to humanitarian assistance or for humanitarian purposes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4761F9AAD504EB8A562762C6785E6D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>transporting goods or services that are necessary to carry out operations relating to humanitarian assistance or humanitarian purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F6D532D4B4F4C769B41344A00AD4B99"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may, on a case-by-case basis and for periods not to exceed 180 days each, waive the application of sanctions or restrictions imposed with respect to a foreign person under this section if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before such waiver is to take effect that the waiver is vital to the national interest of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC0C35F70354247A0A8634214310DC05B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H6820194040254DB486659B850C5BEC92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, prescribe regulations as necessary for the implementation of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2DD500CD01A439FABE42F70C7555F8C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>Not later than 10 days before the prescription of regulations under paragraph (1), the President shall notify the appropriate congressional committees regarding the proposed regulations and the provisions of this Act that the regulations are implementing.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99709691A13243559FC53C65A4883D1B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5ADB1FEE36F14796ABADEAE152109261"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations prescribed to carry out this Act to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section 206.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7CB407A2AAFB4B088753D3D790E20973"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Termination of sanctions</header><text>The President may terminate the application of sanctions under this section with respect to a foreign person if the President determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees not later than 15 days before the termination of the sanctions that—</text><paragraph id="H4EA85CA53880414A8825F6D3AC46E7E4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>credible information exists that the foreign person did not engage in the activity for which sanctions were imposed; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F5100644BB4411FB0399F9853A09DBA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the foreign person has been prosecuted appropriately for the activity for which sanctions were imposed; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7773A9316324D1EAA58E9196FA7FA2E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the foreign person has credibly demonstrated a significant change in behavior, has paid an appropriate consequence for the activity for which sanctions were imposed, and has credibly committed to not engage in an activity described in subsection (a)(1) in the future.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H220B89AA2C4E48679E0C44628A6AA9D4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority to impose sanctions under this section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7ABAE6F5BD2841628A8FA86145FEC91E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Consideration of certain information in imposing sanctions</header><subsection id="HA720D24297D74750AE9C4BA2ACC64A77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after receiving a request from the chairman and ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees with respect to whether a person, foreign person, or foreign financial institution, as the case may be, meets the criteria described in this Act, Executive Order 14033 (86 Fed. Reg. 31079; relating to blocking property and suspending entry into the United States of certain persons contributing to the destabilizing situation in the Western Balkans), or any Executive order issued pursuant to this Act or under the Balkans regulatory regime, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H8B5D91C2BC0D480C9F1217C93E7A11F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine if the person, foreign person, or foreign financial institution, as the case may be, meets such criteria; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA86ED45A0FDE4549B05C1C6AC623DE69"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit a classified or unclassified report to such chairman and ranking member with respect to such determination that includes a statement of whether or not the President imposed or intends to impose sanctions with respect to such person, foreign person, or foreign financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H08CD2EBCD08D4459877BBD04C3387932"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall terminate on the date that is five years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H7712DDA69A824B9185C8EA9DDA18B772"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exception for importation of goods</header><subsection id="H6E612683C6DC4CF7936383FE9799C596"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions under this Act shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7AE4ED53D6B4496B8DB7A38871400B42"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply, or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6B7C6B99CD4942269DA44E9682385A73"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8089E1ABEF0043719770E1A557035471"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admitted; alien</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms “admitted” and “alien” have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H551936CB1B344464B648C524E1B90C2B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term “appropriate congressional committees” means—</text><subparagraph id="H8AF9A981207A4B77907F43B737E20AF3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CF217227B394340A99D0C30925D7534"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H173368BB8937467F9925EF8241C9F89E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Correspondent account; payable-through account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms “correspondent account” and “payable-through account” have the meanings given those terms in section 5318A of title 31, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A01DD15876B4BE3A54EFF7894193FA3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Dayton Peace Agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Dayton Peace Agreement</quote>, also known as the <quote>Dayton Accords</quote>, means the General Framework Agreement for Peace in Bosnia and Herzegovina, initialed by the parties in Dayton, Ohio, on November 21, 1995, and signed in Paris on December 14, 1995.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB87A2FD9C84B43B7AC9A86C9DFC791C6"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text>The term “foreign financial institution” has the meaning of that term as determined by the Secretary of the Treasury by regulation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H168A018BC7B941E48BA85D70D3F25F56"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term “foreign person” means a person that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57398CE4392C4024A772AF3852D3F39D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Illegal parallel institution</header><text>The term <quote>illegal parallel institution</quote> means an agency, structure, or instrumentality at the Republika Srpska entity level that disrupts the authority of the state-level institutions of Bosnia and Herzegovina and undermines its constitutional order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23E6A6870BC5482280300232D50FE798"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term “knowingly”, with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person has actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4037FD7A4FF44E818DEBA276A1B557EB"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Person</header><text>The term “person” means an individual or entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DD3A5E1F3324066B3793416AF8CEFB8"><enum>(10)</enum><header>United States person</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term “United States person” means—</text><subparagraph id="H021CFA55011B4662B5CDAA5D468B77EA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted to the United States for permanent residence; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA39D9BF0048A454F9EBEF5702F182998"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H345A4F8018994FF58FDC9C9A69F86DDA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any person in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H0F319680D75D46C4AAF254B3A33086EA"><enum>7.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled “Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation” for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220920" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 20, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role><proxy display="yes">Kevin F. McCumber,</proxy><role>Deputy Clerk</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

