<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H884F7DA74E574847BDC72525ACC29A44" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6592 IH: Immigration Transparency and Transit Notification Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6592</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001204">Mr. Meuser</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001118">Mr. Cline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000605">Mr. Perry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000610">Mr. Reschenthaler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000612">Mr. Rose</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Health and Human Services to notify the relevant Federal, State, and local officials of a jurisdiction before placing a covered alien in such jurisdiction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9F578881B3E04AB78F46ABA62E77EC64" style="OLC"><section id="H274CCBD135064D14B0FEE5956A92D2B7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Immigration Transparency and Transit Notification Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HED900B4035ED42C884604BD5E0DDE178"><enum>2.</enum><header>State involvement in the placement of covered aliens</header><subsection id="H55768C7005BB414099A296CA94725680"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification required</header><paragraph id="H4D4F9EDBAAF941239BB1A4852B264176"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as applicable, shall notify the relevant Federal, State, and local officials of a jurisdiction at least 7 calendar days before—</text><subparagraph id="H4F3648A262834E288D8767D79858CC89"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">transporting a covered alien to such jurisdiction by airplane, motor vehicle, or other means for disembarkment (even if such transporting or related processing is carried out on behalf of the Federal Government by a private entity); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82E904DCB62443A8BE28498611426AFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>placing a covered alien in such jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70D344E227D446F6A53B5775EED466EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a notification under paragraph (1) to the Governor of a State, the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as applicable, shall supplement the notification, for each covered alien, to include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBE637641E47C4C8785AA598669B46D86"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Name.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5789A4DEB9A4DEBB1AFEAC9978A43A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Date of birth.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2D620234CC54CECA6A6558B76C85937"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Verification of the covered alien’s country of nationality, consisting of—</text><clause id="HD4D8BECE958945659E14010FA43FFD2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a copy of a government-issued identity document of the covered alien from that country; or</text></clause><clause id="H7C993146C56C4EFF83B45812833D332A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if the covered alien does not have such a document, other such verification.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H325EE6CD1F8647DFB1F5C976139DEEA2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Any biometrics collected from the covered alien.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H433666B6C84146ED8899D1FF21EC3425"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Proof of completion of any required background check, the results of any background check, and any criminal history information, if applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7E3A738E279840379C40A1E0966EB103"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Final destination.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D9AA23E1CE7491CB22BCDA6EDA4E10A"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sponsor information, if applicable, including the sponsor’s name, date of birth, immigration status, and address.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD7AF32D24FF24899929A80C6FE1B87B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Opportunity for Governor To object</header><paragraph id="HD769B7B6A95147F190858A38E0BA3569"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Objection</header><text>Not later than 3 calendar days after receiving a notification under subsection (a), the Governor of a State in which a covered alien is proposed to be placed or transported for disembarkment may submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security or the Secretary of Health and Human Services, as applicable, a written objection to the proposed placement or disembarkment in that State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H20E569D05F2B480D9DA1D4F4CF4656B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternate placement required</header><text>In the case that the Governor of a State objects to the placement or disembarkment of a covered alien in that State under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Health and Human Services may not place or transport for disembarkment the covered alien in that State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9229AB3A0AE44E6A5FB5D07170142AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (2) does not apply in the case of placement of an unaccompanied alien child with, or transport of an unaccompanied alien child to, a family member in accordance with section 235 of the William Wilberforce Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1232">8 U.S.C. 1232</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H810FC735CF404BAA861A7AF9C824DF00"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H730FF78202624253BF07971FCE8AB8DF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unaccompanied alien child</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 462 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/279">6 U.S.C. 279</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7399BA8FAC22460D9C7665057C0F2AC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>covered alien</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HBD0D4C352DB84511B815A3A0983B2E37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an unaccompanied alien child; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7118FD8AE82947F1A2B28B53A516E6D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an alien without lawful immigration status.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H59A8449556BD47609AC5FE3AF896130C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>disembarkment</term> excludes disembarking at an airport for transfer to another airplane at that airport unless the final destination is in the same State as the transfer airport.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5921E754F34486B9759D750AA2D8A27"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>family member</term> means an individual described in any of subparagraphs (1) through (4) of section 410.301 of title 45, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74EE4162C3CD4D88AAA5618EFE3DBB14"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>place</term> and <term>placement</term> include placing a covered alien on a temporary basis in juvenile or other housing. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H126F3B42BF2F477A84E6246118A765E7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The term <term>relevant Federal, State, and local officials</term> means, with respect to a jurisdiction referred to in subsection (a), the following officials:</text><subparagraph id="H5CBF12A591434419B153DFA2EAA5E90E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Governor of the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB19F8EDB4604D10856E5BDD4BF8A96E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Attorney General of the State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ACF2CB0633E486F98BE4ECE7BCE6DA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The head of any county or municipal government that includes such jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35A1B93725734D0692CFBB221234611B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The head or heads of local law enforcement in such jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25BFD23C6101496CBFB153E464AABB2B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Federal and State legislators elected to represent a State or district including such jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEC497D974381489294D2C8902150984E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Quarterly reports to Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not less than quarterly each year, the Secretary of Homeland Security and the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall each submit to the Chair and ranking member of each of the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives, and the Chair and ranking member of each of the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate, a report—</text><paragraph id="H467D3A76B91242288C285F491BA85D4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>including—</text><subparagraph id="H4E78D7BEF90D4E93B69AA7CA5C814519"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the notifications made by the respective Secretary pursuant to subsection (a)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD88E496E5BD543E3BB2A8AA5EAC7C842"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any objections received by the respective Secretary under subsection (b)(1); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7BE359F17A430DB6822D656AB30BA5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying—</text><subparagraph id="H8A03E230A8D94E8C9D74732CFE3B0549"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each private entity that pays all or part of the costs of, or otherwise assists with, any Federal transport by the respective Secretary’s department of a covered alien (as defined in section 2) between jurisdictions; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H942142C872274EC4BE02EA65496AF109"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount and source of any Federal funding used to pay for such transport.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

