<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC83ACDAB5E1144E184F0E3F261B8CC6A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7113 IH: Terminating Securities from Putin Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7113</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 5, United States Code, to prohibit sums in the Thrift Savings Fund from being invested in any security of an entity based in the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H04853CEA9CEC4C808788C575CC9849CA" style="OLC"><section id="HE10FD4841B7A45B5A315B572110CF188" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Terminating Securities from Putin Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TSP Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HEED23CD0704C40D9A917EC0032308D9D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on any TSP Fund investing in entities based in the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="H804C552EF6234AD29A3231FE36E31490"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8438 of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H621A211023064B908A278969262D5111" style="USC"><subsection id="H5D1D227BE2C746658DA00889CF17C07C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, no fund established or overseen by the Board may include an investment in any security of an entity based in the Russian Federation.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9B1E141E47E84843B86614F8E145EADD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Divestiture of assets</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board established under section 8472(a) of title 5, United States Code, shall—</text><paragraph id="H631E931BABA249509A41A027C0541082"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review whether any sums in the Thrift Savings Fund are invested in violation of subsection (i) of section 8438 of that title, as added by subsection (a) of this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49BAA0B17DDB47C7B4DE90F384BE9ACB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if any sums are invested in the manner described in paragraph (1), divest those sums in a manner that is consistent with the legal and fiduciary duties provided under chapter 84 of that title, or any other applicable provision of law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D1ED13539174E9A9FD6D14EA35B5DE4"><enum>(3)</enum><text>reinvest any sums divested under paragraph (2) in investments that do not violate subsection (i) of section 8438 of that title, as added by subsection (a) of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0DDC9A7CE1A847DAA20A5DC7275A6E61"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on investment of TSP funds in entities based in the Russian Federation through the TSP mutual fund window</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8438(b)(5) of title 5, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0FE9B66E1E4041A7958378C498772E55" style="USC"><subparagraph id="H82EF26FA61C54E3087438A674F7D3C07" indent="up1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A mutual fund accessible through a mutual fund window authorized under this paragraph may not include an investment in any security of—</text><clause id="HC89C7BE83C1340ACB4903D38E8927AFC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an entity based in the Russian Federation; or</text></clause><clause id="H894AE816505E49ECBCDA21579FE2BB36"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any subsidiary that is owned or operated by an entity described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

