<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H866BFFD93638412B986E7E7B4FBF4595" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9590 IH: Corey Adams Searchlight Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9590</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To encourage, enhance, and integrate Green Alert plans throughout the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB687912225074E189CF8A33B39FF17D0" style="OLC"><section id="H1097BC4C0B47403896DC1BD29DCA1560" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Corey Adams Searchlight Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H72AC6E146E634853B2458817DB9308F4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H2D287E9308C84E0F8E300ED8890D5925"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Missing veteran</header><text>The term <term>missing veteran</term> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="H12511593615E49FBA8B6798F3D9AAC43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is reported to, or identified by, a law enforcement agency as a missing person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B08136E64B84FDCABB8986A3CF62243"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is a veteran; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDF8AEFDB80C4A44A3760D5A3C405FC2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>meets the requirements to be designated as a missing veteran, as determined by the State in which the individual is reported or identified as a missing person.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H383A94D0D695405D978C6977C2F7391D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the 50 States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the United States Virgin Islands, Guam, American Samoa, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7CD4F45C3334865B3F0DBCDB01FDD22"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Green alert</header><text>The term <term>Green Alert</term> means an alert issued through the Green Alert communications network, related to a missing veteran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD33AD036421A4A848EF3DC3959194E88"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>veteran</term> means an individual who is currently serving or a former member who served in the United States Armed Forces, including National Guard, or a Reserve or auxiliary unit from any branch of the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFDCC2B8DE78E4A9C8CB0283DB129497E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Green alert communications network</header><subsection id="H7A64E358443D4C26835444AB1E75E887"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General shall, subject to the availability of appropriations, establish a national communications network, to be known as the Green Alert communications network, within the Department of Justice to provide assistance to regional and local search efforts for missing veterans through the initiation, facilitation, and promotion of local elements of the network (referred to in this Act as <quote>Green Alert plans</quote>), in coordination with States, federally or State recognized Tribes, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and other concerned entities with expertise in providing services to veterans.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE2F617411B64B3DBB93E85CF6CFF971"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with AMBER alert network and other alert networks</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the Green Alert communications network under subsection (a), the Attorney General shall work with States to ensure, when feasible, the Green Alert communications network is able to operate in coordination with a State’s existing AMBER Alert communications network, established under subtitle A of title III of the PROTECT Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20501">34 U.S.C. 20501 et seq.</external-xref>), and any other State alert networks, to maximize the efficiency of all such alert systems, and to prevent overuse or improper activations of such networks.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB2690F4EE7FB4E4BA9E092E5CCA801C3"><enum>4.</enum><header>Green alert coordinator</header><subsection id="H9411D155A4EF4A8DAE0BAB2E54559F37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>National coordinator within department of justice</header><text>The Attorney General shall designate an individual of the Department of Justice to act as the national coordinator of the Green Alert communications network. The individual so designated shall be known as the Green Alert Coordinator of the Department of Justice (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Coordinator</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H690896B59C034EE3A17B50BEA3D23585"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties of the coordinator</header><text>In acting as the national coordinator of the Green Alert communications network, the Coordinator shall—</text><paragraph id="HBC5FBC05ED484B15985EA9FCB7DF00E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with States and Tribal governments to encourage the development of additional Green Alert plans in the network;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE941C101E77149C893C56B8B325DAF54"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the ability of each State to implement Green Alerts, including the ability and resources available to each State to broadcast such alerts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EC50200C04D44A991A3A572B1B85BD7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish voluntary guidelines for States to use in developing Green Alert plans that will promote compatible and integrated Green Alert plans throughout the United States, including—</text><subparagraph id="HDA56552CD6434F58A4F5C413642C866E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of the resources necessary to establish a Green Alert plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF045253886874C4F8A1E7858364271D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">criteria for evaluating whether a situation warrants issuing a Green Alert, taking into consideration the need to prevent overuse or desensitization to such alerts, including criteria to determine—</text><clause id="HEDDB9328EB9740CABFA9ECB6C78A5729"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the mental or physical capacity of a veteran who is missing, and the circumstances of his or her disappearance, warrant the issuance of a Green Alert, including whether the veteran has a condition related to the veteran’s service in the Armed Forces that increases the risk that the veteran will harm himself or herself, or another person; and</text></clause><clause id="H000E96990CAA45AEA1610FB7B00831A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>whether the individual who reports that a veteran is missing is an appropriate and credible source on which to base the issuance of a Green Alert;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7733BB26841942608DD1C25B6A046B3A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of the appropriate uses of the Green Alert name to readily identify the nature of search efforts for missing veterans; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CCB8E285AF5459EA66A64EE85F8791D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations on how to protect the privacy, dignity, independence, and autonomy of any missing veteran who may be the subject of a Green Alert;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF30303ADA4343209D671D08439C0F41"><enum>(4)</enum><text>develop proposed protocols for efforts to recover missing veterans and to reduce the number of veterans who are reported missing, including protocols for procedures that are needed from the time of initial notification of a law enforcement agency that the veteran is missing through the time of the return of the veteran to family, guardian, or domicile, as appropriate, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9AD406D7711B48628D9548200F8B2CBB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>public safety communications protocol;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCC95C8975D54FDDBFB9CD9BE90BFBB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>case management protocol;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD7286658F184670B01CB52BBB8613D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>command center operations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA861698211147BBB728C01E5065EE4F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>reunification protocol; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D8FA558A55A472B92C56B421E82245B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>incident review, evaluation, debriefing, and public information procedures;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H58B7B95D7A744F6A8D2BF4DD9831EF43"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">work with States and Tribal governments to ensure appropriate regional coordination of various elements of the network;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD94357BE6544BE5A67AF914A3B7D07C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an advisory board to assist States, Tribal governments, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, and other entities involved in the Green Alert communications network with initiating, facilitating, and promoting Green Alert plans, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC6B9691459AF4857BF5C9D587CB253B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to the maximum extent practicable, representation from the various geographic regions of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7C64CF421834152B84B52E682307803"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members who are—</text><clause id="H2F55B219F2864980BA85F1EFA959CEBA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>representatives of veteran advocacy groups, law enforcement agencies, and public safety communications;</text></clause><clause id="H795A3471F1D34243888B22974BFEC6D2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>broadcasters, first responders, dispatchers, and radio station personnel;</text></clause><clause id="H7DD638E70EF748E689FFD0DBD5525715"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">representatives from the Department of Veterans Affairs and representatives of State veterans agencies or offices;</text></clause><clause id="H494EADE6FB174B4DA0A7D666A1E29B32"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">federally recognized tribes or tribes recognized by the State; and</text></clause><clause id="H23EB4C1850154E1A93EFF27D1BE30DF8"><enum>(v)</enum><text>representatives of any other individuals or organizations that the Coordinator determines are necessary to the success of the Green Alert communications network; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE441E90885B34E06A938DCD04F6CFF0C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>act as the nationwide point of contact for—</text><subparagraph id="HA9C5E88560A443FC9FA3A91739079AA4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the development of the network; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23E3458EBBCF412997DE3CBD2759A812"><enum>(B)</enum><text>regional coordination of alerts for missing veterans through the network.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB42BF249A38E4BE7A7439348F21E3F7E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coordination</header><paragraph id="H2EEDC55DFBB64C92850A49394B0CDD25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Coordination with other agencies</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Coordinator shall coordinate and consult with the Secretary of Transportation, the Federal Communications Commission, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, Secretary of the Interior, and other appropriate offices of the Department of Justice in carrying out activities under this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H471F0858DBB544F0A0CE8CC0FB5276E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State and local coordination</header><text>The Coordinator shall consult with local broadcasters and State, Tribal, and local law enforcement agencies in establishing minimum standards under section 5 and in carrying out other activities under this Act, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC825EC8A732F48FF97E47759BE413EA8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Coordinator shall submit to Congress a report on the activities of the Coordinator and the effectiveness and status of the Green Alert plans of each State that has established or is in the process of establishing such a plan. Each such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HC87F8EE94D984C4587831923ADBB1165"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a list of States that have established Green Alert plans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBD02E62135B46D983EFF3FB871517E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a list of States that are in the process of establishing Green Alert plans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA97BCC657F54A9F9BEB905FD8EA2F10"><enum>(3)</enum><text>for each State that has established such a plan, to the extent the data is available—</text><subparagraph id="H4CE07983C5B9407FB9773E3D8C8736FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of Green Alerts issued;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3B5AC03559D649039D852EA48E6F9B91"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a summary of the efforts by the State to coordinate with and engage tribal governments and ensure that tribal communities are included in their Green Alert plans, including in the issuance of Green Alerts;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAED1DC7627340559FE13E6CA09BED6B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of individuals located successfully;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5435225404D4ED294BA529ADD7E6F00"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the average period of time between the issuance of a Green Alert and the location of the individual for whom such Alert was issued;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCB4C68A3ECDA4AA2ADCA76E03DE2195D"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the State, local, or Tribal agencies or authorities issuing Green Alerts, and the process by which Green Alerts are disseminated;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DFC586EB9ED4B2096E8C0E83E7B12E4"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the cost of establishing and operating such a plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA16F32116B33402B8577C7C8DCE2F6E9"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the criteria used by the State to determine whether to issue a Green Alert; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEBFBEE36E2C44899C56F5A6E95B4212"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the extent to which missing individuals for whom Green Alerts were issued crossed State lines;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB662BCB330BB475681DEAC9FAF26EA61"><enum>(4)</enum><text>actions States have taken to protect the privacy and dignity of the individuals for whom Green Alerts are issued;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA30CEFBE6958420D87F7BED889D34554"><enum>(5)</enum><text>ways that States have facilitated and improved communication about missing individuals between families, caregivers, law enforcement officials, and other authorities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7783208D44B547D3A4A3BEB045D56135"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other information the Coordinator determines to be appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H7047058153DD4252950A485EA1ABE9C8"><enum>5.</enum><header>Minimum standards for issuance and dissemination of alerts through green alert communications network</header><subsection id="HB50111EA008E4A298FF46A79A0109A16"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of minimum standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), the Coordinator, in consultation with the Department of Veterans Affairs and the Advisory Committee, shall establish minimum standards for—</text><paragraph id="H5FA10B20A97040C8A6298BE4B39BEDD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the issuance of alerts through the Green Alert communications network; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B896166E78345BA818D5B52C97BE0AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent of the dissemination of alerts issued through the network.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF02C69879C3642168498BB6A55CC7FC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="H4B85C41532A14581A1F8379FD8F4FA61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Voluntary participation</header><text>The minimum standards established under subsection (a) of this section, and any other guidelines and programs established under section 4, shall be adoptable on a voluntary basis only.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5EB0AF8499541919B444C6DB59D7100"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Dissemination of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The minimum standards shall, to the maximum extent practicable (as determined by the Coordinator in consultation with State, Tribal government, and local law enforcement agencies), provide that appropriate information relating to the special needs of a missing veteran (including health care needs) are disseminated to the appropriate law enforcement, public health, and other public officials.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF368B2C8728A428F81921720A70ACEB7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Geographic areas</header><text>The minimum standards shall, to the maximum extent practicable (as determined by the Coordinator in consultation with State and local law enforcement agencies), provide that the dissemination of an alert through the Green Alert communications network be limited to the geographic areas which the missing veteran could reasonably reach, considering the missing veteran’s circumstances and physical ability, the modes of transportation available to the missing veteran, and the circumstances of the disappearance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87D2812E8C514479A61400CFD2BB4F3E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Privacy and civil liberties protections</header><text>The minimum standards shall—</text><subparagraph id="H567DEF58619842188BD4E2B257FCE0C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that alerts issued through the Green Alert communications network comply with all applicable Federal, State, and local privacy laws and regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H364BD91F51654CC0B724F6A40AA59428"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include standards that specifically provide for the protection of the privacy and sensitive medical information of missing veterans.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H16BCE5AFB953496E9CC448CEF49D128B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State and local voluntary coordination</header><text>In carrying out the activities under subsection (a), the Coordinator may not interfere with the current system of voluntary coordination between local broadcasters and State and local law enforcement agencies for purposes of the Green Alert communications network.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAFA4C041905C4CD5A931D4A65F949ADA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Training and other resources</header><subsection id="H502EC50A6C804E74997E3B85C08CB8E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Training and educational programs</header><text>The Coordinator shall make available to States, Tribal governments, units of local government, law enforcement agencies, and other concerned entities that are involved in initiating, facilitating, or promoting Green Alerts, including broadcasters, first responders, dispatchers, public safety communications personnel, and radio station personnel—</text><paragraph id="H9A0FE35525964F2FBACC2D45D996739D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>training and educational programs related to the Green Alert communications network and the capabilities, limitations, and anticipated behaviors of missing veterans, which shall be updated regularly to encourage the use of new tools, technologies, and resources in Green Alert plans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0DEDF0A80814EBBA85060BAF1F70BEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>informational materials, including brochures, videos, posters, and websites to support and supplement such training and educational programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C9B7B1CC8804729B6332039F38C50BE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support, using funding authorized under section 7, to create or integrate such Green alerts into an existing State alert system; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H137F22551BEA4FF7A34ACA6763CF050C"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">funding, using funds authorized under section 7, for a full time State Green Alert Coordinator to carry out the State’s Green Alert Plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H828B04684FA54112A459245A3A58B241"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other assistance, as determined appropriate by the Coordinator, to support the purposes of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEB12B6ECB2DD4D379272F83C355CA7F5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations for the green alert communications network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General $3,000,000 to carry out the Green Alert communications network as authorized under this Act. States receiving assistance under this program must submit a Green Alert Plan containing any information that the Coordinator shall require. Such plan must include a description of how they intend to coordinate with other Alert systems in the State and work with Tribal governments in the State. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

