<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC5BB9714DBF54D86929422BD15D89BAE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8261 IH: Hotel Advertising Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8261</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit unfair and deceptive advertising of rates for hotel rooms and other places of short-term lodging.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H36417C643335494D8A9D98F05FD61381" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8545AF0A73E64F378488199467E1636D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Hotel Advertising Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H0DD1292B72EC42BB9C0C34389003B936"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="HC818831E6C4A425EB2018BF60C37B4E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>As of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act, hotel rooms, short-term rentals, and other places of lodging are often advertised at a rate and later in the buying process mandatory fees are disclosed that were not included in the advertised room rate.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4FA36AF105F4814A31134ECEB537519"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The mandatory fees described in paragraph (1) are sometimes called by names such as <quote>resort fees</quote>, <quote>cleaning fees</quote>, or <quote>facility fees</quote> and they are all mandatory and charged by a place of short-term lodging in addition to advertised room rates.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5DB82A6C45BE43A1A3CED5620D5829B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The number of short-term lodging facilities that charge mandatory resort fees is growing.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53F8364CBF40499F86252A3669793980"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Advertising that does not reflect the true mandatory cost of a stay at a place of short-term lodging is deceptive.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H788503E3432B40DEA17A047E05DE597F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Federal Trade Commission has authority under section 5 of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45</external-xref>) to regulate and prohibit unfair or deceptive acts or practices in or affecting commerce.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H614F260D65D64E24A3A757BD945E2D6A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2012 and 2013, the Federal Trade Commission exercised its authority under such section 5 to issue warning letters to 35 hotel operators and 11 online travel agents. In those letters, the Commission cautioned hotel operators and online travel agents that mandatory resort fees could confuse consumers in violation of section 5(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H010263976D3942A487D6B9FA600D8F26"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2017, an economist at the Federal Trade Commission published an issue paper that found that forcing consumers to click through additional webpages to see a hotel’s resort fee increases the time spent searching and learning the hotel’s price, and went on to state the following: <quote>Separating the room rate from the resort fee increases the cognitive costs of remembering the hotel’s price. When it becomes more costly to search and evaluate an additional hotel, a consumer’s choice is either to incur higher total search and cognitive costs or to make an incomplete, less informed decision that may result in a more costly room, or both.</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HF1E405A46742445083B91952D088A1D1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on unfair and deceptive advertising of hotel room and other short-term lodging rates</header> <subsection id="HA0F424DF67A945568706CD9840755259"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No person with respect to whom the Commission is empowered under section 5(a)(2) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/45">15 U.S.C. 45(a)(2)</external-xref>) may advertise in interstate commerce, including through direct offerings, third-party distribution, or metasearch referrals, a rate for a place of short-term lodging that does not include all required fees, excluding taxes and fees imposed by a government.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC26AF3FA23D8417998DC8B019DCE5325"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Enforcement by Federal Trade Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="H24406C41CDC34F438D4D517986C0E40D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text>A violation of subsection (a) by a person subject to such subsection shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H912296EF575341D58CB99FB005AB9CDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header> <subparagraph id="H4350C74EAFCE42B5A81EB8A26952F76F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this Act. Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9852F54694934EF4B3525F724CDAAC50"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header> 
<clause id="H3C75DA31170248BFAF9961BDC1E31753"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may promulgate such rules as the Commission considers appropriate to enforce this section.</text></clause> <clause id="HF8507811D1EA476C8C8C6374EEC2105F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The Commission shall carry out any rulemaking under clause (i) in accordance with section 553 of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H72FA9CE0D6A24F42B05C829EBE884B1F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement by States</header> 
<paragraph id="HCEB9B9065EF04FA89CBD33763F1B3A2F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In any case in which the attorney general of a State has reason to believe that an interest of the residents of the State has been or is threatened or adversely affected by the engagement of any person subject to subsection (a) in a practice that violates such subsection, the attorney general of the State may, as parens patriae, bring a civil action on behalf of the residents of the State in an appropriate district court of the United States to obtain appropriate relief.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF710D99C7B54F82ACAB0A167F1ECF68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rights of Federal Trade Commission</header> <subparagraph id="HAF1666219D74409DBF5FC008760D2137"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notice to Federal Trade Commission</header> <clause id="H89FD5C25CE004B58857648B46C4688DD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (iii), the attorney general of a State shall notify the Commission in writing that the attorney general intends to bring a civil action under paragraph (1) before initiating the civil action against a person subject to subsection (a).</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2A5649E2E72645609A6D9991F5251EBA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The notification required by clause (i) with respect to a civil action shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate the civil action.</text></clause> <clause id="H9A4ECA2B20AA4DBF93EF62E540160882"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>If it is not feasible for the attorney general of a State to provide the notification required by clause (i) before initiating a civil action under paragraph (1), the attorney general shall notify the Commission immediately upon instituting the civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H89D1F2689AF045708E17BCECB22F4B1E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Intervention by Federal Trade Commission</header><text>The Commission may—</text> <clause id="HDC290DCEDF594D42B8F151BDD7C4A169"><enum>(i)</enum><text>intervene in any civil action brought by the attorney general of a State under paragraph (1) against a person described in such paragraph; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0611007029514B7DB1A73448AEC55811"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>upon intervening—</text> <subclause id="H58D81048C88444A2A0CB2B360850D126"><enum>(I)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in the civil action; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCD20949082B841389B4961411937335B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in the civil action.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H000AFFE954B840ED8DF5C724A0DDF2EB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Investigatory powers</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of the State to conduct investigations, to administer oaths or affirmations, or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary or other evidence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4656C84B12A54D91B9F42FCD8B8D3404"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Effect on State court proceedings</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit an authorized State official from proceeding in State court on the basis of an alleged violation of any general civil or criminal statute of such State.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41E1EFBBDB774E1A94DA87D617325EF8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination with Federal Trade Commission</header><text>If the Commission institutes a civil action or an administrative action with respect to a violation of subsection (a), the attorney general of a State shall coordinate with the Commission before bringing a civil action under paragraph (1) against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission for the violation with respect to which the Commission instituted such action.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H703DEE69CA8B4012BA40C7F29CB77AD3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Venue; service of process</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA14A8CB5D6FA4E12B39B6CFB0F06827F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Venue</header><text>Any action brought under paragraph (1) may be brought in—</text> <clause id="H0A5EB781B75B4B45BCA39C953F8FF2A9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the district court of the United States that meets applicable requirements relating to venue under section 1391 of title 28, United States Code; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB126B1A15A5047409909D14F08C1FD62" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>another court of competent jurisdiction.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6A5F5DA7F3EF46EE81D72ED1EE13E468"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Service of process</header><text>In an action brought under paragraph (1), process may be served in any district in which the defendant—</text> 
<clause id="H82727FE6487A482FAD7051FC6085EF90"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is an inhabitant; or</text></clause> <clause id="H0779DA8EF6714A67B0BE69CDAA824538"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be found.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2180260CC3CE4391A528456C9CE58097"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Actions by other state officials</header> 
<subparagraph id="HD84027FA0631490789D48A01C06A2F3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to civil actions brought by attorneys general under paragraph (1), any other officer of a State who is authorized by the State to do so may bring a civil action under paragraph (1), subject to the same requirements and limitations that apply under this subsection to civil actions brought by attorneys general.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H53545D6D71C1479499181395030DE18B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to prohibit an authorized official of a State from initiating or continuing any proceeding in a court of the State for a violation of any civil or criminal law of the State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H54043BBFCB85439DAAF3C6C15016FEAE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>As used in this section—</text> <paragraph id="H6097DB56A7D84E5FA9DCC3A85F272322"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Trade Commission;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8E267D5A2800496D801FD3DDC93478A4"><enum> (2)</enum><text>the term <quote>place of short-term lodging</quote> means a hotel, motel, inn, short-term rental, or other place of lodging that advertises at a rate that is a nightly, hourly, or weekly rate; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A2EDEE0588F42A9A2A8BAA8119081EB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>State</quote> means any of the several States, the District of Columbia, and any territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE867BD8688E54ECAA3B1BE5951CE55F9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>Subsection (a) shall take effect 270 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

