<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AFB4D8B8CBE4E31A395C1BDFF869FA1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9208 IH: Manufacturing Jobs for Veterans Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9208</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221021">October 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a pilot program to encourage the employment of veterans in manufacturing positions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H38ABAD6C56ED49D697C2F8832C48708C" style="OLC"><section id="H183CBA7417AD480F860D05309E540E4B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be referred to as the <quote><short-title>Manufacturing Jobs for Veterans Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3BBE48B7935E403F9F8D3CDDB73E64AF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Veterans Manufacturing Employment Program</header><subsection id="H52257AF4C32648E48CB415D4D7C01022"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of pilot program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To encourage the employment of eligible veterans in manufacturing, the Secretary of Labor, as part of the Veteran’s Workforce Investment Program, shall carry out a pilot program to be known as the <quote>Veterans Manufacturing Employment Program</quote>. Under the pilot program, the Secretary shall award competitive grants to three States for the establishment and administration of a State program to make grants to manufacturing employers and joint labor-management organizations that provide to eligible veterans covered training, on-the-job training, apprenticeships, and training that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential. Such a program shall be known as a <quote>State Manufacturing Employment Program</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB00DED8A7390445A9D97BCC4EAE89592"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility for grants</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the pilot program, a State shall submit to the Secretary an application that includes each of the following:</text><paragraph id="H43BD9C536BE640F382C10613C34D82D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposal for the expenditure of grant funds to establish and administer a public-private partnership program designed to—</text><subparagraph id="H6DB4C7F6002D4E19BA65E0BBE0445DF1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to eligible veterans covered training, on-the-job training, apprenticeships, and training that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB011799065D4AEA8ED9BFB84E3990C2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure sustainable employment in high-wage, high-skill jobs in manufacturing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF976CC06752D4BEA9E94C0BEF1986A60"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Evidence that the State has—</text><subparagraph id="H455A7544AB054C9EBE49BEA91FE17E9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a population of eligible veterans of an appropriate size to carry out the State program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEFDA6617161F43ACB753CB80AE9B3CB3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a robust and diverse manufacturing industry, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBBE174C878D4F289C27D81424103BF6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the ability to carry out the State program described in the proposal under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2FA4AC2568D4A03B915DEC61C59906B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Such other information and assurances as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1043C0390A514FB4B4F6BB47EA83EBAB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A State that is the recipient of a grant under this section shall use the grant for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="HBD8B515963DE4C99A1EB3A3081348158"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Making grants to manufacturing employers and joint labor-management organizations to reimburse such employers and organizations for the cost of providing to eligible veterans covered training, on-the-job training, apprenticeships, and training that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63AFEFAD29A74FA3811907B8C9C39E22"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Conducting outreach to inform manufacturing employers, joint labor-management organizations, and veterans, including veterans in rural areas, of their eligibility or potential eligibility for participation in the State program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H005E07887E454103BAF95F26F6371D23"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the pilot program, each grant to a State shall be subject to the following conditions:</text><paragraph id="H87C8A361E411491EA3DF422B1433A744"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The State shall repay to the Secretary, on such date as shall be determined by the Secretary, any amount received under the pilot program that is not used for the purposes described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE83309D6CC9D4356AD36B63823DC3C33"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The State shall submit to the Secretary, at such times and containing such information as the Secretary shall require, reports on the use of grant funds.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H793747E1289F4949AA10CDF1A3B5E104"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Employer requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order to receive a grant made by a State under the pilot program, a manufacturing employer shall—</text><paragraph id="H85C7973856804F64B84BAF976D22EE4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the administrator of the State Manufacturing Employment Program an application that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H23B85E334D6B42C08D4FD32AE21AD560"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the rate of pay for each eligible veteran proposed to be trained using grant funds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDB1FD3EAD054469A86F78C79A12F048E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the average rate of pay for an individual employed by the manufacturing employer in a similar position who is not an eligible veteran; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80DD8F8234064CBAA63ABE465BC627CA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information and assurances as the administrator may require; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H730DC46F67C84C5F84B6FE3E10D0AD64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>agree to submit to the administrator, for each quarter, a report containing such information as the Secretary may specify.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBDF932C959CB415A9BED5C169FCC690B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available to a manufacturing employer through a grant under the pilot program may be used to provide training of any kind to a person who is not an eligible veteran.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0354FC2785834F5ABE57A4AEB93DB564"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Together with the report required to be submitted annually under section 4107(c) of title 38, United States Code, the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the pilot program for the year covered by such report. The report on the pilot program shall include—</text><paragraph id="H5A5E692D43CD4396B6840E6670782150"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of activities carried out under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04FEC33F126A4BE1A7A74342698A4AF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the cost per participant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F96B6AEE3494CD28C1649CAC2319DD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an evaluation of the program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17BF757D85FE4A3EBEBEE07E8989A14C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for serving more eligible veterans.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC7FF8C7763640C0B28508CE5CE3797C"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administrative and reporting costs</header><text>Of the amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (j), 2 percent shall be made available to the Secretary for administrative costs associated with implementing and evaluating the pilot program under this section and for preparing and submitting the report required under subsection (f). The Secretary shall determine the appropriate maximum amount of each grant awarded under this section that may be used by the recipient for administrative and reporting costs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4BFEA55FFF1347CCA542D51431B79CC5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H28962FF65099414996B74145E74455D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered training, on-the-job training, apprenticeships, and training that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential</term> means training, on-the-job training, apprenticeships, and training that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential that are—</text><subparagraph id="HF24F4B22AEE7449890405C6B5975BE2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designed to provide the veteran with in-demand skills that are particular to manufacturing and not directly transferable to employment in another industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35F01F9BF96B4920ACD1D2718E89D335"><enum>(B)</enum><text>approved as provided in paragraph (1) or (2), as appropriate, of subsection (a) of section 3687 of title 38, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1501E481026143AC832E7A2B7924B58A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible veteran</term> means a veteran, as that term is defined in section 101(3) of title 38, United States Code, who is employed by a manufacturing employer and enrolled or participating in a covered training, on-the-job training, apprenticeship, or certification class.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H295C1C01AC004D1097190B45C7299B75"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, any term that is defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>) shall have the meaning given that term in such section. </text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45FD9D75A22841B883A02C5427293083"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>manufacturing employer</term> means a business concern—</text><subparagraph id="H0F0D3CA128864F899F64D22F06D579FD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that employs individuals in a trade or business in manufacturing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31D19F9CCF8A4D009F1402A059CAD8AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the production facilities of which are located in the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C6C8404290A4B91972EC4F36E8575B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the primary business of which is classified in sector 31, 32, or 33 of the North American Industrial Classification System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H185390C20DF24CB982D9324F18C1A965"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2028, for the purpose of carrying out the pilot program.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

