<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6EAE0681BA344BB858CF617BD20BB9F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>103 HR 6568 IH: Diné College Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6568</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220202">February 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To fulfill the United States Government’s trust responsibility to serve the higher education needs of the Navajo people and to clarify, unify, and modernize prior Diné College legislation.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H04992817EC6D40E2ACF85A2EFC43A9EB" style="OLC"><section id="HDC97117D92004502AC0BD4A7F9C8D795" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Diné College Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H98D9DAB79F1A409EA73B0B46FFDFE142"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds as follows:</text><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF2D0108AE1FE4D38ACB69F448DE0B906"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Treaty of 1868 between the United States of America and the Navajo Tribe of Indians provides for the education of the citizens of the Navajo Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8607BCB8FD13485DBA9815DB19F75886"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Navajo Nation created and chartered the Navajo Community College by Resolution CN–95–68 as a wholly owned educational entity of the Navajo Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37030EC394C144F9BB6DE4C41E29B58F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 1971, Congress enacted the Navajo Community College Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/189">Public Law 92–189</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640a">25 U.S.C. 640a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C96DEAA61D94CB193A68C1145D4EB7D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Navajo Nation officially changed the name of the Navajo Community College to the Diné College by Resolution CAP–35–97.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F6B1A28158D45BAA18CF21D732DBA5F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The purpose of the Diné College is to provide educational opportunities to the Navajo people and others in areas important to the economic and social development of the Navajo Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H935FF1E4F4F3420386DABC27632E4463"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The educational philosophy of the Diné College is to apply principles of Sa'ah Naagháí Bik'eh Hózhóón (Diné Philosophy) to advance quality student learning through training of the mind and heart.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4A730EC1EEF4AB9900CFA240AD63A95"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The United States has a trust and treaty responsibility to the Navajo Nation to provide for the educational opportunities for Navajo people.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H579861AD8434404CA0E086A74D895427"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Significant portions of the Diné College’s infrastructure are dilapidated and pose a serious health and safety risk to students, employees, and the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6CCB2B34701D4042BC3CAAE7E8D29D31"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act is consistent with Executive Order 13592 (76 Fed. Reg. 76603, relating to improving American Indian and Alaska Native educational opportunities and strengthening tribal colleges and universities) and fulfills the United States Government's trust responsibility to serve the educational needs of the Navajo people.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8E2C8137E1F74E5BBF2222E96C83D64B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure that the Navajo Nation and Navajo people—</text><paragraph id="H791F61C4899841F4AF525473464929FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exercise their right to self-determination, particularly in matters relating to their internal and local affairs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E41E46BA3FE494A8906B88C6D621771"><enum>(2)</enum><text>maintain and strengthen their distinct institutions of higher education through the teaching of the Navajo language, culture, traditions, and history; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD74D7B09AA924D0D89CBE6A4B387BC23"><enum>(3)</enum><text>improve their economic and social conditions through higher education and postsecondary vocational training.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0B067BB5E28D43B4BC01E480C6B3E138"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HAE2D5919AD0D4A94AA7A21AE6079B8E7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HF88577F85DB241DCA79457B3A1E673C3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Indian Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03F9CCCD086647A286EB1CED98C6DB30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources, the Committee on Education and Labor, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4837A35041674348AAD74DA0C383F36E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>College</header><text>The term <term>College</term> means the Diné College.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D7CAE970658409F976111E88A1B0E55"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Operation and maintenance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>operation and maintenance</term> means all costs and expenses associated with the customary daily operation of the Diné College and necessary maintenance costs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53D580FA8BD545CFB527911502DBF673"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>infrastructure</term> means the Diné College buildings, water and sewer facilities, roads, foundation, information technology, and telecommunications, including classrooms and external matters such as walkways.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4365B56D4FA74EA5BD43B8969FC85902"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Renovations and repairs</header><text>The term <term>renovations and repairs</term> means modernization and improvements to the infrastructure.</text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0484D111E3A9402487EBB6F4CBB68CCD"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H27B60AE01F734E0DB934FAAD239920AE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authorization of the Diné College</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress authorizes the Diné College to receive all Federal funding and resources under this Act and other laws for its operation, improvement, and growth, including—</text><paragraph id="H794B24A525AA40E5B0485FABF6C8D7BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to provide programs of higher education for citizens of the Navajo Nation and others;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5D7383CCC2B4E6FBDF9A32357C05F7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide vocational and technical education for citizens of the Navajo Nation and others;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H897486A9BCBF4E49BDD9BFF3C1ED544B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to preserve and protect the Navajo language, philosophy, and culture for citizens of the Navajo Nation and others;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12050177149B4B1A833BB3B188E0EF71"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to provide Navajo communities and people with employment and training opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B8086DF907948A3A3793E46DEF248B7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to provide economic development and community outreach for Navajo communities and people; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC220D6411374492EADA23D3441D90D1D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to provide a safe learning, working, and living environment for students, employees, and the public.</text></paragraph></section><section commented="no" id="H3BFFB7D8CE9A49D88A9691E9706A5A9E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Capital projects and facility needs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">From amounts made available under <internal-xref idref="H668D676729764C21A00332FB6BDB2C5E" legis-path="8.(c)">section 8(c)</internal-xref>, the Diné College may undertake any renovations and repairs to the infrastructure of the College that are identified in the report under <internal-xref idref="H4D9CA20300EA4FC888ACC48D9B911CD9" legis-path="9.">section 9</internal-xref>.</text></section><section id="H3E695FCBD93D4B7493B46F0082250B42"><enum>7.</enum><header>Status of funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Funds provided under this Act to the Diné College may be treated as non-Federal, private funds of the College for purposes of any provision of Federal law which requires that non-Federal or private funds of the College be used in a project for a specific purpose.</text></section><section id="HE160C089557B44CFADBA39E610EC88AD"><enum>8.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="H3ABE7947432943F09F436F13FAD17F57"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are hereby authorized to be appropriated to the Diné College, for each fiscal year, such sums as may be necessary to pay for the operation and maintenance of the College.</text></subsection><subsection id="H21F6EAD8DA2F4F3CABFCDDBE741E78FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Budget Placement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall fund the operation and maintenance of the Diné College separately from tribal colleges and universities recognized and funded by the Tribally Controlled Colleges and Universities Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/1801">25 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H668D676729764C21A00332FB6BDB2C5E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Facilities and Capital Projects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts appropriated under <internal-xref idref="H3ABE7947432943F09F436F13FAD17F57" legis-path="8.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, there are authorized to be appropriated $7,500,000, for each fiscal year, to carry out <internal-xref idref="H3BFFB7D8CE9A49D88A9691E9706A5A9E" legis-path="6.">section 6</internal-xref>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H4D9CA20300EA4FC888ACC48D9B911CD9"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report; inventory; final formula; administrative expenses</header><subsection id="H67427F0289684856BBE041EB120AB916"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="H596B0DD5E8824EEFB901EE9C50056FC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, acting through the Regional Director of the Navajo Regional Office shall locate and provide to the Secretary a copy of the report, dated February 2019, on the detailed survey and deferred maintenance study of all capital projects and facility needs of the Diné College that was authorized under section 4 of the Navajo Community College Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640c">25 U.S.C. 640c</external-xref>), as amended by Navajo Community College Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/471">Public Law 95–471</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640a">25 U.S.C. 640a</external-xref> note), and contracted for by the Bureau of Indian Affairs Navajo Regional Office; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C2A03E172BE4AF8A85137D416510E3E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE643BBB8FAAB4CD48C84051081D5A5B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide to the appropriate committees of Congress the report described in <internal-xref idref="H596B0DD5E8824EEFB901EE9C50056FC3" legis-path="9.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> and an addendum to such report that includes recommendations by the Secretary, and any recommendations or views submitted by the College and the Navajo Nation regarding the capital projects and facility needs of the College; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D461A5CD62947A0AF61DE09DABF5C52"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that the report described in <internal-xref idref="H596B0DD5E8824EEFB901EE9C50056FC3" legis-path="9.(a)(1)">paragraph (1)</internal-xref> is not provided to the Secretary as required by this subsection—</text><clause id="HE878A010DD8A4B389784805AC1EBE9ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide to the appropriate committees of Congress recommendations of the Secretary, and any recommendations or views submitted by the College and the Navajo Nation regarding the capital projects and facility needs of the College; and</text></clause><clause id="HEEE249CCB9C94B809EDCD8CC2106D8D3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>take such steps as may be necessary to ensure that such report is located and provided to the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7618B9DC3E6143C687B8BB5E5D32BD39"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inventory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 31, 2022, an inventory prepared by the Diné College identifying repairs, alterations, and renovations to facilities required to meet health and safety standards and other factors shall be submitted to the Secretary. The inventory shall address the facility needs and outstanding capital projects, including any backlog of such needs and projects, from 1978 through the date of such inventory. The Secretary shall use the inventory as baseline data to inform the report required under <internal-xref idref="H67427F0289684856BBE041EB120AB916" legis-path="9.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H62A393AC70BE4B8185F8AD7F5FBA78BB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Final formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than October 30, 2022, a final formula for ongoing operations and maintenance of the Diné College shall be—</text><paragraph id="HDA1DE5DD01684BA58E3B203A6AF2986D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determined by the Bureau of Indian Affairs, utilizing input from and consultation with the Navajo Nation and the College, the report and addendum provided under <internal-xref idref="H67427F0289684856BBE041EB120AB916" legis-path="9.(a)">subsection (a)</internal-xref>, and the inventory required under <internal-xref idref="H7618B9DC3E6143C687B8BB5E5D32BD39" legis-path="9.(b)">subsection (b)</internal-xref>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29AAD8A657C5441E9D17A5809CD767C6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provided to the appropriate committees of Congress, the College, and the Navajo Nation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF70D37C2934B47DBBF4F0A7157854FC6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administrative expenses</header><text>Funds to carry out this section may be drawn from general administrative appropriations to the Secretary.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB6851092ED994D5CBEDB806CC081ACA3"><enum>10.</enum><header>Supersession of Navajo Community College Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act supersedes—</text><paragraph id="H9594039D071A4B75B8B11FA9777A7C69"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Navajo Community College Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/92/189">Public Law 92–189</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/640a">25 U.S.C. 640a et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01360D45EA5E45F3AFC43FE8A84E3563"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Navajo Community College Assistance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/471">Public Law 95–471</external-xref>, 92 Stat. 1325, 1329); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA14842D3B1754591BDBE9D8914CA1916"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Navajo Nation Higher Education Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/110/315">Public Law 110–315</external-xref>, 122 Stat. 3468).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H07FDC401819E416AA6471A1918C351D7"><enum>11.</enum><header>Continuing eligibility for other Federal funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Except as explicitly provided for in other Federal law, nothing in this Act shall preclude the eligibility of the Diné College to receive Federal funding and resources under any program authorized under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>), the Equity in Educational Land Grant Status Act (title V, part C, of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/103/382">Public Law 103–382</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/301">7 U.S.C. 301</external-xref> note), or any other applicable program for the benefit of institutions of higher education, community colleges, or postsecondary educational institutions.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

