<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF9A58C6B4D15411A8BFA4AEB6CA3C931" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7046 IH: To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit to Congress reports describing the average amount of individual assistance and individual and household assistance provided to certain individuals and households and the rate of denial of such assistance, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7046</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220309">March 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000597">Mr. Rice of South Carolina</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to submit to Congress reports describing the average amount of individual assistance and individual and household assistance provided to certain individuals and households and the rate of denial of such assistance, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3B0F51F8BF03406EBFB1611A9A83077B" style="OLC"><section id="HD7364AFB89BE4FE582F8BBDC7B7FCB48" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>FEMA reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Government Affairs of the Senate a report with respect to fiscal year 2016 through the most recent fiscal year ending before the date of enactment of this Act, and an annual report for any fiscal year beginning on or after the date of enactment of this Act, describing—</text><paragraph id="HB230EDA94B5F47DF8284E839CA3CA2F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average amount of individual assistance and individual and household assistance provided under section 408 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5174">42 U.S.C. 5174</external-xref>), and the rate of denial of household assistance provided under such section, for—</text><subparagraph id="H9379906B8E314A7AAD39A15B533FE8D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all applications for such assistance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01CD6BDF9B304D17A748896E46AF14EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applications containing a self-reported annual income under 75 percent of the national median household income (as calculated by the Bureau of the Census);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1470573C6EED41F4B922A216244C61A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applications containing a self-reported annual income over 125 percent of such national median household income; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD6B35D3D0984C8EBB8540F539155B6D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applications with a self-reported annual income between 75 percent and 125 percent of such national median household income; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4ECD979440D540AAA344E67BD5A193A2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an explanation for any factors causing an increase in the rate of denial of such assistance, if applicable.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

