<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD7E2637050CD4A07B08C2679E998980D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8683 IH: Pacific Islands Embassies Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8683</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of United States embassies in the Republic of Vanuatu, the Republic of Kiribati, and the Kingdom of Tonga, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC8B932425D8A444DA769CEB4C65A9113" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H548599F64ED745F48A6CABB9FCCEABC6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pacific Islands Embassies Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H47027FC6402E4C7292D6BD78A420ADD1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9C2C9144EF8C48A4B169A54666D3526B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Pacific Islands are vital to United States national security and national interests in the Indo-Pacific region and globally.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H328D275875A24D02876C7303777F7F52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Pacific Islands region spans 15 percent of the world’s surface area and controls access to open waters in the Central Pacific, sea lanes to the Western Hemisphere, supply lines to United States forward-deployed forces in East Asia, and economically important fisheries.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H33BC0CE7EA1C49D2B00E18AE4A719953"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Pacific Islands region is home to the State of Hawaii, 11 United States territories, United States Naval Base Guam, and United States Andersen Air Force Base.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EAC664E9C5F40B8A295CD1CAFD04D94"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Pacific Island countries cooperate with the United States and United States partners on maritime security and efforts to stop illegal, unreported, and destructive fishing.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA02693285C4D4DE29DCDFC1AF37F57BC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Pacific Islands are rich in biodiversity and on the frontlines of sea level rise, worsening tropical storms, and coral reef loss associated with climate change.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H92EFB05436EE4AB7AF5FA5A0FE84D7E0"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The People’s Republic of China (PRC) seeks to increase its influence in the Pacific Islands region, including through infrastructure development under the PRC’s Belt and Road Initiative and its new security agreement with the Solomon Islands.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCAC172B9BD4443318B30458B2F255DC0"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The United States Embassy in Papua New Guinea manages the diplomatic affairs of the United States to the Republic of Vanuatu, and the United States Embassy in Fiji manages the diplomatic affairs of the United States to the Republic of Kiribati and the Kingdom of Tonga.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H71E57E7F37AA462199BAB628B8E2EC1F"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The United States requires a physical diplomatic presence in the Republic of Vanuatu, the Republic of Kiribati, and the Kingdom of Tonga, to ensure the physical and operation security of our efforts in those countries to deepen relations, protect United States national security, and pursue United States national interests.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7ED81FC7CB974E38B6384E3B3BEDC8C0"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Increasing the number of United States embassies dedicated solely to a Pacific Island country demonstrates the United States’ ongoing commitment to the region and to the Pacific Island countries.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HD82372259964465BAD254E0F2D200732"><enum>3.</enum><header>Establishment of embassies</header> <subsection id="HC3FA2DA1A924496F98E347EFB8BC3184"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of United States embassies in Vanuatu, Kiribati, and Tonga</header><text>As soon as possible, and not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall establish physical United States embassies in the Republic of Vanuatu, the Republic of Kiribati, and the Kingdom of Tonga and recommend to the President ambassadors to lead each of these 3 embassies.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H862478F848154C5F922B7A0572B56583"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Other strategies</header><text>In establishing embassies pursuant to subsection (a) and creating the physical infrastructure to ensure the physical and operational safety of embassy personnel, the Secretary of State may pursue strategies such as renting or purchasing an existing building or colocation of embassies with like-minded partners like Australia and New Zealand.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H64D09D886ED5468AACD0394F902B0A48"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver authority</header><text>The President may waive the requirements under subsection (a) for a period of one year if the President determines and reports to Congress in advance that such waiver is necessary to protect the national security interests of the United States. </text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3C932742028F498387147B3EB9B878DE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated for the Department of State—</text> <paragraph id="H155CC45CAA7C4C269BFDA55A05CFB397"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$40,200,000 for fiscal year 2023 for embassy construction and maintenance of the 3 embassies to be established pursuant to section 3; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85F59805DC3546C88B631AB33ABF6D68"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$3,000,000 for fiscal year 2024 to maintain the embassies.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="HED7BF0C6A6034A4994EEE08968321D13"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report</header> <subsection id="HBFD91461A71844DB99DF117157FC55C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Progress report</header><text>Not later than 180 days following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="HE7496153B86448FAB0E21342186CF9AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the status of activities carried out to achieve the objectives described in this Act;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDB4E7AD99754E7F847A64000327B4C0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an estimate of when embassies will be fully established pursuant to section 3(a); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F86B92A8C9546FB887DBDDAF984C610"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an update on events in the Pacific Islands region relevant to the establishment of United States embassies, including activities by the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE876A39FEF834AE0A3F09D6C787FEF29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on final disposition</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit a report confirming the establishment of the 3 embassies required under section 3(a). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A56BED3741E4AB29CE386DA0653E9CA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>In this section, the term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> <paragraph id="H00EE6A13C645452282D088B39D1FE265"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0276B05FC38B47999E020E420B4306CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill> 

