<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71FD8285584C48078098093D92C135C7" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>111 HR 8685 IH: Afghan Adjustment Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8685</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide support for nationals of Afghanistan who supported the United States mission in Afghanistan, adequate vetting for parolees from Afghanistan, adjustment of status for certain nationals of Afghanistan, and special immigrant status for at-risk Afghan allies and relatives of certain members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC67EE5FAACF74FA181A0D33AEF29D03F" style="OLC"><section id="HC147152DD34D43B9BCB4C572F4D76AAC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Afghan Adjustment Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5840CAA7DB084A0881720B0987685FA3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="HCCEE36951F7E4B09A1A657D557FA6732"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise specifically provided, any term used in this Act that is used in the immigration laws shall have the meaning given the term in the immigration laws.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE34C651A9124A52A4147C9DF68600C3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H5417ECC98DC944BE9358B85792098B92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text>The term <quote>immigration laws</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0825C1948A46C7AE43DF0EF6966D97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Special immigrant status</header><text>The term <quote>special immigrant status</quote> means special immigrant status provided under—</text><subparagraph id="H2560C700A9E64A31AF61A88267FDADB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/8">Public Law 111–8</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD52E1B2044D34BD58C6263641F5B6C2C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 1059 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/163">Public Law 109–163</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEA8E5E468384F9496B7E1C6F9FC7D79"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified application</header><text>The term <quote>specified application</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1392697B11C7418CBBAA34664ED85E64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an application for special immigrant status;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C0240F1469B4484A6066E811996411F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an application to seek admission to the United States through the United States Refugee Admission Program for an individual who has received a Priority 1 or Priority 2 referral to such program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30CBA31ACFED4937A3777FB8DE1DE622"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an application for a special immigrant visa under section 7 or an amendment made by that section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D39B45998844D068CA02F674E86473D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>United states refugee admissions program</header><text>The term <quote>United States Refugee Admissions Program</quote> means the program to resettle refugees in the United States pursuant to the authorities provided in sections 101(a)(42), 207, and 412 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(42)</external-xref>, 1157, and 1522).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H623D04CB2CC04DF4AEFC897117AB17EB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HFEDC16CBAB654077AACC716A2667101E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>nationals of Afghanistan residing outside the United States who meet the requirements for admission to the United States through a specified application have aided the United States mission in Afghanistan during the past 20 years; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H033DF30C968242A5B5B631561CDC11B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should increase support for such nationals.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7C263AD57BD3484FB79891E1510716EF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Support for Afghan allies outside of the United States</header><subsection id="H2B65946D81584017AFC68475CCF3BF4C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Response to congressional inquiries</header><text>The Secretary of State shall respond to inquiries by Members of Congress regarding a specified application submitted by, or on behalf of, a national of Afghanistan who has provided a confidentiality release.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB4CD7C5CF1AD489DBD10297ED49A4F47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Office in lieu of embassy</header><text>During the period in which there is no operational United States embassy in Afghanistan, the Secretary of State shall establish and maintain an office capable of—</text><paragraph id="H9A68C5A6640E41828253A0D4B3B1A974"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reviewing specified applications submitted by nationals of Afghanistan residing in Afghanistan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63DA503625BB41CBBCDA6152B713FB97"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issuing visas to such nationals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0453115476C4427AB03B25F5BB406380"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to the greatest extent practicable, providing services to such nationals that would normally be provided by an embassy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26C5C643BCCB48DBBE58E49EAA112A2F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carrying out any other function the Secretary considers necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H08EED40AD0514FDD85141B169770E4CB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Interagency Task Force on Afghan Ally Strategy</header><subsection id="HBC61F26AFE514952BBEDD324086FE9DE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall establish an Interagency Task Force on Afghan Ally Strategy (referred to in this section as the <quote>Task Force</quote>)—</text><paragraph id="H44E8396759E64157A06DA46963067374"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to develop and oversee the implementation of the strategy described in subsection (d)(1)(B)(iv); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8178C827EC14EA78C2AC64933FDE328"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to submit the report, and provide a briefing on the report, described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65AA11CA0FA8463099D815F8FEEF08B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H461D9029B926493BA34C95823DBF3874"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Task Force shall be comprised of—</text><subparagraph id="H3529A64C865A49558EA5558CD5817BB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Secretary of State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H535FB2E0DCCD4B75ACC25B3CC1A65B63"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF112402B28CB424D8FAE2D26DBADF6D5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Secretary of Defense;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D7C463AB5CD4C6B886DAC5A2D66EB06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9EA36C214C404817915F74019CAA73F6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Director of National Intelligence; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4AF0882607340089AFEED40344A6FE6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>any other Government official, as designated by the President.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5919A25E370B49C7AC221C6CF4396D95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Delegation</header><text>A member of the Task Force may designate a representative to carry out the duties under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H491BB3652869406A8A8D3180D7AC89E7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Chair</header><text>The Task Force shall be chaired by the Secretary of State.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDDA099A7557E4624B9C242283B1D7767"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="H67FD9173B6D1457397C93922D7322CB0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report and strategy</header><subparagraph id="H4792EA1751174B208B0C649371BBE3D7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Task Force shall submit to the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives a report that includes a strategy for supporting nationals of Afghanistan residing outside the United States who meet the requirements for admission to the United States through a specified application.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45E8D412304945DE89EC588D12DA4E3A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subparagraph (A) shall include the following:</text><clause id="H13174E5EC85E478AA56A2E87DBDFB854"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Estimates of—</text><subclause id="H0C40CB9FB1864C598A4782A3E9E19CB0"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HAC7CD1A905554F1C83A285C10BD7E4F9"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the total number of nationals of Afghanistan residing in Afghanistan who have submitted specified applications that are pending and, as of the date on which the report is submitted, have not been adjudicated; and</text></item><item id="H3FEAE7F455A74142932D86062AB1D9F2" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of such nationals, disaggregated by type of specified application described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of section 2(b)(3); and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HADF1059048604192840222758AAABE20"><enum>(II)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4E0CC2D94A45486B9956A796A5CB71CE"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the total number of nationals of Afghanistan residing in Afghanistan who meet the requirements for admission to the United States through specified applications; and</text></item><item id="HD922EF1F5DC84C4B9F241C91476D6C27" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of such nationals, disaggregated by type of specified application described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of section 2(b)(3).</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HECC5DFED5B7B49F39032CBB6BE06F5A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A description of the steps the Secretary of State has taken and is taking to facilitate the relocation and resettlement of nationals of Afghanistan who—</text><subclause id="HCD1EC457912F48C696A37E84EAF6FCD1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>supported the United States mission in Afghanistan; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HF642AD9140834C80A966B33E6D75B2E6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>remain in Afghanistan or in third countries.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3A9868CA591747A5B05D53392364F5D1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An identification of all considerations, including resource constraints, that limit the ability of the Secretary of State to facilitate such relocations and resettlements.</text></clause><clause id="H3756F72BA6974D90B3E671A0FA5231D4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A strategy and detailed plan that—</text><subclause id="HE94F41547A984EFA872C6540A2C71981"><enum>(I)</enum><text>sets forth the manner in which members of the Task Force will address such considerations in order to facilitate such relocations and resettlements over different periods of time (including 1-year, 5-year, and 10-year periods) and an analysis of the expected number of nationals of Afghanistan who would be relocated or resettled through such strategy; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE244DB15F8134E32B3FBF0D44880FF0D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>addresses the constraints and opportunities for expanding support for such relocations and resettlements, including—</text><item id="H5E7D2A84EF9D4EDDB24B95054C005D46"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the availability of remote processing for individuals residing in Afghanistan;</text></item><item id="H68C792DDAE2F414AB3EC351C564B4D73"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the availability and capacity of mechanisms for individuals to be relocated from Afghanistan, including air charter or land passage;</text></item><item id="HC50FAE64266D42B083A13D6DB59CB98A"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the availability and capacity of sites in third countries to process applications and conduct any required vetting, including identifying and establishing additional sites;</text></item><item id="H0B47B050B93940ACACE07FE929AFFD02"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>resource, personnel, and equipment requirements to increase the capacity to better support such nationals of Afghanistan and reduce application processing times;</text></item><item id="H9F4AACA1C0034A56818EC4577CD42499"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>the provision of updates and necessary information to affected individuals and relevant nongovernmental organizations; and</text></item><item id="H84DF9C1B345B434AB70FB55EAA07B31B"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>any other matter the Task Force considers relevant to the implementation of the strategy.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H0CEA7B8F630E4A99BFC0EE9630C8758A"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Recommendations for how Congress can expand the number of nationals of Afghanistan who can be relocated or resettled over such periods of time by providing additional authorities or resources.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84329E68F30A497FB746D9222E69F809"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subparagraph (A) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2DFA114DA224B10A06396EAC01A5A42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than 60 days after submitting the report required by paragraph (1), the Task Force shall brief the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Appropriations and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives on the contents of such report. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H30105EC782BE45188610E6011F98202E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Task Force shall remain in effect until the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="H411D7AC115FA46CF9E135BA7854D8B55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the strategy required by subsection (d)(1) has been fully implemented; or </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66963F745CDA4B70860AE5585A4C8804"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 10 years after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF35DB6AF39EB4E96862F8C5054860C90"><enum>6.</enum><header>Adjustment of status for eligible Afghan nationals</header><subsection id="HD15CA0DA28D44467B4ADED7F6D71F8F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of eligible afghan national</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>eligible Afghan national</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H04F7EAF7827548F08B567E59784247D4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an alien—</text><subparagraph id="HD5F8D6113F3A40CBBB208956FDA6D1C2"><enum>(A)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H57BC914B919447AB9F0C2E23F8F530C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who is a citizen or national of Afghanistan; or</text></clause><clause id="HFC0EE70C6F7643E0A15E6265BE181D45" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an alien having no nationality, whose former or last habitual residence was in Afghanistan; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H262E9FB7BCFC4FF2A98A9CEAF0BAEE18"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB0AD1A83D4A64EED87C29EB893516797"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who was inspected and admitted to the United States on or before the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></clause><clause id="HA3693DAFCC6741F58A9AE61EED40596A" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who was paroled into the United States during the period beginning on July 30, 2021, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, provided that such parole has not been terminated by the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></clause><clause id="H6E951C5AC8A04B4DAC7DE06BA5BD9794" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whose travel to the United States was facilitated by, or coordinated with, the United States Government; or</text></clause><clause id="H4D2B315D054A4B7B90447685FBD1AAD3" indent="up1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>who arrived in the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act, provided that the Secretary of Homeland Security, in cooperation with other Federal agency partners, determines that the alien supported the United States mission in Afghanistan;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F0CDA0B96E44240866E6D40549FEC23"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an alien who is the spouse or child (as defined in section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</external-xref>)) of an alien described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D97F874E6D44A3ABFE826D7A9A45A66"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an alien who is the spouse or child (as defined in section 101(b)(1) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(b)(1)</external-xref>)) of an alien described in paragraph (1) who is deceased.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC262BB4A62CC4374A069966D20F8AFDA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Streamlined adjustment process for eligible afghan nationals who supported the united states mission in afghanistan</header><paragraph id="HE97316EAE9E04FFA9EE83142AC0B71D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall adjust the status of an eligible Afghan national to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if—</text><subparagraph id="HB5FBD62B6B5E40AEAA04F0585FF65DD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible Afghan national—</text><clause id="H01D9809D6DF140C5AE73101796162452"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has—</text><subclause id="HB1DE0F4B43BD49AA897F83EF8CEF42D5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>received Chief of Mission approval as part of their application for special immigrant status;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBCB4F5A94DAA440F861A90ED7EDFC735"><enum>(II)</enum><text>received a Priority 1 or Priority 2 referral to the United States Refugee Admissions Program; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE1CB1C1AF6384AA9B76C23564E044A3B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a pending application for special immigrant status that was submitted on or before July 31, 2018;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFE10A4FDBC904F5893D5D56E525A0E96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submits an application for adjustment of status in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></clause><clause id="HF19BF01807EA4DE18ADBD1EE2427E9C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), is otherwise admissible to the United States as an immigrant, except that the grounds of inadmissibility under paragraphs (4), (5), and (7)(A) of section 212(a) the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply; and</text></clause><clause id="H04C84F6F1E3F4EB892FFC8FEDB10159E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has complied with the vetting requirements under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (d) to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H678837BAC84D46658A67B43313AB4E72"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the adjustment of status of the eligible Afghan national is not contrary to the national welfare, safety, or security of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86304EAC851948B4B3E3F22192CA3878"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of refugee admissibility requirements</header><text>The provisions relating to admissibility for a refugee seeking adjustment of status under section 209(c) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1159">8 U.S.C. 1159(c)</external-xref>) shall apply to an applicant for adjustment of status under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D1521CAB9B649A8848A3EF6D60B506D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Adjustment process for other eligible afghan nationals</header><paragraph id="HEACEED2F59674CF5997A73E0C96B01FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall adjust the status of an eligible Afghan national who does not meet the requirements set forth in subsection (b)(1)(A)(i) to the status of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence if—</text><subparagraph id="H57FAAA1B67D0498BB689B7ABAEF604F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible Afghan national—</text><clause id="H22ECB6125F02460284680A63E834F5E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been physically present in the United States for a period not less than 2 years;</text></clause><clause id="H0D1F894E7CCE430A9C3A2ABCDE7BB13E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submits an application for adjustment of status in accordance with procedures established by the Secretary of Homeland Security;</text></clause><clause id="HC937E48831BE449C976C6785CFB1721C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>subject to paragraph (2), is otherwise admissible to the United States as an immigrant, except that the grounds of inadmissibility under paragraphs (4), (5), and (7)(A) of section 212(a) the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) shall not apply; and</text></clause><clause id="H61CC8F8139BE4020BE85C11F25A02683"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has complied with the vetting requirements under subsection (d)(1) to the satisfaction of the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31F3393BCBB641BD9EBF145C9C0A3113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the adjustment of status of the eligible Afghan national is not contrary to the national welfare, safety, or security of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E94033A10794AF79004F12E9941B568"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Waiver</header><subparagraph id="HF1EC1904DF78484EAA4E57B9916AEB2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>With respect to an applicant for adjustment of status under this subsection, subject to subparagraph (B), the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive any applicable ground of inadmissibility under section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) (other than paragraphs 2(C) or (3) of such section) for humanitarian purposes, to ensure family unity, or if a waiver is otherwise in the public interest.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50D05E975FF24AFFB7AF15F5E79370B3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not waive under this paragraph any applicable ground of inadmissibility under section 212(a)(2) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(2)</external-xref>) that arises due to criminal conduct that was committed—</text><clause id="H3F5DA13EFA984E2294BBDB2AD5C9E7EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on or after July 30, 2021;</text></clause><clause id="HFAB9DB61FBAA445AB6136E93A8E4AF8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>within the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HB1C05F19139745F7A3387AD550364754"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by an applicant for adjustment of status under this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3399D6902B8F4C2CAB8A64C9BF46C30F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to limit any other waiver authority.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H756B95D06B17476FAFB9BB06BFFC9A8F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to require the Secretary of Homeland Security to complete the vetting process with respect to an applicant for adjustment of status under this subsection within the 2-year period described in paragraph (1)(A)(i).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE12D42D8877D421DA0BA8751A53B3E65"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interview and vetting requirements</header><paragraph id="HB905AE7BE30E4369B7013CC9FCA82D05"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Vetting requirements for all applicants</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish vetting requirements for applicants seeking adjustment of status under this section that are equivalent to the vetting requirements for refugees admitted to the United States through the United States Refugee Admissions Program, including an interview.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0434A2587AA04B82B9A9A5E6CB502097"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional vetting requirements for other eligible Afghan nationals</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, shall maintain records that contain, for each applicant under subsection (c) for the duration of the pendency of their application for adjustment of status—</text><subparagraph id="H14F9F0AC51FB4F428367430CAD9A035E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>personal biographic information, including name and date of birth;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D87F4BAC53D496E909D6366B3CDAE8F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>biometric information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A1C0ADF9D794E2E98608FA043A2D137"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any criminal conviction occurring after the date on which the applicant entered the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF23B17F031304CCAAD076FBB5EDD38DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the history of the United States Government vetting to which the applicant has submitted, including whether the individual has undergone in-person vetting.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0EDFD76B8D54383ACDE29BC4B841DB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to limit the authority of the Secretary of Homeland Security to maintain records under any other law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABB7CBD30F804E989BF744EDB91EEFBD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Protection for battered spouses</header><paragraph id="HE3A034BB87C4412BB048136B84F143AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien whose marriage to an eligible Afghan national described in paragraph (1) of subsection (a) has been terminated shall be eligible for adjustment of status under this section as an alien described in paragraph (2) of that subsection for not more than 2 years after the date on which such marriage is terminated if there is a demonstrated connection between the termination of the marriage and battering or extreme cruelty perpetrated by the principal applicant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73A3CD093FAB48C8A1A828E1077C1642"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability of other law</header><text>In reviewing an application for adjustment of status under this section with respect to spouses and children who have been battered or subjected to extreme cruelty, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall apply section 204(a)(1)(J) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(J)</external-xref>) and section 384 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1367">8 U.S.C. 1367</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB23D44462C5F4E18A54B86CA258FC83D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Date of approval</header><text>Upon the approval of an application for adjustment of status under this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall create a record of the alien’s admission as a lawful permanent resident as of the date on which the alien was inspected and admitted or paroled into the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB22A745781214C0BB489AC5A763F502B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition on further authorization of parole</header><paragraph id="HBEA7F9A3BF734736B06A54C0869C5126"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), an individual who is a national of Afghanistan shall not be authorized for an additional period of parole if such individual—</text><subparagraph id="H5419F7C385854515801E8293A3413968"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is eligible to apply for adjustment of status under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AE3949099E547F9A8710CD0214F2B7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fails to submit an application for adjustment of status by the later of—</text><clause id="HC993F3CA300C4645A6EBFD7ACDCFCE2F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the date on which final guidance described in subsection (h)(2) is published; or</text></clause><clause id="H6A8CF29C66D0403F9964C6861F2DBFAE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date that is 1 year after the date on which such individual becomes eligible to apply for adjustment of status under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B1C438E50364CE1A3A243BCCBC9DC5A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>An individual described in paragraph (1)(A) may be authorized for an additional period of parole if such individual—</text><subparagraph id="H23A74E32C9DB4A4A9389A1A5A8591838"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within the period described in paragraph (1)(B), seeks an extension to file an application for adjustment of status under this section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0E80BCD093544E2AADF905F7706BA9D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has previously submitted to a vetting equivalent of the vetting required under subsection (d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D0C47F1C7B34E0588FDF5650A5B307B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline for application</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), a national of Afghanistan who does not submit an application for adjustment of status within the timeline provided in paragraph (1)(B) may not later adjust status under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H627E9A5BBB78449B838B14A9C89CAAE7"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Implementation</header><paragraph id="HDD7DD3D8D9214A5CAF5493598A2996AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Interim guidance</header><subparagraph id="H4622ABF6346447B1A925773690DDECD7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall issue guidance implementing this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0381421DAD62471DAA29EE1E2DE82A0C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>Notwithstanding section 553 of title 5, United States Code, such guidance—</text><clause id="H9D8DA99D006A47B4A15E68776DA5FD31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may be published on the internet website of the Department of Homeland Security; and</text></clause><clause id="HE730E8EC90494626B5D558B85E4DFBFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall be effective on an interim basis immediately upon such publication but may be subject to change and revision after notice and an opportunity for public comment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H91A5440372524ACEA73DB75FC8155552"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final guidance</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall finalize guidance implementing this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF31D54D4C1E491FAD95A936729C90A2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Administrative review</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide applicants for adjustment of status under this section with the same right to, and procedures for, administrative review as are provided to applicants for adjustment of status under section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8866E754DCFE4D0D954A4F88525336C4"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Prohibition on fees</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security may not charge a fee to any eligible Afghan national in connection with—</text><paragraph id="HD373C7886D244105B0F0A7F053572460"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an application for adjustment of status or employment authorization under this section; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD0BE822316940BA895A0253BBEABEF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the issuance of a permanent resident card or an employment authorization document.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H693F57DB28C548F98A0B3AFCD941F76B"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Pending applications</header><text>During the period beginning on the date on which an alien files a bona fide application for adjustment of status under this section and ending on the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security makes a final administrative decision regarding such application, any alien and any dependent included in such application who remains in compliance with all application requirements may not be—</text><paragraph id="H53836E18A54A49A88539BBA34620C57C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>removed from the United States unless the Secretary of Homeland Security makes a prima facie determination that the alien is, or has become, ineligible for adjustment of status under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8641100A9AA0456AB09FB8D7E7081E38"><enum>(2)</enum><text>considered unlawfully present under section 212(a)(9)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(9)(B)</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2152796A67E4FABABD1793A0CA91CD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>considered an unauthorized alien (as defined in section 274A(h)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1324a">8 U.S.C. 1324a(h)(3)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E2932858AF148B0BB426BFE128244DD"><enum>(l)</enum><header>VAWA self petitioners</header><text>Section 101(a)(51) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(51)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H39064472359A444BBCC5CD155E9B8561"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (F), by striking <quote>or</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10559EAE9A7E4D9099D30EC39A81B291"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43D2DC37DACA4B05BA47A9701182F0ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4CD2279022D24D38852956CFFD995217" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HFCEC5AFA55D74D7CA1A45C1796EE92B6"><enum>(H)</enum><text>subsections (b) and (c) of section 6 of the Afghan Adjustment Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0177AF8BFC6E4A1CBCC7484791F342D4"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Exemption from numerical limitations</header><text>Aliens granted adjustment of status under this section shall not be subject to the numerical limitations under sections 201, 202, and 203 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>, 1152, and 1153).</text></subsection><subsection id="HC065C3AA0CB048DFB2603A7718F1110E"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to preclude an eligible Afghan national from applying for or receiving any immigration benefit to which the eligible Afghan national is otherwise entitled.</text></subsection></section><section id="H6BBC0AA1BAA5414794860665202F8C54"><enum>7.</enum><header>Special immigrant status for at-risk Afghan allies and relatives of certain members of the armed forces</header><subsection id="H90AC7BC34FED48ECB423BC9E6AEB8C53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>At-Risk afghan allies</header><paragraph id="H6C202E4CD6EB40D085AE1638E8057BC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (4)(C), the Secretary of Homeland Security may provide an alien described in paragraph (2) (and the spouse, children of the alien if accompanying or following to join the alien) with the status of special immigrant under section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="HC31E853504B94B5D81E5B3DA43C241C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>or an agent acting on behalf of the alien, submits a petition for classification under section 203(b)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1153">8 U.S.C. 1153(b)(4)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E742E727D7B49539C6A60DADE190AA7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is otherwise admissible to the United States and eligible for lawful permanent residence (excluding the grounds of inadmissibility under section 212(a)(4) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)(4)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBAD7AC98C0B4B5C82527530B909C7CB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clears a background check and appropriate screening, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H736CE6C6707447F9AE4BDF3A5FD24D43"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that the adjustment of status of the alien is not contrary to the national welfare, safety, or security of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA8525EF25014EE4B2135A49788CF1FB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alien described</header><text>An alien described in this paragraph is an alien who—</text><subparagraph id="HB3689752FBF54CC3A2A2B7FA3700D5F0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a citizen or national of Afghanistan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46EAD299A8284AD89109E54AC91ED9AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>was a member of—</text><clause id="H60FE93ED982042F1945AE8CF890F18C3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Afghanistan National Army Special Operations Command;</text></clause><clause id="H2A7C6743B4B349BCB97EEC7A1019285B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Afghan Air Force;</text></clause><clause id="H59060AF7B4354B4FB0BADBAA4A08AF36"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Special Mission Wing of Afghanistan; or</text></clause><clause id="H1F3D77670E8E4F0296EE35410652A462"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Female Tactical Teams of Afghanistan; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD72424BBF13B437D9DD5494D2338B25F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provided faithful and valuable service to an entity or organization described in subparagraph (B) for not less than 1 year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE17B66EFEBAB4FACB6E823331CBA3597"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Department of defense assessment</header><subparagraph id="H0341431062CA4426AED4FB8FB703BFA9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving a request for an assessment from the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense shall—</text><clause id="H518B0D5E0B19438094CE3873BC6866E7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review the service record of the principal applicant;</text></clause><clause id="H10255107DEDF4323892E2875F09EC3FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit an assessment to the Secretary of Homeland Security as to whether—</text><subclause id="H4A48757B2E6246D2BB02B7EF79B4AED4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the principal applicant meets the requirements under paragraph (2); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H452658F0650948A3AFAC3698B8423B02"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the adjustment of status of such alien, and the spouse, children, and parents of such alien, if accompanying or following to join the alien, is not contrary to the national welfare, safety, or security of the United States; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD8BEC752B151482F8A926CD6DFF60FE2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>submit with such assessment—</text><subclause id="H068C7C08B9884B6E86EB35A6560303CB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any service record concerned; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H2231E19358854C8DAFD4B4CCB3DEBB42"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any biometrics for the principal applicant that have been collected by the Department of Defense.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21441B602B834981BA0F042C9D0249F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effect of assessment</header><text>A favorable assessment under subparagraph (A)(ii) shall create a presumption that—</text><clause id="HA6F9814FDF334D748A3F073818EF9A8E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the principal applicant meets the requirements under paragraph (2); and</text></clause><clause id="H1554D293B33F4E02A68AB809C834C7A9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the admission of such alien, and the spouse, children, and parents of the alien, if accompanying or following to join the alien, is not contrary to the national welfare, safety, or security of the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7C8C6F0EDA14F6C8C83E39424BE1403"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Efficient processing</header><text>For purposes of a background check and appropriate screening required to be granted special immigrant status under this subsection, the Secretary of Homeland Security, as appropriate, shall use biometric data collected by the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of State not more than 5 years before the date on which an application for such status is filed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H53FEC7DD23FB472EA90BA53230091DAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Special immigrant status for certain relatives of certain members of the armed forces</header><text>Section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDBC49B61CCC84011A2ADEDA17FA9255E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (L)(iii), by adding a semicolon at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB503FDF9C2594637ABBDD4359E49DD62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (M), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD25039B5BBC40FE84291A171D0AD02E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H619AC1C29BF7424CA020C06C7BC66F3D" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HA80B7B16739C40CFA003CD625EDC283D"><enum>(N)</enum><text>a citizen or national of Afghanistan who is the spouse, child, or unmarried son or daughter of—</text><clause id="HCDE121E0B0C946669969E036281161BE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a member of the armed forces (as defined in section 101(a) of title 10, United States Code); or</text></clause><clause id="HBF874DF4DC3E43CB8F3B22468520197A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a veteran (as defined in section 101 of title 38, United States Code).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66126A53716A409493C3702E3D6BEA11"><enum>(c)</enum><header>General provisions</header><paragraph id="H98179321BC8B4E58A63204CD5BDC4380"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition on fees</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Defense, or the Secretary of State may not charge any fee in connection with an application for, or issuance of, a special immigrant visa under this section or an amendment made by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H220751B4C5FB41BE8E576EC6DF968A6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Representation</header><text>An alien applying for admission to the United States under this section, or an amendment made by this section, may be represented during the application process, including at relevant interviews and examinations, by an attorney or other accredited representative. Such representation shall not be at the expense of the United States Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3574FB44FEB04409B65D0284CE6C12DC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusion from numerical limitations</header><text>Aliens provided special immigrant visas under this section, or an amendment made by this section, shall not be counted against any numerical limitation under section 201(d), 202(a), or 203(b)(4) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(d)</external-xref>, 1152(a), and 1153(b)(4)) or section 602 of the Afghan Allies Protection Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/8">Public Law 111–8</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7080B2962D954180A316408D33F66A92"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Assistance with passport issuance</header><text>The Secretary of State shall make a reasonable effort to ensure that an alien who is issued a special immigrant visa under this section, or an amendment made by this section, is provided with the appropriate series Afghan passport necessary to enter the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D05FE62CBC3458CA49CC1DD18E10589"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Protection of aliens</header><text>The Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies, shall make a reasonable effort to provide an alien who is seeking special immigrant status under this section, or an amendment made by this section, protection or to immediately remove such alien from Afghanistan, if possible.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C0246F06CBB4EE79B1F57577570A455"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Other eligibility for immigrant status</header><text>No alien shall be denied the opportunity to apply for admission under this section, or an amendment made by this section, solely because the alien qualifies as an immediate relative or is eligible for any other immigrant classification.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6945DEFE878E4B5895FB5F63CE619C88"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Resettlement support</header><text>A citizen or national of Afghanistan who is granted special immigrant status described in section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) shall be eligible for resettlement assistance, entitlement programs, and other benefits available to refugees admitted under section 207 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>) to the same extent, and for the same periods of time, as such refugees.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAACA7C985D124CF39C3406E9C917B93F"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Adjustment of status</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (2), (7), or (8) of subsection (c) of section 245 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1255">8 U.S.C. 1255</external-xref>), the Secretary of Homeland Security may adjust the status of an alien described in subparagraph (N) of section 101(a)(27) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(27)</external-xref>) or subsection (a)(2) of this section to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence under subsection (a) of such section 245 if the alien—</text><subparagraph id="H67BC35A2C51D4A9EBC50C73A4AB5B1A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was paroled or admitted as a nonimmigrant into the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE81329B0E0974C75B6DB5B6420E6756F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is otherwise eligible for special immigrant status under—</text><clause id="HED0198579FC640FEAC6A16A004D35349"><enum>(i)</enum><text>this section; or</text></clause><clause id="HB9484B42CAA24121B63E82949E3579C6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB609C77DC5843B5B39403FBFBA710DF"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Appeals</header><subparagraph id="H04B100AE1C1A414FAEC5DCE51F3A8362"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Administrative review</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to aliens who have applied for special immigrant status under this section a process by which an applicant may seek administrative appellate review of a denial of an applicant for special immigrant status or a revocation of such status.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H68F835607BB94AB9BF1B249EF1AB0773"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Judicial review</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (C), and notwithstanding any other provision of law, an alien may seek judicial review of a denial of an application for special immigrant status or a revocation of such status under this Act, in an appropriate United States district court.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F5A0AA02964485EB8EC9A8CBEB9102C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Stay of removal</header><clause id="H7D8BC499D06A4375B46D5CE503BF2C9C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in clause (ii), an alien seeking administrative or judicial review under this Act may not be removed from the United States until a final decision is rendered establishing that the alien is ineligible for special immigrant status under this section.</text></clause><clause id="HA3BA98C5E85D44ADB84E6B1958451203"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The Secretary may remove an alien described in clause (i) pending judicial review if such removal is based on national security concerns. Such removal shall not affect the alien’s right to judicial review under this Act. The Secretary shall promptly return a removed alien if a decision to deny an application for special immigrant status under this Act, or to revoke such status, is reversed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0EA926CC527A4BD8B206076639A1AF58"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remainder of this Act, and the application of the remaining provisions of this Act, to any person or circumstance, shall not be affected.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

