<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B7A7132DB1142EABCF950A10C8A90EC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7536 IH: Civic Duty to Vote Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7536</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220418">April 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require each eligible citizen to appear to vote in each regularly scheduled general election for Federal office, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD1262552BBCE4BAFA4FA30617F0432C1" style="OLC"><section id="HA53EF61E8BC14FEE92856F9C36F6D32E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Civic Duty to Vote Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4C2BAE0895A54C889486482BA224EDF8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirements with respect to voting by citizens</header><subsection id="H443179ADDF9B4F34A1B277218611A74C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement To appear To vote</header><paragraph id="H4BA374BD1EF441CA8EA90AACED4C8885"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Each eligible citizen shall appear to vote in each regularly scheduled general election for Federal office as described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE34D364D3A8424BA3BCE31051117878"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appearing to vote described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible citizen shall be deemed to appear to vote in a regularly scheduled general election for Federal office if such citizen returns a ballot to vote in such election to an appropriate State election official in the State in which such citizen is eligible to vote by any method authorized by the laws of the State in which such election is held.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2284BAFDDEBB4939960861CE6E3422B8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to require an eligible citizen to cast a vote for any candidate in an election for Federal office.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E7E93238F204BE38CFF3F9F03210F93"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Civil money penalty for violation</header><paragraph id="HA3DC2C1C94D34A7EB474B5D912E24DD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in paragraph (4), a civil money penalty in the amount of $20 shall be assessed against any individual found to be in violation of the requirements under subsection (a) unless the individual certifies to an appropriate State election official that the individual has a valid and sufficient reason for not appearing to vote in any such election described in subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AF938AF69CA4408829FECB242594D7B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Valid and sufficient reason described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following shall be deemed to be a valid and sufficient reason for not appearing to vote in a regularly scheduled general election for Federal office:</text><subparagraph id="H872A74E92D7D4E1F9AE0FD3C4BCF0AA5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual is unable to receive or return a ballot in such an election because the individual is not registered to vote in the election in the State after a good faith attempt by the individual to register to vote in such election.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8FA5287431DF44F391CA3B935EC166DD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An individual is unable to appear to vote as a result of an emergency.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDD42F83650CD46F89FCD3FD2CCE6EC20"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual is unable to comply with the requirements of subsection (a) due to sincerely held religious or personal beliefs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F9674A4981042279D70B3DD0B10BC63"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An individual was unaware of the individual’s eligibility to vote in any such election. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H77FF3E39353F494698FF212B694BD5C5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The appropriate State election official shall grant a waiver of the civil money penalty under paragraph (1) with respect to any individual found to be in violation of the requirement under subsection (a)(1) who—</text><subparagraph id="HD9CF101DDE4848C3B50B4BB72647A641"><enum>(A)</enum><text>certifies to the election official that the individual cannot afford to pay such civil money penalty; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H810AE6D4C20C4B6E88B67E757267BAD5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>attests that such individual will complete one hour of community service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C67267DD08D445EB89CF569CDEFA755"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an individual’s first violation of the requirements under subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="HAACFAA410E0F4F73840EA056509D63CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the civil money penalty under paragraph (1) shall not apply; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2B3A86B891774A8FAD26E447ED4D8412"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate State election official of the State in which such citizen is eligible to vote shall send the individual a notice that informs the individual of the violation and the civil money penalty that will be assessed against the individual with respect to any subsequent violation. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66F24354F09B4FE19D668EFF195ACE98"><enum>(5)</enum><header>No additional penalties for failure to pay civil money penalty</header><text>In the case of an individual found to be in violation of the requirement under subsection (a)(1) who fails to pay a civil money penalty assessed under paragraph (1), such individual shall not, as a result of such failure to pay the civil money penalty, be subject to any additional civil or criminal penalties or any denial of government benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H88091749AA044FDAB2C5D7A91C89CA57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition against certain uses of information</header><paragraph id="H69795AD6907B40A792C9F0BDD9541327"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition against information sharing with law enforcement</header><text>A State election official may not share any information provided by an individual for the purposes of certifying a valid and sufficient reason that the individual did not appear to vote under subsection (b)(2) or receiving a waiver of the civil money penalty under subsection (b)(3) with any Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H625F39469B9442CBA583F79954B2B2DA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition against law enforcement use of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No Federal, State, or local law enforcement agency may use any information provided by an individual for the purposes of certifying a valid and sufficient reason that the individual did not appear to vote under subsection (b)(2) to subject such individual to any additional penalties or criminal investigation. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2F32DCF70274869A0DEE8EA2716FD97"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall apply with respect to the regularly scheduled general election for Federal office held in November 2024 and each succeeding election for Federal office.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCEE5C504AE8B4EBCBF42BD758CA9F047"><enum>3.</enum><header>Election Assistance Commission publication of best practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Election Assistance Commission shall develop and publish recommendations for best practices for States to implement the requirements of this Act, including practices for States to provide individuals with an option on a ballot in an election for Federal office to affirmatively decline to vote for any candidate with respect to each office in any such election.</text></section><section id="H2D450729510B46BFACC56290C53C8109" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>4.</enum><header>Election Assistance Commission grants to States</header><subsection id="HA834A8EDFF5340A588B36EA6B43A11FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants to States</header><text>The Election Assistance Commission shall make grants to each eligible State to assist the State in implementing the requirements of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA491F30131A44FD9AC0D950E06EE10B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>A State is eligible to receive a grant under this section if the State submits to the Commission, at such time and in such form as the Commission may require, an application containing such information as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1D1123FE1BD4DE68C40272EDFF4CAFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="HAEB8E5652C074938829E8C1EDCD86848"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H6CBEB94380B54A35989BA6C8D6DD79F9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible citizen</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible citizen</term> means a citizen who is eligible to vote in a regularly scheduled general election for Federal office in a State pursuant to the laws of the State in which the citizen resides.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD51718111BC2481583D775E03823EF50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States and the District of Columbia.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

