<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1FC7A12E94EA47CAA43DF6651442C2D6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7765 IH: American Food Supply Chain Resiliency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7765</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220513">May 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3B71D490C2254EA8AA6644A3337081AE" style="OLC"><section id="H757708A7E8B74606A6E4CE8E4C75C59A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>American Food Supply Chain Resiliency Act of 2022</short-title></quote> . </text></section><section id="H1DE1A4F811974B9D83ABA4FE1C7B47A4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Agricultural Marketing Act of 1946 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1621">7 U.S.C. 1621 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7AC62CEA0E8E4FF0AC1F9CDB66F32021" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subtitle id="H5686EDF955F14634B9FCA0E6943514AA"><enum>H</enum><header>Food supply chain resiliency</header><section id="HC6B31B1E295643E1BB4D8458E3CDE841"><enum>298.</enum><header>Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers</header><subsection id="H1DBD1C44B3554978946442D7197653A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Agricultural Marketing Service, shall enter into cooperative agreements with eligible entities to establish not fewer than 6 Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers to support small-sized and medium-sized producers of agricultural products and small-sized and medium-sized agricultural businesses through activities, which may include—</text><paragraph id="H30648209DAFE429498E9901062C289E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offering coordination, technical assistance, and capacity building support to small-sized and medium-sized producers of agricultural products and agricultural businesses; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46A0A255547E4F69B34932F44D2B7E3A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><italic></italic>supporting supply chain and value chain coordination—</text><subparagraph id="H0009C19766664EED8F241D9DD192D132"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the region in which such producers or businesses are located; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0F93FBDBEE64DF08D195C97469FFC25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with the Department of Agriculture, other Federal, State, and Tribal agencies with relevant resources, regional commissions, and other Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF35603225C374D418CD7B147428194A9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing technical assistance to such producers and businesses; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA7FCC787CB2642CC8752019509E361E6"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">providing grants or other financial assistance to such producers and businesses looking to expand production or a business or start production or a business in such region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE29E30B9E394F1CAB878B0FDFDD2700"><enum>(5)</enum><text>carrying out such other activities as may be specified by the Secretary. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDE1E183FFDF84952A0341E7BB532700F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Focus on Tribal supply chain issues</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">At least one Supply Chain Regional Resource Center established pursuant to subsection (a) shall provide coordination, assistance, and capacity building support to address supply chain issues faced by Indian tribes and Tribal organizations (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF2E55605EE4C4DB8885FAD89F3159381"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><paragraph id="HC0EDBCB40215478299EA3BAD37D7A239"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity (including an entity representing a partnership) seeking to enter into a cooperative agreement under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application, at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including how the Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers established by such entity will address food and agricultural supply chain issues faced by underserved communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF31D531D4254698BEFA7A74367D80E8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Regional diversity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In selecting eligible entities to enter into a cooperative agreement under this section, the Secretary shall ensure the regional diversity of such entities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE752E6E743994EE694659BCD5E127A61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Term</header><text>The term of a cooperative agreement entered into under this section shall be not less than 4 years.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6DC5669F02D248708C923297848FDBB7"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Supply Chain Regional Resource Center shall, as a condition on entering into a cooperative agreement under this section, agree to coordinate with other Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers, when appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H568A3045D9A64BAEA60289923F5238E1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>American Food Supply Chain Resiliency Act of 2022</short-title>, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report on—</text><paragraph id="H9C252A336B8549B3ACC0DD86BB72F068"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the activities carried out by the Secretary under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H96460AE231C848EB82C340AF504B450C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of such activities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BC883F164AF4496A29DB1956059ADE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of such activities on supply chain issues faced by small-sized and medium-sized producers of agricultural products; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93C2AA47B4C6485F8B66C3A8FCC8BDED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to the activities carried out by the Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H41F2D3DEC67F4906BC05D031DC82AA81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a description of such activities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE72CE9E030234F80B3350EBF4E0B0DEA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the impact of such activities on supply chain issues faced by small-sized and medium-sized producers of agricultural products and agricultural businesses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D77BB855B17420A95960D8D470B9F99"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any grants awarded by Supply Chain Regional Resource Centers to such producers and businesses.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1624620CBF6447368E054C4D3ECFDD5A"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H10EB8D76E9C2402FB0460F3EFD6CAD75"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H943E23F1BB814E68AD490D4A3B5CBE8D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a State government (or a political subdivision thereof), regional authority, or an Indian Tribe or Tribal organization; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H87FFA97294CD40B6B130D06B20E65BF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a college or university (as defined in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>)) (including a land-grant college or university); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCCFFF7D47E49F58FE763B26C83863B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a nonprofit organization, including a producer network or association, a food council, an economic development corporation, or another organization.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5EEC73E9D934FA1A61EF065364B1A08"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>State</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1404 of the National Agricultural Research, Extension, and Teaching Policy Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/3103">7 U.S.C. 3103</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99A6A4F4D55840AFAF86AE199D71F417"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $6,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026. </text></subsection></section></subtitle><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3D541278BA2B44C9941780488424E6F7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Agriculture Innovation Centers Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6402(a) of the Farm Security and Rural Investment Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/1632b">7 U.S.C. 1632b(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HDC31D7921BB346C4909D5B0D391F25C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF52A41387A740D2B0E00D39A289B807"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB13401E2825447CF8B1F610CCE78634D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA3E4495D3B68426293D41FC36DF5BC54" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H9534B47F464542BB82C3299B9DCF4452"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">research, technical assistance, support services, outreach, and other services to strengthen, maintain, and secure supply chains related to agricultural inputs and agricultural products produced in the United States. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

