<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB33A679B146C41BCBE628F5DF7E28EBF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9105 IH: National Medical Corps Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9105</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to authorize the establishment of the National Medical Corps Program to create pathway programs for community college students to pursue premedical training and enter medical school, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H93572D377E7C42EA9BAAB55DBCF63A27" style="OLC"><section id="H6A38DB87E37A4C12AA3C0F18B7039AB6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Medical Corps Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>NMC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4F1A2074FD0042F3B133CE93C06AAEF1"><enum>2.</enum><header>National Medical Corps programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part B of title VII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/293">42 U.S.C. 293 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3941C9D3A7394D64B9114238D3BDB0F0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H08748A0CA9354AD1AD1D8242DB96E039"><enum>741A.</enum><header>National Medical Corps programs</header><subsection id="HC1B26A27F015499E8DF79E9BDE7C6D8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Education and the Secretary of Labor, shall make grants to, and enter into contracts with, eligible entities for the purpose of establishing programs to assist community college students to pursue premedical training and enter medical school (referred to in this section as an <quote>NMC Program</quote>, by addressing—</text><paragraph id="H90220C078022493092A8D8CC6F0E8C06"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the shortage of primary care physicians and psychiatrists in vulnerable and underserved communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9491150D02E44A5B18CBD4611507DDA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the widening disparities in access to care in such communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC7C6B9EA2D8402AB1848999CC1E708D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity is eligible to receive a grant or enter into a contract under this section if the entity is a school of medicine, an institution of higher education, or a public or private nonprofit health or educational institution (other than a school of nursing) that—</text><paragraph id="HE46D8977D7454050850964236BBB9647"><enum>(1)</enum><text>forms a consortium that includes, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="HEB8250072AE84DC1A5D6287037B19923"><enum>(A)</enum><text>3 community colleges in the region in which the consortium serves;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC312CC8035440B99827083DEBFD5649"><enum>(B) </enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one 4-year public or private nonprofit undergraduate institution in the region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA56F5ECC33F4477EB557F5F325CB2F10"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one public or private nonprofit accredited medical school located in a State;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E9CAA9758DF44A9A838CA047B609DF7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one primary care association or consortium of community health centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49A7BD8B7CF841778D5965D9B90BACDD"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least one community health center, inclusive of federally qualified health centers, federally qualified health center look-alikes, rural health centers, migrant health centers, frontier health centers, indian health service clinics, and free clinics; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0F468DE732F4A52B950293FC4F1AC82"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other such entities as considered appropriate by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB13681F3DE654E91B38CC4546D486E2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has established, or commits to establish, a community advisory board that is—</text><subparagraph id="HEA9AD5F90CAA4D0A87F2D0C5D40FFB69"><enum>(A)</enum><text>comprised of local business, education, health industry, and other community leaders to oversee and guide the programmatic direction of the program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC36065D3D3FB44CB8255AC983E1DFD95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intended to guide the unique establishment of regional partnerships and opportunities for students along the pathway to support the accomplishment of its targets for student outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B75BC35BB5E4C57ADAB6497C88325CB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application; selection</header><paragraph id="H6F54AFAB975C47BCB55293714163D4EF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit an application at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require. Such application shall contain—</text><subparagraph id="HAEB4CDD8BCCE4324AD15A247A956ECD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the entity selected to operate as the lead entity of the consortium;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2DAF11740FC4A529B3CBD94ED17CD05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>documentation supporting the entity’s eligibility; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA83053BDEBF640A492074E1144D64E9C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8108541DD652454F8781286D0D940F38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select, on a competitive basis—</text><subparagraph id="H17014322A50D407A9490483F3561C23D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>20 eligible entities in the first full calendar year beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86483E63B78144ACBD8F6F52A8017FBC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>20 eligible entities in each of the 5 subsequent calendar years. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H683C389BA7214F7D8B2270A5E88728A2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Conditions on awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The recipient of a grant shall, as a condition on receiving such a grant agree—</text><paragraph id="H1696984A00C94910BC6AAFF20E494C7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>that a student selected to participate in an NMC Program (referred to in this section as a <quote>National Medical Corps Scholar</quote> or an <quote>NMC Scholar</quote>) shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H2E01E827BC1B41E1988A1252DEACC871"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a community college student who has completed at least one semester of community college and is intending to transfer to a 4-year college pre-medical program with the intent to pursue a career in primary care medicine or psychiatry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94F7E2C85A0846599754708D26A59C06"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">from an economically or educationally disadvantaged background; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDC6AEFDBCCC4588BDE4D6D8D2DCB65F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a citizen, national, or lawful permanent resident of the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F8F82653C1B460AA6306953976D7EF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to verify that each individual seeking to be selected as an NMC Scholar—</text><subparagraph id="H09C712E8224D49098FD010E5A8FE7708"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">intends to pursue practice as a physician who practices primary care or psychiatry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF5EB36ECA0A41D0B97A1D5B704F11FE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intends to serve in the National Health Service Corps; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9413F464ADFB4E8F995F3D245A171A67"><enum>(C)</enum><text>has been determined under subsection (f) to be from an economically or educationally disadvantaged background;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H126A49F6D4554F5C89F750403211AC6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide to each NMC Scholar a student-identifying marker prior to entering medical school and to require that the NMC Scholar, as a condition on receipt of support, provides to the grant recipient the National Provider Identifier of the NMC Scholar when the Scholar enters medical school; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B759AE8C6384420A841C7EAC1FEF18B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to select and support (through the provision of scholarships and wrap around services) not fewer than 50 NMC Scholars each year of the grant, selected from three or more of the populations described in subsection (e); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB2489BEB6EB4B86B5C4B71D59FAD6B8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to track the academic and career pathway of such NMC scholars from community college through medical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA202706B89B42919EF4B08CE462B3E4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide individualized guidance with respect to pursuing an alternate career pathway to NMC scholars that elect not to pursue a career as physicians in primary care or psychiatry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D71D427CAFA4D8A952C7D3A905041C5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to limit the amount of an award to an NMC Scholar in a fiscal year to the costs of attendance for the applicable school year. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00414C313A7A471AA09838CDB0649990"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Populations described</header><text>The populations described in this subsection are each of the following:</text><paragraph id="HE54416EB3EF74CF19670AA1C1F091797"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Individuals enrolled in 2-year community college programs with the intention to transfer to a 4-year institution of higher education.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CD34AB4D5B0476D91F54B832E7DC24C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Community college transfer students who are currently enrolled in a 4-year institution of higher education with intention to apply to medical school.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10177178782F49A4AF5DFD8C42A9E711"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals enrolled in medical school who—</text><subparagraph id="H6C1D6CA782CA4C2ABF6961FF92DCCD93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>were previously enrolled for a period of at least 1 year at a community college after completing secondary school but before obtaining a bachelor’s degree; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7904215BBB304C869F5C0122EBFBFD65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>intend to pursue training in primary care or psychiatry to serve rural or underserved communities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H34FA442FC0F041F4AA96CA04A5DE009D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Economically or educationally disadvantaged background</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To determine if a student seeking to be selected as an NMC Scholar is from an economically or educationally disadvantaged background, the recipient of a grant under this section shall—</text><paragraph id="H7488CD0D944342178531DB7E319A2953"><enum>(1)</enum><text>first determine if such student is from an economically disadvantaged background; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H35824537E65445059DBE84CBE9729219"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if a student has been determined not to be from an economically disadvantaged background, the recipient shall evaluate whether the student is from a educationally disadvantaged background. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H87E98B01B3F44D8BB66F33B7C15FA608"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity selected to receive a grant under this section may use funds received through the grant to—</text><paragraph id="H4F52688A848F4A21BAA40BC620631F20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct outreach toward, and recruitment and enrollment of, NMC Scholars;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D831E3AC41E45F9BCFF5BA8978F073C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">plan, develop, and operate a program to support NMC Scholars’ career progression into medical school, including providing advising, mentoring, academic supports for transfer, medical school applications, and identifying and pursuing extracurricular and work opportunities aligned with future health careers, such as part-time employment in a health, public health, or primary care-related position;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85C234EEA91C4A2BA0527C22ACA51537"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide financial assistance in the form of scholarships or stipends for NMC Scholars from community college through entry to medical school;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1380638E1B5C4E029EE5F5786D18DC6E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate NMC Program activities with other existing Federal, State, local, and institutions resources, including the Health Careers Opportunity program under section 736, area health education centers under section 751, programs and services for disabled students under subtitle A of title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act, and Federal TRIO programs<italic></italic> under chapter 1 of subpart 2 of part A of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1070a-11">20 U.S.C. 1070a–11 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51EC7EA809404610A45435E102EE17A6" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement data sharing, analysis, and the continuous testing of data-informed practices, to foster a statewide collaboration of mutual accountability for improvement, consistent with applicable State and Federal law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE95CDB526B346A09D349D34393C105B"><enum>(6)</enum><text>cover the costs associated with maintaining the consortium and advisory board; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D08E814B7864CB2854DAAE132233BF6"><enum>(7)</enum><text>support training in community-based organizations, such as community health centers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B91BB03EF164FA78F6211F944342DD8"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop a partnership agreement and support NMC Scholars with one or more campus-based learning communities, groups, or entities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD06D1C8F24D94F6584BFEFD7B5261ED2"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement and adopt premedical advising standards or standardized guidelines as set out by the consortium lead, in collaboration with consortium membership, including community colleges, four-year undergraduate institutions, and participating schools of medicine. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21C4FF189B8D4A08BF69E77A1FDC7DE1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Priorities in making awards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants or contracts under this section, the Secretary may give priority to consortia that include at least one—</text><paragraph id="HEAC278127DC74A9CB891FB6BB2BBA620"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minority-serving institution, including a historically Black college or university;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6DC87DECF9C44F196300C121C115B16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hispanic-serving institution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30544D72DB7844158592B631DC073017"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Tribal college or university;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4773171753F4A948BF55A61832217C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Asian American and Pacific Islander serving institution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF774CB660384AAE8B5AE86D94DE37CC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Native Hawaiian-serving institution; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE17CCAF4A1AA4CE18C34ABFC05E53F30"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Native American-serving non-Tribal institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A76D887A2664F76BC8E717A87ACF0B5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Coordination with NHSC</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Individuals selected as NMC Scholars shall receive priority consideration for an award under for National Health Service Corps Scholarship Program under section 338A and the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program under section 338B. </text></subsection><subsection id="HE733C380FFBA42E0822078250685A58F"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Report to Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section and every calendar year thereafter, each consortium selected to receive a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary a report on the following with respect to the preceding year:</text><paragraph id="H5037CD6826FD4EFF81A799CD68036B87"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The selection criteria and process used to ensure that the members of the consortium and advisory board represent the intended communities to be served and the demographics of such members and advisory board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4439AB51F1045F484DE4AE915990267"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A summary of the roles of the members of the consortium and advisory board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC871790EDE4C6E8B36F05B560A990A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The selection criteria, process, and strategy used by the consortium to recruit, engage, and select NMC Scholars.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H546C9741E63D458B91EFEF3E9EEA0C93"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With respect to the NMC Scholars participating in the NMC Program—</text><subparagraph id="H4CACE5FBD0914F3BA3275F606FD04759"><enum>(A)</enum><text>self-reported demographic data (including race and ethnicity, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity, date of birth, English proficiency status, fluency in other languages, disadvantaged (educational or economic) background status, disability, the census tract or current address, or other demographic data as appropriate)<italic></italic>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8CF19FBA8954744A1AEDC8A417E4192"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentages of NMC Scholars who successfully achieve transfer-level math and English by the completion of their second year enrolled in a community college, disaggregated by race and ethnicity of student populations so enrolled in such a community college;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H32D90DACD4FA4977A501C3E0B9EEE80F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate of acceptance to participating 4-year institutions of higher education and 4-year college pre-medical training programs for transfer students applying from participating community colleges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A654EEDE75F4686B4D6EBD86D5DDE68"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate of NMC scholars eligible to transfer, or accepted to attend, a participating 4-year institution of higher education after completing two years, two and one-half years, or three or more years, in special circumstances, of enrollment in a community college. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEB224B7B03744E382CA3642B2135B82"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">when available, career advancement data, including—</text><clause id="H5B368ED66AE142CCA66D876346BF69E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether the scholar was accepted to a 4-year institution of higher education, medical school, another health professions program, or another STEM professions program;</text></clause><clause id="H6B39A670D855468BA4A4CEFFDF5250BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether the scholar graduated from medical school, another health professions program, or another STEM professions program;</text></clause><clause id="H6DC252B7BB8E4C0C890743F7262299E7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether the scholar pursued a career in primary care, psychiatry, or another health profession in a rural or underserved setting; </text></clause><clause id="HD8B78190A1C9490AAF01599B834D0C69"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the National Provider Identifier assigned to such student, as available; and</text></clause><clause id="H958F4E18391A46C9908C8B2DF1E8234E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>such other information as determined to be appropriate by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACD4A60E3CC04EA7A32BA8B6A038AD4F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation of the success of the NMC Program, including with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HC165A390E87748AFB658FA2E6A48678D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the program was able to support not less than 50 students in the first year of implementation of the program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23835E4B6B8C43CBBA37D9B54B3C5694"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of semesters in community college each such student enrolled in, what type of college or university the student was enrolled in, which degree the student pursued, and which career pathway the student is pursuing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37C9F2D6DBB149A7AA7058FC80987E42"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the program developed a partnership agreement with one or more campus-based learning communities, groups, or entities, as specified in subsection (g)(8); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E05136BF98C4DC39099A2D2AD5D513D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether and to what extent the program was able to align its goals and equity strategies, and maximize the use of available resources and funds, as specified in subsection (d)(4).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H408AA1DE91C84A53AF960A17FC634D1A"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of fiscal year 2028, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall submit an annual report to the Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H8DBB5F2999AD48B596802441578A0079"><enum>(1)</enum><text>summarizes the information submitted in the evaluation and report under subsections (j) and (k);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF3ABA08A2F4B54912DDC82C0B718CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describes the contracts, strategy, and goals shared between the Secretary and each consortium receiving a grant under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AE47977315F47358A57CC297FE61C32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>includes data on the planned and actual use of funds by the consortium and the Secretary in carrying out this section; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98A206FC2E6846DBAD699688E3B25EBC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assesses the goals and progress of the NMC Program, including the potential impact of NMC Scholars on health care access and quality; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7058DAC1F164D2F82F41C1DF1C57483"><enum>(5)</enum><text>makes recommendations for improvements to the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD162D661AC94AF49C14854171A9FF88" commented="no"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Privacy protections</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In publishing data under this section, the Secretary shall take all necessary steps to protect the privacy of individuals whose information is included in such data, including— </text><paragraph id="H125D5647669A40BD961AA5A824990BC5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complying with privacy protections comparable to those applicable under the HIPAA privacy regulation (as defined in section 1180(b)(3) of the Social Security Act) to covered entities (as defined for purposes of such regulation); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57A694705D484E97A15714F14DD3D277" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not using or disclosing the information generated pursuant to the program for any purpose other than carrying out the program; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ECB8A8379E24DF187EDBDBDEDA56D6E" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>not publishing or selling individually identifiable information generated pursuant to the program nor transmitting such data for purposes other than carrying out the program, including not sharing such information with any local, State, or Federal law enforcement agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DE87D83928B4A67A28B310C9C5555E7"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2CFCFB7776AF486995DCB5BFFC0D1CDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each State of the United States, the District of Columbia, American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands of the United States, and any other territory or possession of the United States, and each federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EBC9774DDE94C169F90ADE5EB282FCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>educationally disadvantaged</term>, with respect to the background of a student seeking to be selected as an NMC scholar, means that the student—</text><subparagraph id="H9B0A77E0A670414ABE2FEA389F989C37"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is a member of a racial and ethnic minority group (as defined in section 1707) that is under-represented in medicine;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D37E0726E644F32963DB1C48C21E9B3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>resides in a low-income community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7B37CC04A4B4E3DAE2FB230B2F301AB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is a first-generation college attendee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC0EB42377164C4D9860C8E1DE049F40"><enum>(D)</enum><text>attended high school—</text><clause id="H8C9639A0893746688B6D9414C6377C79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a health professional shortage area designated under section 332 or a medically underserved area (as defined in section 330I(a)) or in a rural setting (as defined by the Office of Rural Health Policy); or</text></clause><clause id="H408E51DDE1234374B1ED762C30925C94"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with a low grade point average (2.0 cumulative on a 4.0 scale), based on most recent annual data available; </text></clause><clause id="H53822719C3B947C589753A76C10EEF6F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on the most recent annual data available, had either—</text><subclause id="H8D04A05C50D44F6FB3013C40B63B4173"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a low percentage of seniors receiving a high school diploma; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H59690FDEB88C47AFAA057BAF3B8AA2FA"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a low percentage of graduates who go to college during the first year after graduation; or</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H2C52F1EC8F0D45629FF65CF907680C9E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has low per capita funding; or</text></clause><clause id="H899C68873219478A97FB129A63E6DF14"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on the most recent annual data available, a high rate of the enrolled students are eligible for free or reduced-price lunches.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FE0D369DFD74C2795FA916A374F873E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>primary care</term> means, with respect to a physician, practicing as a general practitioner, family practice practitioner, general internist, pediatrician, psychiatrist, or obstetrician or gynecologist.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H98ED9E1AA01545B8966A368FB3AAF70B"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="HDD04A33E86EA486F88AEB9FEC7B0EAB7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section—</text><subparagraph id="HA57C6E3677A44DF3AB0185E2968837D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$27,000,000 for fiscal year 2023; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6B941D097AD4404A54EC4A7779D8AA4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$54,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA81CDD28AD2045829FF8637A2F49C505"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$81,000,000 for fiscal year 2025;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A7DEDDD8FF84022B7CEF7C79BAFBC68"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$108,000,000 for fiscal year 2026; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE69CC2AA2AC8490CA06EB6C03CF550B9"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$135,000,000 for fiscal year 2027.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85CFBCBB17EC4247850958D356488DB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Allocation among consortia</header><text>Of the amount made available under paragraph (1) for a fiscal year, the Secretary shall allot not more than $1, 350,000 to each consortium.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDB82BC502EB4BD9BD0B4CF4BCA2B987"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on administrative expenses</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A consortium may use not more than 30 percent of funds allocated to such consortium for administrative expenses of the consortium in carrying out an NMC Program. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

