<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9AE151EF63C54A2981828B7023DAD235" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8293 IH: Balkans Security Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8293</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220705">July 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001136">Mrs. McClain</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require a report on security cooperation with respect to Western Balkan countries.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC1A36900BC5A4BB0903C4D95588DBC7B" style="OLC"><section id="H3D8FDC618F17412285DC4EC5D1C9646A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Balkans Security Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2536748DFCA940789FF635EA72E95530"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on security cooperation with respect to Western Balkan countries</header><subsection id="H2BCEF6A73F34418C92C282EF0D49B292"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on security cooperation with respect to Western Balkan countries. </text></subsection><subsection id="H760D7E91ADE44C1A835814D97B180540"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters To be included</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following: </text><paragraph id="HBC1EBE925B824B46B03BB795771E2A6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of security cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the Russian Federation, including the following: </text><subparagraph id="H252ED7B8D3CE42CEA167A43D5C7A606E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of Russian weapons systems and other military hardware and technology valued at $1,000,000 or more that have been provided to or purchased by each Western Balkan country since 2012. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7150FBF14195456DAF81342DD817131C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the participation of each Western Balkan country’s security forces in training or exercises with the Russian Federation since 2012. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E1179DFE0F542A8BC2DB482D8C6F2FA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of any security cooperation agreements each Western Balkan country has entered into with the Russian Federation. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C52712B92A44C03B4618FC51098B57C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of intelligence cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the Russian Federation. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF56CE0D01C4B4984A121B0DFB0306192"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of how security cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the Russian Federation affects the security interests of the United States, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), the Western Balkan country, and each NATO member state that borders the Western Balkan country. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEC4DAEB0A5A414596CDCFF59A1DC318"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of security cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the People’s Republic of China, including the following: </text><subparagraph id="H236BE8DBCCB64D59BE9A3CBFCE0E37B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of Chinese weapons systems and other military hardware and technology valued at $1,000,000 or more that have been provided to or purchased by each Western Balkan country since 2012. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4FD3F7529284F7EB4BC3E225D189B6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the participation of each Western Balkan country’s security forces in training or exercises with the People’s Republic of China since 2012. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78DC0084DFF749C1810A1AAEC98D3D96"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of any security cooperation agreements each Western Balkan country has entered into with the People’s Republic of China. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5EC8C55B1674C3BA21EA9A326E5F3B2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of intelligence cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the People’s Republic of China. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAADEF5BC949941AA85F43E192F38A93A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of how security cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the People’s Republic of China affects the security interests of the United States, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), the Western Balkan country, and each NATO member state that borders the Western Balkan country. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA36FF9A8130149B1A0DF2312E95C5268"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of security cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the United States, including the following: </text><subparagraph id="H6C73F4987C954A2EB01494B261B43F2D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A list of United States weapons systems and other military hardware and technology valued at $1,000,000 or more that have been provided to or purchased by each Western Balkan country since 2012. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABCE47D5693A4A33B4F3EA9767C45EE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the participation of each Western Balkan country’s security forces in training or exercises with the United States since 2012. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85DE5B147508430F822E79EE9B734E87"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A description of any security cooperation agreements each Western Balkan country has entered into with the United States. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H106CD5E0BD004A24AC655A286B82C06F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of intelligence cooperation between each Western Balkan country and the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7B2BCDA1B1E48C28953F5BD03B4EA73"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of security cooperation between each Western Balkan country and NATO. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36BA9427E2284DF4AAB546BD0644F7A2"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of each Western Balkan country’s participation and activities in NATO’s Partnership for Peace program, if applicable. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0234F7B3AA4B401183D67319A8BF11FD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>An assessment of the Russian Humanitarian Center in Niš, Serbia, and any influence or coordination it may have with Russian Federation Intelligence Agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H997B8D07F78D414C8EADD1383B21EC77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assessment and determination relating to conduct of significant transactions under CAATSA</header><paragraph id="HC41274F9BA414795B80BEE312A54A678"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State, acting through the President, shall include in the report required by subsection (a) an assessment and determination of whether any Western Balkan country has conducted a significant transaction described in section 231 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9525">22 U.S.C. 9525</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4502D36C30E24FDE9332CF3182D07AD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection may be construed to obviate any requirement of section 231 of the Countering America’s Adversaries Through Sanctions Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H74003770E57246DE9DB481A71DCF051E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. </text></subsection><subsection id="H13F89D0FA8684EA49FCE677810B4120F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section—</text><paragraph id="H86D8E468A1744B7BACCD6BBC434C8AE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H273F3DCA8486467193CB563BE85D15F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>congressional defense committees (as such term is defined in section 101 of title 10, United States Code); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8706D340C65A4A72A92E6BFD01D01EA5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE750B480073A461CA9A56939C226A440"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term ‘‘Western Balkan countries’’ means—</text><subparagraph id="HBB95BFA8559147FAB6A9FF1EEE63513E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Albania;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27F004288CF24DB9B748311F8FFAEFF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Bosnia and Herzegovina; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9784C3F38D824ADDB511CBC8806E3008"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Croatia; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D4A5501C99A4A36956568FCAF2C53E4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Kosovo; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD695C2257AE444E4A2CFE3B3F388025B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Montenegro;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A3426C2C97A4985AD36090E6625013B"><enum>(F)</enum><text>North Macedonia; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1C1D96E3FCD4F9781C601A9CBF87D14"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Serbia; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB11E3404B5094258A4CD59BD9F2BB32C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Slovenia.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

