<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F10C1238A2840A8B6EBA2BC75040BA5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6982 IH: Public Lands Telecommunications Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6982</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To support the establishment and improvement of communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands through the retention and use of rental fees associated with such sites, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE4D78DE27491473EA2AE3B5BA9EC7B3B" style="OLC"><section id="H6E8FBF0EC29443639035CB92EA8982D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Lands Telecommunications Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1F0C98879B4A4F1CB3A443227BEFDC64"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC56E667A65D243EC80F0064BE042700C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Communications site</header><text>The term <term>communications site</term> means an area of Federal lands designated or approved for communications use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C6F230A04734F0EAA4E206B781F2428"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Communications use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>communications use</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HA7D5F9A51A10444094B99ACAD5DB1C94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means the placement, operation, or both, of infrastructure for wireline or wireless telecommunications, including cable television, television, and radio communications, regardless of whether such placement or operation is pursuant to a license issued by the Federal Communications Commission or on an unlicensed basis in accordance with the regulations of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57E9707AF0D64FB3A3A3F10FD2B69D85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes ancillary activities, uses, or facilities directly related to such placement or operation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10DAFD0630F744059317CD42FA7672DA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Communications use authorization</header><text>The term <term>communications use authorization</term> means a right-of-way, permit, or lease granted, issued, or executed by a Federal land management agency for the primary purpose of authorizing the occupancy and use of Federal lands for communications use.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94E86868F7D941B582C667DF59861048"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal lands</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal lands</term> means lands under the jurisdiction and management of a Federal land management agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H510CE9E8A3544ACB9DBF10C3016D0022"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Federal land management agency</header><text>The term <term>Federal land management agency</term> means the National Park Service, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, the Bureau of Land Management, and the Bureau of Reclamation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD791CBFF58484012B8EFD9E50558BBF4" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rental fee</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rental fee</term> means a fee collected by a Federal land management agency for the occupancy and use authorized by a communications use authorization pursuant to and consistent with authorizing law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HE8FF04E9355B481DB35E7CBED200780D"><enum>3.</enum><header>Collection and retention of rental fees associated with communications use authorizations on Federal lands and Federal land management agency support for communications site programs</header><subsection id="H842CE8E130DD480AA0E78C45D365BB46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Special account required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall establish a special account in the Treasury for each Federal land management agency for the deposit of rental fees received by the Federal land management agency pursuant to this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H605B093F765F462FBBA42F8151281433"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fair Market Value</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any rental fee collected pursuant to this Act shall be of a fair market value with respect to other uses of the communications site.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2822DAB628044A6B9D64A47E2FA58FEB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rental fees</header><paragraph id="HCEC82E7A84954E12A0348B1ED79D3C4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Limitation on amount of rental fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rental fees shall not exceed the fee schedules published by the Secretary of the Interior for communications use rights-of-way or the fair market value under subsection (b), whichever is greater.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H815200BBA21A40E69DD9F48573453742"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Revision of rental fee schedules for communications sites rights-of-way</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, through a public process that includes consideration of industry comments, the Secretary of the Interior shall revise the communications sites rights-of-way rental fee schedule to reflect fair market value and current communications technologies, including the physical footprint of such technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6914AF6E414D49FAB3A2C1C28927C3BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deposit and retention of rental fees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Rental fees received by a Federal land management agency shall—</text><paragraph id="H14F2519CA5C54F2381AF622D28D7BEBB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be deposited in the special account established for that Federal land management agency under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFD377C3C7B84943A91F48393D5538D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">remain available for expenditure under subsection (e), to the extent and in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HE3536EC84A354AC298DF9526690B8E80"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Expenditure of retained fees</header><text>Amounts deposited in the special account for a Federal land management agency pursuant to this Act shall be used solely by that Federal land management agency for activities related to communications sites on lands managed by that Federal land management agency, including the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H2DDE193F98824F09A1CF77F5044328A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Administering communications use authorizations, including cooperative agreements under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H07AEFCE2EE684417A9E6F79A39C11D94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Preparing needs assessments or other programmatic analyses necessary to establish communications sites and authorize communications uses on or adjacent to Federal lands managed by that Federal land management agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1D877435740C44F8B63E17B032914A1A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Developing management plans for communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands managed by that Federal land management agency on a competitively neutral, technology neutral, nondiscriminatory basis.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H2D0C380E02A2442E91B84351EA833CEC"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Training for management of communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands managed by that Federal land management agency. </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6AE939357E2F48D0B2AE153395C52DD9"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Obtaining, improving access to, or establishing communications sites on or adjacent to Federal lands managed by that Federal land management agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H71A10D84F13740AEBD181F5E4FBE798A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No effect on other fee retention authorities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act shall not limit or otherwise affect fee retention by a Federal land management agency under any other authority.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBA2F276D6111452CB7DC33AF659326AF"><enum>4.</enum><header>Cooperative agreement authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the activities described in section 3(e).</text></section><section id="H34BB8534AC2D44378499F12EAAD5738F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Clarification of cooperative agreement authority of the Secretary of Agriculture</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8705(f) of the Agriculture Improvement Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1761a">43 U.S.C. 1761a(f)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H33F49C4BDE6C42FC8E73111F35E227B3" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H713B0665B9BE4F0B978A056E3259EDA3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Cooperative agreement authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements to carry out the activities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D) of paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

