<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H280C66B484F14901AEC101D1795B9993" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6448 EH: Invest to Protect Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6448</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Director of the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice to carry out a grant program to provide assistance to police departments with fewer than 200 law enforcement officers, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HCE4B9D3653ED48ECADE84936AABECA25" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H862C06DFC5A5466FB945C2598F4A9C64" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Invest to Protect Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7D19C9BC527F4250ADCBD149121966ED"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program</header> <subsection id="H73BB31DEE13B490B9185EF3388675068"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text> 
<paragraph id="H0BB2BAD9CCD94118A413CBA06AD8F2EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>De-escalation training</header><text>The term <term>de-escalation training</term> means training relating to taking action or communicating verbally or non-verbally during a potential force encounter in an attempt to stabilize the situation so that more time, options, and resources can be called upon to minimize the need for the use of force and increase the likelihood of voluntary compliance, including persuasion, warnings, creating space, use of physical barriers, slowing down the pace of an incident, and requesting additional resources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H651E7CE325364BD688536930AFAB07B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFEB665B875734496A577DC057E84AC0F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible local government</header><text>The term <term>eligible local government</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H77572A2F8B0D44CBB9D406A9B5044921"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a county, municipality, town, township, village, parish, borough, or other unit of general government below the State level that employs fewer than 125 law enforcement officers; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08351B0FA1384B3AB1BEE84A66C4A060"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a Tribal government that employs fewer than 125 law enforcement officers.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96EDBF86B33C475A81B393DAB75F86B9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Law enforcement officer</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement officer</term> has the meaning given the term <term>career law enforcement officer</term> in section 1709 of title I the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10389">34 U.S.C. 10389</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4AA43B8A07E74902BF0A8C16C8B90009"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Community Oriented Policing Services of the Department of Justice.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC33968BF286644B3B37AF6B332C69889"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established within the Office a grant program to—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB6DCF3AD097341EAA4F3A19454895847"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide training and access to mental health resources to local law enforcement officers; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H48080E1AB6A3420889B4636F986FFB4B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>improve the recruitment and retention of local law enforcement officers.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H893F3EC2A5144D3AACEAFE961336F990"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall award grants to eligible local governments as a part of the grant program established under subsection (b). </text></subsection> <subsection id="H4C50DE6F186243E6A0D00621C95ADBBA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header> <paragraph id="H200B6226B09A4D46B07739778032A411"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Barriers</header><text>The Attorney General shall determine what barriers exist to establishing a streamlined application process for grants under this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E893496A0C14736B7D5EC3B56F2ADB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFB4C2F8293A643C2AE82B4C8DED0E4B1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall submit to Congress a report that includes a plan to execute a streamlined application process for grants under this section under which an eligible local government seeking a grant under this section can reasonably complete the application in not more than 2 hours.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAC364268F9B84AB8836973C816BC1DA2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of plan</header><text>The plan required under subparagraph (A) may include a plan for—</text> 
<clause id="H1AB59D67DF394C51BB67A2657ED267EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>proactively providing eligible local governments seeking a grant under this section with information on the data such eligible local governments will need to prepare before beginning the grant application; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD78C1901C8724C4084BF4F86EE26B396"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensuring technical assistance is available for eligible local governments seeking a grant under this section before and during the grant application process, including through dedicated liaisons within the Office.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H48AE10B3348E4798B0DCF5EA417F1258"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>In selecting eligible local governments to receive grants under this section, the Director shall use the streamlined application process described in paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E775ABB245E4263AB36ADF7A9BCAD86"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Preference</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Attorney General may give preference to applicants who specify in their applications that grant amounts will be used for the eligible activities set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (9), and (10) of subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1A11F9F2AFE246289221D2B7B521BD3A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible activities</header><text>An eligible local government that receives a grant under this section may use amounts from the grant only for—</text> <paragraph id="H1E82EAE1FB6F471BBBB65648F707AC82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>de-escalation training for law enforcement officers;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D84176962264663A33573B63D97038A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>victim-centered training for law enforcement officers in handling situations of domestic violence; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H01AD2F0A8781449C8A5ED897C652938D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evidence-based law enforcement safety training for response to calls for service involving—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H4EE0B6B87F6E4274835C5235EFF7DE7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>persons with substance use disorders;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H226DC5FC1EF44D2EA8789896F42DEA74"><enum>(B)</enum><text>persons with mental health needs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCAC4AA53E6E448B89C9EE3D31DE28A38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>veterans;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5245EDFFC2DD461C920718180D20F7D4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>persons with disabilities;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2A1157089CB24BA48DE88279BA624A5E"><enum>(E)</enum><text>vulnerable youth;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC59F56FF2C094D7AAD333D5F793086F8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>persons who are victims of domestic violence, sexual assault, or trafficking; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H801E7731690B45C2A268DED15A766056"><enum>(G)</enum><text>persons experiencing homelessness or living in poverty;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6E9ADA41E947450F9530B2119C26F8D9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the offsetting of overtime costs associated with scheduling issues relating to the participation of a law enforcement officer in the training described in paragraphs (1) through (3), (9) and (10);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCA393046C5F14F3F91C4D4880BA5594A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a signing bonus for a law enforcement officer in an amount determined by the eligible local government;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA8BC1DB2B724497968A91F107902D57"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a retention bonus for a law enforcement officer—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H843FC1FF3F734A3DBEE5650FC2168094"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in an amount determined by the eligible local government that does not exceed 20 percent of the salary of the law enforcement officer; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE66781697FED4A73923B2CD46E54BC5E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who—</text> 
<clause id="H23B0143C63FF490997FD3FDB8845E51D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been employed at the law enforcement agency for not fewer than 5 years;</text></clause> <clause id="HC024C4A3315C41D7BBA3C7B8609559E8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has not been found by an internal investigation to have engaged in serious misconduct; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HAA57D4C7ED734ADCB978F89E665AD713"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>commits to remain with the law enforcement agency for a minimum 3 years from the time of receipt of the bonus;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F050B9A58914CA4AFEC95D5451BF1B2"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a stipend for the graduate education of law enforcement officers in the area of mental health, public health, or social work, which shall not exceed the lesser of—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H90EF83F625AB4BA8A8FD5ED215FD033B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFE1FA21FF8A44021911A4A3C61C7B3B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount the law enforcement officer pays towards such graduate education;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4EF236DEDABE4891B806D280605D92BA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>providing access to patient-centered behavioral health services for law enforcement officers, which may include resources for risk assessments, evidence-based, trauma-informed care to treat post-traumatic stress disorder or acute stress disorder, peer support and counselor services and family supports, and the promotion of improved access to high quality mental health care through telehealth;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H306F2F6949D24082B78DA73D00CB7A36"><enum>(9)</enum><text>implementation of evidence-based best practices and training on the use of lethal and nonlethal force;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFE9E173B50314C94B16B8A7B1F1EA7DF"><enum>(10)</enum><text>implementation of evidence-based best practices and training on the duty of care and the duty to intervene; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B423224273C4BB5B59290E4CF20EFE7"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data collection for police practices regarding officer and community safety.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE191C445438A4928BC06F22C5BD7B10F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting requirements for grant recipients</header> 
<paragraph id="HB0E39418D6434671AE679F3C62371EE3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director shall establish reporting requirements for eligible local government that receive a grant under this section in order to assist with the evaluation by the Office of the program established under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE90A169EE3BB484B97FBDBE086D1ADBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In establishing any requirements under paragraph (1), the Director shall consider the capacity of law enforcement agencies with fewer than 125 officers to collect and report information.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB189A417ED5D49F8B72661019C5134E7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Disclosure of officer recruitment and retention bonuses</header> 
<paragraph id="HC60A2EBE9CDD4808868272DE1670A66E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date on which an eligible local government that receives a grant under this section awards a signing or retention bonus described in paragraph (5) or (6) of subsection (e), the eligible local government shall disclose to the Director and make publicly available on a website of the eligible local government the amount of such bonus.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9AEC66C86F004B759919751BF3E5A5AC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Attorney General shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees an annual report that includes each signing or retention bonus disclosed under paragraph (1) during the preceding year.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF3D62672DC444558A473181F91C5F885"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Grant accountability</header><text>All grants awarded by the Director under this section shall be subject to the following accountability provisions:</text> <paragraph id="H45ECF1C74B534A44AD628F91B059D473"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audit requirement</header> <subparagraph id="H62AC542FEAD64892B3B40CB06A913435"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>unresolved audit finding</term> means a finding in the final audit report of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice that the audited grantee has used grant funds for an unauthorized expenditure or otherwise unallowable cost that is not closed or resolved within 12 months from the date when the final audit report is issued.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0CA6E4FF5C774D33BFEE83203BAD1BC1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year beginning after the date of enactment of this subsection, and in each fiscal year thereafter, the Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall conduct audits of recipients of grants under this section to prevent waste, fraud, and abuse of funds by grantees. The Inspector General of the Department of Justice shall determine the appropriate number of grantees to be audited each year.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8A43E963AF0A4FE7AC87F5AF0785122E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mandatory exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A recipient of grant funds under this section that is found to have an unresolved audit finding shall not be eligible to receive grant funds under this section during the first 3 fiscal years beginning after the end of the 12-month period described in subparagraph (A). </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC065146FC3054EBB9D50401674C97616"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Reimbursement</header><text>If an eligible local government is awarded grant funds under this section during the 3-fiscal-year period during which the eligible local government is barred from receiving grants under subparagraph (C), the Attorney General shall—</text> <clause id="H9AA35E34634C415A87DA35D7F4ABBAB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>deposit an amount equal to the amount of the grant funds that were improperly awarded to the grantee into the General Fund of the Treasury; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H474EAACDDABE42EA9527C875C1170A79"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>seek to recoup the costs of the repayment to the fund from the grant recipient that was erroneously awarded grant funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB6147F574B074CE4A2F1EF5F7C561623"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual certification</header><text>Beginning in the fiscal year during which audits commence under paragraph (1)(B), the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives an annual certification—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H11249C7E3C7F447DB82B4C3938999086"><enum>(A)</enum><text>indicating whether—</text> <clause id="H87BEC16CB6EE485795BD34F521AB1B3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all audits issued by the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Justice under paragraph (1) have been completed and reviewed by the appropriate Assistant Attorney General or Director;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H83483E622EF0454CAB1AA278E3CC2D1B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all mandatory exclusions required under paragraph (1)(C) have been issued; and</text></clause> <clause id="H5CC372A3F4D842CCA6DCAE2257012157"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>all reimbursements required under paragraph (1)(E) have been made; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2CF5AFD1F37843308F64A277B4AED1B7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that includes a list of any grant recipients excluded under paragraph (1) from the previous year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H8389C7CF6F3E4545BED50112EF503585"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Program evaluation</header><text>The Attorney General shall, on an annual basis, conduct analyses of the information provided by grant recipients pursuant to subsection (f) to evaluate the efficacy of training programs funded through the grant program established by this Act in reducing the incidence of use of force by the law enforcement agency.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H71FCD6ADA334492CA131FC78882FCEEE"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Preventing duplicative grants</header> 
<paragraph id="H0424FCD622C74791A89C6C4703E8175B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Before the Director awards a grant to an eligible local government under this section, the Attorney General shall compare potential grant awards with other grants awarded by the Attorney General to determine if grant awards are or have been awarded for a similar purpose. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H65393DECD3124AF2959AD1D89B0362B0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>If the Attorney General awards grants to the same applicant for a similar purpose, whether through the grant program established by this Act or other grant programs provided by the Department of Justice, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate and the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE5DBF6AEACCC4B4C98ABF176967A5792"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a list of all such grants awarded, including the total dollar amount of any such grants awarded; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE608FEBFF9FD4D98B1C15210D3450185"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the reason the Attorney General awarded multiple grants to the same applicant for a similar purpose.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB82062BE7B924EEDA75FE845FE67B76F"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Funding</header> 
<paragraph id="HFA7C86688A914B3D8BE1D4AF67F50BD4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $60,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to carry out the grant program under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5D70BC0BE640482ABF390F363B4A299D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section for a fiscal year, if the amounts made available in appropriations Acts for that fiscal year is not less than the amount authorized to be appropriated under paragraph (1), the Director shall use not less than 20 percent of such amounts in that fiscal year for grants under this section to eligible local governments that will use the grants to carry out one or more of the eligible activities set forth in paragraphs (1), (2), (3), (4), (9), and (10) of subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220922" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 22, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


