<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF910D1E6BCDF4639B32155D0B8C79DA0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8898 IH: To require the Comptroller General of the United States to assess the efforts of the Secretary of Defense with respect to the National Defense Stockpile, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8898</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to assess the efforts of the Secretary of Defense with respect to the National Defense Stockpile, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H64B7A8596FDA4194B999D74301C3155D" style="OLC"><section id="H9C4F72EBD37C491D801DF51BA6AEA642" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>National defense stockpile assessment</header><subsection id="H886C1AA59C9A43B19C0970C0410A0B2F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than April 1, 2023, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report assessing the efforts of the Secretary of Defense with respect to the National Defense Stockpile, including—</text><paragraph id="HB4FA45B0E200416EBBCB5F05F0599F32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the assumptions used by the Secretary to make the recommendations with respect to the requirements of the National Defense Stockpile in the most recent report submitted under section 14 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98h-5">50 U.S.C. 98h–5</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9F307ADDC784847A7D24037D4145CEF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the extent to which the Secretary has assessed whether the reserves of strategic and critical materials that are contained in the National Defense Stockpile reduce the dependence of the United States on foreign sources or single sources for supplies of such strategic and critical materials in times of national emergency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H843C29AFFE604334AEEF9A46D6AF2D8A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the risks identified by the Secretary of Defense arising from insufficient reserves of certain strategic and critical materials in the National Defense Stockpile; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H629658B9DCFC4DBB937020E6E437264E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for improvements with respect to the items described in paragraphs (1), (2), and (3).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AB8CF2A965E4C21A52BA898809CD444"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text>Not later than April 30, 2023, the Comptroller General shall provide to the Committee On Armed Services of the House of Representatives a briefing on the findings and recommendations of the report required by subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H10883266913345D895EF089055093282"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H193180C89E674B5CB20FE4091F3E07AD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>National emergency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>national emergency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 12 of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98h-3">50 U.S.C. 98h–3</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8F4807F3DFA4D219DE39F6BD733B59E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Strategic and critical material</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>strategic and critical materials</term> means a material determined to be strategic and critical material by the President pursuant to section 3(a) of the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/98b">50 U.S.C. 98b(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

