<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Received-in-Senate" dms-id="HA04271D480FE42549A5D2C054B8D7E54" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 8656 : To designate the clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Mishawaka, Indiana, as the “Jackie Walorski VA Clinic”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num>H. R. 8656</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20220906">September 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received</action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Mishawaka, Indiana, as the <quote>Jackie Walorski VA Clinic</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8F98DC4E0A0448F284457005C91FDBC4" style="OLC"><pagebreak></pagebreak><section id="HEE0FC069B4224B4C8BA8519F89C26BE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H6F806E2DBD204F62B813F9243A4245F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Jackie Walorski was born August 17, 1963, in South Bend, Indiana.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B407D38C7874A5BB1DCDDA87A604482"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Jackie Walorski grew up in South Bend raised by her parents, Martha, who worked at a local grocery store, and Raymond, an Air Force veteran and firefighter who owned an appliance store.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A76C792A1B8473ABF98FC84B4471B6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Jackie Walorski graduated from James Whitcomb Riley High School in 1981 and is an alumna of Taylor University.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A96BE1A06434DF591E1EBEF8C666BEB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Upon her graduation, Jackie Walorski worked as a reporter for a television station in South Bend and later worked for local chapters of the Humane Society and Chamber of Commerce as well as served as a development officer for area universities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4881CF79C50B4174A208B29242567D1B"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2000, she and her husband Dean Swihart moved to Romania and founded Impact International, a nonprofit foundation that provided medical supplies and attention to impoverished children while they served as missionaries there for four years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H852DB344A91C4A21999CA203402FB1BD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2004, she was elected to the Indiana House of Representatives and subsequently reelected to that office every two years where she served three full terms in office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2231EAC699E44869467F34D07B40B2F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>In 2012, she was elected to the United States House of Representatives and subsequently reelected to that office until her death in a tragic car accident in 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCA9B5F95E69417DB7BE9282199C5749"><enum>(8)</enum><text>During her service in the United States House of Representatives, she was a passionate advocate for all her constituents, but especially veterans in the area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F1CBB0A5EB14A9090C65DA4450AF49F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>During her service in the United States House of Representatives, she served on the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs for two terms, during that time authoring the Veterans Mobility Safety Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/256">Public Law 114–256</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47FF015C9FF34248AB0DF432886E4723"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 2017, through her persistent advocacy for area veterans, the Department of Veterans Affairs completed construction of a medical clinic in St. Joseph County, Indiana, to meet the needs of Michiana area veterans.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H44251EF5EC06418B9FD57CDE1705D0F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of Jackie Walorski Department of Veterans Affairs Clinic</header><subsection id="HAC61B5A3CDF64FE7ABB9EDF60C7CF372"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The clinic of the Department of Veterans Affairs located in Mishawaka, Indiana, shall after the date of the enactment of this Act be known and designated as the <quote>Jackie Walorski VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9064801DE9C045EAA76476953EE7BFC3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>References</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the clinic referred to in subsection (a) shall be considered to be a reference to the <quote>Jackie Walorski VA Clinic</quote>.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220812" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives August 12, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

