<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42A8FC5333FA47EB9966C265A0F7A473" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8476 IH: Housing Inspections Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8476</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretaries of Housing and Urban Development and Agriculture to submit annual reports to the Congress regarding dwelling units in assisted housing that fail property inspections, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H956504C04B40461585AC4F20A317DBB9" style="OLC"><section id="HD004ACAFF3F346F99E4B48785B501FB2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Housing Inspections Accountability Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7FF83E778937450487A7D07C59EA9497"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual reports and database regarding failed inspections</header><subsection id="H1F41AEDFEDCD4E7DB643CA8521FDCDBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H93A7B13156344E0A9C7EEF7B1DBBC42F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Secretary of Agriculture shall jointly submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report—</text><subparagraph id="H34355DB66A764100A6152E5C579DFF40"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifying—</text><clause id="HD6E7CF3BB42240CDA401B31DB9871E28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all inspections of covered properties conducted during the preceding 12 months that resulted in a failing or unsatisfactory score for the property;</text></clause><clause id="HE34358AD88AE4EE9B964F0E929ADE7D0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the program under which such property was assisted at the time of the inspection;</text></clause><clause id="H6C4F7101140F493DAC0F1D3719ED30CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the defects and violations identified by the inspection and the status of remediation with respect to such defects and violations;</text></clause><clause id="H79B134B5DBB94CC38F3580F6BB46C023"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the number of households in such properties on waiting lists to be moved to a different unit, the reasons they need a different unit, the duration that they have been on such a waiting list, and the typical duration before a household on such a waiting list is moved to a different unit or property; and</text></clause><clause id="H9AD9F7FB898F4D51AE2D80A2A49C34D2"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of covered properties with a failing score that have requested an appeal and the share of covered properties that were granted an appeal; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1EA11CD79754B478F4D16767DBE8D06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>including such other information that either such Secretary considers relevant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90C06EBF76204C6881EA58403EA7B99E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each Secretary identified in paragraph (1) shall make the reports submitted pursuant to such paragraph publicly available online and shall ensure that the reports do not include any personally identifiable information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03215DB0D0CD4AF78E6AA1C01D0BBD17"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>covered property</quote> means any housing project that is provided rental assistance under a rental assistance program administered by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development or the Secretary of Agriculture.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA20B98DD10B84077A970CDC4B7640998"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Database</header><paragraph id="HB5836D36CDE24EE797D8BBFCE8441A7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 12-month period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretaries identified in subsection (a)(1) shall jointly develop, and make publicly available online, a searchable database that enables the public to search, find, and download data regarding the inspection status and scores of individual housing projects provided rental assistance under a rental assistance program administered by either such Secretary, information regarding defects identified in individual housing projects, and information regarding whether such defects have been resolved.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA82173C3C83D4839A03089488D7830E6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updating</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretaries identified in subsection (a)(1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H3500566AFF6A44E99E4A50E0E0D02AB0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>update the information in the database developed pursuant to paragraph (1) regularly to reflect current information regarding the status and inspection scores for individual housing projects; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H745540846A674C6FBDA2A24C0221D66E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that the database is updated with any newly determined score for a project not later than 30 days after such score is determined.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EE4339AFE0F4DEDA3A3CFAF60FC878C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text>The database developed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall not make available any personally identifiable information.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

