<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9F0FE1D3FCFD4BE1876C47D5A11B0499" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7594 IH: Too Narrow to Succeed Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7594</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220427">April 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve access for diverse-owned asset management firms, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3EA9658ACE034E7680B40256CCC98AE5" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HEC6E3DCD882048248B6BF5BD08C99854"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Too Narrow to Succeed Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1A8708ABCAB34AB59555E2353A66307A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to improve access for diverse-owned, including women- and minority-owned, asset management firms by—</text><paragraph id="HC02A3A0F0D7F46D28467787C7DC9FDD8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing transparency regarding the asset management firm selection processes of Federal institutional investors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H615DF5052F014AEEB5EF9BA07495ED63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifying common and potential barriers that limit business opportunities for diverse-owned asset management firms and developing strategies to remove these barriers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8015CFD3F2F048FD9B633166A594EB3B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>enabling both public and private retirement funds to adopt broader and more inclusive selection processes to reduce systemic risk and maximize returns, consistent with administrators’ fiduciary responsibilities. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HB1910E8B241D4691878CD8BBB0EEF4A9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB99B8993C66E4B2C8F919074E47A4131"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset management firm</header><text>The term <term>asset management firm</term> means any investment firm that—</text><subparagraph id="HE2E836AD98E14DCBB5B08B9A0A42EC7E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>manages a portfolio of securities or other assets for a defined benefit plan or other institutional investor; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8052C8A790B44FD88B6DA4F0870C65CA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offers investment options, such as mutual, private equity, real estate, or other commingled funds, to participate in a defined contribution or other comparable retirement plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E00153D19964C36A144103C269E0E90"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diverse-owned</header><text>The term <term>diverse-owned</term>, when used with respect to an asset management firm, means any threshold or other requirements determined appropriate by the Secretary under section 4(a)(3).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98F86A43EAC040B6BF6B19AA9720B909"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal institutional investor</header><text>The term <term>Federal institutional investor</term> means each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H5BB770687F844E14A3D2E3C1A96F6381" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Board.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBFCD8100CEAD4318B653F46F6D76D50D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The entity that administers—</text><clause id="H6C13D25B5C214CCB8C83EF8434A45B99"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the funds of the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation established under section 4005 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1305">29 U.S.C. 1305</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H2C100F63D4DC47869205C687418D5002"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the funds of the National Railroad Retirement Investment Trust established under section 15(j) of the Railroad Retirement Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/231n">45 U.S.C. 231n(j)</external-xref>); </text></clause><clause id="HC0E7177116F54B0980322B62E92E11AE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the funds of the Federal Reserve System Retirement Plan;</text></clause><clause id="H193FE90726C94E0E843D5DA37B309CBA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the funds of the Federal Reserve System Thrift Plan;</text></clause><clause id="HA2F087E6C55D4B8E8CD36BDED3016D57"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the funds of the Tennessee Valley Authority Retirement System;</text></clause><clause id="H6503304AF126440BB6D0D140A8F48077"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the funds of the Tennessee Valley Authority Retirement System Savings and Deferral Retirement Plan;</text></clause><clause id="H39D20514EF394995914647F181888BDB"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the funds of the Army and Air Force Exchange Service Retirement System;</text></clause><clause id="H03D01429E53C4FAABC1AC187189A4E82"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the funds of the Navy Exchange Service Command Retirement Plan; or</text></clause><clause id="H801DE8D0114D42848AB00DA7B88AAE1C"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>the endowment funds of the Smithsonian Institution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BFBA1D098C44B11B5325A7377EEEDB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any other Federal entity that administers a fund—</text><clause id="HF8CEED777FF442C482ECA2D65ED02EB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with more than $1,000,000,000 in assets invested for which the entity uses the services of, or contracts with, an asset management firm; and</text></clause><clause id="H92C66160C5E34C2E8BD97400FF173E52"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that the Secretary determines is similar to the Thrift Savings Fund or a fund described in subparagraph (B). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CD7D97AC6414F788DCE2A6CEF73838D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal investments</header><text>The term <term>Federal investments</term> means investments of sums in a fund administered by a Federal institutional investor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD11E0F4D5E55472E892A428CFCBA270D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF2AF89CD67948FFABB617952FAED62E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Subcontractor asset management firm</header><text>The term <term>subcontractor asset management firm</term> means an asset management firm that—</text><subparagraph id="H40748FEB311D44C1A855BD8829C1C386"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enters into a contract (including a subcontract) with an asset management firm that is the primary manager of Federal investments, through the use of services or by contract, for a Federal institutional investor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD804BF74710B45F1A0FA3A8D62EB5A28"><enum>(B)</enum><text>under the terms of the contract, manages Federal investments of the Federal institutional investor. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HBB58E80EE5534CF6B6F16DCF3E46C58A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improving access for diverse-owned asset management firms</header><subsection id="H2E9DAF4185904D32A721D3913FB9F2BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual reports by Federal institutional investors that invest in externally managed assets</header><paragraph id="HC9CC44E8CBCD4E76BE236C5F73A44BB5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><subparagraph id="H112D06DED70D4BA9A0992CE9C7B9A9EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reports required</header><text>By not later than December 31, 2022, and annually thereafter, each Federal institutional investor that uses the services of, or contracts with, an asset management firm to manage Federal investments shall prepare and submit a report to the Secretary on the usage of diverse-owned asset management firms by the Federal institutional investor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H476E4A8577E34522825FA47E8F74008B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of subcontractor asset management firms</header><text>The report under subparagraph (A) shall also include all subcontractor asset management firms of the Federal institutional investor. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7C334742234415EA7FD67095607CB96"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Content of reports</header><text>Each report described in paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to any fund administered by the Federal institutional investor that uses the services of, or contracts with, an asset management firm—</text><subparagraph id="HD88C7BA8332646E59FC36B4A2AF008DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amounts of assets in such fund that are managed by non-diverse-owned asset management firms and by diverse-owned asset management firms, as determined by the Secretary under paragraph (3), disaggregated by race, ethnicity, and gender;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8E27F6ECB8246CF91449ACCB48C5FB0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the challenges, if any, the Federal institutional investor faces in reporting on diverse-owned and non-diverse-owned asset management firms;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE1809F0E567444485DB1DCBAE1985D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the challenges the Federal institutional investor faces in selecting diverse-owned asset management firms (including through subcontractor asset management firms) to manage investments of sums in the fund administered by the Federal institutional investor;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD88B307BF9544CFB9DD1481AADF91AF2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the actions taken during the reporting period, or planned to be taken, by the Federal institutional investor to alleviate barriers that limit participation of diverse-owned asset management firms; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCAEDBFA1F2446EE952A30F201599DAD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the actions taken during the reporting period, or planned to be taken, by the Federal institutional investor to increase opportunities for diverse-owned asset management firms to compete for contracts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69362E935CAE4C03BA5FE7082D7ECE35"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Diverse-owned</header><text>The Secretary shall evaluate industry benchmarks to determine the threshold or other requirements necessary for an asset management firm to qualify as diverse-owned.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDCF7641A79E46AA803C8F2BD14EBFA4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make each report submitted under paragraph (1) publicly available.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5A83822C84884BF981BF87B552AFD39A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress relating to diverse-Owned asset management firms and covered private sector plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Advisory Council on Employee Welfare and Pension Benefit Plans (commonly known as the <term>ERISA Advisory Council</term>) routinely consider barriers to the usage of diverse-owned asset management firms among covered private sector plans, and methods to overcome such barriers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D07059AE2A34E29AE4BBA3EF2552ED4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey of fund management best practices</header><paragraph id="HFF1819AFA6E3421886F15D7E698215AC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="H651DAB4190374AA0BEA8B98B75C090AB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct a survey of the best practices in fund asset management with respect to increasing the utilization and capacity of diverse-owned asset management firms; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H18B897A3BC334ADAAD84670731172813"><enum>(B)</enum><text>prepare and submit a report to Congress not less often than every 3 years, or more frequently as the Secretary considers to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA82A34F7EC84173BD7B0DDEC5374BD8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements of survey</header><text>The Secretary shall survey a sample of public and private-sector pension plans subject to the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) and other retirement funds that are engaged in (or looking to engage in) strategies to improve access to, and representation by, diverse-owned asset management firms. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2067CFB898AF45E0B9B03DE8072AE9E5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary shall make publicly available a report to Congress on the best practices of pension funds and other retirement funds with respect to implementing strategies to improve access to diverse-owned asset management firms. The report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HC8B7FDB9A59F434FA7E1BD31A044C201"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the challenges pension funds and other retirement funds may face in adopting or executing strategies to engage more with diverse-owned asset management firms as the primary institutional fund manager or as subcontractor asset management firms, including women- and minority-owned asset management firms; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AAEC72A8B3C4A5AB6E44A9FF2B82EC2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an identification of the strategies adopted to implement programs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

