<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA851B50972DA4B1896F2952FACA81BD3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7649 IH: To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to open a public docket for the submission of public comments regarding factors that should be taken into consideration when reviewing a proposed modification to an approved risk evaluation and mitigation strategy, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7649</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to open a public docket for the submission of public comments regarding factors that should be taken into consideration when reviewing a proposed modification to an approved risk evaluation and mitigation strategy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB92C132A8B894889AFD8F2AED728E9CA" style="OLC"><section id="H4961AC4EA2D344D7828551B88B5110B1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Public docket on proposed modifications to approved strategies</header><subsection id="H284048B91ECB4E8B9E779BE34987F670"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall open a public docket<italic></italic> for the submission of public comments regarding factors that should be taken into consideration when a proposed modification to an approved risk evaluation and mitigation strategy is reviewed under section 505–1(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/255-1">21 U.S.C. 255–1(h)</external-xref>), including factors related to patient access to the drug that is the subject of the strategy and provider administration. The Secretary may close such public docket not earlier than 90 days after such docket is opened.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA4320BBF5AC0415383D2A820BD926B06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2026, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on—</text><paragraph id="H36455C99718241E48C7675EEBB23408C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of proposed modifications to an approved risk evaluation and mitigation strategy the Secretary has granted under section 505–1(h) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/255-1">21 U.S.C. 255–1(h)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF076A4428452456DB893BBAB434B83DD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any issues affecting patient access to the drug that is the subject of the strategy or provider administration that arose as a result of such modifications; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD4A0DB0696447AAA6627190E13D494E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>how such issues were resolved, as applicable.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

