<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H52E2B6F424294A9E9B07EB5B9ADFF5DF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6755 IH: Cooperation Among Police, Tech, and Users to Resist Exploitation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6755</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Comptroller General of the United States to submit to Congress a report on big tech and law enforcement, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7F03EFC9012E4E3CAD30D0F85962EE85" style="OLC"><section id="HFECF0029616C42F1BF39CE2C0C57C724" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Cooperation Among Police, Tech, and Users to Resist Exploitation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CAPTURE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA68E4061B42E49359C93261095E3EBA2"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study and report on big tech and law enforcement</header><subsection id="H2A202BD5C057438B9890D9F5E882584C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall complete a study on the following:</text><paragraph id="H86B43F4844A44B44A2B3B1442B2B853A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>How social media companies currently communicate, consult, and coordinate with Federal, State, and local law enforcement to address illegal content and activity online.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBE9E8A04A0448908DB0913AD1A792BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Document successes and failures by social media companies in cooperating with Federal, State, and local law enforcement agencies in events of imminent injury or death to individuals.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD9009587C704CDAA5C005EDD2C355B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Ways in which social media companies can better communicate, consult, and coordinate with Federal, State, and local law enforcement to address illegal content and activity online.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3190028C49AB4179B0406E528AF05C03"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress required</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report that contains—</text><paragraph id="H63BE03256C814D9C8B2108CEA2A43DB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the results of the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A9369F54332488FA0BE62022A8E84FA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations to—</text><subparagraph id="H3AD465D7669946FE975AD45F01B2CE81"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop legislation that may assist social media companies to better communicate, consult, and coordinate with Federal, State, and local law enforcement to address illegal content and activity online; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E24070CCBBF47A8ABE7F5DE808CA248"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require social media companies to establish a single point of contact in every State for Federal, State, and local law enforcement entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

