<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3655595EE87A4AB1A557B0168216873C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8908 IH: Fighting Stimulant and other Substance Use Disorders Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8908</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220920">September 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services to review a safe harbor under the anti-kickback statute for certain contingency management interventions, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6FD765DEF9744BF483A0750C3082A839" style="OLC"><section id="H18382DFD93394C1B9929792EA1C649F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fighting Stimulant and other Substance Use Disorders Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H5B95DB314BB941C3A11E95E1BCC14E9E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Review of safe harbor under the anti-kickback statute for certain contingency management interventions</header><subsection id="H07E678ABF1B54ADAA1B4CF6FAB6BC670"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1128D(a) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1320a–7d(a)) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2B8A6467EAF04345A6D718E51F781525" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6208283FDDD7481A94E616A6E2854DB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Review of safe harbor for certain contingency management interventions</header><subparagraph id="HF47E012900B548FD9C6EF0DD21E1B4B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Pursuant to the final rule titled <quote>Medicare and State Health Care Programs: Fraud and Abuse; Revisions to Safe Harbors Under the Anti-Kickback Statute, and Civil Monetary Penalty Rules Regarding Beneficiary Inducements</quote> and published in the Federal Register on December 2, 2020 (85 Fed. Reg. 77684), not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall conduct a review on whether to establish a safe harbor described in paragraph (1)(A)(ii) for evidence-based contingency management incentives and the parameters for such a safe harbor. In conducting the review under the previous sentence, the Secretary shall consider the extent to which providing such a safe harbor for evidence-based contingency management incentives may result in any of the factors described in paragraph (2).</text><clause id="H44AB4BD3FE4343868755E53E87A851AC" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, the Secretary and the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress recommendations, including based on the review conducted under subparagraph (A), for improving access to evidence-based contingency management interventions while ensuring quality of care, ensuring fidelity to evidence-based practices, and including strong program integrity safeguards that prevent increased waste, fraud, and abuse and prevent medically unnecessary or inappropriate items or services reimbursed in whole or in part by a Federal health care program. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

