<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6CD6EDB1E29A485A9675B8A522962A7B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7702 IH: Ensuring Lasting Smiles Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7702</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000568">Mr. Griffith</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide health insurance benefits for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6CB287BBB3994841A9FE6EAF1D291ABA" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H2104C7220C074533B67431BC89FD2706"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Lasting Smiles Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD603C74C89BC4732AED16E9664B4938D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Coverage of craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect</header> <subsection id="HAC30BE4390CF4A8AA8A1C0C5C982C123"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Public Health Service Act Amendments</header><text>Part D of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C6E3BC44E0B45679C5B5A8D47633723">
<section id="H1B0A85CB0DE441EFB46B296CB4304033"><enum>2799A–11.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect</header>
<subsection id="HA35C5AE125BC42FD9F6426D250A1A8CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for care and Reconstructive Treatment</header>
<paragraph id="HEB29E454FA0049BF96AEB0D2B6014967"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, shall provide coverage for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0639A108480847F1AB9731CFAD9A11E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <subparagraph id="HC90C914A96E54970BA85C03EFB7E240D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage provided under paragraph (1) shall include any medically necessary item or service to functionally improve, repair, or restore any body part to achieve normal body functioning or appearance, as determined by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), due to craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H998394AD63244EA5B673692440BF61F9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financial requirements and treatment requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any coverage provided under paragraph (1) under a group health plan or individual or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer may be subject to coverage limits (such as medical necessity, pre-authorization, or pre-certification) and cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required by the plan or issuer, that are no more restrictive than the predominant coverage limits and cost-sharing requirements, respectively, applied to substantially all medical and surgical benefits covered by the plan (or coverage).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD0FE9389EF8345E999762EE60E81148F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<subparagraph id="H3168BF98E4F84DC6ACA24B146E3831AC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>treatment</term> includes, with respect to a group health plan or group or individual health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer, inpatient and outpatient items and services performed to improve, repair, or restore bodily function (or performed to approximate a normal appearance), due to a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect, and includes treatment to any and all missing or abnormal body parts (including teeth, the oral cavity, and their associated structures) that would otherwise be provided under the plan or coverage for any other injury or sickness, including—</text> <clause id="H22EA725B13D242568699A20AFC4CD31F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any items or services, including inpatient and outpatient care, reconstructive services and procedures, and complications thereof;</text></clause>
<clause id="H5ECCA36E98AA43EF922C9FB3C3BD83C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjunctive dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic support from birth until the medical or surgical treatment of the defect or anomaly has been completed, including ongoing or subsequent treatment required to maintain function or approximate a normal appearance;</text></clause> <clause id="H00AA16CD7DAE408EA40D0DBCF8A070EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures that materially improve, repair, or restore bodily function; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H077BCEE43549435C93C4320CEBF22E63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures for secondary conditions and follow-up treatment associated with the underlying craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H356F15353FAB4A7786C4A9DF8AF58360"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>treatment</term> shall not include cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H25F428C473444EB88B9778ED762937B2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, shall, in accordance with regulations or guidance issued by the Secretary, provide to each enrollee under such plan or coverage a written description of the terms of this section. Such description shall be in language which is understandable to the typical enrollee. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H4316D43F402949168E4C6D15CF7B4251"><enum>(b)</enum><header>ERISA amendments</header> <paragraph id="H2BD29E066B364152957B02DDD9EC77FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEBA46F7B39094BF8AF8B27A82CBCC614">
<section id="H8BA91D3B693242B1BAE4CE5FA022E7E3"><enum>726.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect</header>
<subsection id="H7DAB46C0DD1B4F45B21D81E57C85324F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for care and Reconstructive Treatment</header>
<paragraph id="H3B251FA483564E5DBA8FC807C8879CE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, shall provide coverage for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD4157177533B45559B988A190C9D622F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header> <subparagraph id="H86AE693452704E778C5ADE7E322F97FD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage provided under paragraph (1) shall include any medically necessary item or service to functionally improve, repair, or restore any body part to achieve normal body functioning or appearance, as determined by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), due to craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF257DCB419A5487387F7EC3CDF3B439D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financial requirements and treatment requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any coverage provided under paragraph (1) under a group health plan or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer may be subject to coverage limits (such as medical necessity, pre-authorization, or pre-certification) and cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required by the plan or issuer, that are no more restrictive than the predominant coverage limits and cost-sharing requirements, respectively, applied to substantially all medical and surgical benefits covered by the plan (or coverage).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3973E01519DA4885909CB90F7F772F50"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text>
<subparagraph id="H66CF7A440C064ADE8344F530752F917B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>treatment</term> includes, with respect to a group health plan or group health insurance coverage offered by a health insurance issuer, inpatient and outpatient items and services performed to improve, repair, or restore bodily function (or performed to approximate a normal appearance), due to a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect, and includes treatment to any and all missing or abnormal body parts (including teeth, the oral cavity, and their associated structures) that would otherwise be provided under the plan or coverage for any other injury or sickness, including—</text> <clause id="HE528EB288F854FE2AC61EC9CDF419EBC"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any items or services, including inpatient and outpatient care, reconstructive services and procedures, and complications thereof;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6BFDD0D427C445A68A90AE422AD44788"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjunctive dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic support from birth until the medical or surgical treatment of the defect or anomaly has been completed, including ongoing or subsequent treatment required to maintain function or approximate a normal appearance;</text></clause> <clause id="H28EAEBA9ABA5466598E7F2DFC9A4B273"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures that materially improve, repair, or restore bodily function; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H8A0E9341579745D68506BA07C92A466B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures for secondary conditions and follow-up treatment associated with the underlying craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4B75EDDB0814141A9B43836387DC668"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>treatment</term> shall not include cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H453F9A47AACF47DF9EA9B78BEE2E67F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, a group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage, shall, in accordance with regulations or guidance issued by the Secretary, provide to each participant or beneficiary under such plan or coverage a written description of the terms of this section. Such description shall be in language which is understandable to the typical participant or beneficiary. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9E44189F597D4FA99B222DFD66D804FF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of such Act is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 725 the following new item:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF14E1347CC2945AF95CD39A405DB2A5B">
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration">
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 726. Standards relating to benefits for craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5F420B1B56145DB89D67ACDE060E302"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Internal Revenue Code amendments</header>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H20B763C96B2C42B78C61E10AEA3FCEA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7A402BD1092A4958AD6B6A064BD56E5B"> <section id="HAA02382DED814519B0E31C937ED62AD4"><enum>9826.</enum><header>Standards relating to benefits for craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect</header> <subsection id="HBD36D735C5E64741904041CA719BAB54"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for care and Reconstructive Treatment</header> <paragraph id="H548957EBFCD6410E895742109E56F0B0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan shall provide coverage for outpatient and inpatient items and services related to the diagnosis and treatment of a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H5790199849664E26AB48A87AF1CF5568"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header>
<subparagraph id="H0B6D3638DD6042FA85E655B1BC4F8274"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coverage provided under paragraph (1) shall include any medically necessary item or service to functionally improve, repair, or restore any body part to achieve normal body functioning or appearance, as determined by the treating physician (as defined in section 1861(r) of the Social Security Act), due to craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC7CF9D40A0B848869153F831E7BC396A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Financial requirements and treatment requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any coverage provided under paragraph (1) under a group health plan may be subject to coverage limits (such as medical necessity, pre-authorization, or pre-certification) and cost-sharing requirements (such as coinsurance, copayments, and deductibles), as required by the plan, that are no more restrictive than the predominant coverage limits and cost-sharing requirements, respectively, applied to substantially all medical and surgical benefits covered by the plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A249A4513814AFE91F7229CF73C9F1D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <subparagraph id="H14AACE8A6D3844A18390AF7D451F6BBC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), the term <term>treatment</term> includes, with respect to a group health plan, inpatient and outpatient items and services performed to improve, repair, or restore bodily function (or performed to approximate a normal appearance), due to a craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect, and includes treatment to any and all missing or abnormal body parts (including teeth, the oral cavity, and their associated structures) that would otherwise be provided under the plan for any other injury or sickness, including—</text>
<clause id="H363E54114E5E46A9B0FB66D98EBD58B4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any items or services, including inpatient and outpatient care, reconstructive services and procedures, and complications thereof;</text></clause> <clause id="HC854175201B3435C9BF908BE8FCB37B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>adjunctive dental, orthodontic, or prosthodontic support from birth until the medical or surgical treatment of the defect or anomaly has been completed, including ongoing or subsequent treatment required to maintain function or approximate a normal appearance;</text></clause>
<clause id="H5EE35F2190C9439EA0E85FBC754337D2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures that materially improve, repair, or restore bodily function; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7453EBA56B6A4C0FAEB8F7B7B2782B1C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procedures for secondary conditions and follow-up treatment associated with the underlying craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1EF3BB52D8B0416AACC427A1A5DBC078"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text>The term <term>treatment</term> shall not include cosmetic surgery performed to reshape normal structures of the body to improve appearance or self-esteem.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFF6E6C5CF5804D5A878A7A78DF278EBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this section and annually thereafter, a group health plan shall, in accordance with regulations or guidance issued by the Secretary, provide to each enrollee under such plan a written description of the terms of this section. Such description shall be in language which is understandable to the typical enrollee. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA79AC2CF1A7445AE951483A44AAE6AED"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for such subchapter is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0CC5153C817F4424AA5BF9BA698CC427"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9826. Standards relating to benefits for craniofacial, oral, or maxillofacial congenital anomaly or birth defect.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4D2AC539DD0648A59B4E66C9AB6398BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>A group health plan or health insurance issuer shall provide the benefits described in section 2799A–11 of the Public Health Service Act (as added by subsection (a)), section 726 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (as added by subsection (b)), and <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9826">section 9826</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (as added by subsection (c)) under the terms of such plan or health insurance coverage offered by such issuer.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB226565411AF4506895B72F8A9B9D335"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2024.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

