<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB69C5C9A84814F77B95247D7E5B56D09" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8604 IH: Free City Commission Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8604</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Free City Commission to examine the effects of liberal Government policy on American cities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE85DA99D51EA4D738ABB2E74722BC3EB" style="OLC"><section id="H618FF15C1ADC4B359389C94FB5037FFC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Free City Commission Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H37728596BFE5416E89905A145335BDB8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment and purpose of Commission</header><subsection id="H98F804E1766F408C8F506839257780DF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the legislative branch a commission to be known as the <quote>Free City Commission</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H8F6E730C5A714C83AB9473334624317D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Commission is to study the effects of progressive governance on cities within the United States over the last 75 years. </text></subsection></section><section id="H04FDE576E9C1400FBEA93427F450EF4C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Composition of Commission</header><subsection id="H7D8C76012AEE4076B2560A18AA93BA7F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Members</header><paragraph id="H1BC87C759A8F4652A31303D3E7A92313"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 20 members, to be appointed not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, of whom—</text><subparagraph id="H802880A3DB8A44E895C973047F9C8424"><enum>(A)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H049DCC7A67C3402FA8F6C03C7DBAD7A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3086625EFF8A424CB8EDE9B52CC6AF7F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27319ED43728420790F0418A07050643"><enum>(D)</enum><text>5 members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB06877CD6C164B97B0491FB63F7B08A8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Members appointed under subsection (a) shall consist of individuals with expertise in any of the issues described in paragraphs (1) through (10) of section 6. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71D1BF8B8EB947B5A972C55BAA490CD4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>An individual appointed to the Commission may not be an officer or employee of the Federal Government.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H947ADDD0C2F04769810F207B4078C3C9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chair, vice chair, and meetings</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a simple majority of the members of the Commission are appointed under paragraph (1), such members shall meet to elect a chair and vice chair from among such members and shall determine a schedule of Commission meetings.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB84A287735444C0499830082E31F2F94"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Commission shall meet and begin the operations of the Commission not later than 30 days after the appointment of a simple majority of members of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF709863E21D34997896F58DE270F97AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Quorum and vacancy</header><paragraph id="HF439B1E8E6484C5E89CC422D2937C49A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A simple majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62A3EA9D554F4F708CEEA39A676F7CA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>Any vacancy in the Commission shall not affect its powers and shall be filled in the same manner in which the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H95352B5182EF483398EAF26D508CFEE5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Duties of Commission</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Commission shall, with respect to cities in the United States during the 75-year period preceding the date of enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="HEA896EA4F7B74A78A190124075048553"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examine the causal link between permissive drug policies and the increase in drug violence and drug usage;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8145D0A29724748B3DA2AA8EABFEA73"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine the effects of a lack of educational opportunities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F7CE0822C7C43298D11EF4BBD6A88F8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evaluate the success of law enforcement tactics in preventing violence and protecting civilians;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EB29BA707AF43948F134F32DFCF7A92"><enum>(4)</enum><text>examine the prevalence of abortion in minority communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56F40E08A5F54D409B526563E347B5F0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>examine the failures of public schools in urban environments;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E81404C61A345A593A52D0F4C4C849E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>evaluate the success of opportunity zones;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30FD191B53AE4630B22E0EAB7CF116AC"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the link between home ownership and community stability;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD26D93CAF7324E8FA10911DFCFBE08F7"><enum>(8)</enum><text>investigate mental health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB58CA0468AF4AA2AA4EC66ED5DCC959"><enum>(9)</enum><text>study signs of civic engagement like voting and parental involvement in schools;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0606D57D19B4CF3B9B4579B18EBFFA1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>investigate public health markers like chronic disease and sexual health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA832B7F6692344979A370B5E7507E704"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rates of religious affiliation, participation, and belief in these communities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31E614B272BA47919E592D724DF9E736"><enum>(12)</enum><text>not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, submit a report on the findings under paragraphs (1) through (11) to the individuals described in section 6(b)(2).</text></paragraph></section><section id="HADF2C8349C67459B9A820554A3BC0A55"><enum>5.</enum><header>Powers of Commission</header><subsection id="H3962B9D030994712A58A452AB8DF7E84"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission may hold such hearings, meet and act at such times and places, and receive such evidence as may be necessary to carry out the functions of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB52220E0097C4F0593C7B7DEC777F498"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header><paragraph id="H7A0FFCAF61E145D4B5605153373AC477"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may access, to the extent authorized by law, from any executive department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality of the Federal Government such information, suggestions, estimates, and statistics as the Commission considers necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6EA56D3D12F49FCA7DF72B4BC96509F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of information</header><text>On written request of the chair of the Commission, each department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality shall, to the extent authorized by law, provide the requested information to the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CEDA9B870694F72BBA5325FAAC0FA11"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Receipt, handling, storage, and dissemination</header><text>Information shall only be received, handled, stored, and disseminated by members of the Commission and its staff consistent with all applicable statutes, regulations, and Executive orders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E56276D3F8B42B8BF60FDF361774CF9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance from Federal agencies</header><paragraph id="HBD390EF7608645D1BDB89F333E91B5A7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>General Services Administration</header><text>On request of the chair of the Commission, the Administrator of General Services shall provide to the Commission, on a reimbursable basis, administrative support and other assistance necessary for the Commission to carry out its duties.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52AAA048F2EB4ED5B2943AA97362B98E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other departments and agencies</header><text>In addition to the assistance provided for under paragraph (1), departments and agencies of the United States may provide to the Commission such assistance as they may determine advisable and as authorized by law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H92D7E12623A34E209EEB2DBFB89C835C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contracting</header><text>The Commission may enter into contracts to enable the Commission to discharge its duties under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H14AE58E5BD9C48F0A3BFDCEBD488B3FA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Donations</header><text>The Commission may accept, use, and dispose of donations of services or property.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF03B8860CC5148DF9DE77F8C4078DCF7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as a department or agency of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0188B8F6D10B477AA57008BFE727A3E1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Staff of Commission</header><subsection id="HFC6974778FD84871A72C97EBCFECD19F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The chair of the Commission, in consultation with the vice chair, in accordance with rules agreed upon by the Commission, may appoint and fix the compensation of a staff director and such other personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its functions, in accordance with the provisions of title 5, United States Code, except that no rate of pay fixed under this subsection may exceed the equivalent of that payable for a position at level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H502693480DAA46008AFE8B316F37498E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Staff of Federal agencies</header><text>Upon request of the chair of the Commission, the head of any executive department, bureau, agency, board, commission, office, independent establishment, or instrumentality of the Federal Government may detail, without reimbursement, any of its personnel to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its duties under this Act. Any detail of an employee shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subsection><subsection id="H94304E63460B4D6CB83A579286840F05"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultant services</header><text>The Commission is authorized to procure the services of experts and consultants in accordance with section 3109 of title 5, United States Code, but at rates not to exceed the daily rate paid a person occupying a position at level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="H5176B14BAC18430D95D7EE1D65511A98"><enum>7.</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Each member of the Commission shall serve without compensation, but shall receive travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, in accordance with applicable provisions in the same manner as persons employed intermittently in the Government service are allowed expenses under section 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text></section><section id="HBFAC62FF01174C8FB69370B07560EDE5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act applicability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of the Federal Advisory Committee Act shall apply to the Commission, including the staff of the Commission.</text></section><section id="H090917B8E3974E9CBD22BD3C29136550"><enum>9.</enum><header>Reports of Commission; termination</header><subsection id="H10A5984685154D29A750C845C0D5AE52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Other reports and information</header><paragraph id="HC15F1E9079354C7B9F01F154B5EB5485"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>The Commission may issue additional reports as the Commission determines necessary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11ACF75304C74AB0A33FE500E14FE9F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information</header><text>The Commission may hold public hearings to collect information and shall make such information available for use by the public.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA81D98A9BAF4E8A998A59E8D5076DC6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Final report</header><paragraph id="H14E7E15A071B453FBFE6B59AD0538581"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall, not later than 18 months after the date of its first meeting, submit to the individuals described in paragraph (2) a final report containing specific findings, conclusions, and recommendations required under this Act as have been agreed to by a majority of Commission members.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H552E3405BCDD45AD99AEA965C0E396DE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Individuals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The individuals described in this paragraph are the President, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, the Attorney General, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, the minority leader of the House of Representatives, the majority leader of the Senate, and the minority leader of the Senate. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8761D71F9B84F5A9E5DE65D35E3BC49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><paragraph id="H5FAE73F160C24720AB3B0B65E520CF86"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission, and all the authorities of this Act, shall terminate on the date that is 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6B3DE9CA9F24ADC989D9DFE49EB4B68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Records</header><text>Not later than the date of termination of the Commission under paragraph (1), all records and papers of the Commission shall be delivered to the Archivist of the United States for deposit in the National Archives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

