<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4369B78E2B3D459F87126D12C2DCCAD8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>106 HR 7450 IH: Build the Wall Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7450</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001311">Mr. Bishop of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To remove legal impediments preventing construction of a border barrier along the international border between the United States and Mexico, improve the construction requirements for such barrier, make previously appropriated funds available for constructing such barrier until expended, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H7776DBDEF2AC454D936A41FFF6808A03" style="OLC"><section id="H9B3186A14CD64D5A8CB8CE79230768DE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Build the Wall Now Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7F06EEBC90DC4AC3948B8E49A63B54C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Resume construction of barriers and roads along United States and Mexico border</header><subsection id="H07683C167D374327AE8B9B802503DEFA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H4073475F8567428295E607D50AED71EE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Immediate resumption of border barrier construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 hours after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall resume any project relating to the construction of physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, and technology along the international border between the United States and Mexico that were underway, or being planned for, prior to January 20, 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DFAEA5CFFA74F75B92DF8C43FBE09DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No cancellations</header><text>The Secretary may not cancel any contract for activities related to the construction of the border barrier system that was entered into on or before January 20, 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA649F71BCF5849E0B1D9C37612D08DFF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>To carry out this section, the Secretary shall expend all funds appropriated or explicitly obligated for the construction of the border barrier system that were appropriated or obligated, as the case may be, for use beginning October 1, 2016.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C775728575048F28B48447E8C567013"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Uphold negotiated agreements</header><text>The Secretary shall ensure that all agreements executed in writing between the Department and private citizens, State, local, or Tribal governments, or other stakeholders are honored by the Department relating to current and future construction of the border barrier system as required by such agreements.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E81FE2CB7AC40579FD713A1ECF0D4A1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, each amount appropriated or otherwise made available for any project relating to the construction of such physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, and technology for fiscal year 2018, 2019, 2020, or 2021 shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3BDC9669CF9743A299BD1345AE64D70E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>The amounts made available under subsection (c) for fiscal year 2021 shall only be available for barriers, technology, or roads that—</text><paragraph id="HD947EC21D7E642EDA75E4990B933A392"><enum>(1)</enum><text>use—</text><subparagraph id="H47D64F56610F4612A7DCE2679DDCEA04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>operationally effective designs deployed as of the date of enactment of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>), such as currently deployed steel bollard designs, that prioritize agent safety; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE629457FD984FBEA9E7A3F1330CB970"><enum>(B)</enum><text>operationally effective adaptations of such designs that help mitigate community or environmental impacts of barrier system construction, including adaptations based on consultation with jurisdictions within which barrier system will be constructed; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD577FFEF7E7C40888DA01C5D18A21FA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>are constructed in the highest priority locations as identified in the Border Security Improvement Plan.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H307A466311DF4D8CBE81B7AF061EFF60"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2B40463D0EF949C8926F85564415C128"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Physical barriers</header><text>The term <quote>physical barriers</quote> includes reinforced fencing, border barrier system, and levee walls.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D4174F7DEAF456C8DE0B71EE96235B2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tactical infrastructure</header><text>The term <quote>tactical infrastructure</quote> includes boat ramps, access gates, checkpoints, lighting, and roads.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD4FFF974F0EB41A4A56DE63E62DE2763"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technology</header><text>The term <quote>technology</quote> means border surveillance and detection technology, and includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H56C4AB9589144B4AA9962DC4362697D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tower-based surveillance technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF174D5849AD49FE8826532B25A1B618"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Deployable, lighter-than-air ground surveillance equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8930A8F256E74232878EC150DAA3CFAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Vehicle and Dismount Exploitation Radars (VADER).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC7BBB4455FC40058FE65014405ED77C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>3-dimensional, seismic acoustic detection and ranging border tunneling detection technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A8C2BE02C264C4F94E16EC2D9073190"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Advanced unattended surveillance sensors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86D19C1D797B41D584201C803AEF781E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Mobile vehicle-mounted and man-portable surveillance capabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4CB8EA445F54AA982BD6582B4CF75A3"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Unmanned aircraft systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H817E51F2726145A883D4F2D3906A9EEB"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Other border detection, communication, and surveillance technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2BFE55456CCC4D9EBE146FD3430BFACC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Improving the requirements for barriers along the southern border</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102 of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1103">8 U.S.C. 1103</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H898D9D36469D4E48B962558B53A0DD34"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (a) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H10670F7019C3436F8291180A1DD38D15" style="OLC"><subsection id="H9556345FAED34F79B77CF35E7C4FAE8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall take such actions as may be necessary (including the removal of obstacles to detection of illegal entrants) to design, test, construct, install, deploy, integrate, and operate physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, and technology in the vicinity of the United States border to achieve situational awareness and operational control of the border and deter, impede, and detect illegal activity in high traffic areas.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5B53032A81A4570A3DC820CED04E1FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H418EC5E103A54B87B9804FF887FF01C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the subsection heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Fencing and Road Improvements</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Physical Barriers</header-in-text></quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21C70FC2CE9B4F2E91ED8F8756765C50"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H48BFE9343D45420F8CB9914D826DADD3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><subclause id="H932D56F08B4B4F6DACB373E60DC2DFFA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>this section</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCBA6D4D5C5B044B3A1677ECC38F805ED"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>roads, lighting, cameras, and sensors</quote> and inserting <quote>tactical infrastructure, and technology</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H32F2950F092D40FF8E9F422648810DB2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking <quote>gain</quote> and inserting <quote>achieve situational awareness and</quote>;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HAB84B3544C824BD8A10F0AA7B51AEDC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HB5ECBBFD44324C8BAB9438807002DFC2" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H16E43E3996944F6DBC845078A1949D31"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Physical barriers and tactical infrastructure</header><text>The Secretary, in carrying out this section, shall deploy along the United States border the most practical and effective physical barriers and tactical infrastructure available for achieving situational awareness and operational control of the border.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H3D8BF94CD855480887798E91292F8D32"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><subclause id="H0C5204812ADA4172B5E7958D4E245868"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HA0C261AFCF3A4DE4846737F133430292" style="OLC"><clause id="H850EE62294134E86A0D011FF0B7F7161"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall consult with appropriate Federal agency partners, appropriate representatives of Federal, State, Tribal, and local governments, and appropriate private property owners in the United States to minimize the impact on the environment, culture, commerce, and quality of life for the communities and residents located near the sites at which such physical barriers are to be constructed.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="H33A3B07D42AA479A83A074D85248AB1B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text><item id="H7A25B0EDC4C543959BD044E1CC595C5C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in subclause (I), by striking <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></item><item id="HCCB1B7098EEF41E9AB7E8D4BAF3D1E75"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by amending subclause (II) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4150C1786F1D4C689EA3BC23842DFDC0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="H5C2E96E648514074A787EDA3895A63AD"><enum>(II)</enum><text>delay the transfer to the United States of the possession of property or affect the validity of any property acquisition by the United States by purchase or eminent domain, or to otherwise affect the eminent domain laws of the United States or of any State; or</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></item><item id="H8B0510CD6E244F21926CCBF56D7A8F46"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block id="H3B5BA99460E140CDBFF469C39720450A" style="OLC"><subclause id="HC5E3AD627457420BAED8419FA8744042"><enum>(III)</enum><text>create any right or liability for any party.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></item></subclause></clause><clause id="HEA111052C7C3433C8B9682A643A0FC70"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (D);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H228FD9628B3A444E81992988617B2B78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H0EC14B416AE844B7A162073A106D566A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Attorney General</quote> and inserting <quote>Secretary of Homeland Security</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H4633962915484415A61C8FB16B6B8849"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>this section</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HE5CCBB6363FC4BE89706F6144998922E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>construction of fences</quote> and inserting <quote>the construction of physical barriers</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF59A4FC547614931BFBD5ACD44013184"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H00788017F771494CBD206B93668A2D49" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H99A67F0ABECA4271AA9296F8C8B16CCF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Agent safety</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security, when designing, constructing, and deploying physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, or technology, shall incorporate such safety features into such design, construction, or deployment of such physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, or technology, as the case may be, that the Secretary determines are necessary to maximize the safety and effectiveness of officers or agents of the Department of Homeland Security or of any other Federal agency deployed in the vicinity of such physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, or technology.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00D1351C0C4541EBBEC39C36396F1FF3"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>this subsection</quote> and inserting <quote>this section</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H46AC472E398745A3967DD23096647D0B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HDC183D2844B14CE19D6C3C69FFE5C4A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H03DFBF173A214A9495D79D753837D389" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H3BB48029A8F947638D9482EA051F5690"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall have the authority to waive all legal requirements the Secretary determines necessary to ensure the expeditious design, testing, construction, installation, deployment, integration, and operation of the physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, and technology under this section. Such waiver authority shall also apply with respect to any maintenance carried out on such physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, or technology. Any such decision by the Secretary shall be effective upon publication in the Federal Register.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F44B71D709D432FAA5E5B7BCFE1EAC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (2) as paragraph (3); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C86088188994234A4D29EBB2F17D8EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HD98D4495E32E4DAA87652CAA07D1CF8F" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H9F94E26078C94C039CE037FA383B7631"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>Not later than 7 days after the date on which the Secretary of Homeland Security exercises the waiver authority under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate of such waiver.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3C1C0914A84B03836C7526BD29F1E2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block id="HA380B572A78347ADA560FA944FB0F881" style="OLC"><subsection id="H8559E2F988E54242879659B7BD0E5912"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technology</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, in carrying out this section, shall deploy along the United States border the most practical and effective technology available for achieving situational awareness and operational control of the border.</text></subsection><subsection id="H152C51C13A2C46AB96F5F15E86982A79"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H30508517B9B94646A150E51DD36256EC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advanced unattended surveillance sensors</header><text>The term <quote>advanced unattended surveillance sensors</quote> means sensors that utilize an onboard computer to analyze detections in an effort to discern between vehicles, humans, and animals, and ultimately filter false positives prior to transmission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H327D3B3CA48A4AB2B049E51ED8A477C4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High traffic areas</header><text>The term <quote>high traffic areas</quote> means areas in the vicinity of the United States border that—</text><subparagraph id="HEA674F80D3EA4A76B181E35BDD1F3A0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are within the responsibility of U.S. Customs and Border Protection; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBD862EF95DB488C99262A9C09C86C8C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have significant unlawful cross-border activity, as determined by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0280951503F4CA9B0C663E7890E27A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Operational control</header><text>The term <quote>operational control</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 2(b) of the Secure Fence Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/367">Public Law 109–367</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1701">8 U.S.C. 1701</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10D00F6F314A4D508FFC4B8DC7014184"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Physical barriers</header><text>The term <quote>physical barriers</quote> includes reinforced fencing, border barrier system, and levee walls.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D269B40A7C74D009FEB22629174586D"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Situational awareness</header><text>The term <quote>situational awareness</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1092(a)(7) of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/223">6 U.S.C. 223(a)(7)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD968CF8F56CF43E482203B52EEFAA09E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Tactical infrastructure</header><text>The term <quote>tactical infrastructure</quote> includes boat ramps, access gates, checkpoints, lighting, and roads.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BF20208A6FB46E486DA8716E2929768"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Technology</header><text>The term <quote>technology</quote> means border surveillance and detection technology, and includes the following:</text><subparagraph id="H54E2E6FBC6904466A3420314B97D78C4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Tower-based surveillance technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D03CA05D0A64EB0AED9CDCA427E04AC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Deployable, lighter-than-air ground surveillance equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83C706074C2F412FADADF5DBFC2754B3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Vehicle and Dismount Exploitation Radars (VADER).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H907A7E94DC694AD3A49C0331E3B3D8FD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>3-dimensional, seismic acoustic detection and ranging border tunneling detection technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D2B48A0694747A1A5421678F53F5D7D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Advanced unattended surveillance sensors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77EEDEE68F5C4DAD9DD8B1C830C5C490"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Mobile vehicle-mounted and man-portable surveillance capabilities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21916A853FDC45619D6A2003A3BEBCC6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Unmanned aircraft systems.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BD308FC27394F63A3236F13F63D7E90"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Other border detection, communication, and surveillance technology.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B976ABD33D7416883598D8E91D913A4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Unmanned aircraft system</header><text>The term <quote>unmanned aircraft system</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 44801 of title 49, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H3A6202D1ACCD48489BB3A4E6BB850C0B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Codifying previously waived legal requirements</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(c) of the Illegal Immigration Reform and Immigrant Responsibility Act of 1996 (division C of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/208">Public Law 104–208</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1103">8 U.S.C. 1103</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HBCDEEBC5837443659C8E5FE60D4FFC6E" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H2CF2E0F9C205441CBB2E71CA0FBE4719"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Previously waived legal requirements</header><subparagraph id="HAE0EDA2B3803489CABE7A6F3E9CE0F06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any project relating to the construction of physical barriers, tactical infrastructure, and technology along the international border between the United States and Mexico shall be exempt from any law or regulation described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H787AA17685DB48C289421C92897F6B90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The laws or regulations described in this subparagraph are the following:</text><clause id="HD31AE433263C43C1B7B895113CD2CB2A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An Act to facilitate the work of the Forest Service (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/87/869">Public Law 87–869</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HA47F262590DD441A894580FABF1DB3F2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Administrative Procedure Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/5/500">5 U.S.C. 500 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H10F6ADF85E2C4CD585D14E0A7C489E5A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The American Indian Religious Freedom Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H5F28649E89CC4ED2AD5035195186F63A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Arizona Desert Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/460ddd">6 U.S.C. 460ddd et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H95029E6D165F44A28D875E8D5DB87E29"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Arizona-Idaho Conservation Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/100/696">Public Law 100–696</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H73C20BAFDDF744C4BA77A3DACC4E1FB1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The Bald and Golden Eagle Protection Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668">16 U.S.C. 668 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H94754462B58A40E98B93A546B02AB34C"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HA41C5E72A31D47F59AD76DE29649CE53"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The Clean Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1151">33 U.S.C. 1151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H4D1D79560AAA46B4AA409EE762A27B55"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>The Coastal Zone Management Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1451">16 U.S.C. 1451 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H8BF33CCDEC89411196FAB143B9FBDDBF"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H248CBCB348A24343AC101CCE9B205845"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>The Endangered Species Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H98F9F962A6124443BEEE3CED70473469"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>The Farmland Protection Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/4201">7 U.S.C. 4201 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H2FE307FD73AA4C1B896B11F743B12FCF"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>The Federal Cave Resources Protection Act of 1988 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4301">16 U.S.C. 4301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H0BC228B91BBF43BC83A192B646DEA8E5"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>The Federal Grant and Cooperative Agreement Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/6301">31 U.S.C. 6301 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HBFDBEBDF9AA04D5BB15D4AE5BC9B5ACD"><enum>(xv)</enum><text>The Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1701">43 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H1F9B7A4F0D75492ABE6217A82E10ECD4"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text>The Fish and Wildlife Coordination Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/662">16 U.S.C. 662 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HB7F38A08BD3D40DBBC57CA07B0653328"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text>The Migratory Bird Conservation Act of 1929 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/715">16 U.S.C. 715 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H83C9BA695B034AD4B987B9ACADA842D4"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>The Migratory Bird Treaty Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/703">16 U.S.C. 703 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HD20FE51450614703A3EB272CB7B40626"><enum>(xix)</enum><text>The Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1999 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/65">Public Law 106–65</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HC521404992934B0B8321D7E1241DCDE4"><enum>(xx)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Multiple-Use and Sustained-Yield Act of 1960 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/583">16 U.S.C. 583 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HA7A99C242E224907A2F953856DF09A8B"><enum>(xxi)</enum><text>The National Environmental Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/190">Public Law 91–190</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H6F2DCD39B47F44019894AD8C1F04D5E8"><enum>(xxii)</enum><text>The National Fish and Wildlife Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/742a">16 U.S.C. 742a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H8AA7BF8C041147AF84ACA9A6AD45BF20"><enum>(xxiii)</enum><text>The National Forest Management Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/472a">16 U.S.C. 472a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H7AF033217EBF44FFAF27AAE96C5C6308"><enum>(xxiv)</enum><text>The National Historic Preservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/89/665">Public Law 89–665</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H748E822AEE2C43278B76F5136E65A93D"><enum>(xxv)</enum><text>The National Parks and Recreation Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/625">Public Law 95–625</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H8D54592A89444184BDE3D5F55CE952CD"><enum>(xxvi)</enum><text>The National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H4B1409EC68434B10995D792143354F87"><enum>(xxvii)</enum><text>The National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/668dd">16 U.S.C. 668dd et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H194A08F35407437B83C8F23AB4A333EF"><enum>(xxviii)</enum><text>The Native American Graves Protection and Repatriation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/3001">25 U.S.C. 3001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HE3DC497D5A7640E8AE7B2BF97AF92EEC"><enum>(xxix)</enum><text>The Noise Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4901">42 U.S.C. 4901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HF8472DE2E17D4D099BE823DD4D161D29"><enum>(xxx)</enum><text>The Otay Mountain Wilderness Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/106/145">Public Law 106–145</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H30D610DE592B4257B45DAB8AAC214CA3"><enum>(xxxi)</enum><text>The Paleontological Resources Preservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/470aaa">16 U.S.C. 470aaa et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H84563A0FB3584724A461A9587992E5F1"><enum>(xxxii)</enum><text>Section 10 of the Reclamation Project Act of 1939 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/387">43 U.S.C. 387</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H3555369445D74DD581B077215FAFAD12"><enum>(xxxiii)</enum><text>The Religious Freedom Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000bb-4">42 U.S.C. 2000bb–4 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HD5272B708AC942EFA5117B75BEE12A49"><enum>(xxxiv)</enum><text>The Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H154C9EEE2F5B4053B332EB01F4CD6202"><enum>(xxxv)</enum><text>The Rivers and Harbors Act of 1899 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/403">33 U.S.C. 403 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HB52D2B0F2203490FA30672979380D414"><enum>(xxxvi)</enum><text>The Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H4FA0F252140E459EAFCA1647FBD4F8CD"><enum>(xxxvii)</enum><text>The Sikes Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/670a">16 U.S.C. 670a et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H1AA7960FECE64B94B7C4BAD40CB13413"><enum>(xxxviii)</enum><text>The Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/631">15 U.S.C. 631 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H60C0B4F3F4CE4695A23AFBD55C5E7442"><enum>(xxxix)</enum><text>The Solid Waste Disposal Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6901">42 U.S.C. 6901 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HDC1292C994F14296AA373F0C64760C6C"><enum>(xl)</enum><text>The Wild and Scenic Rivers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1281">16 U.S.C. 1281 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H0E3145A39C104595A9390614FB46DD9C"><enum>(xli)</enum><text>The Wild Horse and Burro Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1331">16 U.S.C. 1331 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HDCB03A418A4941EB93523ED96541A7EA"><enum>(xlii)</enum><text>The Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="H3231D86E459D4382BA182F3BFEF7F49D"><enum>(xliii)</enum><text>Part 125 of title 13, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H01AE49EC9F794650BCFD2FD74E473151"><enum>(xliv)</enum><text>Sections 16.504, 16.505, 17.205, 17.207, 22.404, 22.404–5, and 28.102–1 of title 48, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></clause><clause id="H5C9FB53007F2401BA93ED6EDF10F0072"><enum>(xlv)</enum><text>Section 550 of title 40, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="H0DE5ECCAD38C49658D6007A82C4B75C5"><enum>(xlvi)</enum><text>Chapters 1003, 1005, 1007, 1009, 1021, 3125, 3201, and 3203 of title 54, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="HB313B23C17D74D548ED94C0E58C9FE95"><enum>(xlvii)</enum><text>Division A of subtitle III of title 54, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="HAC7B32E7373D4F4E9D18DF05DD32DAD5"><enum>(xlviii)</enum><text>Sections 100101(a), 100751(a), 102101 of title 54, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="H8BCEE980E13147EFBE21A18C9859FC87"><enum>(xlix)</enum><text>Sections 2304, 2304c, 2305, 2505a, and 2306a of title 10, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="HB117351FF4AF436FBA51415754A68B84"><enum>(l)</enum><text>Title 41, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H02DE23F9EA89426DB756B7A74A1C77FB"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition against use of funds to implement or enforce Presidential Proclamation 10142</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">No funds, resources, or fees made available to the Secretary of Homeland Security, or to any other official of a Federal agency by any Act of Congress for any fiscal year, may be used to implement or enforce Presidential Proclamation 10142, issued on January 20, 2021.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

