<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F00EB4BB0CF424FB94DE255D8535B1A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6890 IH: Bringing Oligarch Accountability Through Seizure Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6890</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220301">March 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000601">Mr. Palazzo</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Russian vessels from operating in the navigable waters of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBDDA030AFB974B5296EFB0B6B8A1ACB4" style="OLC"><section id="HBF7F69F556DB4F05BE74B9234C33905D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bringing Oligarch Accountability Through Seizure Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BOATS Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H87E28ACEA7FC42328EBCC724C43216FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on entry and operation</header><subsection id="HD3FB65D008B346048E5235C146668813"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H2F1C49C9CF2A4581996DE7A3998586F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this section, no vessel described in subsection (b) may enter or operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H777E5DC190E947669DA1A1464D0C6C18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitations on application</header><subparagraph id="HFB6246D8835749EA92F69E24DC3549F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The prohibition under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to a vessel described in subsection (b)(1) if the Secretary of State determines that—</text><clause id="HAFE53AB57BC4484EAEF84A93CB8AD2DA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the vessel is owned or operated by a Russian national or operated by the government of the Russian Federation; and</text></clause><clause id="idD7C3441C755C484CB586C89D7295DE45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>it is in the national security interest not to apply the prohibition to such vessel.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3028F78B81C64BA9AF179CE69E4A5551"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>Not later than 15 days after making a determination under subparagraph (A), the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate written notice of the determination and the basis upon which the determination was made.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4CDB94C08FF464F8523ABAC30CE3010"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Secretary of State shall publish a notice in the Federal Register of each determination made under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B1CAF26480A42B08E4E0CA31F472921"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Vessels described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vessel referred to in subsection (a) is a vessel owned or operated by a Russian national or operated by the Government of the Russian Federation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC2F8A9430E804001A46C61485AD38FEA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Information and publication</header><text>The Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, with the concurrence of the Secretary of State, shall—</text><paragraph id="HA4FBA5DE12014593B2779E5C3C01DD2C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintain timely information on the registrations of all foreign vessels owned or operated by or on behalf of the Government of the Russian Federation, a Russian national, or a entity organized under the laws of the Russian Federation or any jurisdiction within the Russian Federation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7ACFAD5541548E5A943182ABA72C9AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>periodically publish in the Federal Register a list of the vessels described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE4914DDA5B1C48A186984B7BF1ACBD2A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification of governments</header><paragraph id="HBDB63DEA45A849D69135221559DEF2C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall notify each government, the agents or instrumentalities of which are maintaining a registration of a foreign vessel that is included on a list published under subsection (c)(2), not later than 30 days after such publication, that all vessels registered under such government’s authority are subject to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86587F230EEE4299AB8A3CABD4AC01F3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional notification</header><text>In the case of a government that continues to maintain a registration for a vessel that is included on such list after receiving an initial notification under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall issue an additional notification to such government not later than 120 days after the publication of a list under subsection (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H24489B0C2949468C877B184F5C735B60"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Notification of vessels</header><text>Upon receiving a notice of arrival under section 70001(a)(5) of title 46, United States Code, from a vessel described in subsection (b), the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall notify the master of such vessel that the vessel may not enter or operate in the navigable waters of the United States or transfer cargo in any port or place under the jurisdiction of the United States, unless—</text><paragraph id="H68995FAB0CA04B6C8D2C947F9710CA7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of State has made a determination under subsection (a)(2); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA360EFF3DC0D48DEA79C84B1A0792D08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating allows provisional entry of the vessel, or transfer of cargo from the vessel, under subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8F9F4B86FBAB40D8899B25A2C89B230D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Provisional entry or cargo transfer</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating may allow provisional entry of, or transfer of cargo from, a vessel, if such entry or transfer is necessary for the safety of the vessel or persons aboard.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0B7EAC197AF14C5B9ED73A1E6BF122CE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Seizure and forfeiture of vessel; fine and imprisonment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any owner, agent, master, officer, or person in charge, or any member of the crew of any such vessel fails to comply with any regulation or rule issued or order given under the provisions of this subtitle, or obstructs or interferes with the exercise of any power conferred by this subtitle—</text><paragraph id="H41752E0D8ACA43D690AD9D22C0F5F871"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the vessel, together with the tackle, apparel, furniture, and equipment, shall be subject to seizure and forfeiture to the United States in the same manner as merchandise is forfeited for violation of the customs revenue laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EDED8BD1B2F491A940D1803EBF12214"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the person guilty of such failure, obstruction, or interference shall be punished by imprisonment for not more than 50 years and fined not more than $10,000,000,000.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H139A474DEAE945E1A37C9CE8A72F42C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Auction and proceeds of vessel seizure</header><subsection id="HFABD495A996D4C598132F7D599B58B3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any vessel seized and forfeited under section 422 shall be sold at auction to any entity that is not the Government of the Russian Federation, a Russian national, or a entity organized under the laws of the Russian Federation or any jurisdiction within the Russian Federation. The proceeds of any such auction may only be used for humanitarian aid to Ukraine that is provided by a state that is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization. </text></subsection><subsection id="H027E83AE539F4429B33810C6B74B7D72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall be effective until the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HAD4113C40B8F4DC8BD714BBA7092CBC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>1 year after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9ED878745CD416796F728DF47B0CC84"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the President certifies that the conflict between the Russian Federation and Ukraine has concluded. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

