<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H760E690E65F94833A6633768DC8DDAF6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8550 IH: Public Service Reform Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8550</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="R000614">Mr. Roy</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide that all Federal employees in the executive branch of Government are at-will employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5F4EE29E1A7B443D9A8BE6CB34E12F64" style="OLC"><section id="H4BBEEED077DB469E8C408F3B4F6285DA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Service Reform Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H8276120E23B74D9289BDFCEF6DED236E"><enum>2.</enum><header>At-will employment for Federal executive branch employees</header><subsection id="H0DA8B95F27114ED5AA8EDB25DE9A187B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>At-Will employment</header><paragraph id="H747AD70F4CD24348BA58C885CC074C2B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, rule, or regulation, and except as provided in paragraph (2), any employee in the executive branch of Government shall be considered at-will, and—</text><subparagraph id="H8702DFDB43E64FC8BAFE40057C037D6D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be subject to any adverse personnel action (up to and including removal) for good cause, bad cause, or no cause at all; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB12C1247FBA042949A15929E443A0B0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not challenge or otherwise appeal such an action except as provided in subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD69FC203957F49CF88F5943C13509D86"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><subparagraph id="H819C1FC1E5064F918AE97E91A023A903"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employee may not be subject to any adverse personnel action under this Act for any reason prohibited section 2302(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H215B66947D474AD6BF7BC287435F1DFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>The President shall establish procedures to enforce compliance with paragraph (1), including providing for disciplinary measures against any employee who violates such paragraph. Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed to grant an employee the right to review or appeal an adverse personnel action outside such procedures.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95CAD45876E64E6A9BC0B0E17274C580"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Removal of career employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the removal of a career employee, the following procedures shall apply:</text><paragraph id="HBED0DCF832494BE1A69237F4AC33F140"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Before an agency removes the employee, the agency official authorized to propose such action (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>proposing official</quote>) shall provide the employee with written notification of the proposed removal and the reasons therefore. The employee shall have 14 days to provide a written response, except that the agency head or designee shall have sole and exclusive discretion to alter the response period on a case-by-case basis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE500F3251F344477BAE3E75B9BA179F9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Under procedures prescribed by the agency head, in the head’s sole and exclusive discretion, an agency official other than the proposing official (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>deciding official</quote>) shall decide whether to remove or retain such career employee. The deciding official shall review the proposed removal and employee response under paragraph (1), and may, in their sole and exclusive discretion, conduct a hearing on the matter. After such review or hearing (as the case may be), the deciding official shall determine whether the employee shall be removed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A9C6801800A42889B64B076472C583E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The deciding official’s determination under paragraph (2) shall be the agency’s final decision unless, within the 7-day period following such determination, the agency head or designee reverses the decision, in which case the agency head’s or designee’s decision shall be the final agency decision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FC8C0B959E644FFA0A6A6B20C507637"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agency’s final decision under paragraph (3) shall be final and not subject to any appeal or challenge, unless the President overrules the agency’s final decision.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABA2DFCFC277426A971272170057DE3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/43">Chapter 43</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, shall not apply to any personnel action taken with respect to an employee under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H426ACED817D9414891AEAF9159672600"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Abolishment of MSPB</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date of enactment of this Act, the Merit Systems Protection Board is hereby abolished. The Chairman of the Board may take such actions as are necessary to dispose of the assets, obligations, and liabilities of the Board.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEE927C62821B4F7AA7A601D8D479B9ED"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HF20385435B3A4C40885CFF0BFEF9CE13"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text>The following provisions of title 5, United States Code, are hereby repealed:</text><subparagraph id="H7C28BC7F64F44831A0D9478666F9DE76"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Subchapter I of chapter 12.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H950FDB19F7424B9ABDD78922EA96C621"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1212(c).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC737E3ACA3B4B9EA048408BB84F7B62"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsections (b)(1), (b)(2)(B) through (D), (b)(3), (b)(4), (c), (g), and (i) of section 1214.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE1EE9605FA1493BA883422A57F432EA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sections 1215 and 1221.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07E30A162D7A4256842D3F9FA76B1596"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Section 4303.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0CCB1F544384DD5B60A8568D5C72C07"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Chapter 75.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08D84440F56947C28DC93872DE18FA0C"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Chapter 77.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE1672565B2349E88273E86645C49D6E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other amendments</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/71">Chapter 71</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H3EEB2D46560D4579BF2CF4C7310BAC36"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in section 7103(a)(14), by redesignating subparagraphs (B) and (C) as subparagraphs (C) and (D), respectively, and by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H425A721090EF4A899F0FF64B311F1403" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H57729FCDC54147E2B0F166F92588B8F2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relating to adverse personnel actions, as provided by the Public Service Reform Act;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E0FAAF2964E4A98903F1DD01DC7FC51"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in section 7121(c), by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H8E9932BA4ED04F4BB7D2297528480DC4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HBE03905176B149E5A8A5DBB79FC47096"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any adverse personnel action under the Public Service Reform Act;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4119F2644B264FEFBBDB43EFC7EE3D07"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Whistleblower protections</header><paragraph id="H5140656CD947419FB0745EFA4F225315"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within the 14-day period described in subsection (b)(1), the Office of Special Counsel may make a recommendation to the agency head or deciding official on whether an adverse personnel action taken against an individual was in retaliation for making a whistleblowing disclosure.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEF4FE7B9AEA4D0CAFD9FF3813C85299"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual subject to an adverse personnel action who claims such action was taken in retaliation described in section 2302(b)(8) or (b)(9) of title 5, United States Code, may appeal such action to the United States court of appeals in the circuit in which the duty station of the individual is located.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DEE0E3FF4CC423AABFB05D5879BC03F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Decision</header><subparagraph id="H7D95FCB9071C4835BD8701A32DE996FA"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If such court is finds that the individual’s appeal under paragraph (2) is in bad faith or frivolous, the individual’s annuity under chapter 83 or 84 of such title shall be reduced by 25 percent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C9D6CA64E24A6CA8250A5C22C33EE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If the individual prevails under an appeal under paragraph (2), the individual shall—</text><clause id="H628B128F82EE4792B2766F25B553938C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be placed, as nearly as possible, in the position the individual would have been in had the adverse personnel action not occurred; and</text></clause><clause id="HCE52E137A5AE442E811AF5CAF264412C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be reimbursed for attorney’s fees, back pay, and related benefits, medical costs incurred, travel expenses, any other reasonable and foreseeable consequential damages, and compensatory damages (including interest, reasonable expert witness fees, and costs).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F75B7E3A89F4E1286A3088B85EFE3A7"><enum>(g)</enum><header>EEOC appeals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, including section 717 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964, an individual who is an employee or applicant to be an employee and who alleges that the individual was subject to an adverse personnel action that is a prohibited personnel action described in section 2302(b)(1) of title 5, United States Code, shall seek relief for such action from the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission as if such individual was an employee of an employer (as that term is defined in section 701 of such Act).</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4CB8EC564354E14A125F0D5FA84CD7A"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act—</text><paragraph id="H1A24B1BF233A4E0FAB15B168F78A0316"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>adverse personnel action</quote> means a removal, a suspension for more than 14 days, a reduction in grade or a reduction in pay, and a furlough of 30 days or less; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H003AA6E0B8E443E4BCD8F36F98EE49CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <quote>career employee</quote> means any employee who is not a political employee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11275823FB6F441F9CC831E86AE39FED"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the term <quote>employee</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 2105 of title 5, United States Code, and includes—</text><subparagraph id="HB3E4DCA71865436EB72294419B91A293"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an officer or employee of the United States Postal Service or the Postal Regulatory Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64F54F5D4C724AA0BAACE0174A79DD37"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notwithstanding subsection (b) of section 7425 of title 38, United States Code, any employee described under subsection (a) of such section; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC35FD50911CE4EEBBC96E9BEAFDB19EC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the term <quote>political employee</quote> means any employee who is—</text><subparagraph id="H0B21292A9DDD46238AC1D3B14E6FA413"><enum>(A)</enum><text>appointed by the President;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H957DF82C1C2C483C8ECC9C2448C03231"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a noncareer appointee (as that term is defined in section 3132(a)(7) of title 5, United States Code) in the Senior Executive Service;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0EE72B6378ED41F1B654A5AB5B6960F8"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">occupying a position under schedule C of subpart C of part 213 of title 5, Code of Federal Regulations; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1E42DE245E3455C904205702644F15B"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in any other civil service (as that term is defined in section 2101 of title 5, United States Code) position classified as a political position after the date of enactment of this Act under regulations as the Director of the Office of Personnel Management may prescribe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

