<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1093AC5C9C2C468BBA2D105313D4F766" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9672 IH: Farmers Feeding Families Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9672</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221222">December 22, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 to provide additional agricultural products for distribution by emergency feeding organizations; and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H4F089B96197B44159515F77748938D94" style="OLC">
<section id="HFB570CAC54A54924850656C958D011F7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Farmers Feeding Families Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H6D84180273E44BA4837469B143BC77BE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Amendments</header> <subsection id="HDCD48FC4B7D24B679806B7453306C737"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purchase of priority agricultural products</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 203D of the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7507">7 U.S.C. 7507</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HD7BABDEA394A45AE8B24922AF5BFC267"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a) by inserting <quote>or that State agencies purchase using funds made available under subsection (d),</quote> after <quote>distribution,</quote>,</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA46F92291959499B8ABFB2912FEFC11A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b) by inserting <quote>or purchased</quote> after <quote>donated</quote>,</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCAF175F2A37746A3B3E08AF729E25001"><enum>(3)</enum><text> by striking subsection (c),</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22B63851433F40CC87DD0E93F0EBF7DD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H18D2CA04F58B400DA34196CB99A26714"><enum>(A)</enum><text> by striking <quote>(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>(c)</quote>, and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H458A0CB9C5D54AB8843423A6884A3F19"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text>
<clause id="H51AF9EEB42BE489196CB9C4A65867955"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>subparagraphs (B) and (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote>, and</text></clause> <clause id="HD12D6FCFBD064CCF9FCAFBE0705E1F7C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> by striking subparagraph (B), and</text></clause>
<clause id="H50C8BE6790344170992C874A104E0983"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B), and </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B282BCBB2D64E44B37C887158496C3E"><enum>(5)</enum><text> by inserting after subsection (c) the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9A8429438FB940CAB65F255ED5E8874B" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<subsection id="HF9583D2D84E1462086171DD700BE9E06"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Projects for States To purchase certain commodities from eligible entities</header>
<paragraph id="HDACAEAE981A94FA583D5C34536C1B66E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> <subparagraph id="HA09E6DC70EAF4955B7133D2A335E7D1F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>project</quote> means the purchase of priority agricultural products from eligible entities, and the distribution of those products to needy persons through emergency feeding organizations under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35EF633BC2E2498C91F15D4E855A4E72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Priority agricultural product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>priority agricultural product</quote> means a fruit, vegetable, dairy, meat, seafood, grain, poultry, or other commodity food product, available for sale by eligible entities and that States determine to be nutritious, appropriate for distribution through emergency feeding organizations, and culturally relevant to the local communities that will distribute the products.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAA86E7A5327F42D0A12D1FD6DB43A0FC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means any of the following small businesses (as defined by the Small Business Administration) that is a grower, packer, processor, distributor, food-hub, or a cooperative, and that—</text>
<clause id="HC7C075745DA4493EA9DE621A97AE11DE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is—</text> <subclause id="HD4A417366475465891A37531F727624F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>underserved, including women-owned or veteran-owned; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H5F3246B2E36B40BE8F5B5E9CFE7E08A5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>composed of, or sources agricultural products from, beginning farmers, or small or mid-sized farms that are structured as family farms; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H7C368B41F81E4084BB46F3BBEE87A36E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>can deliver the priority agricultural products to emergency feeding organizations selected by the State as being most in need of the products; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H9E808A9616B745989AC2CCA14A040CFC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that is committed to serving local communities and forging strong relationships with emergency feeding organizations, public agencies, and Tribal governments through a project, as determined by the State.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98638B30659B4E78BBB7119253A3D454"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal funding for projects</header> <subparagraph id="H2BA94F0A55144841A857683568B90506"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C) and paragraph (4), using funds made available under paragraph (5), the Secretary may provide funds to States to pay for the costs of carrying out a project.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2D297E1E3206486E9D95D2113A843B04"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Guidance</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall issue guidance to States—</text> <clause id="H1462497A86774880AEFFAAA553AB25E6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to carry out this section;</text></clause>
<clause id="H29E1A3EA9BA6469791172AAFD2B30D84"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to inform States of their allocations under paragraph (3);</text></clause> <clause id="H07A48575588A4252BA96411A9D48C250"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to encourage States to partner with a wide range of emergency feeding organizations, including those that face barriers to entry to participating in existing Department of Agriculture nutrition programs; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HB2135436025D41368AF7AB6BC19C0DAF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to inform States of public reporting requirements and minimum project performance standards, as developed by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H19EB30A4351C4B41A2DE893F8B2CACCF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Allocation</header> <clause id="H526B0FC0960A42FE8B4351996E952E2C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Eligibility for allocation</header><text>The Secretary shall allocate funds made available under paragraph (5) based on the formula in effect under section 214(a), among States that submit a State plan of operation for a project that includes—</text>
<subclause id="H1C6A61BE5F7A4302AE8269235BE55DA5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a list of eligible entities and emergency feeding organizations in the State that will operate the project in partnership with the State agency;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HE260A43613A74BCB9BA75C0680FF173F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the option of the State, a list of priority agricultural products located in the State that are available for purchase and transport to emergency feeding organizations to identify which foods may be included in the project;</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H4A5D5576548D40999167A0F532BC18F7"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a time line of when the project will begin operating; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HA5D4F4E021774115B5C5D83FA3FDB189"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to comply with the standards set out in subparagraph (B)(iv).</text></subclause></clause>
<clause id="HAFD89322CD67483EBF8C81FBD1EFC6B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Reallocation</header><text>If the Secretary determines that a State will not expend all the funds allocated to the State under clause (i), the Secretary shall reallocate the unexpended funds to other eligible States.</text></clause> <clause id="H8139150D05A74CAA98E08A93D076DB6D"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Each State that receives funds allocated under this subparagraph shall submit to the Secretary financial reports on a regular basis describing the use of the funds.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8D265D4390B04A1AAC7E0C17F61354FC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Project purposes</header><text>A State may only use Federal funds received under paragraph (2) for a project the purposes of which are—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E884B2D429D42D8BFA333B0AE93CCBF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maintain and improve food and agricultural supply chain resiliency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8837C00F4C1D49368AAFB996853DA998"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to provide food to individuals in need; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H29D700832845417CA78BAEB5247A5D12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to build relationships between the State, eligible entities and emergency feeding organizations through the purchase of food.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H97C73088BC16436E9AA313EDADB4C006"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header>
<subparagraph id="H3CD71DFAF4F54BECBF3DCC51ECE0C5EA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A State agency that carries out a project using Federal funds received under this subsection may enter into cooperative agreements with State agencies of other States under section 203B(d) to maximize the use of commodities purchased under the project.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8AAEDA9970C94E409894BB10D8C29A7F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>Not later than 15 days after entering into a cooperative agreement under clause (i), a State agency shall submit such agreement to the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3D6BCCC8C4F482FA2D0FFA1979ACF34"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Out of funds not otherwise appropriated, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer to the Secretary to carry out this subsection $50,000,000 for each of the fiscal years 2024 through 2028, to remain available until the end of the respective subsequent fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H686453BE7D98400FB8A6A7CD270D096B"><enum>(6) </enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the effective date of this subsection, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee of Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate a report containing—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD7AC3503AF0446839F97637F5CB92F3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of the effectiveness of this subsection in providing nutritious food to individuals in need, improving agricultural supply chain resiliency, and expanding economic opportunity for eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C437ADE7B374D27B9AD398A61755313"><enum>(B) </enum><text>recommendations for the implementation of this subsection to improve nutrition outcomes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF96A996A75CC403FAA7358433639BD69"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202A(b)(5) of the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7503">7 U.S.C. 7503(b)(5)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>donated commodities received under section 203D(d)</quote> and inserting <quote>commodities donated under subsection (c), or purchased under subsection (d), of section 203D</quote>.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H13EC94889C0842428B7DF48A2E8D4091"><enum>3.</enum><header>State Plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 202A(b)(4)(A) of the Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7503">7 U.S.C. 7503(b)(4)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H326B1324741F43BDA4A4DCAD66539A7F" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subparagraph">, including at a minimum all individuals or households with an income less than 250 percent of the poverty line</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="HE6BA235F6FDA470CA38EFD532A3101D4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Intradepartmental coordination</header>
<subsection id="H2EBE83EDDC4F477CA499FC90E220289D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Working group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Agriculture shall create a cross-agency working group within the office of the Secretary to work with relevant agencies and organizations of the Department of Agriculture and with stakeholders to review and reconsider how all Department procurement of priority agricultural products can be directed to support a wider range of agricultural producers and agricultural product distributors in a manner that meets the Department’s overarching goals of nutrition security, resilient local and regional food systems, rural job creation, and reversal of the concentration of the ownership of the resources for the production and distribution of agricultural products. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H0BDEA35B4A114526811F745050814D3B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The working group established under subsection (a) shall submit to the Committee on Agriculture of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry of the Senate, an annual report describing the working group’s accomplishments, suggestions, and recommendations for administrative actions and proposed legislation relating to the activities of such group under such subsection.</text></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


