<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9473B9F905A94707894E8DED67336760" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9457 IH: Crypto-Asset Environmental Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9457</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221207">December 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require an interagency study on the environmental and energy impacts of crypto-asset mining, to assess crypto-asset mining compliance with the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8BEBA438664F45E6A111456DC15CBBDD" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H7585A51817D341BBA0AAEBC87F37568D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Crypto-Asset Environmental Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5B556DEABA2D4DE38D8EEBE185694B02"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8F6A26562BBD4707A41CD782F83D1F2D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">human activity is the dominant cause of observed climate change in the past century;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB032F40C853941489D2BA9A49F1DBDCA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">climate change is increasing the frequency and intensity of wildfires, droughts, severe storms, heat waves, rising of sea levels, and severe weather events;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD0F4353BCB7A4053A736D7E334A92CF6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Government has—</text> <subparagraph id="HC3CAEA8F432F4860B24DE8D048AF7621"><enum>(A)</enum><text>committed under the decision of the 21st Conference of Parties of the United Nations Framework Convention on Climate Change, adopted in Paris, France, December 12, 2015 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paris Agreement</quote>), to reduce greenhouse gas emissions by 50 to 52 percent by 2030; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H026E4AE283524A229D50D675CB36F80C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a responsibility to mitigate current and future impacts of climate change to protect the health, safety, and welfare of individuals of the United States; </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28B93D57CA82407C96304A269BBB4B25"><enum>(4)</enum><text>crypto-asset mining operations—</text> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H959BB484DE234A608DD0A2328AC8B3A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">can be energy intensive; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H185BB0A74891473EA6EC6FC814267673"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">unlike most other technologies, are often designed to generally increase computing requirements over time, which can lead to increased energy consumption;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3FFD25C6B98940B4AAFA26DF0F8B0B5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a crypto-asset network, Bitcoin, consumes more energy annually than countries such as Chile or Bangladesh consume;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H74310A73B70D4FAEA72E15C7A75B4200"><enum>(6)</enum><text>crypto-asset mining operations often rely on fossil fuels for power, which contributes to greenhouse gas emissions;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6AF164BD237141A3B77D172695D97B80"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the carbon dioxide emissions of the United States from Bitcoin mining were estimated at 21 to 35 megatons per year in 2022, which is equivalent to the annual emissions from more than 4,500,000 to 7,500,000 gasoline-powered cars driven for 1 year;</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H00A8B6FB218946A69C64D11FFD451873"><enum>(8)</enum><text>crypto-asset mining can also cause local noise and water pollution;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A8472670FF944E3A930F55B62205138"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the number of crypto-asset mining facilities in the United States is increasing, and the share of the United States of global Bitcoin mining rose from 3.5 percent in 2020 to 38 percent in 2022;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC35C3720CCE466EA28493FE7D3A925F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>crypto-asset mining is an emergent industry, and the potential of crypto-asset mining to exacerbate systemic racial, social, environmental, and economic injustices is not sufficiently understood;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H85855F8E10244451AA602C59F6CD672F"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there is no comprehensive, independent study of crypto-asset mining operations in the United States, including the energy use, resource mix, and greenhouse gas emissions of those crypto-asset mining operations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7270B9A47F34C21A057BE630FF0AD05"><enum>(12)</enum><text>one of the primary recommendations of the report of the Office of Science and Technology Policy entitled <quote>Climate and Energy Implications of Crypto-Assets in the United States</quote> and dated September 2022 was to obtain detailed data on energy use and emissions from crypto-asset activity.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H042823D9052741D6AC29646337440B0E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="HD19C5D2E4AD0493E987F4B6574897055"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBAA6D2B03E2A408DABD4CEABB2952D58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air pollutant</header><text>The term <term>air pollutant</term> has the meaning given the term in section 302 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7602">42 U.S.C. 7602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5E52B398207346CA8BFB6AB5AC61CA7F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Block</header><text>The term <term>block</term> means a group of data stored as a single record in a blockchain.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H26DCE9883F564D0ABFD4D8AA0A13C101"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Blockchain</header><text>The term <term>blockchain</term> means a distributed ledger technology in which—</text> <subparagraph id="H2D3BB47E8E3547F28767FD8FF873424B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the data are shared across a network that creates a digital ledger of verified transactions or information among network participants; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6BF75D2E16C14700A760528C67AD00C5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the data are typically linked using cryptography to maintain the integrity of the ledger and execute other functions, including transfer of ownership or value.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3B493C98A854880BF489B20E64B81A4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consensus mechanism</header><text>The term <term>consensus mechanism</term> means a process to achieve agreement among network participants on the current state of a blockchain.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BFD0A04A20943618E04FEA459A075D3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Crypto-asset</header><text>The term <term>crypto-asset</term> means a digital asset, which may be a medium of exchange, a representation of value, or both, for which generation or ownership records of the digital asset are recorded in a distributed ledger technology that relies on cryptography.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA9FE1C49E9841C3B95BC4E1F327D5CC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Crypto-asset mining</header><text>The term <term>crypto-asset mining</term> means the process of performing computations to add a valid block of data to the blockchain, typically in exchange for a reward or fee.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD61216804BC147F3BBDD32556DD19BB3"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Power load</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>power load</term> means the amount of electrical power, in megawatts, that can be consumed by a qualifying crypto-asset mining operation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47C1E9294FEC49C6B7C69D3F00C9F2C6"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Qualifying crypto-asset mining operation</header><text>The term <term>qualifying crypto-asset mining operation</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H07EA2B175CC24BB693224238AD16A316"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an individual crypto-asset mining facility that has a power load that is greater than or equal to 5 megawatts; or </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H263330F2653E49BD938BA7094C407EFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>multiple crypto-asset mining facilities that—</text> 
<clause id="H0DC6B809005645B6A7646D97FBCC1524"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are owned by the same company; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0DCF06DAA8E444DFA60607933BC08F7C"><enum>(ii)</enum> <subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H02BEE47655454767B6DCB9830005576E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>each have a power load that is less than 5 megawatts; but </text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF4E96C222A60406A90592933E4DABC23" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have a cumulative power load that is greater than or equal to 5 megawatts.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D0F695C228B40C3B90F35BDF3F1B935"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Scope 1 emissions</header><text>The term <term>scope 1 emissions</term> means greenhouse gas emissions directly from sources that are operated, controlled, or owned by an individual or entity performing a qualifying crypto-asset mining operation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0EF4C2F9F55846FABC295A1161F697D5"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Scope 2 emissions</header><text>The term <term>scope 2 emissions</term> means indirect greenhouse gas emissions associated with the purchase of electricity, steam, heat, or cooling by an individual or entity performing a qualifying crypto-asset mining operation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H424F67A80B36403DA31FACD3C3FA918A"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE728EF2A96774EDFB9A124390FCE350A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compliance with the Clean Air Act</header> 
<subsection id="HF272235D59C94246B463512A7BCD0FD9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Rulemaking required</header> 
<paragraph id="H7361C6BF29FD49E5A63BA190CF97F7E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Proposed regulation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue a notice of proposed rulemaking to revise part 98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act)—</text> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H85BBF8367DC647EF9B3DF20A5857C403"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to require qualifying crypto-asset mining operations to report as covered facilities under subpart A of that part;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB0E7F55650D54EC292FCDC4C34419B99"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to add a new subpart to that part that includes qualifying crypto-asset mining operations as a source category;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA8DD6DA6DE634C48BFF90974234B1422"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to include in the new subpart created under subparagraph (B) appropriate calculation methodologies, reporting guidelines, and monitoring operations of, with respect to qualifying crypto-asset mining operations, scope 1 emissions and scope 2 emissions; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE9856F1B8A06404EA5A96F746AA56A06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to designate the qualifying crypto-asset mining operations source category established pursuant to subparagraph (B) as a source category that is subject to greenhouse gas reporting requirements and related monitoring, recordkeeping, and reporting requirements under section 98.2 of that title, regardless of whether a qualifying crypto-asset mining operation emits at least 25,000 metric tons of carbon dioxide-equivalent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5B13F3A9ACF41FFBD788BEBE31F733D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Final Rule</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the public comment period on the proposed rule under paragraph (1) closes, the Administrator shall issue a final rule revising part 98 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8095113B34B544D78C8CC952DA99FD0C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Administrator finalizes the rule required under subsection (a), the Administrator shall, pursuant to section 114(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7414">42 U.S.C. 7414(a)</external-xref>), issue requests for information for the purpose of conducting an assessment of, with respect to qualifying crypto-asset mining operations, the permit programs under the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7401">42 U.S.C. 7401 et seq.</external-xref>), which shall include identifying the extent to which any qualifying crypto-asset mining operations are improperly operating without a valid and current permit under that Act.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H40FD0CE70953488F869C034894416D1C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection> 
<subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H6708BAD5EF294D6D8E7B632CF0DB5522"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text>Nothing in this section limits the ability of the Administrator to require the reporting of emissions of any type in another source category.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC9893D6761B645C7A534ABD52288C472"><enum>5.</enum><header>Impact study</header> <subsection id="HD8B37C3D073C45E3B7C5C0175EAD41A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, the Administrator of the Energy Information Administration, the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, and the head of any other Federal agency the Administrator or the Secretary determines appropriate, shall conduct a study on the environmental impacts of crypto-asset mining in the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7A9C12B5671549B081B8F1144494D9F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study Requirements</header><text>The study required under subsection (a) shall include—</text> <paragraph id="H8258FBB98F2349E98B964BD820ABC99B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number and location of any existing or planned qualifying crypto-asset mining operation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H87178E604C934AE48BC2D818C560DF93"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the amount of greenhouse gas emissions and other air pollutants that are—</text> <subparagraph id="H7FB612A29E0A40C19E988C284FB19531"><enum>(A)</enum><text>released by an onsite energy source; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF0C65BC0D8F94E5DB65F7D1F0D0A2291"><enum>(B)</enum><text>attributable to offsite-generated electricity, steam, heat, or cooling provided to a qualifying crypto-asset mining operation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCD9B31E9B4994843AFE8AA42C513B07C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the anticipated increase of new, and expansion of existing, qualifying crypto-asset mining operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA63133110B2E4CBFB85426283A58DD66"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the potential impacts of electric energy consumption by qualifying crypto-asset mining operations, including by prolonging the use of fossil fuel generators, on the ability of the United States to achieve the greenhouse gas emission reductions necessary to keep global warming below 1.5 degrees Celsius compared to pre-industrial levels;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D6D4CE02DD647E6A3F7B63366617470"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the ecological impacts, including ecological impacts associated with electronic waste generation and the use or discharge of cooling water, caused by qualifying crypto-asset mining operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF2D20DD082747BEB74AE321C8968A30"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the potential public health impacts due to the reduced air and water quality and increased water stress on communities near qualifying crypto-asset mining operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H245BBF0D4B4C4C06B0F780A626126267"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the potential public health impacts from greenhouse gas emissions released by qualifying crypto-asset mining operations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H56A8EFFF36684677AD91EA7CE132DD89"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the potential public health and ecological impacts from noise generated by qualifying crypto-asset mining operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H099F86F7569B479BBE9BBE9ABD07D7B4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>the amount of electric energy consumed by each qualifying crypto-asset mining operation, including the time of use of electricity and the potential grid stress posed by the power load of the qualifying crypto-asset mining operation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4240304033D545638071EE48458A1620"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the source of electric energy consumed by each qualifying crypto-asset mining operation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H04FC2B9EC7464768A14FF981C6B2D097"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the aggregated energy-use statistics and greenhouse gas emissions statistics for qualifying crypto-asset mining operations in the United States;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H95D698AC079F41348AAC89DE1827AF04"><enum>(12)</enum><text>an analysis of energy use and greenhouse gas emissions by type of consensus mechanism;</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H91BA8B15F66546C4AC3BBF605A5D053E"><enum>(13)</enum><text>an analysis of demand-response programs negotiated between qualifying crypto-asset mining operations and electric utilities; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B1B07A072484DEF9F95111C944EDFFB"><enum>(14)</enum><text>an analysis of potential rate-design measures that could be implemented by State and local regulators to reduce the energy consumption and dependence on fossil fuel energy sources of crypto-asset mining operations;</text></paragraph> <paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H4432932FDB5A40AAB6D35825CB95F64B"><enum>(15)</enum><text>a geospatial assessment of the extent to which crypto-asset mining operations are located within environmental justice communities, as defined by the Administrator or within the Climate and Economic Justice Screening Tool of the Council on Environmental Quality; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H47007AE590AB43F0A4B5DB4809B05641"><enum>(16)</enum><text>an identification of, and recommendations for, best practices for data types, data sources, and methodologies for accurately measuring, modeling, and tracking the environmental impacts of crypto-asset mining operations in the United States in the future.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC8DCF2CBAF664BFE83E25024E17CD145"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public Comment</header><text>Before conducting the study required by subsection (a), the Administrator shall provide an opportunity for public comment and advice relevant to conducting the study.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H43E823BA7A464768A852986EF1E57BF7"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committees on Energy and Commerce and Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, and publish on the public websites of the Environmental Protection Agency and the Department of Energy, a report that contains the results of the study required by subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4C5292C726524F21820C6DC65C24A2DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator to carry out this section $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, to remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H257EDEE5A62F440AAB9F90EBEED61A75"><enum>6.</enum><header>Energy efficiency of data center buildings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 453(a)(1) of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17112">42 U.S.C. 17112(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H6AA74216CD014F63B0BBCA898D6C12E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (A), by striking ‘‘or’’ at the end after the semicolon; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8135411470354460835EF264F4FFAB6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (B), by striking the period at the end and inserting ‘‘; or’’; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3D89AAB08F5B498183386035A620F50B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following: </text> 
<quoted-block id="H7E20F5C7332A4E67B86FCF8E59EB2F9D" style="OLC" act-name=""> 
<subparagraph id="H5A63B39F4BEE497481D7D6DDD7C90F38"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a facility in which 2 or more computers perform logical operations to mine or create crypto-asset (as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Crypto-Asset Environmental Transparency Act of 2022</short-title>).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

