<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC13434A3D8124A01ABF1F8570A7A83B3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7956 IH: Providing Reports On The Efforts Combating Threats in Schools Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7956</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the President to submit a report to Congress on the actions Executive agencies are taking to make school security improvements at public elementary and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFAFA3DEC956D4CBEBFC8DB63B7170AE8" style="OLC"><section id="HAAF00F741673480FB80426E93BBF4E72" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Providing Reports On The Efforts Combating Threats in Schools Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PROTECTS Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HD2B2512975F645F8AAAA77FD3EE063BB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on actions to protect children in public elementary and secondary schools</header><subsection id="HE869A9B7C80340FEB0F9D359AAEC4EE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall submit to the relevant congressional committees a report on the actions Executive agencies are taking to make school security improvements to protect children in public elementary and secondary schools, including—</text><paragraph id="H66B848B167BF481197D2BCB14B22406F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>improvements to the infrastructure of school property perimeter, parking lot perimeter, building perimeter, entrance and exit points of the school building, video monitoring equipment, and the interior and perimeter of the classroom, and any other physical improvements related to camera systems and related hardware, alarm and notification technology, and visitor management technologies; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E024E7FDE904CB0A878D188C5DFC89A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increasing the number of school resource officers and other law enforcement agencies at such schools.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B135B0333E74031986F811A17D415B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3062C8B1077C4F16B93EC394C8E8FB61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text>The term <term>Executive agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD633499587C46109ECB870A4DDAE407"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>relevant congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HE77C466BF55E46B98881C66AD1D0F98C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884FA75A3E6243CC97A6F9F25E546FE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Education and Labor, the Committee on the Judiciary, and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

