<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEBC78909AC8D416A9D640BE67CDE9EEC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9162 IH: Stop Our Scourge Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9162</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221007">October 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001172">Mr. Smith of Nebraska</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001311">Mr. Bishop of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001192">Mr. Stewart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001087">Mr. Crawford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to designate illicit fentanyl as a weapon of mass destruction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H97E8F5200E644460A21BF130B474AF68" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H73E0AAD663534ACEB64258B25397B833" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stop Our Scourge Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SOS Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H7C19D5760351498395712F5788AC0D33"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HD8C4EBED38AF429D99D9F6B91C8721BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of annual drug overdose deaths in the United States has quintupled since 1999.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9876B40C3D824C24882A271782CAF114"><enum>(2)</enum><text>According to the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, deaths involving illicit fentanyl are on the rise, and the number of overdose deaths involving synthetic opioids in 2020 was more than 18 times the number in 2013.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDDCF2C70669B42F28BE8F6F9CB54E729"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention states that in 2020 more than 56,000 people died from overdoses involving synthetic opioids (other than methadone) in the United States, accounting for over 82 percent of all opioid-involved deaths.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9FD792585DB43D8996308F64757E9C8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the National Center for Health Statistics, the age-adjusted rate of drug overdose deaths involving synthetic opioids other than methadone (such as fentanyl) increased 56 percent, from 11.4 in 2019 to 17.8 in 2020 per 100,000 standard population.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0A49E86C59BD4AC390BCD2006D0CB317"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention finds that reports on increases in synthetic opioid-involved deaths <quote>are being driven by increases in fentanyl-involved overdose deaths, and the source of the fentanyl is more likely to be illicitly manufactured than pharmaceutical</quote>.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A103896B807435CB69CB13AD7E2AB6C"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In August 2021, the U.S.-China Economic and Security Review Commission published an issue brief noting that, in response to China’s May 2019 fentanyl scheduling announcements, <quote>Chinese illegal fentanyl producers began seeking new ways to evade authorities, including developing new fentanyl precursors, working with traffickers in other countries, and using technology to avoid detection</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD78A16047F5F4EF38B452041B01CB159"><enum>(7)</enum><text>According to the Drug Enforcement Agency, fentanyl is being mixed with other illicit drugs to increase the potency of the drug, sold as powders and nasal spray, and increasingly pressed into pills made to look like legitimate prescription opioids.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25F4AB39921D49EDAEB4A497486F2B21"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In an August 2022 op-ed, Dr. Rahul Gupta, Director of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, wrote, <quote>While clandestinely produced drugs such as fentanyl hardly ever leave China in their final form, precursor chemicals for these drugs often are imported by criminals from China to Mexico, where lethal synthetic drugs are produced and trafficked to countries across the globe, including the U.S.</quote>.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5E094D7C5194F52A52AB781B35A15B2"><enum>(9)</enum><text>In fiscal year 2022, U.S. Customs and Border Protection seized 12,900 pounds of illicit fentanyl, which was primarily manufactured in foreign laboratories and smuggled into the United States through Mexico—a sufficient quantity to kill over 2.9 billion people.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90AAAA5E01A14C1A966107D518B5A8C2"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Current policies to counter the continued proliferation of illicit fentanyl have been shown to be inadequate at protecting the Nation’s communities.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H56BD75480D85419DA313B362D51C252A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of fentanyl as a weapon of mass destruction</header> 
<subsection id="HE67CEAE1134A44FB8008DF6E56C94E34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security shall designate illicit fentanyl as a weapon of mass destruction for purposes of title XIX of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/590">6 U.S.C. 590 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3253D487872046D393A1FFD42C7FAFC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>illicit fentanyl</term> means fentanyl and any analogue thereof that is manufactured, distributed, or dispensed, or possessed with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, in violation of section 401, 406, or 416 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>, 846, 856).</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H232D987F30144D75BE6AC5121B3AEE09"><enum>4.</enum><header>Assessment regarding illicit fentanyl</header> 
<subsection id="HCCF4E820B9274ECC9C807A68ADFAC2B1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The head of the Office of National Drug Control Policy, in consultation with the heads of such other Federal agencies as the head of the Office of National Drug Control Policy deems appropriate, shall conduct an assessment of the following:</text> <paragraph id="HF0E4BF0ACF8F418F94666C3CF148E9EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Foreign manufacturing of illicit fentanyl.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6EDB743E04674F3F81655D5EA969FB94"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The tools and capabilities across Federal agencies to address trafficking of illicit fentanyl.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7DB688DE47364255AD66F2243BACE3CD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>How coordination of Federal efforts to address such trafficking can be improved, including identification of duplicative Federal efforts.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA6D9CC8923734BE6AC72F30D04758E98"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The capacities of the Mexican military to conduct counterdrug missions with respect to illicit fentanyl.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2E9860898FB4A90AE466D85CB27A21C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capacities and willingness of the People’s Republic of China to curtail the flow of illicit fentanyl, conduct inspections and investigations with respect to illicit fentanyl, screen for illicit fentanyl at ports of exit, implement <quote>know-your-customer</quote> standards, and hold traffickers of illicit fentanyl accountable.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H082AFA83F70B4FD2AF1C7A32263D7C07"><enum>(6)</enum><text><italic></italic>Illicit fentanyl being trafficked into the United States from Mexico, including the purity, formulation, and weight of the illicit fentanyl.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDE562C78F06A4F61AFECBFFCFBF16C78"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing; report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the head of the Office of National Drug Control Policy shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H6DE9A1935B4E4A73A569E9037D6A29AA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>complete the assessment required by subsection (a); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9B937A05F10942B5B5F8C2B613380056"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit a report to the Congress on the results of such assessment.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A4B90690283499F99EF5C6EE8FF1D03"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>illicit fentanyl</term> means fentanyl and any analogue or precursor thereof that is manufactured, distributed, or dispensed, or possessed with intent to manufacture, distribute, or dispense, in violation of section 401, 406, or 416 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/841">21 U.S.C. 841</external-xref>, 846, 856).</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

