<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6DA747C1C2074B19A49BF0DD1B72481A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7144 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a feedback tool for use by members of the Armed Forces and their spouses to identify, rate, and compare housing, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7144</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a feedback tool for use by members of the Armed Forces and their spouses to identify, rate, and compare housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE5E3692E3C094205A05BA2A107C82B0D" style="OLC"><section id="HC4723D80753F4F8187629CE09AA1472D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Military housing feedback tool</header><subsection id="H00A232EFD7B3467583348FC2B5DC602E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall develop a feedback tool, such as a rating system or similar mechanism, under which members of the Armed Forces and their spouses may anonymously identify, rate, and compare housing under the jurisdiction of the Department of Defense (including privatized military housing).</text></subsection><subsection id="H89EDDF0B597846918F23A3541EFF5E0D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The tool required under subsection (a) shall include the following components:</text><paragraph id="H809F84BEB46941AFB4AA2267F06DE6F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The capability for users to—</text><subparagraph id="HC06F97E9F4604FBC9AEC728FAC18FB8F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>rate housing using multiple quality measures, including safety, the timeliness and quality of maintenance services, and the responsiveness of management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCC881A1CC3674E7F8DC5BA8FF768C6D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upload visual media, including images; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BE06A8386B44925832146C59F729BD9"><enum>(C)</enum><text> include written comments.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D262529C90F4EE18B5C30FA7E2AB743"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A comparison feature that can be used to compare ratings for different housing communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H29A8EDE3518B43D1BB1FE7EC2D797A6B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Accessibility by members of the Armed Forces, their family members, and members of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H75B78D431DAF4F349D6B158AF54B8CC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and House of Representatives, and make available to the Secretary of each of the military departments, an annual report that includes a summary of the data collected using the feedback tool required under this section during the year covered by the report. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

