<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H25EE336118944DBFB5960DC4A84ED263" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 923 EH: Georgia Support Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 923</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To support the independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity of the Republic of Georgia, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HB9683D83FE3743AFA8B055B958DB565D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H08BCE6BD7A4D48D89F31F52DB9FAD4B9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title and table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HB22D1B10BDD148A98A0F163387140726"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Georgia Support Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H7328BEDC58784C4EBDC2D9E2F873A790"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry idref="H08BCE6BD7A4D48D89F31F52DB9FAD4B9" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title and table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H71FF03FA821148339F8AB16F055364D4" level="section">Sec. 2. United States policy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7122937FFA3F40B0827E42A0DCE3D64D" level="title">Title I—Assistance Provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H7870DEEEF1E142149356200E259CD213" level="section">Sec. 101. United States-Georgia security assistance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H59324BB5ACBA4F3BA38BEE4B3A1110E2" level="section">Sec. 102. Report on United States democracy and governance assistance to Georgia.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HF2ABF98F0C944D778EC6AE6FD25C1EE8" level="section">Sec. 103. United States cybersecurity cooperation with Georgia.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H599FAA16245D483E874F58CAFD5018DB" level="section">Sec. 104. Enhanced assistance to combat Russian disinformation and propaganda.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H444E74D57E7F4625880C27BE98951B42" level="title">Title II—Sanctions Provisions</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H456420F5F2B141D497E19D75679D4E59" level="section">Sec. 201. Imposition of sanctions on persons complicit in or responsible for serious human rights abuses, including right to life in Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia occupied by Russia.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3089732A59504F50AE0E70689892391E" level="title">Title III—Determination of Budgetary Effects</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H986B667516BB4213948FA9D955F47145" level="section">Sec. 301. Determination of budgetary effects.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="H71FF03FA821148339F8AB16F055364D4"><enum>2.</enum><header>United States policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text> <paragraph id="HD60F59BB5934448D8154CDC9CE305A27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>support continued development of democratic values in the Republic of Georgia, including free and fair elections, an independent and accountable judiciary, public sector transparency and accountability, the rule of law, and anticorruption efforts;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3BCE54E4857247E89FF6C347902501F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support Georgia’s sovereignty, independence, and territorial integrity within its internationally recognized borders;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF9E1BFF361304999B9F3CD093035D94D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support Georgia’s capacity to protect its sovereignty and territorial integrity from further Russian aggression or encroachment on Georgian territory in light of Russia’s full-scale invasion of Ukraine;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCE59B26DA196473B96215CF44E1F3197"><enum>(4)</enum><text>support the right of the people of Georgia to freely determine their future and make independent and sovereign choices on foreign and security policy, including regarding their country’s relationship with other nations and international organizations, without interference, intimidation, or coercion by other countries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CC0C25FFAB74AFA8CAC18315D51C65E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>support Georgia’s Euro-Atlantic and European integration;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0844C9D6C659473E89FA65FCEB9B3DD4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not recognize territorial changes effected by force, including the illegal invasions and occupations of Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia by the Russian Federation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF58843A240884E488FEB0371AE6800C5"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">condemn ongoing detentions, kidnappings, and other human rights violations committed in the Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia forcibly occupied by the Russian Federation, including the recent killings of Georgian citizens Archil Tatunashvili, Giga Otkhozoria, Davit Basharuli, and others in the Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE6DAD03E80F34FF995662420B65B1CCA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>support peaceful conflict resolution in Georgia, including by urging the Russian Federation to fully implement the European Union-mediated ceasefire agreement of August 12, 2008, and supporting the establishment of international security mechanisms in the Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia and the safe and dignified return of internally displaced persons (IDPs) and refugees, all of which are important for lasting peace and security on the ground.</text></paragraph></section> <title id="H7122937FFA3F40B0827E42A0DCE3D64D"><enum>I</enum><header>Assistance Provisions</header> <section id="H7870DEEEF1E142149356200E259CD213"><enum>101.</enum><header>United States-Georgia security assistance</header> <subsection id="H8C4319E83C364414A088EFD5E908660C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9FFE9B74FAC9483BAFA2241ED221173F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In fiscal year 2021, the United States provided Georgia with $2,200,000 in assistance under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2347">22 U.S.C. 2347 et seq.</external-xref>; relating to international military education and training) and $35,000,000 in assistance under section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>; relating to the Foreign Military Financing Program) and in 2021 announced the Georgia Defense and Deterrence Enhancement Initiative (GDDEI) to enable further modernization of the Georgian Ministry of Defense and the Georgian Defense Forces.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA406D4AAAE884959861FBA7AAD273F38"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Georgia has been a longstanding NATO-aspirant country.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H353D0D87C59F451D999646C1019049D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Georgia has contributed substantially to Euro-Atlantic peace and security through participation in the International Security Assistance Force (ISAF) and Resolute Support Missions in Afghanistan as one of the largest troop contributors.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2073371F94184283ABF364C98A8DF5F4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that United States assistance to the Republic of Georgia under chapter 5 of part II of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act should be increased.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HCA5A52711F23435FBD2138514D2C646D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States, in consultation with the Republic of Georgia, to enhance Georgia’s deterrence, resilience, and self-defense, including through appropriate assistance to improve the capabilities of Georgia’s armed forces.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8F35ADE473A648798118CEB888EDE407"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review of security assistance to Georgia</header> <paragraph id="H373B1E6C1D184D6088A9975702D8BD7A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate United States departments and agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report reviewing United States security assistance to the Republic of Georgia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3F5869B9602F4EA1888C4F3E35984B85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HAFA56BCCEF324032A0DA2761BBA78843"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of needed security assistance to improve Georgia’s capacity to defend its sovereignty and territorial integrity from further invasion of Georgian territory by Russian forces, including an assessment of need for anti-armor, anti-air, and anti-tank weapons, as well as intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance capabilities.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9BCAF3C1A3CA4B4A8BC7A966DF3D18D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A detailed review of all United States security assistance to Georgia from fiscal year 2008 to the date of the submission of such report.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H449510282C96420CB9E42C95D21C5F86"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of threats to Georgian independence, sovereignty, and territorial integrity, including an assessment of changes to the force posture or intent of Russian forces occupying Georgian territory.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8A7365FD6D224D7A94EF44DFEBFCDEB9"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of Georgia’s capabilities to defend itself, including a five-year strategy to enhance Georgia’s deterrence, resilience, and self-defense capabilities that incorporates plans to address the capability gaps subject to the assessment described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8661F53C02FF439D8607752742157DF3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H59324BB5ACBA4F3BA38BEE4B3A1110E2"><enum>102.</enum><header>Report on United States democracy and governance assistance to Georgia</header> 
<subsection id="H18BAB9BEB2D14658ABD7A47BB50094E3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate Federal departments and agencies as appropriate, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on United States democracy and governance assistance to the Republic of Georgia.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H036492CFB2B54EBBAED8259A7FC0D5F6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H456E3DC97A3F4E069CECAD4AEF6BC782"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of goals for United States democracy and governance assistance to Georgia and its democratic institutions, including how such assistance is supporting Georgia’s stated goals for European integration. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCF7A4386D86A4DF4A644250C515281F4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact of United States democracy and governance assistance to Georgia since fiscal year 2008, including challenges to achieving the goals described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3DD1159BB4424605ACE0322870E37A9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of Georgia’s progress relating to freedom of the press and support for independent media, including steps to hold accountable those responsible for attacks on independent media and on LGBTQ rights activists on July 5, 2021, in Tbilisi.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF43733C545B44D728ADA435F5D28CE22"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An assessment of Georgia’s progress on strengthening its democratic institutions, including through electoral and judicial reforms necessary to build public confidence.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2FFFB8436EFD4A7B835FC4D6B7CDE641"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of barriers and challenges to United States investment in the Georgian economy, as well as an assessment of how support from the United States International Development Finance Corporation in Georgia could help create a better developed and more transparent investment climate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2DBF9BF6A7A445088F23F1F8BFAED454"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF2ABF98F0C944D778EC6AE6FD25C1EE8"><enum>103.</enum><header>United States cybersecurity cooperation with Georgia</header> 
<subsection id="H833A5AF6702F4DC284273361E463727F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of State should take the following actions, commensurate with United States interests, to assist the Repubic of Georgia to improve its cybersecurity:</text> <paragraph id="H9F4D4BB79B614C6092398C3857CAB9A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Provide Georgia such support as may be necessary to secure government computer networks from malicious cyber intrusions, particularly such networks that defend the critical infrastructure of Georgia.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6C0B783B3B534B579E977299A0D651C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Provide Georgia support in reducing reliance on Russian information and communications technology.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8387C1ECF473417DA044B8147813D342"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Assist Georgia to build its capacity, expand cybersecurity information sharing, and cooperate on international cyberspace efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F60B381BC8A4BEFB8FF368838B89192"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="HA2313D0A94494B9890D7B214D692664E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on United States cybersecurity cooperation with the Republic of Georgia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79366CF8D6794058B0573704A7E86882"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters to be included</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include information relating to the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HBBCC4DD5354641B695043B0B5BC21118"><enum>(A)</enum><text>United States efforts to strengthen Georgia’s ability to prevent, mitigate, and respond to cyber incidents, including through training, education, technical assistance, capacity building, and cybersecurity risk management strategies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD63A08D4EEE74DB19EA4A1E7B1E56E75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The potential for new areas of collaboration and mutual assistance between the United States and Georgia to address shared cyber challenges, including cybercrime, critical infrastructure protection, and resilience against automated, distributed threats.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE4283A8731064B91AA828899E35F04E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>NATO’s efforts to help Georgia develop technical capabilities to counter cyber threats.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H599FAA16245D483E874F58CAFD5018DB"><enum>104.</enum><header>Enhanced assistance to combat Russian disinformation and propaganda</header> <subsection id="H7704E72AF5364FB5926728B4B5C2BC56"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It shall be the policy of the United States to enhance the capabilities of the Republic of Georgia to combat Russian disinformation and propaganda campaigns intended to undermine the sovereignty and democratic institutions of Georgia, while promoting the freedom of the press.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF8BB3BEFE17842E098A6AFA5BEE0A8CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required strategy</header> 
<paragraph id="HC7CD4284411244198517C28E4CF56C6D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the heads of other appropriate United States departments and agencies, shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report outlining a strategy to implement the policy described in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H451E3DDACA6640B7B9C0145A37DA919A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Components</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB4E533EB196C426A8581CBA54C2BEDFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A detailed assessment of Russian disinformation and propaganda efforts across all media platforms targeting the Republic of Georgia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9D8BD4B26CD44C09B21EC170EFCA5B1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of Georgia’s capabilities to deter and combat such Russian efforts and to support the freedom of the press.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03E20EF9311D4CD5B28054DFB9EB23BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A detailed strategy coordinated across all relevant United States departments and agencies to enhance Georgia’s capabilities to deter and combat such Russian efforts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H20E5316E6E8D4F368C4E7FAF3EA4529A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form but may contain a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </title> 
<title id="H444E74D57E7F4625880C27BE98951B42"><enum>II</enum><header>Sanctions Provisions</header> 
<section id="H456420F5F2B141D497E19D75679D4E59"><enum>201.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions on persons complicit in or responsible for serious human rights abuses, including right to life in Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia occupied by Russia</header> 
<subsection id="H65A2E214E204485C92B64AB81DCC3F0B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President shall impose on a foreign person the sanctions described in subsection (b) if the President determines that such foreign person, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H07C7DBDE9D8C4E819A48FE8E6CA3D31C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for, complicit in, or responsible for ordering, controlling, or otherwise directing the commission of serious human rights abuses in the Georgian regions of Abkhazia and Tskhinvali Region/South Ossetia forcibly occupied by the Russian Federation;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC84260E7FB8841DB901FABEA8E5E7376"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is materially assisting, sponsoring, or providing significant financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to, a foreign person described in paragraph (1); or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA46E3C710A7B42F39EC38852359396BF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by a foreign person, or is acting on behalf of a foreign person, described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA3A0A26440D840369316514A97FA427F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text> <paragraph id="H09FDE6EDB3AA4A148632DE16085E72ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Asset blocking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exercise of all powers granted to the President by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of a person determined by the President to be a person described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person, including by taking any of the actions described in paragraph (1) of section 203(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1702">50 U.S.C. 1702(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9487DF4E992E45A183381FA22020F10C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inadmissibility of certain individuals</header> 
<subparagraph id="H9D6322C14BF64F73B4AA4F90F5EF31EE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Ineligibility for visas and admission to the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person determined by the President to be a person described in subsection (a) is—</text> <clause id="H23AD68D22FA74A27B1EE7C9EF16412E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause> 
<clause id="HCB20AA7930754EEFA800A1C4D1A00315"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause> <clause id="H7ACC76B412EE4B4F8E4A5AC5D703C1AB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC57EC56CE96F486C8721C24029EBAA25"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person determined by the President to be a person described in subsection (a) is subject to the following:</text> <clause id="H1DD561357E0340A3A67B38CAC50988CF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Revocation of any visa or other entry documentation regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H545CE20E364240A1969C7C7CEF18940F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text> <subclause id="HEDFFF716EEAD45129DDE87DC477A68BA"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HF6A31109814B496CA7099168B333FDBE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the foreign person’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3A761F8C4CC4778876F639E653D8956"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception to comply with United Nations Headquarters Agreement and law enforcement objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Sanctions under subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an individual if admitting such individual into the United States would further important law enforcement objectives or is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H3E69B0E5800C4831882D9BFF2FE3431E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive the application of sanctions under subsection (b) with respect to a person if the President determines that such a waiver is important to the national interests of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H51D5FCDC8BED45ABAA99994FD9E29D80"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation; penalties</header> <paragraph id="H785FB2DF20F24D8F842274500C32AA0C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF37E2318C29B406A9FC4F27BB3B483AD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of subsection (b)(1) or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out such subsection shall be subject to the penalties specified in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H7A826B75B09D49FEB982D499BAFA7942"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act and at least once every 180 days thereafter for a period not to exceed two years, the President, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall transmit to Congress a detailed report with respect to persons that have been determined to have engaged in activities described in subsection (a).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0219370A635540018EDC9715D62F3197"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header> 
<paragraph id="HFCD981B8D7F941BFBC86582D7487A18A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities and requirements to impose sanctions under this title shall not include the authority or requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BCBF810A3D44A1F8D8718C95C41C804"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment and excluding technical data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </title> 
<title id="H3089732A59504F50AE0E70689892391E"><enum>III</enum><header>Determination of Budgetary Effects</header> 
<section id="H986B667516BB4213948FA9D955F47145"><enum>301.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></title> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220427" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives April 27, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

