<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H207E7B82A4C14417B6243383638A1019" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6745 IH: Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6745</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Small Business</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish or modify requirements relating to minority depository institutions, community development financial institutions, and impact banks, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB494C3D7B5EA451F9ECCC356AC77E513" style="OLC"><section id="HC6A469C2E2064C99953A4EF83F079990" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HAAF7B5BB17554B56B578093552B81122"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9DDBE4F9C6EB4EABBA1758847990F621"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HC6A469C2E2064C99953A4EF83F079990" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAFB8D30E98E04EAA86A6DEAF85F79242" level="section">Sec. 2. Sense of Congress on funding the loan-loss reserve fund for small dollar loans.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAA5096E656F0454287362A84A22179F4" level="section">Sec. 3. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7E022E85BE6F4C2FB54364443D7AC647" level="section">Sec. 4. Inclusion of women’s banks in the definition of minority depository institution.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H833D9C38921C486FBF5F7400F41CFAFF" level="section">Sec. 5. Establishment of impact bank designation.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0A4A64D36B944AA9ACD9F6ABF6A1BF91" level="section">Sec. 6. Minority Depositories Advisory Committees.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H7EE90F3FFC1E4DB99B56FE81B782F46A" level="section">Sec. 7. Federal deposits in minority depository institutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H360DAE5E98EA47F594D666D9377286B1" level="section">Sec. 8. Minority Bank Deposit Program.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFB25B684E5FD41F1905334C8D1F80D6D" level="section">Sec. 9. Diversity report and best practices.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB83F1DC220FD4D949AEC26E52A88C288" level="section">Sec. 10. Investments in minority depository institutions and impact banks.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF8F4C48CA9CB458EAC2566B72B6926AE" level="section">Sec. 11. Report on covered mentor-protege programs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA33516B3D14F44DDBC651696BED709B5" level="section">Sec. 12. Custodial deposit program for covered minority depository institutions and impact banks.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H14D7EB2A40A3480794665F0DDB403AF3" level="section">Sec. 13. Streamlined community development financial institution applications and reporting.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2F34C2F3918C41FAB9A5DB06143EA9B5" level="section">Sec. 14. Task force on lending to small business concerns.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HAFB8D30E98E04EAA86A6DEAF85F79242" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on funding the loan-loss reserve fund for small dollar loans</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The sense of Congress is the following: </text><paragraph id="H65E8EA9773374750A32483A508CB0E40" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Community Development Financial Institutions Fund (the <quote>CDFI Fund</quote>) is an agency of the Department of the Treasury, and was established by the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994. The mission of the CDFI Fund is <quote>to expand economic opportunity for underserved people and communities by supporting the growth and capacity of a national network of community development lenders, investors, and financial service providers</quote>. A community development financial institution (a <quote>CDFI</quote>) is a specialized financial institution serving low-income communities and a Community Development Entity (a <quote>CDE</quote>) is a domestic corporation or partnership that is an intermediary vehicle for the provision of loans, investments, or financial counseling in low-income communities. The CDFI Fund certifies CDFIs and CDEs. Becoming a certified CDFI or CDE allows organizations to participate in various CDFI Fund programs as follows:</text><subparagraph id="HD5EB6151E1BB481A9C3D0F6AA92BAF0D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Bank Enterprise Award Program, which provides FDIC-insured depository institutions awards for a demonstrated increase in lending and investments in distressed communities and CDFIs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE86F97A76DD44CBAB6E880B99A5B588" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The CDFI Program, which provides Financial and Technical Assistance awards to CDFIs to reinvest in the CDFI, and to build the capacity of the CDFI, including financing product development and loan loss reserves.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB1DCD5DD11A4DC38E48586CCB51D54D" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Native American CDFI Assistance Program, which provides CDFIs and sponsoring entities Financial and Technical Assistance awards to increase lending and grow the number of CDFIs owned by Native Americans to help build capacity of such CDFIs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC35A6FD165184D71839240BA1AE26EB1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The New Market Tax Credit Program, which provides tax credits for making equity investments in CDEs that stimulate capital investments in low-income communities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85EB9CEA37BE48ED812F9B74D0B3A56A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Capital Magnet Fund, which provides awards to CDFIs and nonprofit affordable housing organizations to finance affordable housing solutions and related economic development activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02C5C96708B24A65843EF32ADECF189F" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Bond Guarantee Program, a source of long-term, patient capital for CDFIs to expand lending and investment capacity for community and economic development purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A1135FC34ED40E7A7A5844A91F7AEC6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury is authorized to create multi-year grant programs designed to encourage low-to-moderate income individuals to establish accounts at federally insured banks, and to improve low-to-moderate income individuals’ access to such accounts on reasonable terms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H954D72C751284E3C90F904993BE1B3CB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Under this authority, grants to participants in CDFI Fund programs may be used for loan-loss reserves and to establish small-dollar loan programs by subsidizing related losses. These grants also allow for the providing recipients with the financial counseling and education necessary to conduct transactions and manage their accounts. These loans provide low-cost alternatives to payday loans and other nontraditional forms of financing that often impose excessive interest rates and fees on borrowers, and lead millions of Americans to fall into debt traps. Small-dollar loans can only be made pursuant to terms, conditions, and practices that are reasonable for the individual consumer obtaining the loan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADCABC70E9824C8C83F67EF64B89E566" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Program participation is restricted to eligible institutions, which are limited to organizations listed in section 501(c)(3) of the Internal Revenue Code and exempt from tax under 501(a) of such Code, federally insured depository institutions, community development financial institutions and State, local, or Tribal government entities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBBEC479C0684C058824326BAEC67235" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>According to the CDFI Fund, some programs attract as much as $10 in private capital for every $1 invested by the CDFI Fund. The Administration and the Congress should prioritize appropriation of funds for the loan loss reserve fund and technical assistance programs administered by the Community Development Financial Institution Fund.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HAA5096E656F0454287362A84A22179F4"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act: </text><paragraph id="H418EC8AC018341BCB1B332C2A4BB3976"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Community development financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community development financial institution</term> has the meaning given under section 103 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/4702">12 U.S.C. 4702</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA8C1C3DD84441A8ACABAB1E5E0D5DB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minority depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority depository institution</term> has the meaning given under section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note), as amended by this Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7E022E85BE6F4C2FB54364443D7AC647"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inclusion of women’s banks in the definition of minority depository institution</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 308(b)(1) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3D21F86E134049A5B231D90432D58D48"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) as clauses (i), (ii), and (iii), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6FB7AEE51384D8F88151AE9FFE0E9CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>means any</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H055F3299DF0E457FB94DDE04728D07EB" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text>means—</text><paragraph id="HD36434ACB3D740A79B676A9A1386E605"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H93AE9642E3E44EC097801A61A939B1D2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in clause (iii) (as so redesignated), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6B89FAC542F4EDFBE0434E71FB4237C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H8A5254CD21064C57AA23A0D4559594F3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HF215C28C691C4AE6B8E72C9EE08D0223"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any bank described in clause (i), (ii), or (iii) of section 19(b)(1)(A) of the Federal Reserve Act—</text><clause id="H84BECF67B4984775A21C2A5EF662166B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">more than 50 percent of the outstanding shares of which are held by 1 or more women; and</text></clause><clause id="H8EC95EBE86174EA789AEBECE568C505D" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the majority of the directors on the board of directors of which are women.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H833D9C38921C486FBF5F7400F41CFAFF"><enum>5.</enum><header>Establishment of impact bank designation</header><subsection id="HEC2839CDB5EB4EDEA23551CC504A8998"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal banking agency shall establish a program under which a depository institution with total consolidated assets of less than $10,000,000,000 may elect to be designated as an impact bank if the total dollar value of the loans extended by such depository institution to low-income borrowers is greater than or equal to 50 percent of the assets of such bank.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8A311723473D466081B3F4951298F59B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification of eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on data obtained through examinations of depository institutions, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall notify a depository institution if the institution is eligible to be designated as an impact bank.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA01B682E9EA049DF87B164FE16887F5D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Regardless of whether or not it has received a notice of eligibility under subsection (b), a depository institution may submit an application to the appropriate Federal banking agency—</text><paragraph id="H59CB8B4B1E11464196B054FBBB12D685"><enum>(1)</enum><text>requesting to be designated as an impact bank; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C035E58769941BC8B66EA9639722C5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>demonstrating that the depository institution meets the applicable qualifications.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H66222BF88B6E442E8A1FA3AB4342776D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation on additional data requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking agencies may only impose additional data collection requirements on a depository institution under this section if such data is—</text><paragraph id="H5A17F9359B2D402CAA7CF7F7BB107102"><enum>(1)</enum><text>necessary to process an application submitted by the depository institution to be designated an impact bank; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0EC08AA30EC14D26913FEBAAEB0AA355"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to a depository institution that is designated as an impact bank, necessary to ensure the depository institution’s ongoing qualifications to maintain such designation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EF6ABC2D35E414ABC9D3B2A43AD4B09"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Removal of designation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the appropriate Federal banking agency determines that a depository institution designated as an impact bank no longer meets the criteria for such designation, the appropriate Federal banking agency shall rescind the designation and notify the depository institution of such rescission. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC7BD3FB58196453593436BC95FB7B1FF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reconsideration of designation; appeals</header><text>Under such procedures as the Federal banking agencies may establish, a depository institution may—</text><paragraph id="H9E1DE0C311584FAD8F4BBD6737DE5C85"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the appropriate Federal banking agency a request to reconsider a determination that such depository institution no longer meets the criteria for the designation; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78E176BAE9C0490D9D58144C95421196"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">file an appeal of such determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40FA4E6DF796464CB8679FD4B54569BE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal banking agencies shall jointly issue rules to carry out the requirements of this section, including by providing a definition of a low-income borrower.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5D7B512EB904FBEA1AC98EC8B8F9977"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Federal banking agency shall submit an annual report to the Congress containing a description of actions taken to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEBBFE7B05C874FB194220D346BA2C715"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Federal Deposit Insurance Act definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <term>depository institution</term>, <term>appropriate Federal banking agency</term>, and <quote>Federal banking agency</quote> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section><section id="H0A4A64D36B944AA9ACD9F6ABF6A1BF91"><enum>6.</enum><header>Minority Depositories Advisory Committees</header><subsection id="H584F3C118A094EE0B857ADE76F4AFA92"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered regulator shall establish an advisory committee to be called the <quote>Minority Depositories Advisory Committee</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE230EAC422A468FA17EE4DC0CE59507"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Minority Depositories Advisory Committee shall provide advice to the respective covered regulator on meeting the goals established by section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note) to preserve the present number of covered minority institutions, preserve the minority character of minority-owned institutions in cases involving mergers or acquisitions, provide technical assistance, and encourage the creation of new covered minority institutions. The scope of the work of each such Minority Depositories Advisory Committee shall include an assessment of the current condition of covered minority institutions, what regulatory changes or other steps the respective agencies may be able to take to fulfill the requirements of such section 308, and other issues of concern to covered minority institutions.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC5F588A3E19746C9997387C404DE0C01"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Membership</header><paragraph id="H20AEC3569D7240FEA74BCBFB93AB6F85"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each Minority Depositories Advisory Committee shall consist of no more than 10 members, who—</text><subparagraph id="H66B8C60AD782476EBE0B542F80F762EF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall serve for one two-year term;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CB1C08EA2A048A28CE0B622B3AC64DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall serve as a representative of a depository institution or an insured credit union with respect to which the respective covered regulator is the covered regulator of such depository institution or insured credit union; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF657CE00C8534810B6130C7DAC1513CF"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not receive pay by reason of their service on the advisory committee, but may receive travel or transportation expenses in accordance with section 5703 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C2E89C2A6AB400B83ABC265B3E92459"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Diversity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, each covered regulator shall ensure that the members of the Minority Depositories Advisory Committee of such agency reflect the diversity of covered minority institutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2750A86978F74F42A0378CF39917DC60"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Meetings</header><paragraph id="H68C155BE24E346318F2E21C7D1B1E245"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Minority Depositories Advisory Committee shall meet not less frequently than twice each year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0BC583C9822A46A3A7274D29267C8E25"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice and invitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Minority Depositories Advisory Committee shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF2DE1C89700C493E9C6767C4B4A07B6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">notify the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate in advance of each meeting of the Minority Depositories Advisory Committee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0BBF58D43CE4ED79F18BB3215D02F71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>invite the attendance at each meeting of the Minority Depositories Advisory Committee of—</text><clause id="H2FE913C1F1634FC58B59946A06694603"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one member of the majority party and one member of the minority party of the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="HDF160CCD36984C6AA9A34E94E60F8FF4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one member of the majority party and one member of the minority party of any relevant subcommittees of such committees.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5091A4EF94F407C90A49E5C5F7F16B9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No termination of advisory committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The termination requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Federal Advisory Committee Act /14">section 14</external-xref> of the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. app.) shall not apply to a Minority Depositories Advisory Committee established pursuant to this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC7218D8B7A69400ABB5210FAF5EE6415"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H953D0310E2274E88B441705D427E1CCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered regulator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered regulator</term> means the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EE1C66100934FE99746E94232D275E3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered minority institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered minority institution</term> means a minority depository institution (as defined in section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8139C3DFC474BD9A535A9601CE7F553"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text>The term <term>depository institution</term> has the meaning given under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H91D7692FE4F9457197A20A68914560B6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Insured credit union</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>insured credit union</term> has the meaning given in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED5FED1229EE42F3B221DC3391BEB06F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1C9A40610A434D9BB883DBC1E2FC3CD7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HFFA96F89A80A4CCD98F1718443718D0C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>depository institution</term> means an <term>insured depository institution</term> (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>)) and an insured credit union (as defined in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>)). </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H7EE90F3FFC1E4DB99B56FE81B782F46A"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal deposits in minority depository institutions</header><subsection id="H63F607AD31F44E19B0487BFCF2C786EE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H485BEA59CA9F40D3B4A02956E6A77887"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H06CD77A39058433EB69D5BBE2DF05E67" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H2220DB78D4F848419A70076A60F279FD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall ensure that deposits made by Federal agencies in minority depository institutions and impact banks are collateralized or insured, as determined by the Secretary. Such deposits shall include reciprocal deposits as defined in section 337.6(e)(2)(v) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on March 6, 2019).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H6613E9554CBF4EF1841651A1BD4BBE29"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b), as amended by section 6(g), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H15ACFD7219164ED2A1BF97392BAE7EBA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HB29EAA2E11C644E58B1D48F65B64CF96"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Impact bank</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>impact bank</term> means a depository institution designated by the appropriate Federal banking agency pursuant to section 5 of the Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H970A264B207C4B80991054213C3720B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA563A12CF68B4FED9D80838B1E940D09"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>section—</quote> and inserting <quote>section:</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H661DF0412A6F412482E82A5BEDFEE430"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the paragraph heading for paragraph (1), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">financial</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">depository</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H360DAE5E98EA47F594D666D9377286B1" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Minority Bank Deposit Program</header><subsection id="H7C134CC2292D4B09988365E08FB0D58B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1204 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1811">12 U.S.C. 1811</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H906CFECBAAB641E7A5E509064E15E254" style="OLC"><section id="HEA6AA0A6819646EBA4EC3028229F4A1D" commented="no"><enum>1204.</enum><header>Expansion of use of minority depository institutions</header><subsection id="HA7A1AFC4C76940FAA35BAEE701895BA4" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Minority Bank Deposit Program</header><paragraph id="H626321F0E0E44BB2A43DE70297A3193D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established a program to be known as the <quote>Minority Bank Deposit Program</quote> to expand the use of minority depository institutions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB82398B7C1DD4B4CA35F41B22213A75C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, acting through the Fiscal Service, shall—</text><subparagraph id="H7EDDAE477EC549A38CECDD99D0C5FA86" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on application by a depository institution or credit union, certify whether such depository institution or credit union is a minority depository institution;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE25BCD1F60E4E1294E94AAB8A4E1D63" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>maintain and publish a list of all depository institutions and credit unions that have been certified pursuant to subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H529179199C59465D83A0B940C8AC160E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>periodically distribute the list described in subparagraph (B) to—</text><clause id="H4DFB8B3B7CBF47F398A2AF5B446348B5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all Federal departments and agencies;</text></clause><clause id="H26A15E6C0A5A4D09BDAE1D30130BCE24" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>interested State and local governments; and</text></clause><clause id="HD2AECE72D4DA4A99871F78D7488AD9AB" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>interested private sector companies.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H47D8109E88D04D01AFAB13B9679E3C4B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of certain entities on list</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A depository institution or credit union that, on the date of the enactment of this section, has a current certification from the Secretary of the Treasury stating that such depository institution or credit union is a minority depository institution shall be included on the list described under paragraph (2)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD1969E1F11934EEBBB1C1AB3450D532A" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Expanded Use Among Federal Departments and Agencies</header><paragraph id="H33BE5F32C7F94A00927B66AABAB4DDB5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the establishment of the program described in subsection (a), the head of each Federal department or agency shall develop and implement standards and procedures to prioritize, to the maximum extent possible as permitted by law and consistent with principles of sound financial management, the use of minority depository institutions to hold the deposits of each such department or agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3FDAD580A2C470F961B226BBE552129" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the establishment of the program described in subsection (a), and annually thereafter, the head of each Federal department or agency shall submit to Congress a report on the actions taken to increase the use of minority depository institutions to hold the deposits of each such department or agency.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8662B04290EE42C1B45EFCEC6E900BC8" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>For purposes of this section:</text><paragraph id="H35D0214E83FE4A8E8283ECA558778247" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Credit union</header><text>The term <term>credit union</term> has the meaning given the term <term>insured credit union</term> in section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1752">12 U.S.C. 1752</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H491860EC0BDF43B3953057456E6DC28D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text>The term <term>depository institution</term> has the meaning given in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H753394ADAE30479A888955B6A4FACB91" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minority depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority depository institution</term> has the meaning given that term under section 308 of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4C49B8AF1BFB4CF7B1D4AD4FBA624AC3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming Amendments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following provisions are amended by striking <quote>1204(c)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>1204(c)</quote>:</text><paragraph id="H80FAD56997A348F69E945DDAD7B9AF33" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 808(b)(3) of the Community Reinvestment Act of 1977 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/2907">12 U.S.C. 2907(b)(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D49BBDB39564DC7A3C2A40936505679" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 40(g)(1)(B) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1831q">12 U.S.C. 1831q(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A8C94682D7C4452A4C32C8D6AFFECD9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 704B(h)(4) of the Equal Credit Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1691c-2">15 U.S.C. 1691c–2(h)(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFB25B684E5FD41F1905334C8D1F80D6D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Diversity report and best practices</header><subsection id="H20EB0A56F5C7446D93EC10141A37A6E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each covered regulator shall submit to Congress an annual report on diversity including the following:</text><paragraph id="HCEF9624355F04D94ACD392EA8734F410"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Data, based on voluntary self-identification, on the racial, ethnic, and gender composition of the examiners of each covered regulator, disaggregated by length of time served as an examiner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7CA55BEF76CE42189C022A6FB62751FB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The status of any examiners of covered regulators, based on voluntary self-identification, as a veteran.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C7E15D7B3434823BFC6CC38B8D2793A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any covered regulator, as of the date on which the report required under this section is submitted, has adopted a policy, plan, or strategy to promote racial, ethnic, and gender diversity among examiners of the covered regulator.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA92EC35EA8AC49BA95EBB8B05BD40428"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether any special training is developed and provided for examiners related specifically to working with depository institutions and credit unions that serve communities that are predominantly minorities, low income, or rural, and the key focus of such training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC001B0249304BF48BCE923916E3B15F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each Office of Minority and Women Inclusion of a covered regulator shall develop, provide to the head of the covered regulator, and make publicly available best practices—</text><paragraph id="HC0A29755AFA84F108B4E2FD85E7F0B5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>for increasing the diversity of candidates applying for examiner positions, including through outreach efforts to recruit diverse candidate to apply for entry-level examiner positions; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E4FDEE7B01E43CFB33F68CF5439D12C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>for retaining and providing fair consideration for promotions within the examiner staff for purposes of achieving diversity among examiners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H01835982E71E4A6BA47F1306ED111DB4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Covered regulator defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>covered regulator</term> means the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, and the National Credit Union Administration.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB83F1DC220FD4D949AEC26E52A88C288" commented="no"><enum>10.</enum><header>Investments in minority depository institutions and impact banks</header><subsection id="HBFD9AEFC664B4E629AA1D13CE224FB8D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Control for certain institutions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 7(j)(8)(B) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1817">12 U.S.C. 1817(j)(8)(B)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBFBD2F4B903B480DBB60ECAD0DE3D928" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H5C37C0C44DE142F2B282DFF01824FF7D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>control</quote> means the power, directly or indirectly—</text><clause id="H1BE654C656B44107A30EDCF80500D98E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to direct the management or policies of an insured depository institution; or</text></clause><clause id="H63BD4D4AEC78453D8F2D08DB45764533"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBCCCBF1DC73B42BE8D195EEF59124A55"><enum>(I)</enum><text>with respect to an insured depository institution, of a person to vote 25 per centum or more of any class of voting securities of such institution; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA03B7F0339C84DA380174CD72A55DC34" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to an insured depository institution that is an impact bank (as designated pursuant to section 5 of the Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act) or a minority depository institution (as defined in section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989), of an individual to vote 30 percent or more of any class of voting securities of such an impact bank or a minority depository institution.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9613C1EAF9C74D798E00AE085001218B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Federal banking agencies (as defined in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1813">12 U.S.C. 1813</external-xref>)) shall jointly issue rules for de novo minority depository institutions and de novo impact banks (as designated pursuant to section 5) to allow 3 years to meet the capital requirements otherwise applicable to minority depository institutions and impact banks.</text></subsection><subsection id="H329BA90F30F64A79A4D91D6D45974ADA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal banking agencies shall jointly submit to Congress a report on—</text><paragraph id="H1EC824643A3D4EBB96487C1FA50C27BB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the principal causes for the low number of de novo minority depository institutions during the 10-year period preceding the date of the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0113AAD1397449978C2451782A8F74D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the main challenges to the creation of de novo minority depository institutions and de novo impact banks; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FEC8D0A72E84B9CBFE314753F614938"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regulatory and legislative considerations to promote the establishment of de novo minority depository institutions and de novo impact banks.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF8F4C48CA9CB458EAC2566B72B6926AE"><enum>11.</enum><header>Report on covered mentor-protege programs</header><subsection id="HAF5910AAA059421C9BEE58CCF2F479D7" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report on participants in a covered mentor-protege program, including—</text><paragraph id="H6FCF2F51816B49619456F2F7217879AC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an analysis of outcomes of such program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22704F055B614430AFD82881DF4D80C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of minority depository institutions that are eligible to participate in such program but do not have large financial institution mentors; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H722968D8A31149B6B5AA7A4C6B12DE6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for how to match such minority depository institutions with large financial institution mentors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE829C6B174D457A9B099741EE0CF898" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H84B56514D69C4AFC969BEE27FCD514C1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered mentor-protege program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>covered mentor-protege program</term> means a mentor-protege program established by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to section 45 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657r">15 U.S.C. 657r</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14783B7B64944DE2B58238AB2A6DCF3D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Large financial institution</header><text>The term <term>large financial institution</term> means any entity—</text><subparagraph id="H4AD72F30CE79498C95733A9BF7F9DF80" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>regulated by the Comptroller of the Currency, the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, or the National Credit Union Administration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0EFCA12A065402D88ECCCD9FBD675EE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that has total consolidated assets greater than or equal to $50,000,000,000.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA33516B3D14F44DDBC651696BED709B5" section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no"><enum>12.</enum><header>Custodial deposit program for covered minority depository institutions and impact banks</header><subsection id="H63BF32792D14458FB9D808B02B4D14B5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury shall issue rules establishing a custodial deposit program under which a covered bank may receive deposits from a qualifying account.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E3229991F6B47F997CF29FB816ED2F7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In issuing rules under subsection (a), the Secretary of the Treasury shall—</text><paragraph id="HF6BBEE9474514635985C9B8B42AA9DCE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Federal banking agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03AD650AB5394F439706FFF3A6538A55"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure each covered bank participating in the program established under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H1C63B1A718F34775BF0F98BD0A41DEB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has appropriate policies relating to management of assets, including measures to ensure the safety and soundness of each such covered bank; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B8E989F12C4485958A958E51F03CF8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is compliant with applicable law; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F5A4C7F74D042DE96B22E6013A2049B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure, to the extent practicable that the rules do not conflict with goals described in section 308(a) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1463">12 U.S.C. 1463</external-xref> note).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14FF97DCA6A845D9B652DC699C7BED62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Limitations</header><paragraph id="H3894674194214DD995351C07C467113F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deposits</header><text>With respect to the funds of an individual qualifying account, an entity may not deposit an amount greater than the insured amount in a single covered bank.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5679FC4624524E3BAB34F6271DEA737D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Total deposits</header><text>The total amount of funds deposited in a covered bank under the custodial deposit program described under this section may not exceed the lesser of—</text><subparagraph id="HD46E25BEBF614756A5E2266BEEB67D5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>10 percent of the average amount of deposits held by such covered bank in the previous quarter; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE1DC4291B22446486E5EC8E81754611"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$100,000,000 (as adjusted for inflation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD8FB079D5D524D10A348CC41E16668D2" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each quarter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall submit to Congress a report on the implementation of the program established under this section including information identifying participating covered banks and the total amount of deposits received by covered banks under the program. </text></subsection><subsection id="HC0113E60DAA748F4A9E8B605630B42A5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H6E653E31162E475CAB0698DE3E3DD91C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered bank</header><text>The term <quote>covered bank</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H75F8EC63E60D4E88813683490E00C351"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a minority depository institution that is well capitalized, as defined by the appropriate Federal banking agency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D44FABE0D9545E8AAB6565AD39EB892"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a depository institution designated pursuant to section 5 of the Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act that is well capitalized, as defined by the appropriate Federal banking agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H999F4DEA83024359B9BD1EC3B42E23D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insured amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>insured amount</quote> means the amount that is the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="H0ACF73784F9640D7B8B03CAE1B275BC3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the standard maximum deposit insurance amount (as defined in section 11(a)(1)(E) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1821">12 U.S.C. 1821(a)(1)(E)</external-xref>)); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A26BBC584E14ED89F82803C26D409D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such higher amount negotiated between the Secretary of the Treasury and the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation under which the Corporation will insure all deposits of such higher amount.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C9D1DCFFA64E01A7429B7FE0407BFC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal banking agencies</header><text>The terms <quote>appropriate Federal banking agency</quote> and <quote>Federal banking agencies</quote> have the meaning given those terms, respectively, under section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88D4444CB47945E7AF1AE57ADEF4A65B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Qualifying account</header><text>The term <quote>qualifying account</quote> means any account established in the Department of the Treasury that—</text><subparagraph id="H76EDC0F4CA9A43B98F54750AEC42AB3C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is controlled by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FB8B4B8564F4B83BDAEC8C9C7FE055A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is expected to maintain a balance greater than $200,000,000 for the following 24-month period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H14D7EB2A40A3480794665F0DDB403AF3" commented="no"><enum>13.</enum><header>Streamlined community development financial institution applications and reporting</header><subsection id="H7A1930B78E0647CC9E639EE03807D097"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Application processes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act and with respect to any person having assets under $3,000,000,000 that submits an application for deposit insurance with the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation that could also become a community development financial institution, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, in consultation with the Administrator of the Community Development Financial Institutions Fund, shall—</text><paragraph id="H7B689ACF695D4902AFD1CD4AC04FBBD5" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop systems and procedures to record necessary information to allow the Administrator to conduct preliminary analysis for such person to also become a community development financial institution; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2428AEDA554404D9FD40C8E0D35F05E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop procedures to streamline the application and annual certification processes and to reduce costs for such person to become, and maintain certification as, a community development financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H17123F7576E14D89918AEC491679C19B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation shall submit to Congress a report describing the systems and procedures required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HCC65C8BFD1C843DBAF34E159E50DF2D9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H4FC442C4B1F24227A41BD68DB64792F5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 17(a)(1) of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1827">12 U.S.C. 1827(a)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H6587BCCE078045AFB5A96592946AC570"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FD566EFECF64BAFA2777D2F1B3E5FC9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (F) as subparagraph (G);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCB82563C2F64B028C4F1FF34D618D91"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (E) the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF6BAE4131B3C40F0982ED22024A52225" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HD8894684EEDD4FEA8AFC9FB86FE82068"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicants for deposit insurance that could also become a community development financial institution (as defined in section 103 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994), a minority depository institution (as defined in section 308 of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989), or an impact bank (as designated pursuant to section 5 of the Ensuring Diversity in Community Banking Act); and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD470BF96291E47A1BB7D7F25A2361A47"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendment made by this subsection shall apply with respect to the first report to be submitted after the date that is 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2F34C2F3918C41FAB9A5DB06143EA9B5"><enum>14.</enum><header>Task force on lending to small business concerns</header><subsection id="HB9FA64B205A94699998CB933F2FE3EF8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall establish a task force to examine methods for improving relationships between the Small Business Administration and community development financial institutions, minority depository institutions, and impact banks (as designated pursuant to section 5) to increase the volume of loans provided by such institutions to small business concerns (as defined under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>)).</text></subsection><subsection id="HB21FD45A79E84293AF76F57D4862A47E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the establishment of the task force described in subsection (a), the Administrator of the Small Business Administration shall submit to Congress a report on the findings of such task force.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

