<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H23350D7DEFC24AE3B3BFD197C8B378FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8270 IH: Emergency Advance Refill Notification Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8270</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act, and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to require group health plans and health insurance issuers offering group or individual health insurance coverage to provide notices relating to prescription drug refills to individuals covered under such plans or coverage who reside in emergency areas during emergency periods.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8B73F380EA7D4FA8954DA2C40B3785AA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H27B1972DBC75425FACC90CCE68530D6B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Advance Refill Notification Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBAB574B7F66E4D5FB102D893976E9B44"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requiring prescription drug refill notifications during emergencies</header> <subsection id="H679BD5E62ABF4687AB47DD72FA77B06E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>ERISA</header> <paragraph id="HF075097C58C54621B74D2C7774EF9DC7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1185">29 U.S.C. 1185 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD8EA7090DD274E4B9727C17686208524" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HEABE9A35F3AB4EED81AFB82EF409DA6D"><enum>726.</enum><header>Provision of prescription drug refill notifications during emergencies</header> 
<subsection id="HB73851AB891240C5B5BB6134E265E6E7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering health insurance coverage in connection with a group health plan, that provides benefits for prescription drugs under such plan or such coverage shall provide to each participant or beneficiary under such plan or such coverage who resides in an emergency area during an emergency period—</text> <paragraph id="HA312E1AA7C0347ECBC4E141FA5FFAC9E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 5 business days after the date of the beginning of such period with respect to such area (or, the case of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act, not later than 5 business days after the date of the enactment of this section), a notification (written in a manner that is clear and understandable to the average participant or beneficiary)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HF6C9971282F34F3B8D8E3BD5A0117CF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of whether such plan or coverage will waive, during such period with respect to such a participant or beneficiary, any time restrictions under such plan or coverage on any authorized refills for such drugs to enable such refills in advance of when such refills would otherwise have been permitted under such plan or coverage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD1CEAFC4DD2D4091B39778B1A0387C3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case that such plan or coverage will waive such restrictions during such period with respect to such a participant or beneficiary, that contains information on how such a participant or beneficiary may obtain such a refill; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07AF5549DB90448F93BA0EB13D7B7C01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case such plan or coverage elects to so waive such restrictions during such period with respect to such a participant or beneficiary after the notification described in paragraph (1) has been provided with respect to such period, not later than 5 business days after such election, a notification of such election that contains the information described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9EA70C4F82D440FBBB44AE73BAB02219"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency area; emergency period</header><text>For purposes of this section, an <quote>emergency area</quote> is a geographical area in which, and an <quote>emergency period</quote> is the period during which, there exists—</text> 
<paragraph id="H7C3CA2A74A964714B12791C2FC94012F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6DE6E6F4FF9F439F828B9A05F4DCE646"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 319 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB5259D4A1EEE4E6DB3B4174397B2C8E7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 725 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB51C04FE973B4DDCB56D8F1BC3BA0426" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec. 726. Provision of prescription drug refill notifications during emergencies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDB5CD168F2EE4D5EBA757409890A3762"><enum>(b)</enum><header>PHSA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part D of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2FA17545F47042B28731A2C4E131A018" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HE6E4D435FE1D4460B79B7C8D092B6471"><enum>2799A–11.</enum><header>Provision of prescription drug refill notifications during emergencies</header> 
<subsection id="HC6E421C32CDE4827AF7FCD68DE2C185E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan, and a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage, that provides benefits for prescription drugs under such plan or such coverage shall provide to each participant, beneficiary, or enrollee enrolled under such plan or such coverage who resides in an emergency area during an emergency period—</text> <paragraph id="HC68B5A7BDD38487B8A3E4D25D7F41D65"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 5 business days after the date of the beginning of such period with respect to such area (or, the case of the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act, not later than 5 business days after the date of the enactment of this section), a notification (written in a manner that is clear and understandable to the average participant, beneficiary, or enrollee)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1F723737B80947C8872065766F6787F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of whether such plan or coverage will waive, during such period with respect to such a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee, any time restrictions under such plan or coverage on any authorized refills for such drugs to enable such refills in advance of when such refills would otherwise have been permitted under such plan or coverage; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB4BC05D942734995B48A13FF91D26FCA"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that such plan or coverage will waive such restrictions during such period with respect to such a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee, that contains information on how such a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee may obtain such a refill; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H878B8F4A5FF14FECB75BA64FDF4727E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case such plan or coverage elects to so waive such restrictions during such period with respect to such a participant, beneficiary, or enrollee after the notification described in paragraph (1) has been provided with respect to such period, not later than 5 business days after such election, a notification of such election that contains the information described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H91A75223E217422EBCF7F0B4A9DEC2C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency area; emergency period</header><text>For purposes of this section, an <quote>emergency area</quote> is a geographical area in which, and an <quote>emergency period</quote> is the period during which, there exists—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB919CB1C673F4FB0BF1906894E923351"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFCD9F8776AC4666AD1C0AEFAF520853"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 319.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD8D7514048B14C098966BB946BC3F28A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>IRC</header> 
<paragraph id="HC722573CF69543BB834DF85C980BC339"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1FA8018CB85D45DF9CCA91FB10BB4AA4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HC395D68118A34C7C938066AE6539022B"><enum>9826.</enum><header>Provision of prescription drug refill notifications during emergencies</header> <subsection id="H7C6F13F4A56B4549828A1AC6545EEC51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A group health plan that provides benefits for prescription drugs under such plan shall provide to each participant or beneficiary enrolled under such plan who resides in an emergency area during an emergency period, not later than 5 business days after the date of the beginning of such period with respect to such area (or, the case of the emergency period described in described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act, not later than 5 business days after the date of the enactment of this section)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H887709DAFA7B4F6F939D07690001DDC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a notification (written in a manner that is clear and understandable to the average participant or beneficiary)—</text> <subparagraph id="H3726576E68E048EEBD5191B32103D4CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">of whether such plan will waive, during such period with respect to such a participant or beneficiary, any time restrictions under such plan on any authorized refills for such drugs to enable such refills in advance of when such refills would otherwise have been permitted under such plan; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE1E094B9BEF7459D9C0EC67D3E36F192"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case that such plan will waive such restrictions during such period with respect to such a participant or beneficiary, that contains information on how such a participant or beneficiary may obtain such a refill; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H821DA15B6400411893BBF2FE746E7DDF"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case such plan elects to so waive such restrictions during such period with respect to such a participant or beneficiary after the notification described in paragraph (1) has been provided with respect to such period, not later than 5 business days after such election, a notification of such election that contains the information described in subparagraph (B) of such paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEA42B008105646C5843E685DFA888B81"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Emergency area; emergency period</header><text>For purposes of this section, an <quote>emergency area</quote> is a geographical area in which, and an <quote>emergency period</quote> is the period during which, there exists—</text> <paragraph id="H6339D541743E411EB1DE7F354318F562"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an emergency or disaster declared by the President pursuant to the National Emergencies Act or the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB07C54C1625C472AA47F5B71D208F326"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a public health emergency declared by the Secretary pursuant to section 319 of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBA31F63D7027475A8A9187BF8581EF5E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7346356E216846A89E5AEB402547EC4B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9826. Provision of prescription drug refill notifications during emergencies.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H767401F8A61D42109F136DE305237BA8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to—</text> <paragraph id="HAED04ABB837E45E992620BB5F97599C2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>emergency periods beginning on or after the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFAD9322FB9EF48DB8FF433728C792FDD"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the emergency period described in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

