<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HDD62A8858BA24D7083DA62F5CE810B1A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3009 RH: Improving Language Access in Mortgage Servicing Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code> 
<calendar display="yes">Calendar No. 281</calendar> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3009</legis-num> 
<associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–370, Part I]</associated-doc> 
<current-chamber display="yes">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<action display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20210507">May 7, 2021</action-date> 
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor></action-desc>
</action>
<action> 
<action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc> 
</action> 
<action>
<action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc>
<action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction>
<action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on May 7, 2021</action-instruction>
</action>
<action display="yes"> 
<action-desc display="yes"><pagebreak/></action-desc> 
</action> 
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Truth in Lending Act and the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 to establish language access requirements for creditors and servicers, and for other purposes.<pagebreak/></official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H1716F804EFB94217A3C629BE01C66754"> 
<section id="H6BB03D8962364B808E432B7C02C558D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Language Access in Mortgage Servicing Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H278084F7DA0C40ACA6860EA4B94817EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Language access requirements and resources</header> <subsection id="H161670614F9741498D09BDABB29D26CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Chapter 2 of title I of the Truth in Lending Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1631">15 U.S.C. 1631 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 129H the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" id="H0345F0DA44EB4EA9B09E19AD66E2EABA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H9B7388ADB4904F02A9689EB3032850A3"><enum>129I.</enum><header>Language access requirements.</header> 
<subsection id="H5D0FB43EE4384098B4CFDFD23FDCCB6B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Standard language preference form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this section, the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall, after consulting with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Secretary of Veterans Affairs, and the Commissioner of the Federal Housing Authority, by rule, establish a standard language preference form which includes a standard language preference question asked in each of the 8 languages most commonly spoken by individuals with limited English proficiency, as determined by the Director of the Bureau using information published by the Director of the Bureau of the Census.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE2EF2A3598184F35A1F7FE2EE2830104" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for creditors</header> <paragraph id="HE44ADBFE945941E7B1AAF903879E7571" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Use of standard language preference form by creditors</header> <subparagraph id="HB7A62A71D9374FA391C463EE81351D8A" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inclusion in application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each creditor shall include, in any written application used in connection with a residential mortgage loan, the standard language preference form established by the Director of the Bureau under subsection (a). </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA312D0D7DA8144C4A83A6B14E26D316C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of disclosure</header><text>Each creditor may include with such standard language preference form a disclosure stating that documents and services may not be available in the preferred language indicated by the consumer on the standard language preference form.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4A87BD692914E85A14AC7EC26362E34" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Documentation and transfer of preferred language information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a creditor, or assignee of a creditor receives information about a language preference of a consumer through the standard language preference form, orally or in writing in connection with a residential mortgage loan, as determined by the Director of the Bureau, including from another creditor or a servicer, such creditor or assignee shall document this language preference in each file or electronic file of information associated with such consumer and shall transfer such information and the standard language preference form to any servicer of the loan and to any creditor that may own the loan in the future.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H313CAC05CFC04B389927576BE91819B1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of translated documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Federal agency or a State or local agency in the State or locality in which the residential property is located has produced a translation of a document used in association with a residential mortgage loan in the preferred language of a consumer documented by a creditor pursuant to paragraph (1)(C), such creditor shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H74FD2679A3F04597B7F73CCD6011BB05"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide such translation in addition to any English version of such document that would have been provided to such consumer who indicated such preferred language; and </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCCEF9281C65F4F1D9603F486A1FFE74C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a notice on the English and translated versions indicating that the English version is the official and operative document and the translated version is for informational purposes only.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H98B9C4AA1FE847889D0B25B6DDB2CA65"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Oral interpretation services</header> <subparagraph id="HA13AB321A0BD44EDB9D4165380F1910A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a creditor receives information about a language preference of a consumer through the standard language preference form, orally or in writing in connection with a residential mortgage loan, as determined by the Director of the Bureau, including from another creditor or a servicer, such creditor shall provide oral interpretation services to such consumer.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H62A4F033086D4E8E92FB1145D190C0B3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Oral interpretation services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a creditor is required under subparagraph (A) to provide oral interpretation services to a consumer, such creditor shall ensure qualified oral interpretation services, as defined by the Director of the Bureau, are made available in the preferred language of the consumer for all oral communications between the such creditor and the consumer and these oral interpretation services may be provided by qualified staff of the creditor or a qualified third party. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H78BBB511A76E4CDE8B295DB13B07916D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notice of available language services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a creditor receives information about a language preference of a consumer through the standard language preference form, orally or in writing in connection with a residential mortgage loan, as determined by the Director of the Bureau, including from another creditor or a servicer, such creditor shall not later than 10 business days after receiving such information, notify such consumer in writing, in the preferred language of the consumer, of any language services available, including the services required under paragraphs (2) and (3). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF04B7C54FCD945A3A0F8D4B2F65E623B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Transfer of language preference information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a creditor transfers the servicing associated with a residential mortgage loan, such creditor shall notify the transferee servicer of any known language preference of the consumer associated with such residential mortgage loan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47290F0EF77B4354B25B301A75C86E3F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Information on website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each creditor shall on the website of the creditor publish—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H05D56706C1F84E7C82808F55BE41CA12"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">links to and explanatory information about the websites maintained by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection that identify housing counselors approved by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2649ED262F44B10ACF5F35C48DD5D6B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a link to and explanatory information about the language resources website established by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 1(e) of the Improving Language Access in Mortgage Servicing Act of 2021.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H36AEF92625F9498BAC28D48AD4B4B10E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Translation of mortgage documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to each document published by the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Department of Housing and Urban Development, the Department of Veterans Affairs, and the Department of Agriculture and used in association with a residential mortgage loan transaction, including origination and servicing documents, the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection and the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency shall jointly—</text> <paragraph id="H5D8C066430B24109821311499F3F32BF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this section, publish versions of such documents translated into each of the 8 languages most commonly spoken by individuals with limited English proficiency, as determined by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection using information published by the Director of the Bureau of the Census; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD7A8D1379FDF4DAD867513F5725C7030"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this section, publish versions of such documents translated into at least 4 additional languages spoken by individuals with limited English proficiency that are regionally prevalent in the United States, as determined by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection using information published by the Director of the Bureau of the Census.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE6E6487CA9B54BD7B14C69A0AF13835C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Director may issue such rules as the Director determines necessary to implement this section. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H50FF187FDF074619A547E690C1E3223B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements for Servicers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6 of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0593E6BC06BB437B83BB6D6E792BB53E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HC2123A771C8045528A12850D5E1BD323"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Language access requirements</header> <paragraph id="H81BADD07C3EC4139B586D9FC0F49F6EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header> <subparagraph id="H64E06867C0BE456EBE017A3A4EF926EB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Inclusion in notices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each servicer shall include the standard language preference form with—</text> 
<clause id="H0914268BEF95440A8AF81D688A86C79A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any notice required under section 1024.39(b) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations; </text></clause> <clause id="H6919505428854DF8BAA981CF924088F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any notice required under section (c);</text></clause> 
<clause id="H1C0F55E12E9341A8AEBB3F4172373F64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any notice required under section 1024.41(b)(2) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations;</text></clause> <clause id="H4505AA751EB1436A9918171F9032BE56"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any notice required under section 1024.41(c)(2)(iii) of title 12, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H970ED3B65F0D4550A67D58BFB398DF6B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other additional notice as the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection determines necessary. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBB64153589C48539257789E0478A02A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of disclosures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A servicer may include with the standard language preference form a disclosure stating that documents and services may not be available in the preferred language of the borrower indicated by the consumer on the standard language preference form.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H11958369CCF14DF88B450506096D20E1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Documentation and transfer of preferred language information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a servicer or an assignee of a servicer receives information about a language preference of a borrower through the standard language preference form, orally or in writing in connection with a federally related mortgage, as determined by the Director of the Bureau, including from another servicer or creditor, such servicer or assignee shall document this language preference in each file or electronic file of information associated with such borrower and shall transfer such information and the standard language preference form to any other servicer that may service the loan in the future.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H584CD679304640D6AB013260F5E7A7DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required language services for servicers</header> <subparagraph id="HA2F76EC07F824FA98FE72F90B93ACDC2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Provision of translated documents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a Federal agency, or a State or local agency in the State or locality in which the property subject to the federally related mortgage loan is to be located has produced a translation of a document used in associated with a federally related mortgage loan in the preferred language of a borrower as documented by the servicer pursuant to paragraph (1)(C), the servicer shall—</text> 
<clause id="H73BC2000AC4A4EEAA335570F2AE2FE24" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide such translation in addition to any English version of such document that would have been provided to such borrower; and </text></clause> <clause id="HD61024828D0F40079FB8354D0DEB9264" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include a notice on the English and translated versions, in the preferred language of the borrower, indicating that the English version is the official and operative document and the translated version is for informational purposes only.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFAD70251B0E3478B8E8D7B87302F860D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Oral interpretation services</header> 
<clause id="H8B1BFEF1DDDB4944AF863C569006FC8E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a servicer receives information about a language preference of a borrower through the standard language preference form, orally or in writing in connection with a federally related mortgage, as determined by the Director of the Bureau, including from another creditor or a servicer, such servicer shall provide oral interpretation services to such borrower.</text></clause> <clause id="H0A522B5A30134D72B13214C2401ADECA"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Oral interpretation services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a servicer is required under subparagraph (A) to provide oral interpretation services to a borrower, such servicer shall ensure qualified oral interpretation services, as defined by the Director of the Bureau, are made available in the preferred language of the borrower for all oral communications between the such servicer and the borrower and these oral interpretation services may be provided by qualified staff of the borrower or a qualified third party. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB775503369B24E058C14E60835E20B1F" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Notice of available language services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a servicer receives information about a language preference of a borrower through the standard language preference form, orally or in writing in connection with a federally related mortgage, as determined by the Director of the Bureau, including from another creditor or a servicer, such servicer shall, not later than 10 business days after receiving such information, notify such borrower in writing, in the preferred language of the borrower, of any language services available, including the services required under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H463E063AEB9F47B8AF3FB1CC37167194"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Transfer of language preference information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a servicer transfers the servicing associated with a federally related mortgage loan, such servicer shall notify the transferee servicer of any known language preference of the borrower associated with such federally related mortgage loan.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD26CAFE7358C42368FFB9CC600D4C4C8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Standard language preference form defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>standard language preference form</term> means the standard language preference form established by the Director of the Bureau under section 129I of the Truth in Lending Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD2A0350D53C94BDF9C39EE004D016D9B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Information on website</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each servicer shall on the website of the servicer publish—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H2F2F571F95414FAC9C543ECCCC83778A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">links to and information about the websites maintained by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection that identify housing counselors approved by the Department of Housing and Urban Development; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD330CBFB71DF401596E0842F3EB7778F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a link to and information about the language resources website established by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under section 1(e) of the Improving Language Access in Mortgage Servicing Act of 2021.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2E44D6EA73A4A8EA9520DEBEC9825FC" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection may issue such rules as the Director determines necessary to implement this section. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HC521B1E4659C4F64A97961AB5D071B43"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections in chapter 2 of the Truth in Lending Act (15 U.S.C. 1631 et seq) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 129H the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2A72EE024F4548A8BB9018BDBF6A3E83" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="section">129I. Language access requirements.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8F50C33E097E4FB9A96DC5ABA9EE632F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, and each year thereafter, the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall submit a report to the Congress that contains—</text> <paragraph id="HE52CCAB73FB746D7B692ED1EE68A1AFB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>regulatory recommendations to enhance mortgage origination and servicing processes for persons with a preferred language that is not English;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE2A0D5E41152453A872E9191883BCAA4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any legislative changes needed to provide authority necessary to implement the regulatory recommendations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBAC06CEFD0540F7B34DC5B291E9F913"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any progress on the implementation of any legislative or regulatory recommendation made in a previous report.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC15025876CF04B6A84A7AB1D41C497FF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Language resource website</header> 
<paragraph id="H9A4720B7C43644149F2B246D1587E5C7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section establish and maintain a website that provides language resources for creditors, servicers, and consumers.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEF65FB5818FB42E6B850765773BEB0C3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Website requirements</header><text>The website developed pursuant to paragraph (1) shall include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H45774BB7B24041EE99D1E5C85ACA1CCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the translations of documents published pursuant to section 129I(c) of the Truth in Lending Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D49B201B334426E9F335BA56FD517B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a glossary of terms relating to residential mortgage loans and federally related mortgage loans, provided in each commonly spoken language;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H550CD3B66FD04720B2450CA57D938D3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>guidance for creditors and servicers working with persons who have a preferred language that is not English; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00960CFD2F984E6185ECCE5CCB6EFC1B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">examples of notices that may be used by creditors and servicers to inform persons of available language services, provided in accordance with section 6(n)(2) of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974 and section 129I of the Truth in Lending Act. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA0BF76C6446A45BA8DEBED3C933BAAA7"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Advisory group</header> 
<paragraph id="HC94CECC98A04486992138202F5DFC532"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall establish an advisory group consisting of stakeholders, including industry groups, consumer groups, civil rights groups, and groups that have experience improving language access in housing finance transactions, to provide advice to the Director about—</text> <subparagraph id="H119DC7AFC8984BD2928ED78F66DA852B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>issues that arise relating to mortgage origination and servicing processes for persons with a preferred language that is not English; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8288AF370E0C4D819BE50B08F8919A92"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development of the standard language preference form by the Director under section 129I(a) of the Truth in Lending Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H13151F85468643B4B172047B407281DC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">updates to the language resource website established by the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, the Director of the Federal Housing Finance Agency, the Secretary of Agriculture, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs under subsection (e). </text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1CF260DF59DC4582AA4161D12A3F78FE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required consulting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection shall consult with the advisory group established pursuant to paragraph (1) with respect to any issues that arise relating to mortgage origination and servicing processes for persons with a preferred language that is not English.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HC7E7A007838D43DA9EA018423556FF71"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Housing counseling agency language resources</header> <paragraph id="H48E55EC8BB2949579474FBAD75D38EEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Enhanced search capabilities</header> <subparagraph id="H4C453EBD5A524748AA7D5B0A97FFC3B3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>HUD</header><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section update the website maintained by the Secretary that identifies housing counselors approved by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, to allow for searching for housing counseling agencies based on the language services they provide.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8818A967CE94C5E9B3589519597FFC3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Bureau</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial protection shall not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section update the website maintained by the Director that identifies housing counselors approved by the Department of Housing and Urban Development, to allow for searching for housing counseling agencies based on the language services they provide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF44ACDD9B0E342DEA988E7080A30F64C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, such sums as are necessary to support language training for HUD-approved housing counselors, counseling agencies, and their staff.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF014B9449FBB456086C1E9358743FF04"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section—</text> <paragraph id="H066B1F6FFF934E829D3EE9A6C170EB82"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>creditor</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Truth in Lending Act and shall include any assignee of a creditor. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H078BD0F9715145B6AECDEA9BD3F2D939"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>director</term> means the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3F6F9FE070ED469781B5FD27DEE1E738"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>servicer</term> has the meaning given the term in section 6(i) of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9FAE68A3515847EB87F6C73792E78F0E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>residential mortgage loan</term> has the meaning given the term in section 103 of the Truth in Lending Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H633555829D184704AE1E9BF5B46DAC92"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <term>federally related mortgage loan</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Real Estate Settlement Procedures Act of 1974. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body> 
<endorsement display="yes"> 
<action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date> 
<action-desc>Reported from the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Financial Services</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc>
<action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement> 
</bill> 


