<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73D1B7074F684E9B81B223AFE17449A0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9042 IH: TVA Reform and Consumer Protection Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9042</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Power Act and the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 to reform the Tennessee Valley Authority’s ratemaking authorities, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H1F9424D80F9347048AE12736A5610AE0" style="OLC">
<section id="HE901A03C686A44408A0C5A7BAC605F71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>TVA Reform and Consumer Protection Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HD0F505B848F04F0DBE0F311C2F1722C8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tennessee Valley Authority reforms</header> <subsection id="H5231F7D4D1BB434882B4AA9DC675F5C9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal Power Act amendments</header> <paragraph id="H055497CABB214405BBF37A38A36F27DB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability of part</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 201(f) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824">16 U.S.C. 824(f)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(other than the Tennessee Valley Authority)</quote> after <quote>instrumentality</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7C7E2334C3F3461FA190DB8FCE8D7BC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain wheeling authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 211 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824j">16 U.S.C. 824j</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H6ECCB7D0CCE74DC0A224C8225DC16A5F" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HE515B0B613B54C4685D54E9654DD704E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transfer of control of transmitting facilities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section authorizes the Commission to require the Tennessee Valley Authority to transfer control or operational control of its transmitting facilities to a Transmission Organization that is designated to provide nondiscriminatory transmission access. </text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H2D367A20480B406387E2735089D33829"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Provisions regarding certain orders requiring interconnection or wheeling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 212(j) of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824k">16 U.S.C. 824k(j)</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD2EA7EF165284792B714366875AF6425"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 amendments</header> <paragraph id="H0968F5F822104D1F8C6DFC250C616A57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Duties of the board of directors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2(g)(1)(L) of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/831a">16 U.S.C. 831a(g)(1)(L)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, subject to approval by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</quote> before the semicolon.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H14F8E743C4E14DCA8CCC47AB39FC007F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sale of surplus power</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 10 of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/831i">16 U.S.C. 831i</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="H2E2BB3D391D64ADA9DDB8A3E60C0B6BA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for a term not exceeding twenty years</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6F288C805EB6490A97DBE70CA587485D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>all contracts made with private companies or individuals for the sale of power, which power is to be resold for a profit, shall contain a provision authorizing the Board to cancel said contract upon five years' notice in writing, if the Board needs said power to supply the demands of States, counties, or municipalities. In order</quote> and inserting <quote>in order</quote>; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H929E9EDBC3FA429EAF24F883E95F0522" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>at reasonable rates and to make such rules and regulations governing such sale and distribution of such electric power as in its judgment may be just and equitable</quote> and inserting <quote>at just and reasonable rates, and to make rules and regulations governing such sale and distribution of such electric power that are just and reasonable, subject to approval by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</quote>; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H6647026940BD4A8DA3A6C95AF4B93843" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and in case the purchaser shall fail to comply with any such terms and conditions, or violate any such rules and regulations, said contract may provide that it shall be voidable at the election of the Board</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to approval by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35DE896FB69E495B91C8BDF84270BC55" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rates when sold for resale at profit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 12 of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/831k">16 U.S.C. 831k</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>as reasonable, just, and fair; and in case of any such sale, if an amount is charged the ultimate consumer which is in excess of the price so deemed to be just, reasonable, and fair by the Board, the contract for such sale between the Board and such distributor of electricity shall be voidable at the election of the Board</quote> and inserting <quote>as just and reasonable, subject to approval by the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A5DB3EE232F4380B5F482645F3030C6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Restriction on contracts for sale or delivery of power</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 15d(a) of the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/831n-4">16 U.S.C. 831n–4(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HB24227458F2846AE9752C32FCD33808A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Unless otherwise specifically authorized by Act of Congress the Corporation shall make no contracts for the sale or delivery of power which would have the effect of making the Corporation or its distributors, directly or indirectly, a source of power supply outside the area for which the Corporation or its distributors were the primary source of power supply on July 1, 1957, and such additional area extending not more than five miles around the periphery of such area as may be necessary to care for the growth of the Corporation and its distributors within said area: <italic>Provided, however,</italic> That such additional area shall not in any event increase by more than 2<fraction>1/2</fraction> per centum (or two thousand square miles, whichever is the lesser) the area for which the Corporation and its distributors were the primary source of power supply on July 1, 1957: <italic>And provided further,</italic> That no part of such additional area may be in a State not now served by the Corporation or its distributors or in a municipality receiving electric service from another source on or after July 1, 1957, and no more than five hundred square miles of such additional area may be in any one State now served by the Corporation or its distributors.</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFBBC4F30E6134B4390CC82CCC775E93E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the Corporation or its distributors from supplying electric power to any customer within any area in which the Corporation or its distributors had generally established electric service on July 1, 1957, and to which electric service was not being supplied from any other source on the effective date of this Act.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B953DFAB8C34CC88777B81BCACC139A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Nothing in this subsection shall prevent the Corporation, when economically feasible, from making exchange power arrangements with other power-generating organizations with which the Corporation had such arrangements on July 1, 1957</quote> and inserting <quote>Nothing in this Act shall prevent the Corporation or its distributors from supplying electric power to any customer within any area, nor prevent the Corporation, when economically feasible, from making exchange power arrangements with other power-generating organizations</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


