<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9D13B41C482B474CAB68AE1EA2F1CA5A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7087 IH: To require inns, hotels, motels, and other establishments that provide lodging to transient guests to include all mandatory fees and other charges in the advertised rental rates for such lodging, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7087</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220315">March 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require inns, hotels, motels, and other establishments that provide lodging to transient guests to include all mandatory fees and other charges in the advertised rental rates for such lodging, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H47241AF8916046C896B208E0FA1FF19B" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF5588BEF999E4F319FF288F28FFFCBAC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Lodging fee disclosures</header> 
<subsection id="HF06E8A0503704277843E76E9F32922E6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A person who operates an inn, hotel, motel, or other establishment that provides lodging to transient guests shall include all mandatory fees and other charges in any advertised rental rate for such lodging.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H499F1A3033504768BE1CFB8ED7B26730"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) does not require the inclusion in an advertised rental rate of any tax, fee, or other charge assessed, or required to be assessed, by a government entity.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H22BBE22402B14AFDBB17D465549EF0DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> 
<paragraph id="HEBD44C3FB7A14E8886944B2A6680F53C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Unfair or deceptive acts or practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of this section shall be treated as a violation of a regulation under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>) regarding unfair or deceptive acts or practices.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFBB8017310D44188844ABC055839D0A3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Powers of commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) were incorporated into and made a part of this section. Any person who violates this section shall be subject to the penalties and entitled to the privileges and immunities provided in the Federal Trade Commission Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB5A4AD7987234083B5B802AA1E84FF3D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Mandatory defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>mandatory</term> means, with respect to a fee or other charge assessed in connection with the rental of lodging, that the fee or other charge must be paid as a condition of renting such lodging.</text> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

