<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE071A7B39C804C959325D1B0C7E00578" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7054 IH: COVID–19 Oral History Project Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7054</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220311">March 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Librarian of Congress to establish a program in the American Folklife Center to collect video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials of those affected by the COVID&#8211;19 pandemic, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H846B396982234009980B285EDD16E85C" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HB4845C11309F4F48932ECB78C684ABD6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>COVID–19 Oral History Project Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H1FCF308046F34152915DBE6CFA6EAD60"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of program at American Folklife Center to collect video and audio recording of histories of the COVID–19 pandemic</header> <subsection id="H9E4B69C6C29E4333A0426719E5558905"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Librarian of Congress shall establish an oral history program in the American Folklife Center at the Library of Congress to collect and make publicly available in a digital format individual stories of events and experiences during the COVID–19 pandemic in the United States. In carrying out the program, the Librarian shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H988389E45D014A568643BF44D20EC400"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect video and audio recordings of personal histories and testimonials of those who were affected by the COVID–19 pandemic, such as first responders and health care workers, individuals who survived the disease, family members of those who passed away from the disease, individuals who were repatriated from other countries or from cruise ships, individuals with major life events affected by responding to the outbreak, as well as any other individuals whose lives were altered;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC53B7AE97AD04D83A417426566B5A730"><enum>(2)</enum><text>create a collection of the recordings obtained (including a catalog and index) which will be available for public use through the digital collections of the Library of Congress and such other methods as the Librarian considers appropriate to the extent feasible subject to available resources; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9234DA7020AA48939332499F667A9C71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>solicit, collect, and make available in a digital format written materials (such as letters and diaries) relevant to the personal histories of health care workers and first responders who served during the COVID–19 pandemic and to catalog such materials in a manner the Librarian considers appropriate, consistent with and complimentary to the efforts described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H950C5245F473470E85FFB786B876BF3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of and consultation with other entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Librarian may carry out the activities described in paragraphs (1) and (3) of subsection (a) through agreements and partnerships entered into with other government and private entities, including through collaboration with existing archival and oral history programs throughout the United States, and may otherwise consult with interested persons (within the limits of available resources) and develop appropriate guidelines and arrangements for soliciting, acquiring, and making available recordings under the program under this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H440348B5EC2545E3B3BF12D04B918836"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Timing</header> 
<paragraph id="H10ACAFD4D70A4091B527D300555D5F4B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initiation</header><text>As soon as practicable after the enactment of this Act, the Librarian shall begin collecting video and audio recordings under subsection (a)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38B082AD0EF94A64BE115499A59DBAA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority of the Librarian to collect video and audio recordings under subsection (a)(1) shall terminate upon the expiration of the 5-year period which begins on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H3F04B1A96E3F4CBB9D0793E70E692838"><enum>3.</enum><header>Private support</header> 
<subsection id="HB8BE350113C24E10B896E7BD4DF9F0F6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Acceptance of Donations</header><text>The Librarian of Congress may solicit and accept donations of funds and in-kind contributions to carry out the oral history program under section 2.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HCEA9C212FE35487488E89FBE0D43BC55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of Separate Gift Account</header><text>There is established in the Treasury (among the accounts of the Library of Congress) a gift account for the oral history program under section 2.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4FE86347A61F46FA9853AAAA6860A94C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Dedication of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law—</text> <paragraph id="H20312DFCF52840A8B0B2CD5EAC81E37B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any funds donated to the Librarian of Congress to carry out the oral history program under section 2 shall be deposited entirely into the gift account established under subsection (b);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF1CC66B28BC4654936DE94B2B349B21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the funds contained in such account shall be used solely to carry out the oral history program under section 2; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6372931F11EB4217B881386A8BF4ED91"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Librarian may not deposit into such account any funds donated to the Librarian which are not donated for the exclusive purpose of carrying out the program under section 2.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H640F841C6BF347EDA0ACDE22DCFAD740"><enum>4.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<subsection id="HBB0CE5BECD3C426F8491DA5A34C659D3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act—</text> <paragraph id="H813367EA16E845F9BCB9B6852FCFBF6C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$4,100,000 for fiscal year 2022; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1B889D9FFE2D4705A29883F6BBC0FD5D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such sums as may be necessary for each succeeding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H15AEE40422DD47B4B247A887C297FEBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Continuing availability of funds</header><text>Any amount appropriated pursuant to the authorization under this section shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

