<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H118A9477B15A4AE3BE47AA61906DF552" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 1456 EH: Peace Corps Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1456</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Peace Corps Act to reauthorize the Peace Corps, better support current and returned volunteers, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="H2A97A41DE50B4D1E907B1F5B1DEA4A76" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9C647DCC288C47B5B4361201853413A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="HB0F28D0C64C74CB491AB408C72F7A46F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Peace Corps Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H992ED895212B477AB0A71107025E3DF3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"> 
<toc-entry idref="H9C647DCC288C47B5B4361201853413A4" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HADF8121FE0F54283BAA055F1F90C23B3" level="section">Sec. 2. Authorization of appropriations; integration of information age Peace Corps volunteer opportunities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HD35FED496BD1490D82339715BD8DD1AD" level="section">Sec. 3. Readjustment allowances; expedited re-enrollment and transition assistance.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HC0DA4B4485A240C09554444C742D863B" level="section">Sec. 4. Health care continuation for Peace Corps volunteers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HBFBB556CAAFF47E2B1E4D8C9654FABA9" level="section">Sec. 5. Access to antimalarial drugs and menstrual products for Peace Corps volunteers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8F145026B3F043ED87036943D23F2FA2" level="section">Sec. 6. Codification of Executive Order 11103.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H52E6B57064A248E7B91BEAEECD73FD20" level="section">Sec. 7. Volunteers providing virtual services for the Peace Corps.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H3E2E66D30B72495FB90A145606AEC544" level="section">Sec. 8. Protection of Peace Corps volunteers against reprisal or retaliation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H10BBE3DA3A8A41038FA5982E898D30CB" level="section">Sec. 9. Comprehensive illegal drug use policy with respect to Peace Corps volunteers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HA3A97103CB3C4D34A711FC9BCF338540" level="section">Sec. 10. Peace Corps National Advisory Council.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H943FBB38A1EC48BDB1832AA91AE22817" level="section">Sec. 11. Peace Corps volunteers serving within the United States at the request of another agency.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H55B409487D79488C9B2957302A9DC2D6" level="section">Sec. 12. Use of official seal, emblem, and name of the Peace Corps.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H571802321CE044FC967900077317ECEA" level="section">Sec. 13. Clarification regarding eligibility of United States nationals.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H6632DCB19778497BA746C4AB7008D9F5" level="section">Sec. 14. Memorandum of Agreement with Bureau of Diplomatic Security of the Department of State.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="HFF842078333E41D49A1436F5E91DA2B1" level="section">Sec. 15. Reports to Congress.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H8664CB370448488B9BC90A6FBDBAF5C2" level="section">Sec. 16. Workers compensation for Peace Corps volunteers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H0345A5242C9A456897B0FDC97B742E7B" level="section">Sec. 17. Technical and conforming edits.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry idref="H51D5B5741B6F40C89157CBFE5B5EC4A1" level="section">Sec. 18. Determination of budgetary effects.</toc-entry> </toc></subsection></section> 
<section id="HADF8121FE0F54283BAA055F1F90C23B3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations; integration of information age Peace Corps volunteer opportunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2502">22 U.S.C. 2502</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HB742E9C26FFA4817B1C3A2256E44180A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>$270,000,000 for fiscal year 2000, $298,000,000 for fiscal year 2001, $327,000,000 for fiscal year 2002, and $365,000,000 for fiscal year 2003</quote> and inserting <quote>$430,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 and 2024</quote>;</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB44109BA8A0F499CA4F9C387E2633238"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (e); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H602C17697ED947FDAA13E3FC9A0C018B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H0078CC6C259C475C9BB3FFB90B7ABD27" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HAC9C183099C6403685CD5B0A9727705F"><enum>(f)</enum><text>In recognition of the transformative power of internet access in international development efforts, and, as exemplified by its virtual service pilot initiative, the Peace Corps shall be administered to—</text> <paragraph id="H9EF602A333064F30951258A53B8CBA5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>give particular attention to the expansion of those programs, projects, training, and other activities that leverage the internet, as appropriate, for development, education, and social and economic mobility; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBF021C29E00E4A589B424D5B03CD35DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop positions for Peace Corps volunteers that include such programs, projects, training, and other activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="HD35FED496BD1490D82339715BD8DD1AD"><enum>3.</enum><header>Readjustment allowances; expedited re-enrollment and transition assistance</header> <subsection id="H47E35FD195C84BAAB656EC3EC4E0E86C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Volunteers</header><text>Section 5 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA4C0448850B348D3907681A2EB55201E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the first sentence of subsection (b), by inserting <quote>, safety,</quote> after <quote>health</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6F6129061BD24FACB71F4985E5D60113"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H92652CE895FD45A9BD72FDE4E4E90362"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>$125</quote> and inserting <quote>$375</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD91D22654F874950971AD69EC4C75B89"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>his</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the volunteer’s</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3698856CF33D4C5289EDDADC9F816944"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the volunteer</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H87359CC1198C4ABB995219FFACB7472F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) through (p) as subsections (d) through (o), respectively;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B7D588E148142C09A05670DE0535885"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by amending subsection (e), as so redesignated—</text> <subparagraph id="HA8B2F184B7BF4B61A5FDDC2AB7B096D0"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the subsection heading, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and mental health care</header-in-text></quote> after <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Prescription of medications</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABA44599B2F2497694689A3B26BDEFD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>concerning the mental health care provided to volunteers during their service,</quote> after <quote>experts licensed in the field of mental health,</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H515C6B412E304B57A2619A067A938FE9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (f), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>subsequent</quote>; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEA0382E04156432EAEC392170C7A61BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (g), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H21CD5DD8A6AD45D5B8D5D9B0209889AF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in subsection (m), as so redesignated—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8E9B45D38BD54AD5AAAF7B1FEED529D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="HCE55280E12D2411E84A4AF97E25A43F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subsection (e)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>subsection (d)</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5F06D92CC0E1491DAF92591E807CAD4A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the President</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03996D5AEEE44E338B7354B2BB052498"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>subsection (1)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (k)</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4F0B9C47B72E42E5BDF9A99BE6843F3E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in subsection (n), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>his</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the volunteer’s</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H474DCE147E5A439FBA73BA964EA9FAFD"><enum>(9)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H5CFA05D6D8C2461DADAD485A96EAA2FC" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HA321F936EFA249759D51414CBD3DE4D9"><enum>(p)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, with respect to Peace Corps volunteers and trainees whose service ended involuntarily as a result of an emergency, suspension of operations, or otherwise through no fault of the volunteer or trainee, the Director of the Peace Corps shall—</text> <paragraph id="H043BA57483A045B49915385FB58C91B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>waive such non-medical or non-security application requirements as the Director may determine for the re-enrollment of each such volunteer and trainee during the 2-year period beginning on the date of such involuntary end of service;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0BADF41F5BCC445EA5BC4068C591FCFD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize the medical clearance for each such volunteer and trainee to facilitate re-enrollment; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H343282587C8044759657014AEC243AD0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>permit each such volunteer and trainee, to the extent practicable and in consideration of the needs of overseas posts and the suitability of the volunteer or trainee to meet those needs, to resume the activity of each such volunteer and trainee at the time of the involuntary end of service.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HBEF35E01B961438882A6F7D0F8ED3929"><enum>(q)</enum><text>The Director of the Peace Corps may authorize separation allowances, in amounts determined by the Director, to Peace Corps volunteers and trainees whose service ended involuntarily as a result of an emergency, suspension of operations, or otherwise through no fault of the volunteer or trainee.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9631E2B3DD734C53B40EF081C662C460"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Volunteer leaders</header><text>Section 6 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2505">22 U.S.C. 2505</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H99ECB727F2E54CA1B684B7CDEE1BFE36"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>$125</quote> and inserting <quote>$375</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H02F1F77BC0014D8C8C0D0A342D9A9520"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H3371B2971867446784D60EFF961D525E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32548A3267274514B85E85442A30281E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>in section 5(e)</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>in section 5(d)</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HC0DA4B4485A240C09554444C742D863B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Health care continuation for Peace Corps volunteers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (d) of section 5 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref>), as redesignated pursuant to section 4, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HC3EB4719FC5541188890F2C79963BA6A" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H15C3361EC5C842B1A5893F0F7D4AC77C"><enum>(d)</enum> <paragraph id="H64B63C79AE9948F0A6E4824D36F1F74F" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Volunteers and trainees shall receive such health care (including, if necessary, for volunteers and trainees, services under section 8B) during their service, as the Director of the Peace Corps may determine to be necessary or appropriate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFCC68C10600447F1A423093EDEF8304F" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Applicants for enrollment shall receive such health examinations preparatory to their service, applicants for enrollment who have accepted an invitation to begin a period of training under section 8(a) shall receive, preparatory to their service, such immunization, dental care, and information on prescription options and potential interactions, as necessary and appropriate and in accordance with subsection (e).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2CD3C8C339DE407F9D89BB28E39DD09A" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Returned volunteers shall receive such health examinations within six months after termination of their service, including services provided in accordance with section 8B (except that the six-month limitation shall not apply in the case of such services).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE8D0F97E23824ED6AD67A2453BC4A13A" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Subject to such conditions as the President may prescribe, such health care may be provided in any facility of any agency of the United States Government, and in such cases the appropriation for maintaining and operating such facility shall be reimbursed from appropriations available under this Act. Health care may not be provided under this subsection in a manner inconsistent with the Assisted Suicide Funding Restriction Act of 1997 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/105/12">Public Law 105–12</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2BFE9DC248E64730B6C4D591D8CE2DDE" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Returned volunteers, including those whose period of service is subject to early termination as the result of an emergency, shall receive upon termination of their service with the Peace Corps two months of short-term non-service-related health insurance for transition and travel (SHIFTT), to provide coverage for a 60-day period within which such volunteer will be advised to obtain qualifying health insurance, and an opportunity to extend for an additional 1 month such SHIFTT insurance, at the expense of such volunteer.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5BD1380DDB3E46ADB060C02E49CA35F9" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days before the date on which the period of service of a volunteer or trainee terminates, or 30 days after the date of such termination if such termination is the result of an emergency, the Director of the Peace Corps, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall provide detailed information to such volunteer or trainee on options for health care after termination other than health care provided by the Peace Corps, including—</text> <subparagraph id="H496280D8C7B34E7E8FA1711D08EA4BCC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>where additional, detailed information, including on the application process and eligibility requirements for medical assistance through State plans under title XIX of the Social Security Act (or waiver of State plans), may be obtained, including through external health care <quote>navigators</quote> or health care option identification services available within the public and private sectors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HEF0F03D886384C7C8B6C16C4F72A299F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>where detailed information on qualified health plans may be obtained, including through external health care <quote>navigators</quote> or health care option identification services available within the public and private sectors; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3245C2E1F0674659BA0FF3A68F920C78"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if such volunteer or trainee is 25 years of age or younger, detailed information regarding the eligibility of such volunteer or trainee to enroll as a dependent child in a group health plan or health insurance coverage in which the parent of such volunteer or trainee is enrolled if such plan or coverage offers such dependent coverage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HBFBB556CAAFF47E2B1E4D8C9654FABA9"><enum>5.</enum><header>Access to antimalarial drugs and menstrual products for Peace Corps volunteers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5A of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504a">22 U.S.C. 2504a</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HEB436CAC6A9F459E94F6635D065463EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsections (c) and (e);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF55AE1443D5C4176822CE0DD8BB75C1F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (e);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD43684B881EB4E82BB0291E547A9BEBB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following new subsections:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H6C99CAC4650B4F7DBC639BA27F147B3C" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H4F2A019909D94E4BB63A6CFF2B3975C0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Antimalarial drugs</header> 
<paragraph id="H655D3E5E725B4CE48BBF0F6010E31A6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Peace Corps shall consult with experts at the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention regarding recommendations for prescribing malaria prophylaxis, and implement such recommendations to the extent practicable, in order to provide the best standard of care within the context of the Peace Corps environment.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC287A1F028654BBD94B630254292F992"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certain training</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall ensure that each Peace Corps medical officer serving in a malaria-endemic country receives training in the recognition of the side effects of such medications.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA96EBBF21B6C4A5589C3F445D937BB89"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Access to menstrual products</header> 
<paragraph id="HD9EE9E4C31F0474AB8EF6F80487170A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Director of the Peace Corps shall establish a comprehensive policy to ensure Peace Corps volunteers who require menstrual products are able to access such products by—</text> <subparagraph id="H17947454A21348A382B6C9A1A820FCF7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increasing stipends for such volunteers to purchase such products; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB5EF4A59A2D747FBAA4145DF34BFD1CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>providing such volunteers with such products in the generic product types selected by such volunteer, if available in the country of service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H90A449F37D5F4CA9835C1D380DFA54D9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The policy required under paragraph (1) shall take into consideration the availability for purchase locally of menstrual products, the price of such products, and cultural norms regarding menstruation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H046F95BC2C4849D9ABA3BB3576BC9BEC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost</header><text>If stipends are increased pursuant to the policy required under paragraph (1), the Director of the Peace Corps shall ensure that such increase is sufficient to cover the average cost within the country of service of menstrual products required by volunteers.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="H53F582E5E0BD4AF294740BD6DA6D6CD8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A) of subsection (e), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>, patient confidentiality standards</quote> before <quote>, and guidelines</quote>.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H8F145026B3F043ED87036943D23F2FA2" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Codification of Executive Order 11103</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Peace Corps Act is amended by inserting after section 5A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504a">22 U.S.C. 2504a</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF7678E2E38574104BFE57058C425722D" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="H05BB8D3B67234CEAB103CB49F0CC007D" commented="no"><enum>5B.</enum><header>Codification of Executive Order 11103</header> <subsection id="H98C7E597BB9C4453AE00E1C42DADAB87" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 11103 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref> note; 28 Fed. Reg. 3571; relating to Providing for the Appointment of Former Peace Corps Volunteers to the Civilian Career Services), as amended by Executive Order 12107 (44 Fed. Reg. 1055; relating to the Civil Service Commission and Labor-Management in the Federal Service), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this section, shall remain in effect and have the full force and effect of law, consistent with subsection (b).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H62CFE53EF3CB47BE907B32FCF1BB9C60" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum> 
<paragraph id="HD1D66AD2463C4BEEB2C6ED73A8523301" display-inline="yes-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The period of eligibility for noncompetitive appointment to the civil service provided to an individual by operation of subsection (a), including any individual who is so eligible on the date of the enactment of this section, shall be extended by the total number of days that, during such period—</text> <subparagraph id="HA0EA6374687940C2A62D65D5AF97428A" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a hiring freeze for civilian employees of the Executive branch is in effect by order of the President with respect to any Executive agency at which the individual has applied for employment;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H151EDFA44D4C42F290A5A144793FB6D2" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>there is a lapse in appropriations with respect to any Executive agency at which the individual has applied for employment; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC3AF20012021415EB8871EEE6C3D0CD0" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the individual is receiving disability compensation under section 8142 of title 5, United States Code, based on their service as a Peace Corps volunteer, retroactive to the date the individual applied for such compensation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEEBEAED096CA41C69034205CFCDBF18D" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The period of eligibility for noncompetitive appointment status to the civil service by operation of subsection (a) shall apply to a Peace Corps volunteer—</text> <subparagraph id="H5F7724F5D9DB4F7E9B156505573A9DBA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whose service ended involuntarily as the result of a suspension of volunteer operations by the Director of the Peace Corps, but shall not last longer than 12 months from the date on which such service ended involuntarily; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA0F90EBE85634C95AC33E213725F0C65" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who re-enrolls as a volunteer in the Peace Corps after completion of a term of service.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB28A414C6784CEEA7F2A955FF5A32AB" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFDF563180A6B40EFB3ED80A33B0F4157" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <quote>hiring freeze</quote> means any memorandum, Executive order, or other action by the President that prohibits an Executive agency from filling vacant Federal civilian employee positions or creating new such positions.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F8D4A38CD3E49C692FF9100700A56F1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <quote>Executive agency</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 105 of title 5, United States Code, and includes the United States Postal Service and the Postal Regulatory Commission, but does not include the Government Accountability Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H89B7E142DCEF435C902B68046D2EA3FC" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subsection (b), Executive Order 11103 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref> note; 28 Fed. Reg. 3571; relating to Providing for the Appointment of Former Peace Corps Volunteers to the Civilian Career Services), as amended by Executive Order 12107 (44 Fed. Reg. 1055; relating to the Civil Service Commission and Labor-Management in the Federal Service), as in effect on the day before the date of the enactment of this section, shall, except as set forth herein, remain in effect and have the full force and effect of law. In the event of a conflict between the language herein and Executive Order 11103, the language herein shall prevail.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0CC7DC5DE99F465B95268E834C897B5A" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><text>Any volunteer whose service terminated after January 1, 2020, and who has been certified by the Director as having served satisfactorily as a volunteer under the Act may, for two years after their separation from the Peace Corps, be appointed to a position in any United States department, agency, or establishment in the competitive service under title 5, United States Code without competitive examination and in accordance with such regulations and conditions consistent with this subsection as may be prescribed by the Director of the Office of Personnel Management.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H52E6B57064A248E7B91BEAEECD73FD20"><enum>7.</enum><header>Volunteers providing virtual services for the Peace Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Peace Corps Act is amended by inserting after section 5B, as added by section 6 of this Act, the following new section:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1DFFC469086546AC94F1BCB619C6AF32" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <section id="HEAD560E935F84D86A1BF3F35B38BB4C2"><enum>5C.</enum><header>Volunteers providing virtual services for the Peace Corps</header> <subsection id="HA5B130CC77064CA087187E0FA56E40E4" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress declares that the Peace Corps has a demonstrated ability to deliver information, training, and technical assistance virtually through the internet and other electronic means to communities abroad.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F72D7E7EBE94F4D96F9AB0B929B81F3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps is authorized to recruit individuals, who may be located within the United States or third countries, to provide services virtually by electronic means to communities in host countries to flexibly meet the expressed needs of those countries.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4D0A3EA5782445FF987C7422968D5E52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Peace Corps—</text> 
<paragraph id="H616EE41F3CF54F948D2139C7C94CF167"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may recruit, train, and accept, on such terms and conditions as the Director may determine necessary or appropriate, the services of individuals, especially those individuals who face barriers to serving physically in a host country, who shall serve on a part-time basis as virtual service volunteers to meet the expressed needs of host countries, such as information, training, and technical assistance, through the internet or other electronic or virtual means; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H29F2CD07D455498EB3E403DD931F3B43"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may provide for incidental expenses of such individuals, as determined by the Director to be appropriate for the nature of the assignments.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HEAC1A66E19104132BD5694D92BF37A43"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Individuals not to be considered volunteers</header><text>An individual who provides services under the authority of this section shall not be considered to be a volunteer for purposes of section 5 unless the Director of the Peace Corps requires the individual to physically serve in the host country on a temporary basis.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3AA956DA65BB4BF38252CB122D4D68BE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Individuals not to be considered federal employees</header><text>An individual who provides services under the authority of this section shall not be considered a Federal employee except for the purposes described in section 5(h).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H3E2E66D30B72495FB90A145606AEC544"><enum>8.</enum><header>Protection of Peace Corps volunteers against reprisal or retaliation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8G of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507g">22 U.S.C. 2507g</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> <quoted-block id="H25CAE7BFBB744553B4D6F9F20858C9E1" style="OLC"> <subsection id="H09510BF5449547E6A605DB6C62122BDD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Prohibition against reprisal or retaliation</header> <paragraph id="HD2726C6AAA1648A093340E396C393B81"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall take all reasonable measures, including through the development and implementation of a comprehensive policy, to prevent and address reprisal or retaliation against a volunteer by any Peace Corps officer or employee, or any other person with supervisory authority over the volunteer during the volunteer’s period of service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB06B4CDA4D804A269231B6CAC60599B1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting and investigation; relief</header> 
<subparagraph id="H57C0BAFEA92246EA823032168BAD520E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A volunteer may report a complaint or allegation of reprisal or retaliation—</text> <clause id="HC80445B212A64E25BA78DD8BB39BF55E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directly to the Inspector General of the Peace Corps, and the Inspector General may conduct such investigations and make such recommendations with respect to the complaint or allegation as the Inspector General considers appropriate; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2DA5831B4A24415BB213F886704C1E42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>through other channels provided by the Peace Corps, including through the process for confidential reporting required in subsection (a).</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H886F4367329A453E9BF47BD7751A051A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Relief</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps—</text> 
<clause id="HABDA0239C0204115B9EDD46D32470E4B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may order any relief for an affirmative finding of a proposed or final resolution of a complaint or allegation of reprisal or retaliation in accordance with policies, rules, and procedures of the Peace Corps; and</text></clause> <clause id="H1C743579FAA04F0AA6701DBFEFEAB210"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall ensure such relief is promptly provided to the volunteer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5264691E465A43769A95D0BEE196999C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Appeal</header> 
<subparagraph id="H29002BAD1DC14F02BE75FFE32C49F1EB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A volunteer may appeal to the Director of the Peace Corps any proposed or final resolution of a complaint or allegation of reprisal or retaliation.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2EDBF6332162400E88ADCAE0CE6DDA90"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this paragraph may be construed to affect any other right of recourse a volunteer may have under any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5D7B055207714D489A9316435166C217"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification of rights and remedies</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall ensure that volunteers are informed in writing of the rights and remedies provided under this section.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0F8A81C81B3040EE944DFAD52EA465A5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Dispute mediation</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall offer the opportunity for volunteers to resolve disputes concerning a complaint or allegation of reprisal or retaliation through mediation in accordance with procedures developed by the Peace Corps.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H488BC3ABE1904F53ADD9D3BE2AB6EA4C"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Staff member and volunteer cooperation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Peace Corps may take such disciplinary or other administrative action, including termination of service or finding of ineligibility for re-employment or reinstatement, with respect to a staff member or volunteer who unreasonably refuses to cooperate with an investigation conducted by the Inspector General of the Peace Corps into a complaint or allegation of reprisal or retaliation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF355076072884EFD8F3EF3244A106B26"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7D899F74F8E4491BA4D593ED79B40B2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reprisal or retaliation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>reprisal or retaliation</quote> means taking, threatening to take, or initiating adverse administrative action against a volunteer because the volunteer made a report pursuant to subsection (a) or otherwise disclosed to a covered official or office any information pertaining to waste, fraud, abuse of authority, misconduct, mismanagement, violations of law, or a significant threat to health and safety, whenever the activity or occurrence complained of is based upon the reasonable belief of the volunteer that it has taken place.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5D688D4AE38F4421818E46A6C9000649"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Covered official or office</header><text>The term <quote>covered official or office</quote> means any of the following:</text> 
<clause id="H2641B655AA014A6182693C84C6A8E0B2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Any Peace Corps employee, including an employee of the Office of Inspector General.</text></clause> <clause id="H480A3F96734D4385B10A0798F6F8CF9E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A Member of Congress or a representative of a committee of Congress.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC67DDFFA1E2E466B84FF5E23998C1685"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An Inspector General (other than the Peace Corps Inspector General).</text></clause> <clause id="H131C8BF9C25C43F09BC331D1A7BA8051"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Government Accountability Office.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HD8B52B2ECE2E48C5BAC2F5ACC14A2D58"><enum>(v)</enum><text>An authorized official of the Department of Justice or other law enforcement agency.</text></clause> <clause id="HBDBD80B64366408AACD7F62355157CB7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>A United States court or grand jury.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="H10BBE3DA3A8A41038FA5982E898D30CB"><enum>9.</enum><header>Comprehensive illegal drug use policy with respect to Peace Corps volunteers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Peace Corps Act is amended by inserting after section 8I (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507i">22 U.S.C. 2507i</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> <quoted-block id="H202DB60C220342FDAF4F9F358577B8EE" style="OLC"> <section id="H13A0101966AD4CE4A1206B82576FCE6D"><enum>8J.</enum><header>Comprehensive illegal drug use policy with respect to Peace Corps volunteers</header> <subsection id="H3209E0107B35455E91526F8F011C9A37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall develop and implement a comprehensive drug use policy with respect to Peace Corps volunteers. Such policy shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H356DF254D0CB4A80A829EF3BB0388ABA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a zero tolerance policy regarding volunteer or trainee involvement with illegal drugs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD02AA9A55DB14869BBB7F8D5DE6BB16F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require that every case of volunteer or trainee illegal drug involvement be brought immediately to the attention of relevant Peace Corps leadership, including the Director, and be reported expeditiously by the Peace Corps to the Office of the Inspector General.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDAC07FD37CAB4D81BE13A6F017701133"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the policy described in subsection (a), the Director may consult with and incorporate, as appropriate, the recommendations and views of experts in the field of substance abuse, and shall consult with the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB71E41A576B94E0DB5C5CFE0FF2138DC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the illegal drug use policy required to be developed and implemented under this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HA3A97103CB3C4D34A711FC9BCF338540"><enum>10.</enum><header>Peace Corps National Advisory Council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 12 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2511">22 U.S.C. 2511</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H105CBBAC581541DD91EA05A458F0CA6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1DA5D2FDBF7B4EBCB483C63611179647"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the President and</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H34290E7A9B964D47A718E1BB6477307F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> 
<clause id="HCDA50EEC4B094767900BCE4208F77360"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>conduct on-site inspections, and make examinations, of the activities of the Peace Corps in the United States and in other countries in order to</quote>;</text></clause> <clause id="H9A84D42D681C4D8699E6F932566B52F8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text> 
<subclause id="H54079037A7974AE4ACF5D64C724241CF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the President, the Director of the Peace Corps, and, as the Council considers appropriate, the Congress,</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director and, as the Council considers appropriate, the Congress</quote>; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H51EEC5E3EA974AD08B5B3E933C6FAE9A"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end; </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HFA8ADBEEF1094755A90EED1B86671068"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (D) as subparagraph (G); and</text></clause> <clause id="H4F15BF0E10D84F089A4A58AADE3BB97B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (C) the following new subparagraphs:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HF8BCF0FC915142C68E3291034EF675A3" style="OLC"> 
<subparagraph id="H1EEFA34BBF19434A9C49B2AE878BFFFB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>make recommendations for utilizing the expertise of returned Peace Corps volunteers in fulfilling the goals of the Peace Corps;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA24F9C41519D47948BC4046C70C62549"><enum>(E)</enum><text>make recommendations for increasing recruitment of volunteers from diverse backgrounds and better supporting such volunteers during their training and enrollment in the Peace Corps;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H1496BAF180084023B6FB16EE3C062D38"><enum>(F)</enum><text>make recommendations to reduce any financial barriers to application, training, or enrollment in the Peace Corps, including a volunteer’s medical expenses and other out-of-pocket costs; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFB83A978DCBE4C778F036E8A098FA3FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEBE231AD31EF435787F2352ACDBD4FC4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text> <clause id="H9F9243403B954B2D9A7D9DFA4BE0C04A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text> 
<subclause id="H858CF289737E4F5C9DF1E653B6597D87"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the first sentence—</text> <item id="H87B17554910143EBB77EFFE9A8F8FA28"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>fifteen</quote> and inserting <quote>seven</quote>; and</text></item> 
<item id="HE5C54F046E8F4877977F7D82532FAB14"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director of the Peace Corps</quote>; and</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="H8B0125DE60014DE8B3BAC651FB09266A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking the second sentence and inserting the following new sentence: <quote>At least four of such members shall be returned Peace Corps volunteers, and not more than four of such members may be members of the same political party.</quote>;</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H1393F94CE4AD4FC7A8907DEE3456CF3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (C) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HC2B80D3B17B64CEEBD1A1515C0730A08" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="H080E40C9641C4EE0B93FA7C38EECFDA6" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>No member of the Council appointed under this paragraph may be an officer or employee of the Peace Corps.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="HDA6350570AE94B2DA34347F7234CE2D9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (D) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HD5A7FECB65834894A686733499A9197E" style="OLC"> <subparagraph id="HE270131E4B7F42E8B86DC3F55BC0845E" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The members of the Council shall be appointed to 2-year terms.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause> 
<clause id="H72E723D6915645369BD86ECC1858162E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (E), (F), (G), (H), and (I); and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17BF9C5198C44C49BBE7A164E2E06E1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by amending paragraph (3) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H66C283DA9A00464AB0C00BE65F6CC9E9" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="HE855050F958142C2A64EB969FFCAFB72" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Director of the Peace Corps shall designate one of the members of the Council as Chair, who shall serve in such capacity for a term of two years.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFDE947A0F65E437B888C0C885041E0D8"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(1)(B), by striking <quote>his or her</quote> and inserting <quote>the member’s</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAFB1B3E46A3943FFAD9CE6BB67C6CF7B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (g)—</text> <subparagraph id="H7178BA7D0E8640A9AAA8526B0F3DF32C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the first sentence, by striking <quote>At its first meeting and at its first regular meeting in each calendar year thereafter</quote> and inserting <quote>At its first meeting each calendar year</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H66F7607068754F969F49C33BADAA3B4F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence, by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, and each shall serve in that capacity for a term of two years. The Director of the Peace Corps may renew, not more than once per member, the term of a voting member appointed as Chair of the Council under the preceding sentence</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H66F947FFF91F4542834A9EAEB749ABC7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(1), by striking <quote>The Council</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting the following: <quote>The Council shall hold a regular meeting during each calendar quarter at a date and time to be determined by the Chair of the Council or at the call of the Director of the Peace Corps.</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7289772F9754DB8AC3DBFBD2D2207CF"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (i)—</text> <subparagraph id="HC76E62D9DB6A4194AFDE22E3A4C231EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the President and</quote> (including in the subsection heading) each place such term appears;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7948F09D433749BFBD8C2E10AC2617EB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the President shall</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director shall</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA2405F5D8514266BC74D5A7E440DFF0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the President or</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H298DCE66DA6A4504844257CA70872187"><enum>(7)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsections:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HABBF6712D9EA4B41B2EC11B5FC4155FC" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="HCD9093B84E0640DEBED858009F4AC1ED"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Independence of Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the activities or functions of the Council under subsection (b)(2) may undermine the independence or supersede the duties of the Inspector General of the Peace Corps.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H734FB3A2ADB144BAA3AEC8F57E84E9BA"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Nonapplicability of FACA</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply to the Council.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1DE69BFF91DD40EDA900DE21A67A1CF6"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Funding of the Council</header><text>The Council shall be fully funded from amounts made available to the Peace Corps to carry out this Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H943FBB38A1EC48BDB1832AA91AE22817"><enum>11.</enum><header>Peace Corps volunteers serving within the United States at the request of another agency</header> 
<subsection id="HB20EC9C44D444969AD5C538B8D3D0AA8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Declaration of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress declares that the Peace Corps provided emergency disaster relief in response to Hurricane Katrina in 2006 and provided COVID–19 relief in 2021 at the request of the Federal Emergency Management Agency and therefore it is the policy of the United States that the Peace Corps be authorized to recruit volunteers to serve within the United States at the request of another agency. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H7E131A03E408414D8180B7CA0F5CABA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Recruitment of domestic volunteers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Peace Corps Act is amended by inserting after section 14 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2513">22 U.S.C. 2513</external-xref>) the following new section:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE7935A0BB5BF4687A86355CAA7C1BB2C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HF087CDAAED584EAAAA3375EFA6BE9D89" commented="no"><enum>14A.</enum><header>Peace Corps volunteers serving within the United States at the request of another agency</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Director may recruit, train, and accept, for limited periods of time, on such terms and conditions as the Director may determine necessary or appropriate, the services of individuals who are not then serving outside the United States as volunteers or trainees (unless such appointment is made with the consent of the volunteer or trainee serving outside the United States as an extension of such service), who shall serve without compensation as domestic volunteers within the United States to provide assistance at the request of any Federal Government agency with authority to do so. Such service within the United States may be initiated by the Director following the request from the other agency and a determination by the Director that such action is in the best interests of the United States and the Peace Corps. Domestic volunteers shall not be considered volunteers under section 5 and shall not be deemed a Federal employee except for the purposes described in section 5(h). The Director may provide for incidental expenses of domestic volunteers, as determined by the Director to be appropriate for the nature of the assignments.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> <section id="H55B409487D79488C9B2957302A9DC2D6"><enum>12.</enum><header>Use of official seal, emblem, and name of the Peace Corps</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 19 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2518">22 U.S.C. 2518</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H372577C7AC1E44B59C9AE06DEBECC230"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <subparagraph id="H06B27C47CB734A5286BC3328A73EB70E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The President</quote> and inserting <quote>The Director of the Peace Corps</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2B5283470B654FDDA141FD37726E60F9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2AD438BD99745D9BCCC6A0350C05111"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H009D6393983C4312B3D282B3EB27F4DC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>, except that the official seal or emblem and the name <quote>Peace Corps</quote> may be used on any death announcement, gravestone, plaque, or other grave marker of any person who served as a volunteer or as an officer or employee of the Peace Corps under such rules as may be prescribed by the Director</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD3FF80D654B34A769D2B6794F79E3C17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), in the first sentence, by inserting <quote>or in accordance with the exception specified in paragraph (1),</quote> before <quote>shall be fined</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H571802321CE044FC967900077317ECEA"><enum>13.</enum><header>Clarification regarding eligibility of United States nationals</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2501">22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H45A9B96DF58B4BFA817145B9F0E39D92"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 7(a)(5), by striking <quote>United States citizens</quote> each place such term appears and inserting <quote>nationals of the United States</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H37D026EDEE0449E498C1C73CD3212D9D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 8(b), by striking <quote>citizens</quote> and inserting <quote>nationals</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14AA4A1CC2C040A9A529C455A506373D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 10(b), by striking <quote>citizen or resident</quote> and inserting <quote>national</quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H797B65E1C89D497BA40DC55311F157C7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in section 12(g), by striking <quote>citizens</quote> and inserting <quote>nationals</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H853E8BE498CA42D687BB3FB5F5B46E84"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 26—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7635D3082E7A4088B3631C865A5A2550"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) through (8) as paragraphs (6) through (9), respectively; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4AD6F44EA8FC42239546F652EA451636"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H09DBB33A1BFE47B2BDDEC695753EC775" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H6A608B53496A4477989D3907335834DF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The term <quote>national of the United States</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a)(22) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(22)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H6632DCB19778497BA746C4AB7008D9F5"><enum>14.</enum><header>Memorandum of Agreement with Bureau of Diplomatic Security of the Department of State</header> <subsection id="H2B08A7E3E8434563B2AF5FF872B4FA06"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, and at least once every five years thereafter, the Director of the Peace Corps, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security, shall review the Memorandum of Agreement between the Bureau of Diplomatic Security of the Department of State and the Peace Corps relating to security support and protection of Peace Corps volunteers and staff members abroad and update such Memorandum of Agreement, as appropriate.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H119BFEB6C5BC43748D6B3B8CC9649FA6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification</header> 
<paragraph id="H988836FAC60C4655ACF98B7FC1DBE26D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Peace Corps and the Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security shall jointly submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a written notification relating to an update to the Memorandum of Agreement made pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H93E65082599840A5913F8D883EDCA0E4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of notification</header><text>A written notification submitted pursuant to paragraph (1) shall be submitted not later than 30 days before the update referred to in such paragraph shall take effect.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HFF842078333E41D49A1436F5E91DA2B1"><enum>15.</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header> 
<subsection id="HD795CCCEE3EA472692A9D5D5239568A1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Amendments</header><text>The Peace Corps Act is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H423AE338B90C4EB3B6D36883EC2ED332" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 8E (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507e">22 U.S.C. 2507e</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HAB762E2A9C4D463EB654B66B6415A3C5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>President</quote> and inserting <quote>Director</quote> each place it appears;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE76887E24D2486BB91EC50B858A06E0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>September 30, 2023</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H08E0381CA8C64AA58F2DAF79920BC8B8" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)(A), by striking <quote>September 30, 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06B2D7D9565740A78371482A09192DA1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 8I (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507i">22 U.S.C. 2507i</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCA6B25A0688F41EDBD30C3C435377B25" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>September 30, 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>September 30, 2025</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE1BC51570CCB44F39855B8113BD378F8" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by striking <quote>President</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Director</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0A487BCEEF33461FBC395ECEEE5828C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>GAO report</header> 
<paragraph id="HBB52718CA8DF4026930523916CB2334C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report relating to the post-service health care delivery and insurance coverage pursuant to subsection (d) of section 5 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref>), as amended by section 4 of this Act, and section 8B of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507b">22 U.S.C. 2507b</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7858440D7B7445BD824856F6E1DF1399"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCED1CAA52B9A4F1482C577CD26321883"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Information relating to examinations, counseling, and other mental health care services provided by the Peace Corps to returned volunteers in the six months following the end of the term of service of such volunteers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8F1D981A7D2C41B6AC7AF660F9A83116"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Recommendations relating to—</text> 
<clause id="HEE77A99A2C034F599103892D3C3837C7"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">better protection of patient confidentiality for returned Peace Corps volunteers for mental health care services;</text></clause> <clause id="H48EB43F3FDBE43CFACEAC4DE3361D847"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improved access to mental health providers that will accept payment from the Peace Corps; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HE9AB37426D0C495EA0002AC8989193EB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>whether such mental health care services for returned volunteers would be better provided under the Short-term Health Insurance For Transition and Travel (SHIFTT) plan or a similar commercially available insurance plan to be paid for by the Peace Corps.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H51D0B9D9E8304BE0880D2D17120B2222"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report on mental health evaluation standards</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Peace Corps shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on the guidelines and standards used to evaluate the mental health of Peace Corps applicants prior to service. Such report shall include—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8823C0B44C71421289C61D60E9D2F8A6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a detailed description of mental health screening guidelines and evaluation standards used by the Peace Corps to determine medical eligibility of applicants for service, including a description of the most common mental health conditions of applicants;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC4C161C14E04FC2BF6EB0C2B8390748"><enum>(2)</enum><text>specific standards in the mental health screening process that could lead to an applicant’s disqualification from service, and a description of how these determinations are made;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H816E3235009E456AB1F84CBE74502510"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any expedited mental health clearance process for severe or recent symptom presentation;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H35B49B348CE74A08B86C16DA696ADAED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of periods of stability related to certain mental health conditions and symptoms recommended prior to an applicant’s clearance to serve;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H07DED59C548844EB9E6FF085F4FB9915"><enum>(5)</enum><text>an assessment of the impact of updated mental health evaluation guidance, including a comparison of mental health related volunteer medevacs in years before and after updated guidelines were implemented; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6B5E21D3BCE4D6E9F536770E787F517"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a review of these screening guidelines, conducted by a panel of certified and qualified medical professionals in the United States, that evaluates these standards based on scientific evidence and mental health research and proposes relevant updates or additions to current guidance.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE785F3219FBB4B90AEB693FE4E2C5299"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report on Volunteer Medical Evacuations</header><text>Not later than the first May 1 occurring after the date of the enactment of this Act and annually thereafter for five years, the Director of the Peace Corps shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on volunteer medical and mental health evacuations. Such report shall include—</text> <paragraph id="HC642A6C0C7124BE38AA99F0B795F071E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the number of Peace Corps volunteer medical and mental health evacuations during the previous year;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H841FD2D27B064CC39E4E185EA046E00C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a breakdown of these evacuations into medical and mental health evacuation categories; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6462D038AB914A79AEEFC48937ABE27E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the estimated cost of these evacuations for each year, including a breakdown of costs between medical and mental health evacuation categories.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC4EDCE16AD74C10B9FFF1ED26CF6FEC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report and Extension of the Sexual Assault Advisory Council</header><text>Section 8D of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2507d">22 U.S.C. 2507d</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H0AF304F087504EFF9B471F2273E7FE17"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending subsection (d) to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H429C05CEE5FB4EF9B3601925BB08A50E" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="H84F1E80D0D054CF3B3B07C0974891732"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis for the duration of its mandate, the Council shall submit to the Director, the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report on its findings based on the reviews conducted pursuant to subsection (c) and shall include relevant recommendations. Such reports shall be made publicly available.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE79DBECDE145459C95C6F9D68B0F8A00"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (g), by striking <quote>October 1, 2023</quote> and inserting <quote>October 1, 2025</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1FC544CCD6774C4B9F00DA209DECB619"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report on Pacific Islands region</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of the Peace Corps shall submit to the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate a report on—</text> <paragraph id="H5E810387C7934E72ABB1567AE7334EE1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the presence of the Peace Corps in the Pacific Islands region; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H407419121DB54D53A6E42148A33EC3ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a strategy to expand such presence, as practicable, including—</text> <subparagraph id="HAA47F4890F754097B3E65519201A5828"><enum>(A)</enum><text>outcomes of consultations with regional allies and partners on areas in which cooperation can reduce factors limiting Peace Corps expansion; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA8C10EA2B26047A9A56AE73CDE51CA06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>timelines for expanding and reopening country programs in the Pacific Islands region.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H8664CB370448488B9BC90A6FBDBAF5C2" commented="no"><enum>16.</enum><header>Workers compensation for Peace Corps volunteers</header> <subsection id="H0018BFEDBE3B4B82A0F9A02D5B45BD24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 8142 of title 5, United States Code, is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H371B2515305E41128DBCE1B7AAC8E097"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text> <subparagraph id="HBEB9879627624941ACBBB62E4C21103D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>GS–7</quote> and inserting <quote>GS–7, step 5</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H72F5A2A7390F4255A6E8EDCB370904F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC524F53491444FB2A28A0EF0149463C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (2) and (3), respectively; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5A4720319E744C92963375ED1049FBC4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1), by striking <quote>subsection (c)(3)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c)(2)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HDCE070DD4E7846EB8997895D2DD4366A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The amendment made by subsection (a)(1)(A) shall apply to any volunteer (as that term is defined in subsection (a) of section 8142 of title 5, United States Code) with respect to whom benefits under chapter 81 of such title commence, by operation of such section, on or after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H0345A5242C9A456897B0FDC97B742E7B" commented="no"><enum>17.</enum><header>Technical and conforming edits</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2501">22 U.S.C. 2501 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H44941A16FFD34F82A8D1D00BCF5B54AF" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending section 1 to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1731858AA7E644D8B83E588E8D4E5B13" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H38AF91CBD89141C48C8F021F54BAA704" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header> 
<subsection id="H07DC71E9086A48BCB3F158098929F149" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Peace Corps Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA8AEDBC88EF441D6B70F40F6D26F1DA2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text> 
<toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> 
<toc-entry level="title">Title I—The Peace Corps</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2. Declaration of purpose.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 2A. Peace Corps as an independent agency. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 3. Authorization.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 4. Director of the Peace Corps and delegation of functions.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5. Peace Corps volunteers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5A. Health care for volunteers at Peace Corps posts.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5B. Codification of Executive Order 11103.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 5C. Volunteers providing virtual services for the Peace Corps.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 6. Peace Corps volunteer leaders.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 7. Peace Corps employees.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8. Volunteer training.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8A. Sexual assault risk-reduction and response training.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8B. Sexual assault policy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8C. Office of victim advocacy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8D. Establishment of sexual assault advisory council.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8E. Volunteer feedback and Peace Corps review.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8F. Establishment of a policy on stalking.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8G. Establishment of a confidentiality protection policy.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8H. Removal and assessment and evaluation.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8I. Reporting requirements.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 8J. Comprehensive illegal drug use policy with respect to Peace Corps volunteers.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9. Participation of foreign nationals.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 10. General powers and authorities.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 11. Reports.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 12. Peace Corps National Advisory Council.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 13. Experts and consultants.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 14. Detail of personnel to foreign governments and international organizations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 14A. Peace corps volunteers serving within the United States at the request of another agency.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 15. Utilization of funds. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 16. Foreign currency fluctuations account.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 17. Use of foreign currencies.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 18. Activities promoting Americans’ understanding of other peoples.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 19. Exclusive right to seal and name.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 20. [Reserved.]</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 21. [Reserved.] </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 22. Security investigations.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 23. Universal military training and service act.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 24. Foreign language proficiency act.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 25. Nonpartisan appointments. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 26. Definitions. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 27. Construction. </toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 28. Effective date.</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="title">Title II—Amendment of Internal Revenue Code and Social Security Act</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 201. [Reserved.]</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 202. [Reserved.]</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="title">Title III—Encouragement of Voluntary Service Programs</toc-entry> 
<toc-entry level="section">Sec. 301. Voluntary Service Programs.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF12F4A903E23433EA1080367226C45E0" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a) of section 2—</text> <subparagraph id="H3C789623B4284D8285E645087A7D39DA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>men and women</quote> and inserting <quote>individuals</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H744A18A263174EB3B55F59BA0ECCB006" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>help the peoples</quote> and inserting <quote>partner with the peoples</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CA48A602B7B48728CFF45BA3326F12E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>trained manpower</quote> and inserting <quote>trained individuals</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB86C65E118D742769E4E70C3EF2E6326" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e) of section 3 (as so redesignated by section 2 of this Act), by striking <quote>disabled people</quote> and inserting <quote>people with disabilities</quote> each place it appears;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA8EFB384766243B39FCB818DC01F4053" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (b) of section 4—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1FB2ED6999244F9F8E8CEF86537197E9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>him</quote> and inserting <quote>the President</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H229B2B045A76406F9B59E84915FF5C21" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3DE36D99FD6049EBB39CFC461F19930B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>of his subordinates</quote> and all that follows through <quote>functions.</quote> and inserting <quote>subordinate of the Director the authority to perform any such functions.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1FEDD7CDDAE429B872925F5932AA243" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in section 7—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H6A9F2067194C43E695B743851AEEB1FA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by moving the margins of paragraphs (7) and (8) two ems to the left;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H063CCC1A7A554C8F91464F4B84A1E46C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the second sentence of subsection (c), by striking <quote>in his discretion</quote> and inserting <quote>in the President’s discretion</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB640ABDC82F74FCDA1659140BF6FC0F7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (b);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DE8FBF0C94C4ABD869B34E04EC58603" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in section 8A—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7DCE8578E50E4B6283154253064378B0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by striking <quote>his or her</quote> and inserting <quote>the volunteer’s</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2531A1C7E1D24021AEC9D80FEBD99891" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2) of subsection (d), by inserting <quote>the</quote> before <quote>information</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H17A8BAE2516C4933913C44756F90E7DE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (f)—</text> <clause id="H12843CA3380D462482132E68D98835E6" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (2), by striking <quote>his or her</quote> and inserting <quote>the volunteer’s</quote> each place it appears; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HA529A94472A4405F9B1A175B0803726D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (4), by striking <quote>his or her</quote> and inserting <quote>that person’s</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52E632E348274456AC86058362BC4427" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>in section 8C, in the heading of subsection (a), by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">victims</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">victim</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBD925E7AA954000951283A3765141E2" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text>in section 8E—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B66437432424D04A718FC2A6B580DC9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking <quote>subsection (c),</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB03F36BADE834BCE8339FD3E5B7332C4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1)(F), by striking <quote>Corp’s</quote> and inserting <quote>Corps</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC6E6D49794F648F2B96C5E02413AAF5F" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text>in section 9—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0A5DD3FA3D8E4BBEA3C2268B0DA08F0F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Act proceedings</quote> and inserting <quote>Act. Removal proceedings</quote>;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9007A414963E435581BB87A0D6B3925D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>under which he</quote> and inserting <quote>under which that person</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB99AD12D68B477295D2772E7126115C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>for which he</quote> and inserting <quote>for which that person</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0CC3DCDF88584AEC92E2F3CE24E2A4FC" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text>in section 10—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE7C729D7CCDD48D1B53DF6959B5A8B08" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b) (as amended by section 13 of this Act), by striking <quote>he</quote> and inserting <quote>the President</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A937A343EB7404E8C1282DE994FCE15" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>section 3709</quote> and all that follows through <quote>1949</quote> and inserting <quote>sections 3101(a), 3101(c), 3104, 3106, 3301(b)(2), and 6101 of title 41, United States Code</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD970774A00546E884090F7D8A7CE3E9" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><text>in section 14—</text> <subparagraph id="HA34E462EB81F44F28C455890491F8125" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>his</quote> after <quote>of</quote> and before <quote>agency</quote> and inserting <quote>that</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65329843680B45B58AA15E2F634DAF91" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text> <clause id="H233737F539A0419AACD0FC21A9936191" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>preserving his</quote> and inserting <quote>preserving the</quote>; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F28FB7146094DF3B471C36EB4D21EDA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>he</quote> after <quote>assigned, and</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H247D2FEAAC554AE8AE138A862632152F" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><text>in section 15—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA7CB08846BF749E699B36FC6DE2A6844" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (c), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>that Act</quote> and inserting <quote>such subchapter</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7D1075F0D4A045F9B4677B8B6E07A83E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(7), by striking <quote>his designee</quote> and inserting <quote>the Director’s designee</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H52195D3006D44853A45ECCF00FA229C5" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><text>in section 23, by striking <quote>Universal Military Training and Service Act</quote> and inserting <quote>Military Selective Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3801">50 U.S.C. 3801 et seq.</external-xref>)</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB41B664BA8F544D186377EDABDB97673" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><text>in section 24, by striking—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5D81126804E24C9D83B921C93B977FDE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>his</quote> and inserting <quote>the volunteer’s</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H821AE271FAD34A92B5681774FC383F74" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text><quote>he</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>the volunteer</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B049132AB2D4A4F9C20D72A0130E56E" commented="no"><enum>(15)</enum><text>in section 26 (as amended by section 13 of this Act)—</text> <subparagraph id="H01A5CDC6A2374923AA3D6A789955F63B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>which he or she</quote> and inserting <quote>which the medical officer</quote>;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H64CD407495674FF3A8555369DB506162" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by further redesignating paragraphs (2) through (9) (as so redesignated by section 13) as paragraphs (3) through (10), respectively;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H319EDE1D02E3471188D5A4F98EDD0378" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (1) the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H9832D131F8BF46FF976AA5B5AB6C921A" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H7D5F4E6FCD574C6F9F46C46CAF08710D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Director</quote> means the Director of the Peace Corps.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB0E1BB9EF5642DFB54D8CFBEC41522F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>5(m)</quote> and inserting <quote>5(n)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H399C587F3DA840BF936F13FC6719B7B7" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), as so redesignated—</text> <clause id="H69A63EE603B748778AAB9988F3B91EAA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subparagraphs (A) and (B), respectively, and moving such subparagraphs, as so redesignated, 2 ems to the left; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HBE2E101995F24D519DE9AFC1CEFA52C1" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>section 5(f)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 5(e)</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H248C2CBBBC47427FBFCF9C293621C570" commented="no"><enum>(16)</enum><text>in section 301, by striking <quote>Sec. 301. (a) The Congress</quote> and inserting the following: </text> 
<quoted-block style="traditional" id="H9CE4F3291DAE48FB9BA42A9B39CD28E0" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="HBD3C7AC56E5D40749FAA30110D6BEE0C" commented="no"><enum>301.</enum><header>Voluntary Service Programs</header> 
<subsection id="H5EEC1F43EED347CBB93F406BC6AECC23" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Congress</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> <section id="H51D5B5741B6F40C89157CBFE5B5EC4A1"><enum>18.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section> 
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220919" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives September 19, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
<endorsement display="yes"></endorsement>
</bill> 


