<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H686CBE64C19948F4851D9C277E00F25A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5118 RH: Continental Divide Trail Completion Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 326</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5118</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–419]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210827">August 27, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220718">July 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220718">July 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with amendments, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on August 27, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Agriculture to prioritize the completion of the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H4614D5761BE74477AF99F655B928B3F1"><section id="HD686CBCB70244A3FA8FE7B3B38FB15F1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Continental Divide Trail Completion Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF1506D1170114C8AB0CC87CCCEDFA871"><enum>2.</enum><header>Continental Divide National Scenic Trail</header><subsection id="H0C5EBB6277984BC494DA8DDD8CE2B11A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Completion of trail</header><paragraph id="HF32E14F68A4249139C8CC03049C4FFFD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than November 10, 2028, the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall, to the maximum extent practicable, ensure the completion of the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail as a contiguous route, consistent with the following provisions of the National Trails System Act:</text><subparagraph id="HC6BB0BC8B37F4CDAA67E5680E58D2CAA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Section 3(a)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1242">16 U.S.C. 1242(a)(2)</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H020AE97F627749B59DFEB87FF05178F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Section 5(a)(5) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244(a)(5)</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CAE29F00EE1422CAAD19F3D1F7DD1EF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1246">16 U.S.C. 1246</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F772B583BDB461D996C8FE036D9DDEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Priority of actions</header><text>The Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior shall, to the maximum extent practicable, take necessary actions to achieve this goal, including the following steps, listed in order of priority:</text><subparagraph id="H08B9A869E4834459A75BDF5D18EE5579"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Complete the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail by acquiring land or an interest in land, or by encouraging States or local governments to enter into cooperative agreements to acquire interests in land, to eliminate gaps between sections of the Trail while maintaining the nature and purposes of the Trail.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H104BF9AD551C42DA8485528D2243443A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Optimize the Trail by relocating incompatible existing portions of the Trail on Federal land as necessary to provide for maximum outdoor recreation potential and for the conservation and enjoyment of the nationally significant scenic, historic, natural, or cultural qualities of the areas through which the Trail passes, consistent with the Trail’s nature and purposes.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D7997E0CDE746A9AF16782C18B13A7E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Publish maps of the completed Trail corridor.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B80FB8D61AA410BA09F3A8857603803"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Trail completion team</header><paragraph id="HA360D41779F74C19B5F14E2C2E3C0F39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out subsection (a), not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of the Interior, shall establish a joint Forest Service and Bureau of Land Management trail completion team to work in coordination with the Trail Administrator to facilitate the completion and optimization of the Trail, pursuant to the purposes of section 3(a)(2) of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1242">16 U.S.C. 1242(a)(2)</external-xref>) and the Trail’s nature and purposes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H072A162004FF441E9132D7D5DC318EB6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties of the team</header><text>The Team shall:</text><subparagraph id="H01AC7D60B21E4A3E81D1CE370A7DBBB4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Implement land and right-of-way acquisitions, relocations, and trail construction consistent with any Optimal Location Review for the trail, giving priority to land that—</text><clause id="HDD5B6FB243734071B707A6C9B7BAD10A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>eliminates gaps between segments of the Trail;</text></clause><clause id="H9EE3441600C84843AAF2DEFBDE9F90A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be acquired by the Secretary or the Secretary of the Interior by purchase from a willing seller, donation, exchange, or by cooperative agreement;</text></clause><clause id="H5D620141C15B40118E2596DAE3680F9B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is best suited for inclusion in the Trail corridor in accordance with the purposes, policies, and provisions of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1241">16 U.S.C. 1241 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></clause><clause id="HA658810ED2584C4BBD8339323A6DF732"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>has been identified as a segment of the Trail on Federal land that should be relocated to provide for maximum outdoor recreation potential and the conservation and enjoyment of the nationally significant scenic, historic, natural, or cultural qualities of the areas through which the Trail passes.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F735E50310A4225BF21E1EFCF3BB53F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Provide the necessary administrative and technical support to complete the Trail corridor under subsection (a).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0C90C6FF9464E54B50E4AF3265A3624"><enum>(C)</enum><text>As appropriate, consult with other Federal agencies, Governors of affected States, Indian Tribes, Land Grants-Mercedes, Acequias, relevant landowners or land users of an acequia or land grant-merced, the Continental Divide Trail Coalition, and other volunteer and nonprofit organizations that assist in, or whose members may be affected by, the development, maintenance, and management of the Trail.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC5FF37393DE4C3E86ABCE815583A18E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Support the Secretary in the development of the acquisition and development plan under subsection (c) and annual reports under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB5D3F8514506435EACCA37C60CCAFFF5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Comprehensive acquisition and development plan</header><paragraph id="H51DD8DB056FB43B59CC11E8EC5CB92B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the establishment of the Team under subsection (b), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a comprehensive acquisition and development plan for the Trail.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF752317BBC694451B0F7D18E63083745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of plan</header><text>The comprehensive acquisition and development plan should—</text><subparagraph id="HE05FC44A318347719772E70C3B441B55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identify any gaps in the Trail where the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior have not been able to acquire land or interests in land by purchase from a willing seller, by donation, by exchange, or by cooperative agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5226DC470F7435DA00D050312749E02"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include a plan for closing such gaps by acquiring lands or interests in land; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3AE6940197143F6BBF18380AE41EBC1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include general and site-specific development plans, including anticipated costs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB8FAD3529C7E40309FCB66BA1FB12A3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Method of acquisition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary and the Secretary of the Interior—</text><paragraph id="H2AD9A55435764321862BE9486AC90A93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may acquire land only by purchase from a willing seller with donated or appropriated funds, by donation, or by exchange; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD51362C65EF3493DA8889EFA40C9E7A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may not acquire land by eminent domain.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H25BD1DA494A74760B699542454D5233C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maintaining existing partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Secretary, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Team shall continue to maintain and develop working relationships with volunteer and nonprofit organizations that assist in the development, maintenance, and management of the Trail.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2ACC003D52A94EB6954272AF5651E4C9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><text>Not later than September 30, 2024, and at the close of each fiscal year until the acquisition and development plan is fully implemented, the Secretary shall report on the following, in writing, to the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate:</text><paragraph id="HCEB3C70473E7476F8F2B9DB6B625B319"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The progress in acquiring land or interests in land to complete the Trail consistent with this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FB1DA346C3344EE8A8086EFA4D2388A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The amount of land or interests in land acquired during the fiscal year and the amount expended for such land or interests in land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEF6D537BAD048D68DB6DC8B23826E8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The amount of land or interests in land planned for acquisition in the ensuing fiscal year and the estimated cost of such land or interests in land.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63E83799614742BABCC61ABE9A111E05"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The estimated amount of land or interests in land remaining to be acquired.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23B6A65F7C3F4AB996B5EFEB26B200C5"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The amount of existing Trail miles on Federal lands that need to be relocated to provide for maximum outdoor recreation potential and for conservation and enjoyment of the nationally significant scenic, historic, natural, or cultural qualities of the areas through which the Trail passes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCF326704AF1641DB88F9FC216FEE1FCC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HFC3B5D2EA36644469EF3C7E7FFE0A2D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Acequia</header><text>The term <term>acequia</term> has the meaning of the term <term>community ditch</term> as such term is defined under section 73-2-27 of the New Mexico Statutes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H994DE0C6A1984185BBB0929E076A4FBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Land grant-merced</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>land grant-merced</term> means a community land grant issued under the laws or customs of the Government of Spain or Mexico that is recognized under chapter 49 of the New Mexico Statutes (or a successor statute).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H748909A174E44B1EB5BEC012F36F9C38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Optimal location review</header><text>The term <term>Optimal Location Review</term> means the procedures described in the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail Optimal Location Review Guide, dated November 2017.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3CEE22619204B869AEEA37644424B42"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Agriculture, acting through the Chief of the Forest Service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1FA0BE238024E73A0DF3E3463116140"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Team</header><text>The term <term>Team</term> means the trail completion team established under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BCC6579021D40F3937B4E4B7261EDE2"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Trail</header><text>The term <term>Trail</term> means the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail established by section 5 of the National Trails System Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1244">16 U.S.C. 1244</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><official-title-amendment>Amend the title so as to read: <quote>A bill to direct the Secretary of Agriculture and the Secretary of the Interior to prioritize the completion of the Continental Divide National Scenic Trail, and for other purposes.</quote>.</official-title-amendment><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220718">July 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with amendments, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

