<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HB1F64AAD002D430EA8A733272E77AF37" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 6291 RH: Microelectronics Research for Energy Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 349</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6291</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–452]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20211214">December 14, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220819">August 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220819">August 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on December 14, 2021</action-instruction><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a comprehensive and integrative program to accelerate microelectronics research and development at the Department of Energy, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HSY00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H049A6190311B4D47B21F450C2F005453"><section id="H4ED5B6D4A3624B86AAB2A2602D61B06D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Microelectronics Research for Energy Innovation Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Micro Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7189EEE136174FE1BF434FFAE59E75BD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HA9DEE1760B744884B5CE6A4BAFADBEEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D96398F7EE84BC5986DA5DCC1CF4CB0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Historically black college and university</header><text>The term <quote>historically Black college and university</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A66AEC5E03F434B8FC43146428E5F30"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A3E5903ECC4427995301BB4A7FF0E35"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minority serving institution</header><text>The term <quote>minority serving institution</quote> includes the entities described in any of the paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE425CDB2CD3347F18A8571207739BCB3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>National laboratory</header><text>The term <quote>National Laboratory</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48F4CFCF03CC40A99CB40273020A1AB6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C9DBE838F8D443D8EEA0F075E85B2B1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Skilled technical workforce</header><text>The term <quote>skilled technical workforce</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 4(b) of the Innovations in Mentoring, Training, and Apprenticeships Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1862p">42 U.S.C. 1862p</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46F4DB55F7574DC797F1515CF6238C18"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Tribal college and university</header><text>The term <quote>Tribal College and University</quote> has the meaning given in section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1EB7EF9A16544CCA86E195ACAE82DE8B"><enum>3.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HDFF66A727C4D423F84661EA57A8A0A59"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the coming end of Moore’s Law presents major technological challenges and opportunities for the United States and important implications for national security, economic competitiveness, and scientific discovery;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DA4051C9120477487CDA5C176B07C95"><enum>(2)</enum><text>future progress and innovation in microelectronics, and maintaining a robust domestic microelectronics supply chain, will require an approach that advances relevant materials science, electronic and photonic device technologies, processing and packaging technologies, manufacturing technologies, circuit, chip, and system architecture, and software system and algorithm development in a co-design fashion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5D3CC52273445488D2C0E948D42551B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the National Laboratories possess unique technical expertise and user facilities that are essential to overcoming foundational research challenges relevant to the topics described in paragraph (2), and translating and transferring research outcomes to industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E685C26638C4A23ACB8C950727511FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the assets described in paragraph (3) will enable the Department to drive advances in microelectronics that are essential to meeting future needs in areas critical to its missions as well as the future competitiveness of the domestic microelectronics industry, including high-performance computing, emerging data-centric computing approaches, and energy-efficient computing; optical sensors, sources, and wireless networks; and power electronics and electricity delivery systems.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEEE6BCF57CF04F4A8DCD7A2C2C23B149"><enum>4.</enum><header>Microelectronics research program</header><subsection id="H480B7705D7864ABA88EBEF7D1E5F6CCF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a cross-cutting program of research, development, and demonstration of microelectronics relevant to the mission of the Department and in the service of the Nation’s global competitiveness in the field of microelectronics. In carrying out this program, the Secretary shall coordinate across all relevant programs and offices of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="H47EEBCD7B55B415B99E1755430688383"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Research areas</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall award financial assistance to eligible entities under subsection (c) to carry out research projects in—</text><paragraph id="H2FB572415D5A4CF7A811F1203A95DB1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>foundational science areas, including—</text><subparagraph id="H16C42C514E0547B19701D93F25D9834D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>materials sciences, chemical sciences, and plasma science synthesis, and fabrication;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19F16CF7B484456889A42B67CB8C6306"><enum>(B)</enum><text>novel microelectronics devices, including emerging memory and storage technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BDAF793F3A14D2584E39A0ADF1B5122"><enum>(C)</enum><text>diverse computing architectures and paradigms, including analog computing and edge computing;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H288C60204E09451A86415C7689306213"><enum>(D)</enum><text>data-driven modeling and simulation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8A844F0603D340FCA693021F3FF67A94"><enum>(E)</enum><text>integrated sensing, power harvesting, and communications;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7223F68FB8FF4B54AF6D5396173D5AB6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>component integration and subsystems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19CB75D07A1243708A53680608E9D20A"><enum>(G)</enum><text>photonic integration; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65478C1A69BE480D83D1B09A3BE56BAD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>development of co-design frameworks for all stages of microelectronics design, development, fabrication, and application;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC4FE957913C46C1BFFBC85CFE0E044E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cybersecurity by design to result in trusted and resilient microelectronics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0996FA30300E471DA36981368D7BBFB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>methods for leveraging advanced simulation and artificial intelligence to enhance co-design and discovery in microelectronics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6A8479A187B4AA5BFD00962CA667B9E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, fabrication and processing science and metrology associated with microelectronics manufacturing, including lithography, patterning, surface deposition, etching, and cleaning;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBE06CBECEDA42479CB62F4997E0ADC8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>approaches for optimizing system-level energy efficiency of advanced computing systems, the electrical grid, power electronics, and other energy infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3300BE33606E4E42B1BF58E4AF4C34B7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>approaches for enhancing the durability and lifetime of radiation-hardened electronics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6991D96867744910B659FB61C038E36B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>enhancement of microelectronics security, including the development of integrated devices, packages, and thermal management for severe environments and national security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BBDC16AE38E419A91C2839FA8E6CBD5"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in coordination with other relevant initiatives at the Department, methods to improve the lifetime, maintenance, decommissioning, recycling, reuse, and sustainability of microelectronics components and systems, including technologies and strategies that reduce the use of energy, water, critical materials, and other commodities that are determined to be vulnerable to disruption.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDC3BE1E3E27483FB5F9DABCD5B20505"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>The entities eligible to receive financial assistance under this section include—</text><paragraph id="HD2420673D0DA46AA83884E8D0B50B80D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an institution of higher education, including historically Black colleges and universities, Tribal colleges and universities, and minority serving institutions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB94F6AA4F47D4B03A8F1EA43FD9A6177"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a nonprofit research organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15A9B480F5AB47FFB562D694EF5A6017"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a State research agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8E59116151C4AA48B81E03C68727458"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a National Laboratory;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA403CC69D2834C04887777AC1E4D238F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>a private commercial entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC56407119C41414887B338AD0A16AA34"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a partnership or consortium of 2 or more entities described in paragraphs (1) through (5); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57C889DE81E14368A5DF5E81C8709622"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any other entities the Secretary deems appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A0F3A9324C24F42A1C8482FB582BFDE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technology transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program described in subsection (a), the Secretary, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Technology Transitions, and in consultation with the private sector, shall support translational research and transfer of microelectronics technologies and identify emerging research and development needs of industry and government for the benefit of United States economic competitiveness.</text></subsection><subsection id="H083BC585013F472B9C82027D9F2B981F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Workforce development</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall support—</text><paragraph id="HA4EB8E838CF64040A9CAC82EED8B45AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>workforce development through the existing authorities and mechanisms available to the Department, including internships, fellowships, individual investigator grants, and other activities the Secretary deems appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BCEC3D3FFE04B02923BB7DBEA4A7A32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>education and outreach activities to disseminate information and promote understanding of microelectronics and related fields among students at K-12, undergraduate, and graduate levels. Such activities may include educational programming with an emphasis on experiential and project-based learning. The Secretary shall consult with the Director of the National Science Foundation on activities carried out this paragraph.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B1C9FA051144BF5B645ECCA54489008" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out activities under subsection (e), the Secretary shall ensure program outreach to recruit applicants and engage participants from all regions of the country, especially underserved communities and groups historically underrepresented in STEM.</text></subsection><subsection id="H72A72D343DC64D22ABE6DC7992FACAEA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not less than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, a report describing the goals, priorities, and anticipated outcomes of the program described in subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7FB424533CC648C5B32D5E9366A11BE2"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary to carry out the activities described in this section—</text><paragraph id="HA7BE9E0B0064431EB152094A1303B769"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$75,000,000 for fiscal year 2022;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFE71A287AE647C0921A23B5E6B21E22"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for fiscal year 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H062D8C514EBA47F3BED5F69637EEB307"><enum>(3)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C6B44068C8B48E6AA998AA9D17C2DFB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for fiscal year 2025; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82577E6B5C894AFE8296FB26268B9BFE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>$100,000,000 for fiscal year 2026.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H89DDB219D61343AB9DD4ABFD25AC9FC5"><enum>5.</enum><header>Microelectronics science research centers</header><subsection id="HBD1768B9DCE547B0B563E8EE754C9E2A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under section 4, the Secretary, acting through the Director of the Office of Science, shall establish up to four Microelectronics Science Research Centers (referred to in this section as <quote>Centers</quote>) to conduct mission-driven research to address foundational challenges in the design, development, characterization, prototyping, demonstration, and fabrication of microelectronics and to facilitate the translation of research results to industry.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFA4B4BF8461C4292A6D6F0AF62776B67"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The activities of the Centers authorized under this section shall include research, development, and demonstration activities for—</text><paragraph id="HC77E9BD5099B4C9C888327F41E7179B1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accelerating the development of new microelectronics science and technology, including materials, devices, circuits, systems, architectures, fabrication tools, processes, diagnostics, modeling, synthesis, and, in consultation with the National Institute of Standards and Technology, metrology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2357E5E5655C4B4C929F5C4B17DFA32E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>advancing the sustainability and energy efficiency of new microelectronics devices, packages, and systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB565DDBB0D84419ABC080F8E70B0E887"><enum>(3)</enum><text>application-driven co-design and prototyping of novel devices to facilitate laboratory-to-fabrication transition;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A12DCB903404930AC0D99B42CEC38FC"><enum>(4)</enum><text>advancing knowledge and experimental capabilities in surface and materials science, plasma science, and computational and theoretical methods, including artificial intelligence, multi-scale co-design, and advanced supercomputing capabilities to invent and manufacture revolutionary microelectronic devices;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC33970E72814E368A2C47F32CD4F154"><enum>(5)</enum><text>creating technology testbeds for prototyping platforms for validation and verification of new capabilities and sharing of ideas, intellectual property, and the unique facilities of the Department;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E03F26A787946ECA2DF78015D8D97C1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting development of cybersecurity capabilities for computing architectures that measurably improve safety and security, and that are adaptable for existing and future applications; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H442AFA6171BC42DB916EB3662722A476"><enum>(7)</enum><text>supporting long-term and short-term workforce development in microelectronics.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA8F22964405F43D2ADB80F4E3B4C40CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="H7168371D294948B28A355E71AE5BCFE0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection and duration</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science shall select Centers on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis for a period of not more than 5 years, subject to the availability of appropriations, beginning on the date of establishment of that Center.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52867E2CBFF14218805DAE4D635160C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>An eligible applicant under this subsection shall submit to the Director of the Office of Science an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Director deems appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H006CCB2131B24248B2F4C3C6429F0DC4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible applicants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Office of Science shall consider applications from—</text><subparagraph id="H27DB6D11CC53463584F92D5EF117EDD8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>National Laboratories;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B0A692B3C6447C2B0327C62004707DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">institutions of higher education, including historically Black colleges and universities, Tribal colleges and universities, and minority serving institutions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H16BFF9A3CABA42049469C265EB073DEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>private industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CB0B776D94548EAAB4FE051CC4D6B42"><enum>(D)</enum><text>research centers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91396D0305AC4110A84B1D149134093A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consortia of 2 or more of the entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1303223E627428AA565F063933BC8FE"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any other entity that the Secretary of Energy deems appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H10388C96B7384377A79E4843CF8C3C9B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>After the end of either period described in paragraph (1), the Director of the Office of Science may renew support for the Center for a period of not more than 5 years on a merit-reviewed basis. For a Center in operation for 10 years after its previous selection on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, the Director may renew support for the center on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis for a period of not more than 5 years, and may subsequently provide an additional renewal on a merit-reviewed basis for a period of not more than 5 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE659314FCC644D119E1D6AAA8EB9653C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Consistent with the existing authorities of the Department, the Director of the Office of Science may terminate an underperforming center for cause during the performance period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDC083C28E5114D0A887C5D928B69B1A4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Technology transfer</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Technology Transitions, shall implement partnerships with industry groups for the purpose of facilitating the translation and transfer of research results produced by the Centers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87DD95741D07429E99FA326FE71951CC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H77DF0FE9F44F43B2B9373246C52D39C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish a coordinating network to coordinate cross-cutting research and foster communication and collaboration among the Centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7554269966554EC09A5B108063CDD25B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ensure the coordination, and avoid unnecessary duplication, of the activities of each Center with the activities of—</text><subparagraph id="HD33128CD905A4AE89325FC4360807D17"><enum>(A)</enum><text>other research entities of the Department, including—</text><clause id="HBACBC1C76C2C463A8E81BB0012A8178A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Nanoscale Science Research Centers;</text></clause><clause id="H9610BC14DF9D4442870BD1C987678BD2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the National Quantum Information Science Research Centers;</text></clause><clause id="HFCB48D841CF24BCD9C62EC54296632A1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the Energy Frontier Research Centers;</text></clause><clause id="HE0FD16F90B0742338780509944AC91D1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the Energy Innovation Hubs;</text></clause><clause id="H28D223F908104BE68C5B04AE1C1BA39E"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the National Laboratories; and</text></clause><clause id="H57F2EC8EADFE48A291A23E7A4090C6D5"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other offices of the Department;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E5B3586AFCB4346B068024197FD6A38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the National Semiconductor Technology Center authorized in title XCIX of division H of the William M. (Mac) Thornberry National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/283">Public Law 116–283</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB4556A7F8714912A70CFB6C7E4303BD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>institutions of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC1552942CB64074873A7F0745470FC3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5818928516E14432889E1A12BA4CC0CC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>research activities carried out by other Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEA7314AB120D432C9139449D0B2A5763" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Workforce development</header><text>Centers established under this section shall support workforce development through—</text><paragraph id="HA1568B8719D9453489792DCD38C6CDB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incorporation of undergraduate students, postdoctoral fellows, graduate students, and early career researchers, as well as K-12 students through opportunities such as dual-enrollment programs and work-based learning programs, as applicable;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25C9C8E7A88449728B2678338140D0CF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hand-on research and equipment training programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90085F64ED1C41C4B6399BA89C8A16F3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>technical training and certificate programs for the skilled technical workforce;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5F68C617B1B433B8644EC7CCE52BEE3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>facilitation of engagement between academic, industry, and laboratory researchers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H368496A0AF704D2693CE1DDE037AB008"><enum>(5)</enum><text>public outreach activities, including to students at K-12, undergraduate, and graduate levels. Such activities may include educational programming with an emphasis on experiential and project-based learning.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H841866DDC727409E9202A4D237445AF9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>In carrying out activities under subsection (e), the Secretary shall ensure program outreach to recruit applicants and engage participants from all regions of the country, especially underserved communities and groups historically underrepresented in STEM.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6B03BF2E826349C4930B646EA4875F3E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Intellectual property</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that the intellectual property and value proposition created by the Centers are retained within the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC6A87F01F1924B1E97E6C9C6D0339F09"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>The Secretary of Energy shall allocate up to $25,000,000 for each Center established under this section for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>August 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

