<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Referred-in-Senate" dms-id="H86BA45FB5814407A8455EBACF5B88D45" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6863 : To designate the medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Memphis, Tennessee, as the “Lt. Col. Luke Weathers, Jr. VA Medical Center”.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IIB</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6863</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSVA00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To designate the medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs in Memphis, Tennessee, as the <quote>Lt. Col. Luke Weathers, Jr. VA Medical Center</quote>.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFAC1565F3EBB466882BF9DEC3B9EA946" style="OLC"><section id="H9130BDF13EB64640B0942B5A09ACA345" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H4A6EDC7BB99042EDA897542F3F32490F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., was born December 16, 1922, in Grenada, Mississippi, then moved to Memphis, Tennessee, at age five.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB80FBFCC3C8148DD952D4C5FD3996F19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., graduated from Booker T. Washington High School and is an alumnus of Xavier University in New Orleans.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76447D33A4FD4A589FA31376E1134C47"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon his graduation, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., enlisted in one of the first training programs for Black pilots, beginning his journey as a Tuskegee Airman.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2E9D37220F74B73A9E66F5B6F4FFA9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within his first few years active in the war, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., named his plane <quote>Spirit of Beale Street</quote>, in honor of his hometown, Memphis, Tennessee. He flew this plane with the <quote>Red Tails</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EA4E00C8F4145BC853A99510F366ECB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>He was credited with shooting down German planes while protecting United States Army Air Corps bombers and shooting down two Messerschmitt 109s in Italy while escorting a damaged B–24 Liberator bomber.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB365FD0A17754C5D9553E2F1C78CF0C2"><enum>(6)</enum><text>During his military service, he rose to the rank of Lieutenant Colonel.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEAFA733555C4E7FB1E413574E4B473C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., received numerous honors and awards throughout his long and distinguished career.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1386EA6D99346A29EA4E6CEE88A8DED"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Among them, he was presented with an Air Medal with 7 clusters and an American Theater Ribbon Victory Medal during his military service.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H301041C734E347D9B753477361C02782"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Following the war, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., returned to Memphis, receiving a hero’s welcome and a key to the city.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4A7A712D4A442BB8E6D191698057931"><enum>(10)</enum><text>On July 13, 1947, he married LaVerne Nailling at St. Therese-Little Flowers Catholic Church in Memphis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H253ED53AA0274C979AF9DDDB5C5FBEB6"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 1960, he accepted a job with the Federal Aviation Administration (hereinafter, the <quote>FAA</quote>) as an air traffic control specialist in Anchorage, Alaska.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8FEAAA1EA754FA3990AD716AC1F0457"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In 1965, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., moved back to Memphis, becoming the first Black air traffic controller in Memphis.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H691DF29A327445D6A5AF4671363D4BF0"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Weathers later held positions with the FAA in Atlanta, Georgia, and the District of Columbia, where he eventually retired in 1985, after serving as a reservist in the military for 23 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB6FFC5AE963406492C2F08EEB403CBA"><enum>(14)</enum><text>During retirement, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., remained active with the Tuskegee Airmen, Inc. and continued to support African Americans in the military.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AB175E239D940DA86378235CE32F262"><enum>(15)</enum><text>In 1995, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., moved to Tucson, Arizona, shortly after marrying Jacqueline Moore Weathers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E0099AC82EB488088775C5A2099877F"><enum>(16)</enum><text>In 2007, Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., and the Tuskegee Airmen were honored with a Congressional Gold Medal.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H690D425ED9FF4CA5B40F87B96E243738"><enum>(17)</enum><text>On October 15, 2011, Luke Joseph Weather, Jr., died in Tucson, Arizona, at the age of 90, leaving behind his wife, two sons and daughters, 12 grandchildren, and 10 great-grandchildren as well as a legacy of countless lives he touched.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65C92D36302B4D81BE104854ABCD53B8"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On January 20, 2012, Lieutenant Colonel Luke Joseph Weathers, Jr., was interred at Arlington National Cemetery.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H676F7600CEC44AC88FF547D5F5D98198"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of the Lt. Col. Luke Weathers, Jr. VA Medical Center</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The medical center of the Department of Veterans Affairs located in Memphis, Tennessee, shall, after the date of the enactment of this Act, be known and designated as the <quote>Lt. Col. Luke Weathers, Jr. VA Medical Center</quote>. Any reference in any law, regulation, map, document, paper, or other record of the United States to such medical center shall be considered to be a reference to the Lt. Col. Luke Weathers, Jr. VA Medical Center.</text></section></legis-body><attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20221114" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives November 14, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="yes">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation></bill> 

