<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H80414D6BA4B349128C68B77D15539388" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7056 IH: Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7056</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220311">March 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000462">Ms. Lois Frankel of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="W000812">Mrs. Wagner</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act to modify the data reporting requirements relating to nonimmigrant employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCA4FE43A64B24B119EC961B0AB5A6CA9" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="HF14AB1414F3049BA8F6591C510337DAC"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Visa Transparency Anti-Trafficking Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBF48DF2F459E4597A4E33B1B857AEB96"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H6AA8B8C8FFC94B63ACFEC135F1E8EE70"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bona fide research purposes</header><text>The term <term>bona fide research purposes</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H1915BFDA83F64F4D88E6942B493D2204"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a systematic study or investigation, including research, development, testing, and evaluation, designed to develop or to contribute to fuller or generalizable knowledge or understanding; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDF8DABDD320D45B98F3468F3BCE1D693"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include—</text> <clause id="HB81D7BD577C84FF1ABED9378EC158CEC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>purposes that are commercial, tortious, or criminal in nature;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4F0F10E559334D70A0BF6B6961C55B47"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>purposes that are related to immigration enforcement; or</text></clause> <clause id="HBF94483638804BD58419B166FB0BD407"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>nonresearch purposes that would not have been practicable, but for access to the information.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCCF2E5A08AB64B7B90731FFAE893520F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employment</header><text>The term <term>employment</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="HA5D29F5FEB5A4E48BDFED82A931D4504"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means employment in the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE715642685C64EA18CB5E81615128D75"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes cultural exchanges, training, and business activities in which the nonimmigrant receives any form of compensation (including a stipend) from any source, whether paid in the United States or in the nonimmigrant’s country of origin, and whether or not authorized by law; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFD2D0F4FEDCD4CEC88200D4283FD032F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include the activities of a nonimmigrant described in section 101(a)(15)(B) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)(B)</external-xref>), except—</text>
<clause id="H977B332C5E164F948FBA2E776A08C00F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>personal or domestic servants accompanying or following to join a nonimmigrant employer who seeks admission into, or is already in, the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="HEF345F9C3B184CA7B1770C2CB5D41C88"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>personal or domestic servants accompanying or following to join a United States citizen employer who has a permanent home or is stationed in a foreign country, and who is temporarily visiting the United States;</text></clause>
<clause id="H99D83490E1D34B09A6A55A2F11E902CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>nonimmigrants engaged in training, services, or work normally allowed under other nonimmigrant visa classifications, including—</text> <subclause id="H375DD62D902143349B1B18CE7E979226"><enum>(I)</enum><text>services described in clause (i)(b) of section 101(a)(15)(H) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>); and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H522BD3C5AF664344B3E312D5CB3A48D8"><enum>(II)</enum><text>training described in clause (iii) of such section; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H5C309402325E485DBFE80FC572C89AE0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>nonimmigrants engaged in the supervision or training of others engaged in building or construction work, but not for the purpose of performing any such building or construction work themselves (as described in section 214.2(b)(5) of title 8, Code of Federal Regulations and section 41.31(b)(1) of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB3989A1234554FAAA657A4E1ADEC9F04"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement</term> includes—</text> <subparagraph id="H5B4D50D4FF7F413EAB09A6FF2CDC01FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal law enforcement officers (as defined in section 115(c)(1) of title 18, United States Code);</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H715FA8F58BFD4DC992C86B90B5F3C9D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Federal law enforcement officers and local law enforcement officers (as such terms are defined in paragraphs (5) and (6) of subsection (b) of the Combat Human Trafficking Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/20709">34 U.S.C. 20709</external-xref>)); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7C99F0A3B3A44D0A1A9152DED836A4A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>State attorneys general (as defined in section 4G(1) of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/15g">15 U.S.C. 15g(1)</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H847392D63B2F4AC0A8DBBC11AB9A53FA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonimmigrant visa classification, status, or subclassification</header><text>The term <term>nonimmigrant visa classification, status, or subclassification</term> means any program, level, category, subcategory, or other type of grouping that—</text> <subparagraph id="H4B9C645C9DED48BE948FBBAF4E23A261"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is part of a nonimmigrant visa classification or status—</text>
<clause id="HD9F9BB63602642BA953DC0FDFB133979"><enum>(i)</enum><text>described in section 101(a)(15) or 214(e) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref> and 1184(e)); or</text></clause> <clause id="H9D9B458A83F148678BEDE408DD353705"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>otherwise established under the immigration laws (as defined in section 101(a)(17) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(17)</external-xref>)); and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4C9BADA1C39C4B9780AAD2CFDD3ABE38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may be specifically created, delineated, or defined in—</text> <clause id="H09A25A14EDF24398827A6AB76D228803"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any Federal statute, regulation, agency guidance, directive, memo, or any other source material, including the Code of Federal Regulations, the Foreign Affairs Manual, and Department of State cables (classified or unclassified); or</text></clause>
<clause id="HEAF04E7E3ED64305B74C3DE6904E8C8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any official form, application, or petition used by the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Labor.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD86D6C826AE6494CA06448799CC69C6B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Service providers to human trafficking victims</header><text>The term <term>service providers to human trafficking victims</term> means any nonprofit, nongovernmental organization that has significant knowledge and substantial experience in human trafficking prevention and eradication, investigation and identification of human trafficking, and delivering wrap-around services to human trafficking victims, including grant recipients under—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7B28A546BD1A4E218F6CC5A79198BCFB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 107(b)(2)(A), 107(f), or 112A of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>, 7105(f), and 7109a); or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3EDFE6A0A08493A969B2DE58047C124"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 202 or 203 of the Trafficking Victims Protection Reauthorization Act of 2005 (34 U.S.C. 20702 and 20703).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H87B418AE1F0C4595BF81E93C0A487578"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker</header><text>The term <term>temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker</term> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H36651C0BB8D8468FA14D971875B7683D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a nonimmigrant—</text>
<clause id="H8398997FC2C24F2A99E5ECB37A5FEEDC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who has been issued a visa under section 101(a)(15) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(15)</external-xref>);</text></clause> <clause id="HA1CFE5998CA8481B90B04403B8383540"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who has petitioned for, requested, or otherwise applied for a visa described in subparagraph (A); or</text></clause>
<clause id="H13C9E60A361D49FF8F34C847B21DB241"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for whom such a visa has been petitioned, requested, or applied; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC1FB9EB9B1D541FD8FDA076F0B728A90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any person authorized to be employed in the United States under any nonimmigrant visa classification, subclassification, or program for nonimmigrants that authorizes employment, except for persons who were issued nonimmigrant visas for the purpose of victim or witness protection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1E7CCC5F1C314DB78BB7CC4D07395157"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Third party intermediary</header><text>The term <term>third party intermediary</term>—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A8D0238020342C4BA2358E3A3BB4874"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any natural person, corporation, company, firm, partnership, joint stock company or association, or other organization or entity, including municipal corporations, that recruits, solicits, or engages in related activities with respect to an individual who resides outside of the United States in furtherance of employment in the United States, including when such activity occurs outside of the United States; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEE38E3F2DAA34DF5A0522AEA88D02A0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes recruiters, subrecruiters, placement agencies, staffing agencies, labor contractors, and sponsor organizations designated by the Secretary of State, including for-profit and not-for-profit sponsor entities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCA596F1B18364EA6BCB683257404388E"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Worker protection organization</header><text>The term <term>worker protection organization</term> means any nonprofit, nongovernmental organization that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H54B4C811F6C4411CBD7E0870C4B6CCD2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promotes compliance with antidiscrimination, wage, occupational health and safety, workers’ compensation and other labor and employment laws and regulations; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE6F79102423646F5BDADD0FA59BA78C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise advocates for safeguarding labor standards and improving workplace protections and working conditions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section>
<section id="H63B1F28363164D2B9D3D104D12B68099"><enum>3.</enum><header>Annual report to Congress on nonimmigrant visas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1184">8 U.S.C. 1184(c)(8)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H99C1509711CE4905A982275768FC4C3B"> <paragraph id="H8413E55BD3384695A7EB0C7A6A60C4CB" indent="up1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the end of each fiscal year, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit a report to the <committee-name committee-id="SSJU00">Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate</committee-name> and the <committee-name committee-id="">Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives</committee-name> that includes, with respect to the reporting period—</text>
<subparagraph id="H7C47F1A3EABA4728985D47FC1F492A33"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of citizens of countries with a Compact of Free Association with the United States who—</text> <clause id="H0E0D2210618D464AAEA9A71CF737AFB4"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are authorized by such Compact to reside indefinitely in the United States as nonimmigrants; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H3495E14F10A44C158824FBEEEDF2C29C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">were admitted to the United States;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H22D73F9E11BC4B0B9E7A76656E513686"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the ports of entry at which the individuals described in subparagraph (A) were admitted; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3313316A5F20455FB825CD8CD9E54756"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to each nonimmigrant visa classification, subclassification, or program for nonimmigrants that authorizes employment, as applicable (except for visas issued for the purpose of victim or witness protection), to the extent that the following data are collected by the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Labor, the Department of State, or any other Federal agency to which the collection of such data has been delegated by any such Department, or by any successor agency to any such department—</text> <clause id="H692A03CD5C8245B8A98AD91469745FA2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of visas that were issued;</text></clause>
<clause id="HC36F8E949A5A4659ADB88B6732E8C68B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of persons who were admitted into the United States;</text></clause> <clause id="H91D754373C5B4AF9A2B14DC13F5E700B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of persons who were otherwise granted legal status;</text></clause>
<clause id="H4515A66720EB4C28BDEDA9181C25CD07"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of visas that expired, were revoked, or were otherwise terminated, respectively;</text></clause> <clause id="HF6B8410F9AB944FABA74EBC1CE49C07A"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers employed in each State;</text></clause>
<clause id="HE55982729BCA4DE2818E94EE6AC09C15"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 employers that hired the most temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers;</text></clause> <clause id="H0A71D5B0C3A64C5A89D853AD03E75999"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 occupations, listed by Standard Occupational Classification Code, in which the largest number of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers are employed in the United States, and the average hourly and yearly salary paid to temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers in each such occupation;</text></clause>
<clause id="HF8C627B0DD374C91AB35037272C2D255"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 most common nationalities of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers;</text></clause> <clause id="HCF219DCB8E4742D184F4C85BAE4AC282"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the 10 third party intermediaries that recruited or hired the most temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers;</text></clause>
<clause id="H3D2CF11C12CB41EBAD3DFA1CE87D3BAD"><enum>(x)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers at each major education level;</text></clause> <clause id="H84B5CBBD66CD45C39A79DB63F7E189C3"><enum>(xi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers who are younger than 20 years of age, between 20 and 24 years of age, between 25 and 29 years of age, between 30 and 34 years of age, between 35 and 39 years of age, between 40 and 44 years of age, between 45 and 49 years of age, between 50 and 54 years of age, between 55 and 59 years of age, between 60 and 64 years of age, or older than 65 years of age, respectively;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA5961C64E665481E980285722D5BEE88" indent="up1"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>the percentage of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers of each sex who were issued visas; and</text></clause> <clause id="H6F111166A06044AE904B46B5ADD659C0" indent="up1"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text>the source of the data described in clauses (i) through (xii).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
<section id="H5FA78EB89B6D4EE497139D25B5F02A1B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Database</header>
<subsection id="H65D85C063480447E94F866CFFF46288A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header>
<paragraph id="H25324EEA3084430C996661B5E483585C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Availability of information</header><text>At the time the Secretary of Homeland Security submits each annual report under section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3, with respect to each temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker, the Secretary shall make the information described in subsection (b) (except for information regarding visas issued for the purpose of victim or witness protection) that is collected by the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Labor, the Department of State, or any other Federal agency to which the collection of such data has been delegated by any such department, or by any successor agency to any such department on a dedicated and searchable database.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBE05060031ED449594513F07E08F4A0B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sources; redundancies</header><text>The database established pursuant to paragraph (1) shall—</text>
<subparagraph id="H8458D40310844CEBBCDEFAD0EBF825FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>indicate the sources from which the information described in subsection (b) is derived; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA19197E218047019F800EE0A057F16F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to the extent that any of the information described in subsection (b) is available from more than 1 source or Federal agency—</text>
<clause id="H026DF4660D2B43508A1F0696B2A23384"><enum>(i)</enum><text>reproduce the information from each source or Federal agency; and</text></clause> <clause id="H24826E3B4CD24293B9DFE5B3C16B8131"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>indicate the source from which such information was derived, including the Federal agency and any relevant petition or application form.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H282511EFA9FF467A885D7232C42684B7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required information</header>
<paragraph id="H1F64F55D0DC641DE8754130E88A7BF92"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Biographical information</header><text>The information made available in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for each temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker—</text> <subparagraph id="H5ACC0817B3054C1DA56289C249937660"><enum>(A)</enum><text>his or her age;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H51461A14A1604B6D87652F827B2F890E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>his or her sex;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7F2D7FDB937043899171CC9095E634D6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>his or her country of origin and local region or State;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA6883ED0DDA14BF38B598222BBAA4D2F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the highest level of education attained, the institution from which such education was attained, and his or her primary field of study; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4E65B31CAB6940B9A1A454BBE0B511A4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the name of the university at which he or she is enrolled.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0B3238CF3DDC46EA98155EBAF2554EF7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Visa information</header><text>The information made available in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for each visa requested by a temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker—</text> <subparagraph id="HFAF4A5ACFAC4436492101240C3259F21"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the visa classification or status that was requested, including—</text>
<clause id="H523958B8F2F44BECBA513A5F48E23340"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any applicable subclassification, preference, or program associated with the visa classification or status; and</text></clause> <clause id="H0CC4F6B7E293403EA8D0E17D0AC4E05C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if applicable, any section cited from the Code of Federal Regulations, Foreign Affairs Manual, or any other Federal guidance document that corresponds to such subclassification, preference, or program;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H29B0DC25BE0A4B64AA29BD6E9C174A90"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the request is for a new visa or an extension of an existing visa or status;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE2491A4EF9DE4FD6BA3D91E50D5B92EE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the status of the visa, such as issued, expired, revoked, or terminated;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDA5026A7EF99411B9409BA1178007796"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the visa was issued pursuant to a blanket petition; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D4CE64ACBB54969AEDA24A8DBC03AC4"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the visa or status was issued at a port of entry and, if so, the port of entry where it was issued.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H326287B198BB4EDCB6183FF0F85FE48E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employment information</header><text>The information made available in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H82BE9C1E533F4E1EAF1BB5B139C767BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for each offer of employment in the United States—</text>
<clause id="H1ABD64167D8049D6B68F1EB7A7463523"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker’s occupation and the standard occupational classification code for the occupation, or any other occupational code listed;</text></clause> <clause id="H70EF64DD5E0E48D5B40DE3DA6458CFAA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the wages, salary, and any other compensation to be paid to the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA6A051FE4E49400CA4F6DB1BE5EF4316"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the address where the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker will work, and any additional worksite addresses;</text></clause> <clause id="H567C39BE6DB64745B529B58A89C65ED7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the address where the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker will reside during his or her employment;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBDCD7BEC927348A99BD6CB43BC0F71CB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>whether the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker will be assigned to work at an offsite location; and</text></clause> <clause id="HBBFF408EA08E45CEB953693B54B8C804"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>whether the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker’s position is a full-time position; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAE85B391C04F4FC0B280D2B2F6E8E422"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for each accepted offer of employment in the United States—</text> <clause id="H2C4C022614E84910973EE6D3A585AC31"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the dates on which the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker began and ended employment; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H57F112B8F26944D0A5255EB2318D9668"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date on which the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker entered the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7A4A0B021DC7459B85BA38F554BD36A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Employer information</header><text>The information made available in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for each employer of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers—</text>
<subparagraph id="H694FDA66FDC545BC9633037B71DA919E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name and address of the employer;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2EB755362F44823A401775C77366355"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if the employer is a household employer, the nationality of the employer;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF6D58DE104114A87B2199367A4EA3307"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the employer is an H–1B dependent employer (as defined in section 212(n)(3)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(n)(3)(A)</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H33177A33C74F4E06BFDF0DBEB2D94E9D"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the employer has ever been found to be a willful violator or to have violated any law or regulation under the employment, labor, or immigration laws of the United States;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8644607B76324F3C978D39B0B13077C0"><enum>(E)</enum><text>whether the employer conducts outplacement of nonimmigrants; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC70AC831D2424863AA650E77B41B3999"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the percentage of nonimmigrants comprising the United States workforce of the employer, including whether the percentage is less than 30 percent, between 30 and 50 percent, or more than 50 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7382C1ECA5994416B96F03C255297339"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application information</header><text>The information made available in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include, for each application filed on behalf of a temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker—</text> <subparagraph id="H477A425EA45B4CA48D11BF96CEB468D8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the date on which the application was filed;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7028863198D140EDB2E8A3E9B0080DDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the status of such application, such as approved, rejected, denied, withdrawn, or awaiting final action;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H78688E6299544B6ABB9914FBB1B74E2D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the application was for the purpose of—</text>
<clause id="H7D61C10568D944B88A1A2B0BBA186CB7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>beginning new employment;</text></clause> <clause id="HC7A46CD02EFA47888724FBFACEA24AD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>continuing previously approved employment with the same employer without change;</text></clause>
<clause id="HBA730701D53C4E8FA1003B6D22A43973"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>changing from previously approved employment;</text></clause> <clause id="HCF450441038940A480FBB6D9F8662A9F"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>new concurrent employment;</text></clause>
<clause id="HA52C91B02BA240EBB4C16C491786B2FC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>changing of employer;</text></clause> <clause id="H63C88C6AAAC84C85BE4519BD4AABDE42"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>amending a petition;</text></clause>
<clause id="H789A26F51A28490BB814F52AB25B9618"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>requesting initial permission to accept employment;</text></clause> <clause id="H205854873789488B8514F7EB180DE111"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>renewing permission to accept employment; or</text></clause>
<clause id="H8E741566B4594AC594A71CC69D0CCEB0"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>something not described in clauses (i) through (viii);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H91BE44858C5241408CA9AAC3824B9BA5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the application was a blanket petition;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2FE60CEB417841788AFFD6B357B7C74C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the total number of temporary foreign nonimmigrant workers included in the application;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCFC31482375B47808B13B6A88081DAA2"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the application number;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H391BC9CC3AA64E509D187642F1A7290F"><enum>(G)</enum><text>whether the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker is eligible for employment authorization based on pre-completion optional practical training, post-completion optional practical training, or STEM optional practical training;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H92E95909C45F4A9F80847871AA227306"><enum>(H)</enum><text>if the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker is eligible for employment authorization based on STEM optional practical training—</text>
<clause id="H83D5FE406ADC419196129C8200192C18"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the worker’s degree; and</text></clause> <clause id="HF071989B2A3741E7A75B106B9FEC03CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the name of the worker’s employer; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7E10A8C8E48A4D169D89CB16E1CB9883"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the name of the person or entity that filed a permanent status petition on the behalf of the temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6D1551A8CAFC4D73B15DB9240AE60AFA"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Third party intermediary information</header><text>The information made available in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall include the name and last known domestic and foreign business address of any third party intermediary involved in identifying workers for employment in the United States with a nonimmigrant visa.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HD7AEBC773F924A6F80EF6A77E4D4BBF2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recipient entities</header>
<paragraph id="H3AB95A0424A9448F87AFA6674B8BFF5E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The database established pursuant to subsection (a), including all personally identifiable information including in such database, shall be made available only to—</text> <subparagraph id="H47F90B5BF7A54139BD01211C893E6DFF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">law enforcement agencies;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8D778A3F2AA042DC84068B1727AAAB4C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">service providers to human trafficking victims;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4728E00F8C3A40B3BF2BEBE37F00672F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">worker protection organizations; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDD0BAB0F0F9345AC857471817CF51D8A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entities agreeing to only use such information for bona fide research purposes.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A1F8AA2E3144FB19638CB5359C09DDB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>Any entity receiving data under paragraph (1)(D) for bona fide research purposes shall certify that the entity—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD68E2B9C42A341039A0886C090C1CF71"><enum>(A)</enum><text>will only use the data for research purposes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97B16707029C4C4DABEF71F39CFF33EF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will not share or disclose the data in disaggregated form, in a manner that would make any personally identifiable information discernible, with any individual or entity that has not been approved by the Department of Homeland Security to receive such disaggregated data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6EE6007D2BF24B8A9AB86B9FC963939C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Privacy protection</header><text>Any government official who uses information contained in the database established pursuant to subsection (a) shall take reasonable steps to ensure that such use does not enable such information to be manipulated—</text> <subparagraph id="H0D2881ECDBBE4F31B9920E5AB9AC1C9F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to identify an individual nonimmigrant to whom the information relates; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3D921887E9F84E5D86C1E107E47F6924"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to disaggregate such information into its component parts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H247119DD2ED143B6A64D0F8374A60C9D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rulemaking</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H61448DAE183C4741A15DF58A9EDF7D4E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promulgate a rule that establishes—</text> <subparagraph id="HBE913C7C661D4BAC8FE1C3C3E783D497"><enum>(A)</enum><text>procedures for requesting and accessing information contained in the database established pursuant to subsection (a), which access may not be limited to fewer than 5 years; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H08B1108380344F76B8F39FC8C15A7EFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>security procedures for protecting such information, including rules relating to personnel security, physical security, and network security; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H07C2988620324C64AE25A9F28B622FA1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promulgate regulations making the information described in subsection (a) available to the public in a searchable database format, except for—</text>
<subparagraph id="HFBF0456229D640EAB7C67CFA553FB417"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any personally identifiable information, including—</text> <clause id="HF166C77E62FF4EEE98692DA01E7C0A38"><enum>(i)</enum><text>worksite address, but shall include the State in which the worksite is located; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H0313ABA8CD8647CC874407D46780FCDD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the names of any household employers;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC8F51B05E5964682B70A7280A7838C65"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any query that returns fewer than 10 workers; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB6DBB5CA833B4664AF3C80C29D737B77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any information that, alone or in combination, would allow a reasonable person who does not have personal knowledge of the relevant circumstances, to identify a specific temporary foreign nonimmigrant worker with reasonable certainty.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H2D5D4AC9A1A045F1B745A18140C983EE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Authority to modify forms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, and the Secretary of Labor may take such steps as may be necessary to revise any application, petition, form, or database used to regulate the issuance of visas to nonimmigrants or to grant nonimmigrant status to comply with the reporting requirements set forth in section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3.</text></section>
<section id="H97099C573E60449CBFF9B1D6F37DEA4E"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authority to immediately update fees</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Notwithstanding the requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Administrative Procedure Act</quote>) or any other law, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Labor may, without notice and comment, reasonably adjust applicable fees charged to any person or entity to the extent necessary to recover the full cost implementing this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="HA133B6FB9C574841A7D803A91A3AF3ED"><enum>7.</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State and the Secretary of Labor shall—</text>
<paragraph id="HAE5B6F77C2BD4B0BA036F3CC698B46E3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>annually submit to the Secretary of Homeland Security, in a timely manner, any information collected or maintained by the Department of State or the Department of Labor that is required to be included in the annual report under section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H14A9233FE7BE4835920793BD407BC165"><enum>(2)</enum><text>provide any other related information to the Secretary of Homeland Security, upon request, that may be necessary to carry out the Secretary of Homeland Security’s responsibilities under this Act and the amendment made by section 3.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H4CAD7B37779A4F9CA80E57E08AEF75B3"><enum>8.</enum><header>Exemption from Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The requirements under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), shall not apply to any action to implement this Act or the amendments made by this Act.</text></section> <section id="HE72B13C2645F407D90DE3D2D9F41A716"><enum>9.</enum><header>Progressive implementation</header> <subsection id="HDB9753B3B0AD4722A71DD9703B5D8F65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit the first report required under section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3, based on the information that is available from the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Labor, and the Department of State as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H25A296B1FB2A495C85EAB19E19E65838"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Full report</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall submit the report required under section 214(c)(8) of the Immigration and Nationality Act, as amended by section 3, which shall include all of the information and data listed in subparagraph (C) of such section, which is collected by the Department of Homeland Security, the Department of Labor, the Department of State, or any other Federal agency to which the collection of such data has been delegated by any such Department, or by any successor agency to any such Department.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H3159D965E0194F739A8AA2C91247209D"><enum>10.</enum><header>Continued reporting</header> <subsection id="H913868ADC35B47E2AC45F0D1EB02095E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Federal and State administrative agencies shall continue to publicly report all nonimmigrant visa data required by law as of the day before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H40B0DCBCCA204868AA59486C01F40352"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the reporting requirements under this Act or the amendments made by this Act may be construed to replace—</text> <paragraph id="H8D3B58D9806C47A4A6C3DCACFF71B610"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any reporting requirements under any statute or regulation in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H477900B838A840569749B6B7A4061EA2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any reports or publicly available microdata published by any Federal agency pertaining to any nonimmigrant visa classification that authorizes employment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

