<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H42A45FCA907A41C68DA8A8C5A6AFB4BD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7163 IH: Sanctioning Putin’s Enablers Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7163</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220318">March 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions on government officials of Russia and Belarus who directly enabled Russia’s invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H07D77C7D9F584A2089A962FE0358C70E" style="OLC"><section id="HDDBF6336AC144C71A5A129B468DA09E4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Sanctioning Putin’s Enablers Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H86C788A4DBE5471CB5663F843331509A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Imposing sanctions on government officials of Russia and Belarus who directly enabled Russia’s invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022</header><subsection id="HA26C77996D774939A8AFDEAC7D5489F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 5 days after the date of the enactment of the Act, the President shall impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any individual serving in any of the following positions:</text><paragraph id="H4CEE22FD96B84AB28D5E42A1F4EF7532"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any member of the Russian Federation Council which took part of the February 22, 2022, vote to authorize Russian military force outside the boundaries of Russia which led to the invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCABE363D72A541D59D4C95C8B407166A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any member of the Russian State Duma that voted in favor to authorize Russian military force outside the boundaries of Russia which led to the invasion of Ukraine on February 24, 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D8E9954C7424BF5AAC4ED66AA079EE5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any member of the Russian Security Council who spoke in favor of recognizing Donetsk and Luhansk, also known collectively as Donbas, as independent of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14BBE80C99424743ADB3FED894EFFD7A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any member of the Central Election Commission of Belarus that orchestrated the February 27, 2022, constitutional referendum that permitted Belarus to host the nuclear weapons of Russia permanently in Belarus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFD37FDAE28AB4DE28948C38B1BD0E9B5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text>The sanctions in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H13114F8AEE79496A88CB5CB2CB31CD4F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of an individual described in subsection (a) if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H866206BEE6E64F48BB5E9948ACFBBEF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Ineligibility For Visas, Admission, Or Parole</header><subparagraph id="H3FA4C9C040B144798912A38679496381"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien described in subsection (a) is—</text><clause id="H22B5D364AED647CCB86763EBD9B197A6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="H3D4F015D5DDB402680888AC4AE3D0EBB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H7A53BB66A2254B278108BC2DD2873569"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H198F612EBDF54147938C18A6A1A5B16F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="HFA828873A0A34769B56F8CE028D45A96"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An alien described in subsection (a) is subject to revocation of any visa or other entry documentation, regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="H530ABF3348F44E24B566C9ABFDB1F135"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="H7DFB4EAEE5F14BFC8F1B0B1690C8E8AF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H02D9EBF0770C49488AA2923BBF169266"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H24FDE195E4F84CD4B2D84714D53315A9"><enum>3.</enum><header>Presidential authorities with respect to the conflict in Ukraine</header><subsection id="H17F5CE42EC344EBCAA2D2E93DA85F19C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall, by any means of instructions, licenses, or other regulations as may be promulgated by the President, confiscate any property or accounts subject to the jurisdiction of the United States of any person described in section 2(a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H156A46718A2446F09386DF42E760C9CE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of liquidated funds</header><text>Any funds derived from liquidation or sales pursuant to subsection (a) shall be used solely for the benefit of the people of Ukraine, for the following purposes:</text><paragraph id="HA591EBFCD161401F9D36B93860CB6671"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Post-conflict reconstruction in Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B89E97387784E3B84EE97A470C498E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Humanitarian assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5F6A33F5A9C4EF5BCE75D098643382A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Weapons for the uniformed military forces of the elected Government of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD82745A0C1B43BB8B070D51B6088DCA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Provisions to support refugees and refugee resettlement in neighboring countries and in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H9EE78CF47154412B93FC17D08D8EB8F2"><enum>4.</enum><header>Financial institution requirements</header><subsection id="H56935A835C774657959BEE0CECEEE614"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A United States financial institution shall take all actions necessary and available to cause any entity or person owned or controlled by the institution to comply with any of the provisions of law described in subsection (b) to the same extent as required of a United States financial institution.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCCCB88DD59B94792A85B6D8AFF530DC4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Provisions of law described</header><text>The provisions of law described in this subsection are any prohibition or limitation described in statute, regulation, or order applicable to a United States financial institution concerning the Russian Federation or the Republic of Belarus, involving—</text><paragraph id="HA052D7C964CD4A1DADDA90C9E6E50215"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the conduct of transactions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H967C0E01D50E49BFBE26073C096C5044"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the acceptance of deposits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F6EA761217B40FDBB521981425CEB2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the making, granting, transferring, holding, or brokering of loans or credits;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBD8F51625E54916AD23625DF61B5FAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the purchasing or selling of foreign exchange, securities, commodity futures, or options;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36DC8AF0BCFD4746808DB499C0D1729B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the procuring of purchasers and sellers described under paragraph (4) as principal or agent; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFA6055CE64E48B697DADB26D53FABAD"><enum>(6)</enum><text>any other good or service provided by a United States financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9FD37D8EB42444688840D90A01701F4A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A United States financial institution that violates subsection (a) shall be subject to the penalties described in the applicable statute, regulation, or order applicable to a United States financial institution.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8C10A3930FA24C37BCB4EDE5A2C20F30"><enum>(d)</enum><header>United states financial institution defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>United States financial institution</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>U.S. financial institution</quote> in section 561.309 of title 31, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

