<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H720F46FBC9B54F1092B6BB2AEA115AAF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6866 IH: Safer Seas Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6866</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220228">February 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 46, United States Code, to provide for certain protections against sexual harassment and sexual assault, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H418E2594C82740C2ABB0FF076D6AF2EB" style="OLC"><section id="H701BC0EBB7AA43F2917780083F042719" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safer Seas Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBA06600EFA134C2AB506D03FC7A7DDF1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><subsection id="HC2A6597EE70B496C855B3FB220CC44BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2101 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H720228302C6C4353B3F1EC28CBE4D843"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (45) through (54) as paragraphs (47) through (56), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H800CA181F9D240E787000C3C18A37B07"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (44) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HFA3818732BD54467B6BD91EBF0452C14" style="USC"><paragraph id="HAA451C06095C496687D2371C1A4D20E0"><enum>(45)</enum><text><quote>sexual assault</quote> means any form of abuse or contact as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, or a substantially similar State, local, or Tribal offense.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79261E37D0AF49B6BD81BCD25F8E9DAA"><enum>(46)</enum><text><quote>sexual harassment</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H1344A0ECBBA34C47A69A1D660ABAF8AE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>conduct that—</text><clause id="HF5FAF770725B4423841FA797FD58A8BD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>involves unwelcome sexual advances, requests for sexual favors, or deliberate or repeated offensive comments or gestures of a sexual nature if any—</text><subclause id="HD9EFC8C8A0C049A4A898513E46E42839"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submission to such conduct is made either explicitly or implicitly a term or condition of employment, pay, career, benefits, or entitlements of the individual; </text></subclause><subclause id="H387FDDC86E884B70962BE3AAB0BF09F3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submission to, or rejection, of such conduct by an individual is used as a basis for decisions affecting that individual’s job, pay, career, benefits, or entitlements;</text></subclause><subclause id="H02A6A4EB9CAB4C93A842099D0AB00B23"><enum>(III)</enum><text>such conduct has the purpose or effect of unreasonably interfering with an individual’s work performance or creates an intimidating, hostile, or offensive work environment; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HC11DA2C669774156B92CBCF53AECD4D4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>conduct may have been by an individual’s supervisor, a supervisor in another area, a co-worker, or another credentialed mariner; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H05661CB14EA04FA8BB3E02A7DDC224C0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is so severe or pervasive that a reasonable person would perceive, and the victim does perceive, the environment as hostile or offensive;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9ACF6247C434BFD82B73CE409A38C1E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any use or condonation associated with firsthand or personal knowledge, by any individual in a supervisory or command position, of any form of sexual behavior to control, influence, or affect the career, pay, benefits, entitlements, or employment of a subordinate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1A49A0770244170A5D8501049965A1C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any deliberate or repeated unwelcome verbal comment or gesture of a sexual nature by any fellow employee of the complainant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H73FD74B109B548C4B06A60DD3B99AE9E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commandant of the Coast Guard shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report describing any changes the Commandant may propose to the definitions added by the amendments in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H7DA0C7595D474023BAAFC28EFD49F2DA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Convicted sex offender as grounds for denial</header><subsection id="H9ACB0512D2D546DF978810313D74F958"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/75">Chapter 75</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HAEDF9C00176B414FB244EC3A0074095C" style="USC"><section id="HCDF1099587A44BE086D22CD4AFF7C08D"><enum>7511.</enum><header>Convicted sex offender as grounds for denial</header><subsection id="HFD89627122AC44E9824D07ECE27E8C37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sexual abuse</header><text>A license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document authorized to be issued under this part shall be denied to an individual who has been convicted of a sexual offense prohibited under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/18/109A">chapter 109A</external-xref> of title 18, except for subsection (b) of section 2244 of title 18, or a substantially similar State, local, or Tribal offense.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC47C0C8B4D854068A246DD8F310044F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Abusive sexual contact</header><text>A license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document authorized to be issued under this part may be denied to an individual who within 5 years before applying for the license, certificate, or document, has been convicted of a sexual offense prohibited under subsection (b) of section 2244 of title 18, or a substantially similar State, local, or Tribal offense.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC0606AD2D1654EDEA271251762DDDF3F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/75">chapter 75</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD2B85811406842F89364B15CC4851485" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">7511. Convicted sex offender as grounds for denial.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HE1CD55586C9547B2B3C76152135FA9E1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Sexual harassment or sexual assault as grounds for suspension or revocation</header><subsection id="HEB99C7F66D3040E3B7389F8865BABB61"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/77">Chapter 77</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/46/7704">section 7704</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7299DEC6D516481F815D9FF22266E263" style="USC"><section id="H186BF57A9F8E4DC08902387EDA2315E0"><enum>7704a.</enum><header>Sexual harassment or sexual assault as grounds for suspension or revocation</header><subsection id="HCD33F214F04046738B49733B61BB1C58"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sexual harassment</header><text>If it is shown at a hearing under this chapter that a holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under this part, within 5 years before the beginning of the suspension and revocation proceedings, is the subject of an official finding of sexual harassment, then the license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document may be suspended or revoked.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1010370735E14B1A82DD8916A96F42BF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sexual assault</header><text>If it is shown at a hearing under this chapter that a holder of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document issued under this part, within 10 years before the beginning of the suspension and revocation proceedings, is the subject of an official finding of sexual assault, then the license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document shall be revoked.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCF74BEFE794D4F3BADD4A7B86C2CA661"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Official finding</header><paragraph id="H9B31BEC977BB4BFBABBC90CE2E6B1838"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>official finding</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H3051733F48CC4AB0813195DAFA3CF831"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a legal proceeding or agency finding or decision that determines the individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault in violation of any Federal, State, local, or Tribal law or regulation; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8BAAAC2D40140EB860FC1F1CC2E076F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a determination after an investigation by the Coast Guard that, by a preponderance of the evidence, the individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault if the investigation affords appropriate due process rights to the subject of the investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA44451A2F7B94CF1B65F397D71161790"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Investigation by the Coast Guard</header><text>An investigation by the Coast Guard under paragraph (1)(B) shall include, at a minimum, evaluation of the following materials that, upon request, shall be provided to the Coast Guard:</text><subparagraph id="H1B2D93840D814B518E69308A7B6733C0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any inquiry or determination made by the employer or former employer of the individual as to whether the individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0ABF45F239014D1FA3048503EDC0931C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Any investigative materials, documents, records, or files in the possession of an employer or former employer of the individual that are related to the claim of sexual harassment or sexual assault by the individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02075E4FA91340F6B5CD543FC5BD8C59"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administrative Law Judge review</header><subparagraph id="H79D4621031874E9C9DCF476A51950E88"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Coast Guard investigation</header><text>A determination under paragraph (1)(B) shall be reviewed and affirmed by an administrative law judge within the same proceeding as any suspension or revocation of a license, certificate of registry, or merchant mariner’s document under subsection (a) or (b).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E5A72DC864F4EF2895CA11A43234E3A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Legal proceeding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination under paragraph (1)(A) that an individual committed sexual harassment or sexual assault is conclusive in suspension and revocation proceedings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H2E30B71C41474383B273E4098EDA10B8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The chapter analysis of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/77">chapter 77</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/46/7704">section 7704</external-xref> the following:</text><quoted-block id="HEAFDE61262834BCD8F27F77587E21BC4" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">7704a. Sexual harassment or sexual assault as grounds for suspension or revocation. </toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H3138C7279B1A4F5998BF2C75910A1085"><enum>5.</enum><header>Accommodation; notices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 11101 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H439BB0C3EF814E95869E48CA194FF76B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a)(3), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19562ED0D2034E6F908D590E3A39B5AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9FD83E7B8C74C0F9BD21F6F51AC8E15"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC7C8B9227D704A17B374B0E0F3F1F104" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1AC8307CB59C4B2AA1A7EAC0479FD741"><enum>(5)</enum><text>each crew berthing area shall be equipped with information regarding—</text><subparagraph id="H55CFDC0BCDDF45A2AE598F9109080202"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">vessel owner or company policies prohibiting sexual assault and sexual harassment, retaliation, and drug and alcohol usage; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB91723F36214D558D66FA779ADB9087"><enum>(B)</enum><text>procedures and resources to report crimes, including sexual assault and sexual harassment, including information—</text><clause id="HE720B4D42CD74EBBB774DD2BD983D887"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on the contact information, website address, and mobile application to the Coast Guard Investigative Services for reporting of crimes and the Coast Guard National Command Center;</text></clause><clause id="H4D1DC3BE48BF4B0D9033A05F06D9034A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>on vessel owner or company procedures to report violations of company policy and access resources;</text></clause><clause id="H03E05681151E44DABB08ED7198A3694D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>on resources provided by outside organizations such as sexual assault hotlines and counseling; </text></clause><clause id="H8BD6B9D443874BA29C654E256404C8F0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>on the retention period for surveillance video recording after an incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault is reported; and</text></clause><clause id="H5FF16CE91D7F40BC9142B939C5DBC89B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>additional items specified in regulations issued by, and at the discretion of, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE2898AA3F8E4DA8B4A6F340E1CEB663"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d), by adding at the end the following: <quote>In each washing space in a visible location there shall be information regarding procedures and resources to report crimes upon the vessel, including sexual assault and sexual harassment, and vessel owner or company policies prohibiting sexual assault and sexual harassment, retaliation, and drug and alcohol usage.</quote>. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H63A524FDD4B245BEB10A054D40668A3C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Protection against discrimination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2114(a)(1) of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC13A0F544CA94466A389194C3E4080F0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (B) through (G) as subsections (C) through (H), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H55D5F9A99F4B4143A00F44F9915D8889"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (A) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7F43EC6B7BAF4F198B8882D25E508FFE" style="USC"><subparagraph id="H8FA77942857347D9A8C53B5F6B86846D" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the seaman in good faith has reported or is about to report to the vessel owner, Coast Guard or other appropriate Federal agency or department sexual harassment or sexual assault against the seaman or knowledge of sexual harassment or sexual assault against another seaman;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H7AC129C411254B7193DF5591F9CF1FE5" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Alcohol prohibition</header><subsection id="H9A698C7A356E4BB3AD61C198A4FA4F3F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="HE029D0D367C441E5974A37288533EEF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating shall, taking into account the safety and security of every individual on documented vessels, issue such regulations as are necessary relating to alcohol consumption on documented vessels, according to the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H974882CC26F14F7887ED4C38FA83BB31"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall determine safe levels of alcohol consumption by crewmembers aboard documented vessels engaged in commercial service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71FDBE06144E4BFBA3EB82F0BAB3E4E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary determines there is no alcohol policy that can be implemented to ensure a safe environment for crew and passengers, the Secretary shall implement a prohibition on possession and consumption of alcohol by crewmembers while aboard a vessel, except when possession is associated with the commercial sale or gift to non-crewmembers aboard the vessel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBD8C6D4374149DD97751E7BAE99F2A0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Immunity from civil liability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any crewmember who reports an incident of sexual assault or sexual harassment that is directly related to a violation of the regulations issued under paragraph (1) is immune from civil liability for any related violation of such regulations.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HD832F03382FB406A8049458C0936CA55"><enum>8.</enum><header>Surveillance requirements</header><subsection id="H96FE43013D934F30AA41A2BEBCCE126A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Part B of subtitle II of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H125133EFFE58430CA9D09D426EF2D135" display-inline="no-display-inline"><chapter id="H58EE78CDB5B543928C88810492896811"><enum>49</enum><header>Oceangoing Non-Passenger Commercial Vessels</header><toc container-level="chapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H58EE78CDB5B543928C88810492896811" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H7A369D758E8049FE9605BB12875D000E" level="section">Sec. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">4901. Surveillance requirements. </toc-entry></toc><section id="H7A369D758E8049FE9605BB12875D000E"><enum>4901.</enum><header>Surveillance requirements</header><subsection id="H08259D2DAF0543929FDEB88D940CB5D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vessel engaged in commercial service that does not carry passengers, shall maintain a video surveillance system.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8565C4D16DB24C039AF1AC71015DC00F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>The requirements in this section shall apply to—</text><paragraph id="H16F8358D6FD24ECDB70D6A4BC82DCB82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>documented vessels with overnight accommodations for at least 10 persons on board—</text><subparagraph id="HD1F03834AC294FB7A4A402F2AAF2073A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is on a voyage of at least 600 miles and crosses seaward of the Boundary Line; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE1F1B3000744514A0B52322BBE2FE24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is at least 24 meters (79 feet) in overall length and required to have a load line under chapter 51; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC341A8F851D49049D804C2731776C6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>documented vessels of at least 500 gross tons as measured under section 14502, or an alternate tonnage measured under section 14302 as prescribed by the Secretary under section 14104 on an international voyage; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAF0DC0700E54D37B3C70E6A8913E521"><enum>(3)</enum><text>vessels with overnight accommodations for at least 10 persons on board that are operating for no less than 72 hours on waters superjacent to the Outer Continental Shelf.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H159D6068955B42828318D7039A2A1D38"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Placement of video and audio surveillance equipment</header><paragraph id="HE653CA17FC1B4ABB9E6D4F7EA412BE8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The owner of a vessel to which this section applies shall install video and audio surveillance equipment aboard the vessel not later than 2 years after enactment of the <short-title>Safer Seas Act</short-title>, or during the next scheduled drydock, whichever is later.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02FC9CE72DD141229711D0FB9E19F6A1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>Video and audio surveillance equipment shall be placed in passageways on to which doors from staterooms open. Such equipment shall be placed in a manner ensuring the visibility of every door in each such passageway.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6482CEA4D8BA486D88E3673C880B0030"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notice of video and audio surveillance</header><text>The owner of a vessel to which this section applies shall provide clear and conspicuous signs on board the vessel notifying the crew of the presence of video and audio surveillance equipment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H89218475BE6544F9B1F7A6B34D90C5BB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Access to video and audio records</header><paragraph id="H65D96072AB4040419B7D9179DF17B526"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The owner of a vessel to which this section applies shall provide to any Federal, State, or other law enforcement official performing official duties in the course and scope of a criminal or marine safety investigation, upon request, a copy of all records of video and audio surveillance that the official believes is relevant to the investigation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H056CE6DDEAA54219AD61D862374F6403"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil actions</header><text>Except as proscribed by law enforcement authorities or court order, the owner of a vessel to which this section applies shall, upon written request, provide to any individual or the individual’s legal representative a copy of all records of video and audio surveillance—</text><subparagraph id="H56A893B31DD6451786D7CBBECA697F41"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in which the individual is a subject of the video and audio surveillance;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H10B4B139D9914CAB9325EAF3686A20D0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the request is in conjunction with a legal proceeding or investigation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27878B1BD8F34FA3BA86D5A3EA7005DE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>that may provide evidence of any sexual harassment or sexual assault incident in a civil action.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CC28E4AB542481682D23D3D7DA6DBB7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limited access</header><text>The owner of a vessel to which this section applies shall ensure that access to records of video and audio surveillance is limited to the purposes described in this paragraph and not used as part of a labor action against a crewmember or employment dispute unless used in a criminal or civil action.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H110B9C0F69DB4F9889DE404E9CB38222"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Retention requirements</header><text>The owner of a vessel to which this section applies shall retain all records of audio and video surveillance for not less than 150 days after the footage is obtained. Any video and audio surveillance found to be associated with an alleged incident should be preserved for not less than 4 years from the date of the alleged incident. The Federal Bureau of Investigation and the Coast Guard are authorized access to all records of video and audio surveillance relevant to an investigation into criminal conduct.</text></subsection><subsection id="H52D5201F152A4F2F9BBCD605DFC5AF46"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>owner</quote> means the owner, charterer, managing operator, master, or other individual in charge of a vessel.</text></subsection><subsection id="H61DFB93EB7F248D6A7206B90C055F33E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Fishing vessels, fish processing vessels, and fish tender vessels are exempt from this section.</text></subsection></section></chapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0729D26FCF7642989E08744F4273F72A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of chapters for subtitle II of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding after the item related to chapter 47 the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H5B354709EA7749B6BE10EAFFC2A19D44" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><multi-column-toc-entry level="section" bold="on"><toc-enum>49.</toc-enum><level-header level="section" bold="on">Oceangoing non-passenger commercial vessels</level-header><target>4901</target></multi-column-toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H3F9A838D27AD46458C058F5A8A7211DE"><enum>9.</enum><header>Master key control</header><subsection id="H03FD67C1A6D74AA7A7FE2DFB30A74EC1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/31">Chapter 31</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H491FC7CC31B94AFA99111A5CF68FD388" style="USC"><section id="H252BB62C68914AE08DF98EDD291B0957"><enum>3106.</enum><header>Master key control system</header><subsection id="HAAB08141C01C4E67A67BE426E13D467B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The owner of a vessel subject to inspection under section 3301 shall—</text><paragraph id="H58B7356EDF7F4E2785E209C61E351647"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure that such vessel is equipped with a vessel master key control system, manual or electronic, which provides controlled access to all copies of the vessel’s master key of which access shall only be available to the individuals described in paragraph (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB05B9BFD3D04D76A0FEA4B23DC1D847"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish a list of all crew, identified by position, allowed to access and use the master key and maintain such list upon the vessel, within owner records and included in the vessel safety management system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBA50130E40F4991A1AD416229102F56"><enum>(3)</enum><text>record in a logbook, located in a centralized location that is readily accessible to law enforcement personnel, information on all access and use of the vessel’s master key; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6721227262B74724927B4908562750C2"><enum>(4)</enum><text>make the list under paragraph (2) and the logbook under paragraph (3) available upon request to any agent of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, any member of the Coast Guard, and any law enforcement officer performing official duties in the course and scope of an investigation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD79CBAA33D0F43689202BDC0BD1E9986"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibited use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Crew not included on the list described in subsection (a)(2) shall not have access to or use the master key unless in an emergency and shall immediately notify the master and owner of the vessel following use of such key.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB99B9EF5C8594E7CAFE23D3AF45E1CC4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements for Logbook</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The logbook described in subsection (a)(3)—</text><paragraph id="H58C325A4153047A3A5EF767713BD3EEB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may be—</text><subparagraph id="H63CFBEA7DFF243C4896D29105E23AE72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>electronic;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H828B122C1E4546B1A43F49F0D4B10B94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>included in the vessel safety management system; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34FE40FC52C54CCCBBD23D5991C42C56"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HE0CED56C6A8B4C8F9FCDC9C2E2D53C55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>dates and times of access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B18D2B224994D2DA9F7597BE4D1039B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the room or location accessed; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H147C58266E8849788B8717FFD53668ED"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the name and rank of the crewmember who used the master key.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H505BCD48A5D146C8BE72CE06F45FA136"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Any crewmember who uses the master key without having been granted access pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall be liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $1,000 and may be subject to suspension or revocation under section 7703.</text></subsection><subsection id="H459287515F4C464281298FAD71D3A338"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to vessels subject to section 3507(f).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3A2BB0DE5E174493914CB52E3C02EF29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HACE5BCB7FFB447199FAA9D35EBF8AFE3" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">3106. Master key control system.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HAA69A6DA0FC24F1BAFDD7FABEEC211BA"><enum>10.</enum><header>Safety management systems</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3203 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2E6E0634977343C99C702867B7097D7A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><subparagraph id="H81432E1684BB447798124F2AE32072C8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (5) and (6) as paragraphs (7) and (8); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2E5E2297156453A82F9FB72CEA411A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (4) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD1B6C7300264403C82AB5A1FD51A05C6" style="USC"><paragraph id="H6842A94766224C82BD419084FD03B8F4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to sexual harassment and sexual assault, procedures for, and annual training requirements for all shipboard personnel on—</text><subparagraph id="H2D7F222B94DA4F9A92429CFD4D8E2313"><enum>(A)</enum><text>prevention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0FD201FA81D4ECE8CA7900E9C6F16C8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bystander intervention;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8EE71F8ABFC420F9FC55DFDACB078BF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>reporting;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48A8651EBA6B48349D29DC98E606B4B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>response; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D156D96CC6544CFBD48DBC0EB0E92CC"><enum>(E)</enum><text>investigation;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8F2D361400849318C1FAADB3FFA044C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the logbook required under section 3106;</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H92C3BCEA5B6F470A8ACC77F91D0C186C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (b) and (c) as subsections (c) and (d), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1761F21662945CBA0639D8BB4921630"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HFAC96B42A1054E44901E5F41421C3B0D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3BC3394DE9EB44498CE38CE85E8E2862"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procedures and training requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In prescribing regulations for the procedures and training requirements described in subsection (a)(5), such procedures and requirements shall be consistent with the requirements to report sexual harassment or sexual assault under section 10104.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HECA29FF643DC4CBE95BD69EC3E99BCB6"><enum>11.</enum><header>Requirement to report sexual assault and harassment</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 10104 of title 46, United States Code is amended by striking paragraphs (a) and (b) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF7B4D75C4DB34C3BAE99D00B62B080DB" style="USC"><subsection id="HBCC559A2B8A24377A93FDD5D7EA092F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting by Crewmember</header><paragraph id="H088D71760D994375BA0CE43149C9DF7F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A crewmember of a documented vessel shall report to the Secretary any complaint or incident of sexual harassment or sexual assault of which the crewmember has firsthand or personal knowledge.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA49D1D1C4D04F71843AD054EE5A8D7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A crewmember with firsthand or personal knowledge of a sexual assault or sexual harassment incident on a documented vessel who knowingly fails to report in compliance with paragraph (a)(1) is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $5,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEEC7C1B093243F3ACE44C7E65DC4060"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Amnesty</header><text>A crewmember who fails to make the required reporting in paragraph (a)(1) shall not be subject to the penalty described in paragraph (a)(2) if the complaint is shared in confidence with the crewmember directly from the assaulted individual or the crewmember is a victim advocate as defined in section 12291 of title 34, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB54BD9E2CC6B47E1BD75587E45E01257"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandatory reporting by vessel owner</header><paragraph id="H06950C1D580140E5A7B4D2B3327B3C76"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A vessel owner or managing operator of a documented vessel or the employer of a seafarer on that vessel shall report to the Secretary any complaint or incident of harassment, sexual harassment, or sexual assault in violation of employer policy or law, of which such vessel owner or managing operator of a vessel engaged in commercial service, or the employer of the seafarer is made aware. Such reporting shall include results of any investigation into the incident, if applicable, and any action taken against the offending crewmember.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF736E772C83248C48E4B6B200D6160FA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>A vessel owner or managing operator of a vessel engaged in commercial service, or the employer of a seafarer on that vessel who knowingly fails to report in compliance with paragraph (b)(1) is liable to the United States Government for a civil penalty of not more than $25,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE2209C9C76FE405BB63AF7C20F422D23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting procedures</header><paragraph id="HFEE262C8CB0648E68B666C567C1791B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A report required by subsection (a) shall be made as soon as practicable, but no later than 10 days after the individual develops firsthand or personal knowledge of the sexual assault or sexual harassment incident to the Coast Guard National Command Center by the fastest telecommunication channel available.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H649BDAA5089242D1BA88151D73EFB3C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A report required under subsection (b) shall be made immediately after the vessel owner, managing operator, or employer of the seafarer gains knowledge of a sexual assault or sexual harassment incident by the fastest telecommunication channel available, and such report shall be made to the Coast Guard National Command Center—</text><subparagraph id="HDBD00E5575674E73964625FCDEDB7185"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the nearest Coast Guard Captain of the Port; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A5A052AFA2F45A29DEED31B714309F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate officer or agency of the government of the country in whose waters the incident occurs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC44F84E2AB564A4DA3339136AD54D28C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A report in subsections (a) and (b) shall include, to the best of the reporter’s knowledge—</text><subparagraph id="HD3CB03D86E45448BB137DB9C955BC117"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name, official position or role in relation to the vessel, and contact information of the individual making the report;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D597CFD022645BF818F46E0EA580E71"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the name and official number of the documented vessel;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A902A3940104FA49DB33ADF2C75D412"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the time and date of the incident;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H196CF65727674AB8BF12C76133DDF917"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the geographic position or location of the vessel when the incident occurred; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0000DA087F241479F5E17897FB5461F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a brief description of the alleged sexual harassment or sexual assault being reported.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DFADE1CA54C4333985BB18CE684E858"><enum>(4)</enum><text>After receipt of the report made under this subsection, the Coast Guard will collect information related to the identity of each alleged victim, alleged perpetrator, and witness through means designed to protect, to the extent practicable, the personal identifiable information of such individuals.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HECC9278B0F8C41399AB686193E92718B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The requirements of this section are effective as of the date of enactment of <short-title>Safer Seas Act</short-title>. The Secretary may issue additional regulations to implement the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE01C376D91174CDE8D26AA93E10647BC"><enum>12.</enum><header>Civil actions for personal injury or death of seamen</header><subsection id="HA6FC2B5345F340E9963514BECC2C3F3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Personal injury to or death of seamen</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30104 of title 46, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>, including an injury resulting from sexual assault or sexual harassment,</quote> after <quote>in the course of employment</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1CDA285B6CEF43AA9AEE30BAE534D7DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Time limit on bringing maritime action</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 30106 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAC2389BFA28F4509B8EF2EB185201FF5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">for personal injury or death</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1621EB2D8F74C959EAC79A1D8284326"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Except as otherwise</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H52C60D93D3514391A23E513EA9865385" style="OLC"><subsection id="H79649AC9755E447A80FBEB1A812989A2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as otherwise</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4FB12FD457D46CEB40E4C1BF6F54CB8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H084E928C164F46B59360AE901778D83F" style="USC"><subsection id="H78FB6DAA4BA1474995A0C4009D107ED6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extension for sexual offense</header><text>A civil action under subsection (a) arising out of a maritime tort for a claim of sexual harassment or sexual assault shall be brought not less than 5 years after the cause of action for a claim of sexual harassment or sexual assault arose.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36779CEB48244D6CA6F9D3EEF12677CD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/301">chapter 301</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code, is amended by striking the item related to section 30106 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE9728805466A458DBF89E41044D43DA1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">30106. Time limit on bringing maritime action.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H26CB93B2FFFD490985031C72E4BE3FCF"><enum>13.</enum><header>Exemption from requirement to obtain mariner license</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 51309 of title 46, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HF3E9D6E016954407A841B35ABD0ADAB2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H6A5EB66133934EF28D833C5BB8E2CC60"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption from requirement To obtain license</header><text>The Secretary may modify or waive the requirements of section 51306(a)(2) for students who provide reasonable concerns with obtaining a merchant mariner license, including fear for safety while at sea after instances of trauma, medical condition, or inability to obtain required sea time or endorsement so long as such inability is not due to a lack of proficiency or violation of Academy policy. The issuance of a modification or waiver under this subsection shall not delay or impede graduation from the Academy.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H0004C5B2D6DF4812AACBD32B0D5ECCD2"><enum>14.</enum><header>Protection of cadets from sexual assault onboard vessels</header><subsection id="H01C4EE40E7AA4DBD9B6BA21F4952306E" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 51322 of title 46, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H45B93335933E41718D65CACD74D8C2C1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (a) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6369BC38EA0A45A697615EB36735FB1E" style="USC"><subsection id="H901925AC3676418BAD525E39BB1642CD" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Safety criteria</header><text>The Maritime Administrator, after consulting with the United States Coast Guard, shall establish—</text><paragraph id="H8D074137AFF04520A35D820237805B31" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>criteria, to which an owner or operator of a vessel engaged in commercial service shall adhere prior to carrying a cadet performing their Sea Year service from the United States Merchant Marine Academy that addresses prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43FF31B404B642E1B11657B34E2DAB64" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a process for collecting pertinent information from such owners or operators and verifying their compliance with the criteria.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA368B447378447389D444BE3BC8CDFD4" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Minimum standards</header><text>At a minimum, the criteria established under subsection (a) shall require the vessel owners or operators to have policies that address—</text><paragraph id="H094CD5C773B349B0A3CFA7BCD8790DA1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>communication between a cadet and an individual ashore who is trained in responding to incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F66F8B3B739490C8E770933313CAE9B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the safety and security of cadet staterooms while a cadet is onboard the vessel, including the installation of functional door locks and policies prohibiting shipboard personnel from entering cadet staterooms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6687BE9295A4690B13F9046203AB74B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>requirements for crew to report complaints or incidents of sexual assault, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, and stalking consistent with the requirements in section 10104;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A01FCDDA65F4DFF87E4CA2A025E98B3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the maintenance of records of reports of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking onboard a vessel carrying a cadet;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5414271DCE184CABB356DFCEAE386A7F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the maintenance of records of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking training as required under subsection (f);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCEF9991854D4A29AD895A79ED923D17" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>a requirement for the owner or operator provide each cadet a copy of the policies and procedures related to sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking policies that pertain to the vessel on which they will be employed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AB4057A49754B689F8C43BD88146A8E" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>any other issues the Maritime Administrator determines necessary to ensure the safety of cadets during Sea Year training.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0209C90FA404D678A795DBAF553A399"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Self-Certification by owners or operators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Maritime Administrator shall require the owner or operator of any commercial vessel that is carrying a cadet from the United States Merchant Marine Academy to annually certify that—</text><paragraph id="HD7C9248CB70D43849034D8E1837B55AA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the vessel owner or operator is in compliance with the criteria established under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67E50AF31E904528A66AB5AD592D99F8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the vessel is in compliance with the International Convention of Safety of Life at Sea, 1974 (32 UST 47) and sections 8106 and 70103(c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B8C839307214A849D016E485875DE3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information, training, and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Maritime Administrator shall ensure that a cadet participating in Sea Year—</text><paragraph id="H8256A02015D343F3BFB30C9B1588FC5D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>receives training specific to vessel safety, including sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking prevention and response training, prior to the cadet boarding a vessel for Sea Year training;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DFB4D14E48F4A5F946F9796D4221DA5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is equipped with a satellite communication device and has been trained on its use;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H949AD39A4E624DF7893C6945008E1BBF" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>has access to a helpline to report incidents of sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, or stalking that is monitored by trained personnel; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0D4A66881BD46A895A4B32A83A76FD5" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>is informed of the legal requirements for vessel owners and operators to provide for the security of individuals onboard, including requirements under section 70103(c) and chapter 81.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE40AD28E9F94C18989A3C5B4B460E01" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subsections (b) through (d) as subsections (e) through (g), respectively; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H710B85032D044D488C78C0BB8989CF82" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (e), by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCC87BECDF5784EFEA6E69DC2D7AC8D5E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8170C45E6E6C487C9F762537C80773B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access to information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The vessel operator shall make available to staff conducting a vessel check such information as the Maritime Administrator determines is necessary to determine whether the vessel is being operated in compliance with safety criteria developed pursuant to subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEA3AAC802CF46D4B1FC1AE689BD442D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Removal of students</header><text>If staff of the Academy or staff of the Maritime Administration determine that a commercial vessel is not in compliance with the criteria established under subsection (a), the staff—</text><subparagraph id="HE50992637AF44137AB70132690ABADA7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may remove a cadet of the Academy from the vessel; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDABFC4785CD04813AE36785A28BCEECB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall report such determination of non-compliance to the owner or operator of the vessel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HA88F11E173B848BF805C03500EB8D857" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (f), as so redesignated, by striking <quote>or the seafarer union</quote> and inserting <quote>and the seafarer union</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CE08107145A4851A41CB0E740C5BD2A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCE312A9E322140619CD529B9F4A4AD1B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HDEA65CF1BED84A80BDB25E714E173A38" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Noncommercial vessels</header><paragraph id="H049C4CD3E95F40B09938543373F5AA12" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A public vessel (as defined in section 2101) shall not be subject to the requirements of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACAA8CE6AC794FDC8B6AE6DC94479957" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for participation</header><text>The Maritime Administrator may establish criteria and requirements that the operators of public vessels shall meet to participate in the Sea Year program of the United States Merchant Marine Academy that addresses prevention of, and response to, sexual harassment, dating violence, domestic violence, sexual assault, and stalking.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H40B7633BF4AE4ABAB3016A11A23C53E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><paragraph id="H9F9B2D54ED77486DB1207AFC87CCA7EA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Maritime Administrator may prescribe rules as necessary to carry out the amendments made by this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80C2D6623DAD43B8B28563347431E521"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interim rules</header><text>The Maritime Administrator may prescribe interim rules necessary to carry out the amendments made by this section. For this purpose, the Maritime Administrator in prescribing rules under paragraph (1) is excepted from compliance with the notice and comment requirements of section 553 of title 5, United States Code. All rules prescribed under the authority of the amendments made by this section shall remain in effect until superseded by a final rule.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1CC44EB52214D0CA7BEFD686A3C7476"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HC66F08A86C1B4AD78AFC5B48CCD9ED90"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sea Year compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3514 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/46/51318">46 U.S.C. 51318</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC06BB3806264AA0AD49308761451E0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access of Academy cadets to DOD SAFE or equivalent helpline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3515 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/46/51518">46 U.S.C. 51518</external-xref> note) is amended by striking subsection (b) and redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

