<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0E2B4B7B0AD4EBDA6AF9014376C01E5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7837 IH: National Guard Promotion Improvement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7837</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="K000388">Mr. Kelly of Mississippi</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve promotion practices in the National Guard, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4994A522F29A4D5EA05633AC5A0F591A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H174F4D3F7B844232830C83B516AC73AC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Guard Promotion Improvement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H5F922EFFE7354D82B8823BD15D84891B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA5404F1EB7D5482DA890A8FE51F992B8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>existing processes contribute to the long delays experienced by reserve officers of the National Guard for Federal recognition of State vacancy promotions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H27ACE0C9A65748999825798A8B614DE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>unduly delayed promotions have a significant impact on members of the National Guard as they manage their careers and make financial plans for the future, and pose retention challenges.</text></paragraph> </section> 
<section id="H79B3EF6BB9284D62815BFBAB6B662609"><enum>3.</enum><header>Independent study on Federal recognition process</header> 
<subsection id="HEC685DF50EB949EDBCA049729BD5B77C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent study</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center to conduct a study on the National Guard commissioned officer and warrant officer promotion system and provide recommendations to the Department of Defense, the Department of the Air Force, the Department of the Army, the National Guard Bureau, and individual State National Guard commands.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H5D8C2156D9B641AF976CACAE5D0310DC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The study referred to in subsection (a) shall include a comprehensive review and assessment of the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HCDEB6B26C2CF4FE29D20CF1341EB5470"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Federal recognition process used to extend Federal recognition to State promotions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H562CF33A7CB24E25B7F66C92B4E745A1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Best practices among the various State National Guards for managing their requirements under the existing National Guard promotion system.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H75975960AB29406BA14F2CAE13077E8F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Possible improvements to requirements, policies, procedures, workflow, or resources to reduce the time required for Federal recognition to be extended to a State promotion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6B8415851FDB40B4988BF9F888FB695B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The feasibility of developing or adopting a commercially available solution for an integrated enterprise information technology system for managing National Guard officer and warrant officer promotions that allows seamless transition for promotions as they move through reviews at the National Guard Bureau, the Department of the Army, the Department of the Air Force, and the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE971F35966E140DAAB808273D77F1C74"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Possible metrics to evaluate effectiveness of any recommendations made.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H40379247616C433AAC9D8E183B954624"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other matters the federally funded research and development center determines relevant. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H5F5FFBD4D5D84054B0A9DFA0FB2B8BC6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header> 
<paragraph id="H2BDF1CEC02A54AD2BDEDD841AAEAC22D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The contract under subsection (a) shall require the federally funded research and development center that conducts the study under the contract to submit to the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of the Army, the Secretary of the Air Force, and the Chief of the National Guard Bureau a report on the results of the study.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6325DFA26F96428294BE034915CF429E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after receiving the report required under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall submit an unedited copy of the report results to the congressional defense committees. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="H82B22E8DB52648278A49D9239F23DB44"><enum>4.</enum><header>Backdating of effective date of rank for reserve officers in the National Guard due to undue delays in Federal recognition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Paragraph (2) of section 14308(f) of title 10, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block id="HCA8D872B6B9F4D279847636E53121BEF" style="OLC" act-name=""> <paragraph indent="up1" id="HE257684051594E258B4B5C5AAD017D08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>If there is a delay in extending Federal recognition in the next higher grade in the Army National Guard or the Air National Guard to a reserve commissioned officer of the Army or the Air Force that exceeds 60 days from when the National Guard Bureau received the promotion from the State, and the delay was not attributable to the action or inaction of such officer, the effective date of the promotion concerned under paragraph (1) shall be adjusted by the Secretary concerned to not later than 60 days after the National Guard Bureau received the promotion but not earlier than the effective date of the State promotion.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> 
<section id="HCE7C80A3CBF144F9BA2C99896A002EAE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header> 
<subsection id="H28DFA956F46343E38E5629542B9C8F9F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter until the date specified in subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense, acting through the Chief of the National Guard Bureau and in consultation with the Secretary of the Army and the Secretary of the Air Force as appropriate, shall submit to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report detailing the current status of the Federal recognition process for National Guard promotions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H0BFE0F81C282409DAF7611D751538126"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text> 
<paragraph id="HE549881E63B846D3B872C4A46FDBA7AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An update on actions taken to reduce the average time needed to extend Federal recognition in the next higher grade in the Army and Air National Guards to a reserve commissioned officer promotion.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEFD226282FB145ED9ED3A47DBF172613"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The average time it took during the previous fiscal year to extend Federal recognition in the next higher grade in the Army National Guard to a reserve commissioned officer of the Army, as measured from the date at which the National Guard Bureau received the promotion until the date at which Federal recognition was granted.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5278C6A1CC924419B27A0373D76D8E75"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The average time it took during the previous fiscal year to extend Federal recognition in the next higher grade in the Air National Guard to a reserve commissioned officer of the Air Force, as measured from the date at which the National Guard Bureau received the promotion until the date at which Federal recognition was granted.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1BEC4DAB029C4BE9B1BFCB9437CE391C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The number of Army National Guard officers who experienced Federal recognition delays greater than 60 days in the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2F1B3067B1284C4891C72AB6C5C7D47D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The number of Air National Guard officers who experienced Federal recognition delays greater than 60 days in the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BA741879864497893B5A6F5BC341041"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A summary of any additional resources or authorities needed to further streamline the Federal recognition to reduce average Federal recognition delays to less than 60 days.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H56DBE2BF548F46088FBF51CDA643DA93"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Any other information the Chief of the National Guard Bureau or the Secretaries concerned determine relevant. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD3D5044D023848CAAA1812DD4B9B32C5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expiration of annual reporting requirement</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) may be submitted once every three years after the Secretary of Defense certifies to the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives that the average delay for Federal recognition of Army National Guard and Air Force National Guard members is less than 60 days.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

