<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H81C0C6DA0D2646AEBCF26152E37A30BF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7966 IH: Secure Every School and Protect Our Nation’s Children Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7966</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220607">June 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000809">Mr. Womack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001301">Mr. Bergman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000299">Mr. Johnson of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001196">Ms. Stefanik</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001054">Mr. Carl</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000546">Mr. Graves of Missouri</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000377">Mr. Armstrong</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001212">Mr. Moore of Alabama</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for increased authorization of funding to secure schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0DA20B70DB00461BB6537BA29EC83FDA" style="OLC"><section id="HC2877884C05C499E82972E4F44111A35" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Secure Every School and Protect Our Nation’s Children Act</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>STOP II Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2CA966663FC14E5B81A2B1ECCBD767B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Increased authorization of funding for certain programs</header><subsection id="H805302DFDB0345A8ACD065E1FFEC6368"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Byrne-JAG</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2023, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out the grant program under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), in addition to any amounts made available for such purpose, $500,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided, </italic>That such amounts shall be used for additional personnel.</text></subsection><subsection id="H267F4E89966848C2BCD87F15A40AEDAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>COPS</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2023, there is authorized to be appropriated to the Attorney General to carry out the grant program under part Q of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381 et seq.</external-xref>), in addition to any amounts made available for such purpose, $500,000,000, to remain available until expended: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such amounts shall be used as provided under paragraphs (1) and (2) of section 1701(b) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10381">34 U.S.C. 10381(b)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H650F39F081004ADA8839AD973D01895F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>STOP School Violence</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (a) of section 2705 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10555">34 U.S.C. 10555</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF2AA88AB55E945089161B211EC8943B0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H8010F340C50B456AB77A9A9306F47DF7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated $833,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028, of which—</text><paragraph id="HC271773B78384EEFB4B2338D705623FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$555,333,334 shall be made available to the BJA Director to carry out this part; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H463096A717D44F40BE2EBF6319140AB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>$277,666,666 shall be made available to the COPS Director to carry out this part.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3D37C5117592406AAF3D65B42CBD8F1A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Grants for mental health guidance counselors</header><text>Section 4112 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7122">20 U.S.C. 7122</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H72D6C185CC694F58965BB6F92D97BFFC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by inserting <quote>, other than subsection (c),</quote> after <quote>this subpart</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H753829603F9B4F2C8533ADCCE8078D2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE1DE0889C754485E8553B2CCE88FBC03" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HF9E453915D3E45A883700A2D78296A58"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Mental health guidance counselors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There authorized to be appropriated for the hiring of mental health guidance counselors by State and local educational agencies $1,000,000,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3F1CDBA7BDF48DB9A10E21BCB065854"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Offset</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the unobligated balances from amounts made available under sections 602(a)(1) and 603(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/802">42 U.S.C. 802(a)(1)</external-xref>, 803(a)) on the date of enactment of this Act, $7,055,000,000 is rescinded as of such date: <italic>Provided</italic>, That such rescission shall be applied first on a pro rata basis to the unobligated balances of the payment amounts allocated by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to subsection (b)(3)(B) of section 602 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/802">42 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That any remaining amounts to be rescinded shall be applied next on a pro rata basis to the unobligated balances of the payment amounts allocated by the Secretary of the Treasury pursuant to subsection (b)(1)(B) and (b)(2)(B) of section 602 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/802">42 U.S.C. 802</external-xref>): <italic>Provided further</italic>, That any remaining amounts to be rescinded shall be applied on a pro rata basis to the unobligated balances of the payment amounts allocated by the Secretary of the Treasury for each of the entities authorized to receive payments under section 603 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/803">42 U.S.C. 803</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H227057549C0741EE9E38BE20DED86986"><enum>3.</enum><header>Additional authorized use of STOP School Violence grants</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 2701 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H672D639CF0DD4E5BA6B95927D47F6129"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1), by striking <quote>paragraphs (5) through (9)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (5) through (10)</quote>; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7C4A3E7861D484DB39EF145009D709B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H9B9B0915CB6241978D490CB9001FFEFE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (9) as paragraph (10); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74AEA383161A4A778EC30901106F536F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (8) the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H051C94C2088847A09AD9E8762372CA31" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H8E41D05BEDAF4644892BB5BDFD8C8C66"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessment of a school to find weaknesses in security and identify any lack of coverage in mental health support staff for students.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H13D98D00A1654A1E93388A40EE7D3E76"><enum>4.</enum><header>Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices</header><subsection id="H9F95D37BED584C128EB9267130E4C87C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle A of title XXII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/651">6 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1A96326B8A6444388D93E875225EB15D" style="OLC"><section id="HE7AA6BBBECF145A08EA138EF2D2C5F3A"><enum>2220D.</enum><header>Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices</header><subsection id="H72FA451E67CB4A2598BCE49D51F005C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><paragraph id="HBCF698E8FEE64BB7A0C57A54AC5BD3B9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in coordination with the Secretary of Education, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall establish in the Department a Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices (in this section referred to as the <quote>Clearinghouse</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7FCCD170AC14A59A971FB421E4B5715" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clearinghouse shall be the primary resource of the Federal Government to identify and publish online through SchoolSafety.gov, or any successor website, best practices and recommendations relating to school safety for use by State educational agencies and local educational agencies, institutions of higher education, State and local law enforcement agencies, health professionals, and the general public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EA7597D6D5641829756FE185B259958"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Personnel</header><subparagraph id="HE36FA845697C481687BB4ABF906E119E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Assignments</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall be assigned such personnel and resources as the Secretary considers appropriate to carry out this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F83BEFC356E4E049840F694B11CA166"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Detailees</header><text>The Secretary of Education, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services may detail personnel to the Clearinghouse.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HABA7D794BA7F43409C40E1EAE1AACC2B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exemptions</header><subparagraph id="HFACB7E740E404BD3ABEE2B1FD5D86AD7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Paperwork Reduction Act</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">Chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>) shall not apply to any rulemaking or information collection required under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF394ADEA95C4132B31EAB127A78D27C"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) shall not apply for the purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E663B906B5B48E6B0744619138A16AD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clearinghouse contents</header><paragraph id="H4AA65F77E1B240F7B3B253C24410FA0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In identifying and publishing best practices and recommendations pursuant to subsection (a)(2), the Clearinghouse may consult with appropriate Federal, State, local, Tribal, and private sector entities, and nongovernmental organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC5752C3F381045D3B3A61D86EF57ECC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Criteria</header><text>Best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse identified and published pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall, at a minimum—</text><subparagraph id="H1097AE0FC79A445691E739A9A5239183"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">incorporate comprehensive school safety measures, including threat prevention, preparedness, protection, mitigation, incident response, and recovery to improve the safety posture of a school, including relating to the health, safety, and welfare of persons in school settings; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="H3ADD3ACE84D3431A887617B7875A2B31"><enum>(B)</enum><text>include any evidence or research rationale supporting the determination of the Clearinghouse that the best practice or recommendation at issue has been shown to have a significant effect on improving the safety posture of a school, including relating to the health, safety, and welfare of persons in school settings, including—</text><clause changed="not-changed" id="H7C9A43C4FF1E427584497A57D04E4840"><enum>(i)</enum><text>relevant research that is evidence-based supporting such best practice or recommendation;</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" id="HA0E8763FB4C14704B62611A27C672FED"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">findings and data from previous Federal or State commissions recommending improvements to the safety posture of a school, including relating to the health, safety, and welfare of persons in school settings; or</text></clause><clause changed="not-changed" id="H8553164236614473B5BE99977D83139D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other supportive evidence or findings relied upon by the Clearinghouse in determining best practices and recommendations to improve the safety posture of a school, including relating to the health, safety, and welfare of persons in school settings; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD95CA1AF66A94A418329CD4B31D5B00D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>include information on Federal grant programs for which implementation of such best practices or recommendations is an eligible use for any such program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC2B9A5737A5479598DC71A5DC1A9338"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Other best practices and recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the greatest extent practicable, in identifying and publishing best practices and recommendations pursuant to subsection (a)(2), the Clearinghouse shall so identify and publish, as appropriate, best practices and recommendations to improve the safety posture of a school, including relating to the health, safety, and welfare of persons in school settings, adopted by a Federal, State, local, Tribal, or private sector entity or nongovernmental organization.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B5B3D02D38449A384A9A23B2CE983CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Assistance and training</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Clearinghouse, may publish materials to assist and train State educational agencies and local educational agencies and State and local law enforcement agencies regarding the implementation of best practices and recommendations identified and published pursuant to subsection (a)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H7D43CA63B62040A58EC8752AFA7E0751"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Continuous improvement</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H023F7C19C0D04E05AAB70CE597FFA6FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect for the purpose of continuous improvement of the Clearinghouse—</text><subparagraph id="H4415004FB0B2450EA28F26279913A709"><enum>(A)</enum><text>data analytics; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC44616D188B743CF8EFEBFF82795C6A9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>user feedback on the implementation of best practices and recommendations identified and published pursuant to subsection (a)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph changed="not-changed" id="HA66191F9DB1844E7BADBDF120266187A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any evaluations conducted on implementation of such best practices and recommendations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA22456FCE61E4B1CB9EF66E89BA97AA7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in coordination with the Secretary of Education, the Attorney General, and the Secretary of Health and Human Services—</text><subparagraph id="H00E9785E205F41B790CBC658A4BA013B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regularly assess best practices and recommendations identified and published pursuant to subsection (a)(2) with respect to which there are no resources available through Federal Government programs for implementation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95D6E0B6FC704DFCA4448C01B405D70A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish an external advisory board comprised of appropriate State, local, Tribal, and private sector entities and nongovernmental organizations, including organizations representing parents of students attending elementary schools or secondary schools, to—</text><clause id="HB4A24E03DC3945A881DA7626B6C8610A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide feedback on the implementation of best practices and recommendations identified and published pursuant to subsection (a)(2); and</text></clause><clause id="H5151B0C456214227B6132098E6A2A3D1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>propose additional recommendations for best practices for inclusion in the Clearinghouse.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65246E4CC53D42C0AD2420471263E84E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Parental assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Clearinghouse shall produce materials to assist parents of students with identifying relevant Clearinghouse resources related to supporting the implementation of Clearinghouse best practices and recommendations identified and published pursuant to subsection (a)(2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1336E4B6CB8A4D799441B12E44A538F6"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H35AA5ACE2F9D41D3B22C1D62B549EC63"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Elementary school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>elementary school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAA6D277A2D14DA4AD22445BF2781A12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>evidence-based</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B050D80F56E43C8A88820151DA8C4C6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H772B57295AEB4FE89CF9905E64F91983"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDD28A81CBA144EBB794E10D9B2B2688"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Parent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>parent</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EFB7AB695C3449DBC0EDE6C84DABF68"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secondary school</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>secondary school</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB8F4E5137F04577928CA3BE204F15B5"><enum>(7)</enum><header>State educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State educational agency</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0A9506B2CB974E8A9DE227197015D348"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 2220C the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="H74E1AD69620A44EFAD7711BC95187BE4" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry idref="H0DA20B70DB00461BB6537BA29EC83FDA" level="section">Sec. 2220D. Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H8FD1C18B3AF94021B123C3AB09A5B54C" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>5.</enum><header>Notification of Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices</header><subsection id="HA343696938F24C468625A1EA814B4B07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Notification by the Secretary of Education</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall provide written notification of the publication of the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices (referred to in this section as the <term>Clearinghouse</term>) under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 4, to—</text><paragraph id="H63E2E89B2DCE45CE995B449BB0D07377"><enum>(1)</enum><text>every State educational and local educational agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC8FBBB64CA24ED792139A87B0FB05E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other Department of Education partners in the implementation of the best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABE2B011E2A7465080AA6E118EA7EC88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Notification by the Secretary of Homeland Security</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide written notification of the publication of the Clearinghouse under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 4, to—</text><paragraph id="H7145D0F40EF344C9A61850B2AF5415CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>every State homeland security advisor;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9619555E1E574201B9129FAECE813E7E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>every State department of homeland security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2576E39CF0814CC8A1D92F71058AA40F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other Department of Homeland Security partners in the implementation of the best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA44E79FE360A4110AB9EE3D47FA3E338"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification by the Secretary of Health and Human Services</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide written notification of the publication of the Clearinghouse under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 4, to—</text><paragraph id="HF812368792C84C5192BB7FECD4D7D234"><enum>(1)</enum><text>every State department of public health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H925CF6D723F543718AFF2521171361AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other Department of Health and Human Services partners in the implementation of the best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse, as determined appropriate by the Secretary of Health and Human Services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7A0AB0F0735D49C9B0CC35792D56E4ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Notification by the Attorney General</header><text>The Attorney General shall provide written notification of the publication of the Clearinghouse under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 4, to—</text><paragraph id="H2DE604D3A3B44C6C83C6F243FAE50E9F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>every State department of justice; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF73189AB48340EF85ECAFC2F47B8160"><enum>(2)</enum><text>other Department of Justice partners in the implementation of the best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse, as determined appropriate by the Attorney General.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2792626B4DD44CBFA8CA41FC2BA8287B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Grant program review</header><subsection id="H4AFA24C1AC954CADA401B04A951ACD59"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal grants and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Education, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Attorney General shall each—</text><paragraph id="H4599EB1A511E451392E39174FEC48E80"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">review grant programs administered by their respective agency and identify any grant program that may be used to implement best practices and recommendations of the Federal Clearinghouse on School Safety Best Practices (referred to in this section as the <term>Clearinghouse</term>) under section 2220D of the Homeland Security Act of 2002, as added by section 4;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC7EB7C257B343EA98FF69428C7C6655"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identify any best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse for which there is not a Federal grant program that may be used for the purposes of implementing the best practice or recommendation as applicable to the agency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CB6C2A380284D179901A0BCDE063B3C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>periodically report any findings under paragraph (2) to the appropriate committees of Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2C9B482B29EF40B99A608B64DE62C090"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State grants and resources</header><text>The Clearinghouse shall, to the extent practicable, identify, for each State—</text><paragraph id="HC89FF60055A6491280F14A129D4114AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>each agency responsible for school safety in the State, or any State that does not have such an agency designated;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0B9C792BBB3443185A6D8DCF5005A14"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any grant program that may be used for the purposes of implementing best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE13F6C5686C44BC9B26AA734E80F1EED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any resources other than grant programs that may be used to assist in implementation of best practices and recommendations of the Clearinghouse.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section changed="not-changed" id="H9C7E26D1B14445F39D97B37799B59B3C"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rules of construction</header><subsection changed="not-changed" id="HB2E4C137790D49119E45CC9588A5A76C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Waiver of requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to create, satisfy, or waive any requirement under—</text><paragraph id="H790221964D0D407AB40CBA28291D5564" changed="not-changed"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">title II of the Americans With Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA9B3067043D4847A0FD6DF96B559D10" changed="not-changed"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1B5B6614BFE48388E3399E8F717F94C" changed="not-changed"><enum>(3)</enum><text>title VI of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD76E37978C744004AA7E882CDE4D4E89" changed="not-changed"><enum>(4)</enum><text>title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1841AE07988A4DDE88243369496C276B" changed="not-changed"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Age Discrimination Act of 1975 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6101">42 U.S.C. 6101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H374A88A98E314E37A2CB9ADB201AE72D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on federally developed, mandated, or endorsed curriculum</header><text>Nothing in this Act or the amendments made by this Act shall be construed to authorize any officer or employee of the Federal Government to engage in an activity otherwise prohibited under section 103(b) of the Department of Education Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3403">20 U.S.C. 3403(b)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

