<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HCC0A8E89E3354857A6B585BDC275E147" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6754 IH: Russians Engaged in Threating Ukraine Refuge Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6754</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the solicitation of reimbursement of any travel expenses incurred by the Department of State on behalf of any United States citizen or lawful permanent resident evacuated from Ukraine and repatriated to the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0FFA5ED9AE3347DD81BC502EE06C7C1F" style="OLC"><section id="H7485C913EBFE48CB942BAAD399A3DCDE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Russians Engaged in Threating Ukraine Refuge Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RETURN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7CD1F269EE454F4397F1F6798CFDDE31"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on solicitation of reimbursement</header><subsection id="HF88EDAB1B8974642B826C8B6E8E7294F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (b)(2)(A)(ii) of section 4 of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2671">22 U.S.C. 2671</external-xref>), during the period of evacuation related to a Russian invasion of Ukraine and withdrawal of United States Department of State personnel from Ukraine—</text><paragraph id="HF6D1A8E4A8A14762A6122AEFDD02FB61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of State shall waive any repayment of any travel expenses incurred by the Department of State on behalf of any United States citizen or lawful permanent resident evacuated from Ukraine and repatriated to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6C5D5BAF66D4973856E3E4067A4BF0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any promissory note or other obligation to repay an emergency repatriation loan signed by a United States citizen or a lawful permanent resident of the United States to reimburse the Department of State for travel expenses described in paragraph (1) shall be null and void; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACFCA2B883B744FFA068105B893F5ECB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>no Federal official or employee may solicit or accept any amount from any individual who is a citizen of the United States or a lawful permanent resident of the United States, whether in the form of a reimbursement or as any other condition of using transportation provided by the United States, to repatriate such individual to the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4DEF2A59721243F19AC82F067E682AB5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition of denial of travel</header><text>No traveler on any Department of State-sponsored air travel pursuant to subsection (a) shall be denied a flight if such traveler is unable to abide by the requirements the Amended Order: Requirement for Proof of Negative COVID–19 Test Result or Recovery from COVID–19 for All Airline Passengers Arriving into the United States, published on December 2, 2021.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBA5947660CE74F9E8534C8CB5DCF49F0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>This Act shall terminate on the date that is six months after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

