<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H73AA5FD694CD4471A875E409023E1CAF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8401 IH: Transit Oriented Development Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8401</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220715">July 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000396">Mr. Kahele</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C001055">Mr. Case</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to modify the low-income housing tax credit to incentivize affordable and transit-oriented development and development in certain difficult development areas, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC4B1A00B4314BD3AD11454E4EDA4203" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H378CAE67665447409294FA6973F2ABBA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transit Oriented Development Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H454C00366BEB4E6C92A345429443AC6A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Low-income housing tax credit for transit-oriented development areas</header> <subsection id="H6EAA75CA833B453BBD4B726C9B81B21F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">Section 42(d)(5)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H322E9855D7564F64A5D368DF5D5B52CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subparagraph id="H3375D52B408047F59B8532895D680934"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Increase in credit for buildings in transit-oriented development areas</header> 
<clause id="H8F47AE314BEF46919AC2E46D4572D80E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any building located in a transit-oriented development area which is designated for purposes of this subparagraph—</text> <subclause id="HB9D445315E4A43DA886A52B099159394"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a new building, the eligible basis of such building shall be 180 percent of such basis determined without regard to this subparagraph, and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBEE1B146CD004A05800150EE6D3CF363"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of an existing building, the rehabilitation expenditures taken into account under subsection (e) shall be 180 percent of such expenditures determined without regard to this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA2D7B22C8CE641E6B1FEC54518117901"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Transit-oriented development area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <quote>transit-oriented development area</quote> means an area designated by the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development and State housing credit agency as located in an area within <fraction>½</fraction> of a mile from a rail, bus, harbor, or waterway station and as zoned for high-density.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HC5BEC741334E437CA277323A8F3631A3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Limit on areas designated</header><text>The portions of metropolitan statistical areas which may be designated for purposes of this subparagraph shall not exceed an aggregate area having 20 percent of the population of such metropolitan statistical areas. A comparable rule shall apply to nonmetropolitan statistical areas.</text></clause> <clause id="H4AE7FC095EA84986A7060F31872F7CAC"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Coordination with high cost areas</header><text>If the eligible basis of a new building, or the rehabilitation expenditures with respect to an existing building, are determined pursuant to subparagraph (B), such building shall not be treated as located in a transit-oriented development area for purposes of this subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6A3B42B90E6E4A35B5FD547890700AD3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to buildings placed in service after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB586FCBDD1E045B19F931050523AB755"><enum>3.</enum><header>Low-income housing tax credit for difficult development areas in non-contiguous States and possessions</header> <subsection id="H94D641710DF649C49EEC41BC6A87A5BA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">Section 42(d)(5)(B)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC14FCF36DFA4C01B6EFE7DD1B620445" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<clause id="HA9BFF3BC4F5E4637826E1C205366B293"><enum>(vi)</enum><header>Special rule for non-contiguous States and possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of Hawaii, Alaska, and any possession of the United States, subclauses (I) and (II) of clause (i) shall each be applied by substituting <quote>170 percent</quote> for <quote>130 percent</quote>. </text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="H37D0B6CF73A14000950514CEDC8FF22D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by this section shall apply to buildings placed in service after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="H96E3BD5A48C44329815F21A01181B87B" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>4.</enum><header>HUD study regarding adjustment of tax credit allocations to reflect geographic cost-of-living differences</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall conduct a study to identify cost-of-living differences throughout the United States based on geographic location and proximity and accessibility to transit. Not later than the expiration of the 1-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to the Congress setting forth the results and conclusions of the study and recommending formulas for the adjustment of annual allocations to the States of low-income housing tax credits under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">26 U.S.C. 42</external-xref>) to reflect such cost-of -living differences.</text></section> </legis-body></bill>

