<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B5685FEE8DD45DEB4784ABF43D51ED3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8688 IH: To establish a grant program for certain institutions of higher education to plan and implement projects for economic and community development in economically distressed communities, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8688</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220809">August 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="W000821">Mr. Westerman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a grant program for certain institutions of higher education to plan and implement projects for economic and community development in economically distressed communities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HBFE240D433EB4CBEA21877A690F90D98" style="OLC"><section id="HDEE6D377E1704A768479F2B3C781A7F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Distressed communities grant program</header><subsection id="HDF5D0E69739F4F95BD8A18801B0C3DB5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to award grants to institutions of higher education designated under subsection (b) to plan and implement eligible projects for economic and community development in economically distressed communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8744E080BF8545EFAD094A39EF4E15D6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designation of institutions of higher education</header><paragraph id="HAD68730A4B864F029C9D4A253B5C3045"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List of institutions of higher education</header><text>The Secretary shall develop a list of every institution of higher education that the Secretary determines is located in a distressed community, in accordance with the criteria described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D7CE42686554008B4A36CFE65F4B32E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Distressed community criteria</header><text>The Secretary shall determine that an institution of higher education is located in a distressed community if one of the following circumstances applies to such institution:</text><subparagraph id="HF27FC6B9B63C4E688DE3F4682D1B8EF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution of higher education that is located in a metropolitan or a micropolitan statistical area, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, and in a State in which the median family income is higher than the national median family income, the institution of higher education is located in a zip code in which the median family income is at least 25 percent lower than the median family income for such State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42BBC78F5E654A7F9EBE1A9D7CBC8230" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution of higher education that is located in a metropolitan or a micropolitan statistical area, as defined by the Office of Management and Budget, and in a State in which the median family income is lower than the national median family income, the institution of higher education is located in a zip code in which the median family income is at least 25 percent lower than the national median family income.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BFC3E1C867B4BCDA52D83D5C4E2CFB2"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution of higher education that is not located in a metropolitan or micropolitan statistical area and is located in a State in which the median family income is higher than the national median family income, the institution of higher education is located in a county in which the median family income is at least 25 percent lower than the median family income for such State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H82F1DDF7F58A4DF481C5E6D461DCBE7D"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an institution of higher education that is not located in a metropolitan or micropolitan statistical area and is located in a State in which the median family income is lower than the national median family income, the institution of higher education is located in a county in which the median family income is at least 25 percent lower than the national median family income.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C2ACBAB458540998C69AB738C3945E6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Designation</header><subparagraph id="H285E6A68853A48B785C0621747F72D7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Notification to institutions of higher education</header><text>Upon development of the list of institutions of higher education located in a distressed community under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall notify each institution of higher education that is included in such list that such institution may be designated under this paragraph to receive a planning grant and an implementation grant under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC85C16438C74424B8834698CA9F03CEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification to Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An institution of higher education that receives a notification from the Secretary under subparagraph (A) that intends to receive a planning grant and an implementation grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary a notification of such intent in such form and at such time as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4CA9FF2AECF14421964965167ABF0382"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Grant eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall designate each institution of higher education that submits a notification under subparagraph (B) as eligible to receive a planning grant and an implementation grant under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H21207E9A09B444DABF08D526267F553D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Planning grants</header><paragraph id="H4A544412F2AC431BA02E1A619487A574"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide a grant to each institution of higher education designated under subsection (b) for such institution to develop an implementation plan describing—</text><subparagraph id="H8823993CD8E842F1AD9149F4BA4FB087"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the eligible projects that such institution intends to carry out with an implementation grant under subsection (d); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD68FEC2AEF6847D1ADF19EE5AE75F2E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how such projects will support economic and community revitalization in the community in which such institution is located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6BE3F094957436DBA68C82B50EE6D1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation plan</header><subparagraph id="H51985C3EB77441EDA5FB32FE36D0BFA6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A recipient of a planning grant under this subsection shall complete the implementation plan required under paragraph (1) not later than 2 years after the date on which the Secretary provides a planning grant to such recipient.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6DAD32268AA4004B0F0A71507284D44"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>Upon completion of an implementation plan with a planning grant provided under this subsection, the Secretary shall review such plan for approval.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5669E1E5D80E4BE492C6C598D953CE5E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><subparagraph id="H24A046A9E99A4E798BAD2E3407B72686"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grant term</header><text>The Secretary may distribute funds for a grant provided under this subsection for a period of not more than 2 years.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2F89FF092D649F19A7162067FF0E137"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Total grant amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each grant awarded under this subsection shall be in an amount that does not exceed $100,000 for each year of the grant term.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H659F0C44F1C94CDEB17E0553BB548B4D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Additional amounts</header><clause id="H55BC37BC62E84F25B3B141A353A10B0D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Application for additional grant funds</header><text>Not later than 1 year after a grant funds are first awarded under subparagraph (A), a grant recipient may submit to the Secretary an application to receive additional funds to complete the implementation plan required under paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause id="HCB65EC8AD9054204BB6EA2C2DC5FF9C5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Deadline to receive additional grant funds</header><text>Not later than 90 days after a grant recipient submits an application for additional grant funds under clause (i), the Secretary shall determine whether to award additional grant funds to such recipient and shall distribute such additional grant funds to such recipient.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H342342701F7D4F32B4CC10E72E06E6D8"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Formula</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a formula by which the Secretary shall distribute funds for each grant under this subsection in accordance with this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC536CE6C2E646649A6C2A71FB1961A0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header><paragraph id="H439C389F770941A185164656A99337FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon approval of an implementation plan under subsection (c)(2), the Secretary shall provide a grant to the institution of higher education to carry out eligible projects described in such plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB31BC553911446CA25845BFD952D172"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant term</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term of a grant provided under this subsection shall be 5 years. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FC25A77041B444185AB6DEF62791B3F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Grant amounts</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a formula by which the Secretary shall distribute funds for each grant under this subsection in accordance with the following requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H1799BF072D3347488A545D1766848A1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary shall provide each recipient of a grant under this subsection with a grant in an amount that is not less than $25,000,000 and not more than $50,000,000.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8AC4938AF2884EF6AB097D7121DD4FD8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary shall distribute funds for each grant under this subsection at least once during each year of the grant term.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE411518A5BAB4853B9D6ECC69A05F8F8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>A recipient of a grant under this subsection may only use such grant to carry out an eligible project in the distressed community in which such recipient is located, as determined by the Secretary under subsection (b)(2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEEA85E6273A4A2CB5A8865D90BB1208"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>At least once each year during the term of a grant provided under this subsection, a recipient of such grant shall submit to the Secretary a report describing the activities for which such grant was used during such year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC5F53F149B4D42D784B700DFFE4E3307"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H68CF87EC3CA140A8A7D2B4A7F574E209" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible project</header><text>The term <quote>eligible project</quote> means a project that will spur economic development in the community in which such project is carried out, including a project to—</text><subparagraph id="H9FEFFEEC0CDE4DCEB1F1E3E145C7A834"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">renovate, construct, or maintain buildings that will benefit and be accessible to the community, including—</text><clause id="HC200E2D2BB0846708FEC00D362738580"><enum>(i)</enum><text>commercial buildings located on the campus of the institution of higher education carrying out the project;</text></clause><clause id="H0565F36C36CE413B9511E07120B7ADE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">housing for students, faculty, staff, or members of the community;</text></clause><clause id="HFAAD2A9DC2E040ADBBA9CEFF0898919B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>cultural institutions such as museums, theaters, and arts centers; and</text></clause><clause id="H3C409087E5684C4CAD0737E03B6D5EEF"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facilities such as laboratories or libraries;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ACAC39E179040DCB1AA1970F764065E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish programs, hosted by the institution of higher education carrying out the project, that provide seed money to early-stage companies for small business development;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4586B2C03D24CECA02EF46783B7C035"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop and fund apprenticeships, hosted by the institution of higher education carrying out the project, in local industries to decrease unemployment in the community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA7B756CD34D4EED989898B7D214C3F7"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">build and maintain municipal broadband networks and related infrastructure for the institution of higher education that is carrying out the project and the community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD5F47D726654E26A5B07BB1CAFCCD39"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">build and maintain health clinics accessible to the public on or near the campus of the institution of higher education that is carrying out the project;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C7321B442A148D19740EA7E8C6E5767"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish programs at local health clinics to educate, recruit, and train members of the community to become healthcare professionals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE3440001897408A9D8EAC43FA33192F"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish partnerships between the institution of higher education carrying out the project and local school districts to provide—</text><clause id="H141AAD5EB48847A08F5835A60916B24A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">graduate student teaching support;</text></clause><clause id="H30AFCAE1A95D42D7BBCEBB4F2F52DE1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>administrative support to such school districts; and</text></clause><clause id="H760E73E96A124D94AD68B732204B41C6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>access to facilities of such institution of higher education to local elementary and secondary schools; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D4C7681337B4951AC701A5A68AAACD0"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">fund research on the campus of the institution of higher education carrying out the project that is relevant to the economic needs of the community.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD13F854917F147A7809E099C4B954F50"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><subparagraph id="H4C36926321B543DCB0212E3031FBEACB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> means an institution of higher education (as defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)) that has a physical campus and that offers not more than 25 percent of courses through distance education (as defined in section 103(7) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>)), including an institution of higher education established under the Morrill Act of 1890 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/321">7 U.S.C. 321 et seq.</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D165917E214455D861BE1D8CEC00D63"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> does not include an institution of higher education that—</text><clause id="HC058AABB8C55451F895B1B39C3E86639"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is an institution of higher education established under the Morrill Act of 1862 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/301">7 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H6B70859B32BD4D95A920602D4012BD2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has very high research activity status, as designated by the Carnegie Classification of Institutions of Higher Education; or</text></clause><clause id="H20F8A81FB009418CABD6D07715775933"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a service academy. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3507DD55277C46BDA7580A1094F52EC2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Economic Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11681B4D0C82426AABCB92E08857567D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Service academy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>service academy</quote> means the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBF0719EE943146F8972FD0C62612998B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Military Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4961DF0965324A4B9B9F9514C43CE7E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The United States Naval Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB54B7A6C20B44EDA9A970A0797932520"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The United States Air Force Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC634A498AF1843259D4B59224F0CD166"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The United States Coast Guard Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6614153C26C749F18C1F01AA9CE41728"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The United States Merchant Marine Academy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4909D3BE5674F089EBB5ABA3A828F45" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any college or university designated by the Secretary of Defense as a military college.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58CAFD4104B24055BCA5F8ABD7C17C41"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State or regional maritime academy or college sponsored by a State or group of States and assisted under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/46/515">chapter 515</external-xref> of title 46, United States Code. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

