<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBD43F2C26A474CF88101A2B747A26188" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7647 IH: Supreme Court Ethics, Recusal, and Transparency Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7647</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for a code of conduct for justices of the Supreme Court of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H60E9CB0B2488453098B8A70204019014" style="OLC"><section id="H9C5582F85819413B8BB90AA7CD818852" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supreme Court Ethics, Recusal, and Transparency Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H138F2FDDA19C49FC8C382D1A10826428"><enum>2.</enum><header>Code of conduct for the Supreme Court of the United States</header><subsection id="H8A0204AF2179465DBAA066D62CD8F940"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/16">Chapter 16</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HAA7A5C2ABE374485A6B600CD881F4E89" style="USC"><section id="H244C430562774FF7BCD37494C0C45367"><enum>365.</enum><header>Codes of conduct</header><subsection id="H908A54E75C284DE8922A8B7DECD76578"><enum>(a)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Supreme Court of the United States shall, after appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with section 2071, issue a code of conduct for the justices of the Supreme Court.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1141B2AEAF5410C948CC9CD1DE3BF2F"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Judicial Conference of the United States shall, after appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with section 2071, issue a code of conduct for the judges of the courts of appeals, the district courts (including bankruptcy judges and magistrate judges), and the Court of International Trade.</text></subsection><subsection id="H802AEDD9FFEE42A3A6EC5991022BB574"><enum>(c)</enum><text>The Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference may modify the applicable codes of conduct under this section after giving appropriate public notice and opportunity for comment in accordance with section 2071.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H23E8774B46A04F909065FECC0DFCAD2E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB232035D24664D2F95EC488803CA5699" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">365. Codes of conduct.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H61480A5B4FE642C5A88FF0FED08BA559"><enum>3.</enum><header>Minimum disclosure standards for justices of the supreme court</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 677 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H4445942653704CACA109B353588B1D9C" style="OLC"><subsection id="HEE02A0CB73BD40949AE2E898D47BF1E1"><enum>(d)</enum><text>The Counselor, with the approval of the Chief Justice, shall establish rules governing the disclosure of all gifts, reimbursements, and income received by any justice and any law clerk to a justice. Such rules shall at minimum require disclosure of any information concerning gifts, income, and reimbursements required to be disclosed under the Standing Rules of the Senate and the Rules of the House of Representatives.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HB7A4E5C2743C466FA9992983D46FE14D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Circumstances requiring disqualification</header><subsection id="H547C33A611274FE489ACA911092EB623"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Anticorruption protections</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HDE75820C2A764BD78E0F15BFD1E02812" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HCEDC692ED1E14BB9B6230E4149288A15"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Where the justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States knows that a party to the proceeding or an affiliate of a party to the proceeding made any lobbying contact or spent substantial funds in support of the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of the justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3E64AF8F4EB04377A1F421E2BC5DEF3F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Where the justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States, their spouse, minor child, or a privately-held entity owned by any such person—</text><subparagraph id="H1D7C24F16C6D44988687A30918CD1945"><enum>(A)</enum><text>received income, a gift, or reimbursement (as such terms are defined in the <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /109">section 109</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)) from a party to the proceeding or an affiliate of a party to the proceeding; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF741C178E5854A47BCBDDB02168461E7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such receipt occurred during the period beginning 6 years prior to the date on which the justice, judge, bankruptcy judge, or magistrate judge was assigned to the proceeding and ending on the date of final disposition of the proceeding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5360E916483B49FA8EFF7DC05F5DED51"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duty To know</header><text>Subsection (c) of section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="HD702EE772264450CAAAD388DD10A70ED" style="OLC"><subsection id="HA495624CFCA545CFAB24482D0CC3E6A2"><enum>(c)</enum><text>A justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States shall ascertain—</text><paragraph id="H3D498E526E014567AEA983F9D1ABF139"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the personal and fiduciary financial interests of the justice or judge of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H610EFF0F0C9F4F5D8BA4B9CD27C807A5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the personal financial interests of the spouse and minor children residing in the household of the justice or judge of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD668C9F21B846358BC0282A9FF4AD8B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any interest of such persons that could be substantially affected by the outcome of the proceeding.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1AAD4B7BC5EA44C1B3C2F3F241D11094"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Divestment</header><text>Subsection (f) of section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by inserting <quote>under subsection (b)(4)</quote> after <quote>disqualified</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9D83D26B62224D1AA0BADEF57D41D5D3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duty To notify</header><text>Section 455 of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H18B1F02715B84B26BC8280E8F5FB1A6C" style="OLC"><subsection id="H1217EFD153274AF1BC4E9B4F3F130285"><enum>(g)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge learns of a condition that could reasonably require disqualification under this section, the justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge shall immediately notify all parties to the proceeding.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC58C656FC66C4642A5EC1B64FF2D397D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments</header><text>Section 455 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this section, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="HB74909EB80EA4F629B2BB46598FF7551" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the section heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">judge, or magistrate judge</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge</header-in-text></quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECE866317960486291EC58FC817B5C40" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>judge, or magistrate judge</quote> and inserting <quote>judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H163EB56A83F5436092146247B434A75C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="HF4BA26AA2CC54C81A2F3AFEBC686770A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>the judge or such lawyer</quote> and inserting <quote>the justice, the judge, or such lawyer</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD03306B202A4947BF0D9A04E336B738"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)(iii), by inserting <quote>justice or</quote> before <quote>judge</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA681261A9164B05A044121EB01DDF65"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (5)(iv), by inserting <quote>justice’s or</quote> before <quote>judge’s</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H237DA68CB46E4AE59A3100C2B47CB859"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c), by inserting <quote>justice or</quote> before <quote>judge</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4EEFF842FF84941B97ACE52AC458E6A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (d)(4)(i), by inserting <quote>justice or</quote> before <quote>judge</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE6BF512B6FC4BAB8F2A14F07DD2B9CE" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (e), by striking <quote>judge, or magistrate judge</quote> and inserting <quote>judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D53269F69D443B69B09EB716588E325"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>The rules of each court subject to section 455 of title 28, United States Code, as amended by this Act, shall be amended to require that the clerk shall publish timely notice on the website of the court of—</text><paragraph id="HDD704399B381406C832A9BF416999F33"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any matter in which a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge of the United States is disqualified under such section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5624A2842E70443BA09E9203825C2BE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any matter in which the reviewing panel under section 1660 of title 28, United States Code, rules on a motion to disqualify; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H12AB5B30095B426EA234BC87118AD748"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an explanation of each reason for the disqualification or ruling, which shall include a specific identification of each circumstance that resulted in such disqualification or ruling.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H26C6F8CDE07E413B94259C35C1C57BBA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Review of certified disqualification motions</header><subsection id="HB1BF83AD5A6D4E92B48BFAF58F85FDBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H8A27B1A8627448778DD7A55D0911F890" style="USC"><section id="H8A4E6E80FED94014945DE74F7DEC097D"><enum>1660.</enum><header>Review of certified motions to disqualify</header><subsection id="H4535BA11550E43C5AD91A8AA4F90BBBF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Motion for disqualification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge is required to be disqualified from a proceeding under any provision of Federal law, a party to the proceeding may file a timely motion for disqualification, accompanied by a certificate of good faith and an affidavit alleging facts sufficient to show that disqualification of the justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge is so required.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6116961BA7FB49AEBD89C85A385D9285"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration of motion</header><text>A justice, judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge shall either grant or certify to a reviewing panel a timely motion filed pursuant to subsection (a) and stay the proceeding until a final determination is made with respect to the motion.</text></subsection><subsection id="H287DF6F16B92434980102E043CCC11B7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reviewing panel</header><paragraph id="HC9429E7948134F29A96849E342F1EFB3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A reviewing panel to which a motion is certified under subsection (b) shall be selected at random from judges of the United States who do not sit on the same court—</text><subparagraph id="H572F3B9A8A6A4E609E8339820399118D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as the judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge who is the subject of the motion; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E58B91C8E6E498E8A663D6355E4C979"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as the other members of the reviewing panel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA1E2D3FD6B04128A82741A56E600D49"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Circuit limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than 1 member of the reviewing panel may be a judge of the same judicial circuit as the judge, magistrate judge, or bankruptcy judge who is the subject of the motion.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA14497005E8546DBB15F57210B9BFA6D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supreme Court Review</header><text>The Supreme Court of the United States shall be the reviewing panel for a motion seeking to disqualify a justice.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H5B18FFBEF0554F68B415B0732ED6C9FD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H57B4D4B37ECD4F1D8266C41F575797FF" style="USC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1660. Review of certified motions to disqualify.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H142944D4039E4D07BC08628227C184B9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Disclosure by parties and amici</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Supreme Court of the United States shall prescribe rules of procedure in accordance with sections 2072 through 2074 of title 28, United States Code, requiring each party or amicus to list in their petition or brief a description and value of—</text><paragraph id="H8A4EEBCB5F184F89B9F70103A2BC5078"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any gift, income, or reimbursement (as such terms are defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc-act" parsable-cite="usc-act/Ethics in Government Act of 1978 /109">section 109</external-xref> of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 (5 U.S.C. App.)) provided to any justice or law clerk to a justice during the period beginning 2 years prior to the commencement of the proceeding and ending on the date of final disposition of the proceeding by—</text><subparagraph id="H0A91FC1E5E4A418D84C336AC383EC3BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each such party or amicus, or their affiliates;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A43D30ABE69459EB9E9B1E34DCAF948"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the lawyers or law firms in the proceeding of each such party or amicus; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF594A0DC259B47EA971B9496982248F4"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the officers, directors, or employees of each such party or amicus; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EFA272ABE2F4612B36E196CE85B9972"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any lobbying contact or expenditure of substantial funds by any person described in subparagraphs (A), (B), and (C) of paragraph (1) in support of the nomination, confirmation, or appointment of a justice.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H320749D79A864839B78FBA45F9CE37EC"><enum>7.</enum><header>Amicus disclosure</header><subsection id="H9086E1A1C7054B41A83A6196A0C8B330"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">Chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HF6DEB8BDCBE44BC5B8AC5C0F2AA1F8F6" style="USC"><section id="H7EDAE719206A4ED5B7859760735E5C67"><enum>1661.</enum><header>Disclosures related to amicus activities</header><subsection id="H561B74D12FEF418F8DF4B75ABF0DB905"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>covered amicus</quote> means any person, including any affiliate of the person, that files an amicus brief in a calendar year in the Supreme Court of the United States or a court of appeals of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA3D3D691390D494791F19DD1BE8FAEAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><paragraph id="HFF21B2F84FF34B8A86B2229FB7FDA222"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any covered amicus that files an amicus brief in the Supreme Court of the United States or a court of appeals of the United States shall list in the amicus brief the name of any person who—</text><subparagraph id="HF76BE29562D649979EE53F1560EDEA3E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>contributed to the preparation or submission of the amicus brief;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6825BBA45CF54AF7AF6E2FEB2CFA843A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>contributed not less than 3 percent of the gross annual revenue of the covered amicus for the previous calendar year if the covered amicus is not an individual; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98B5F7B546A941E8A3A280897BDB2FEA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>contributed more than $100,000 to the covered amicus in the previous calendar year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB2362D0DE534547AA0C7E5B8142BEC3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The requirements of this subsection shall not apply to amounts received by a covered amicus described in paragraph (1) in commercial transactions in the ordinary course of any trade or business conducted by the covered amicus or in the form of investments (other than investments by the principal shareholder in a limited liability corporation) in an organization if the amounts are unrelated to the amicus filing activities of the covered amicus.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD2C8DDC3FCD14F528D887C4821AE3677"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audit</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct an annual audit to ensure compliance with this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3FDA695001B045279C65504737D92A8E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendment</header><text>The table of sections for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/28/111">chapter 111</external-xref> of title 28, United States Code, as amended by section 5, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HC116DFFCCE684857B0F2B386204A19F0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">1661. Disclosures related to amicus activities.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H8150962EFF8A40E1ACAEC6058D14ED58"><enum>8.</enum><header>Conflicts related to amici curiae</header><subsection id="H4AE6293C816B44209C74E794E3CDCAB1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subsection (b), the Supreme Court of the United States and the Judicial Conference of the United States shall prescribe rules of procedure in accordance with sections 2072 through 2074 of title 28, United States Code, for prohibiting the filing of or striking an amicus brief that would result in the disqualification of a justice, judge, or magistrate judge.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6C424B484CB1493D9A5079C3D7856FB4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial transmittal</header><text>The Supreme Court of the United States shall transmit to Congress—</text><paragraph id="H549ED68497124658BDD9ADF74AEBF3BE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the proposed rules required under subsection (a) not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B987E60A22F4CDEAE0A0F7520A1D260"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any rules in addition to those transmitted under paragraph (1) pursuant to section 2074 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

