<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" public-private="public" dms-id="H8DDC09A6B9774AE792CD1A4FDAE54312"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9071 IH: Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of American LGBTQ+ History and Culture Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9071</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">House Administration</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of American LGBTQ+ History and Culture, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body><section id="idBCBCE08AC8C841E18349F34E16AEA636" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Commission To Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of American LGBTQ+ History and Culture Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="idF64E4E2CDA534AC5BCE9868AA16B37DD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Commission</header><subsection id="id3A84B37663754370806D815DCD6B6273"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the Commission to Study the Potential Creation of a National Museum of American LGBTQ+ History and Culture (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Commission</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="idD1D5878F45B04DC9A1B6872762F84E15"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Commission shall be composed of 8 members, of whom—</text><paragraph id="idF6A8F1FE693D45ACBE5463F0A5428651"><enum>(1)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the majority leader of the Senate;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idCB3EFA53724D4BA2A0FDFD0D31A8835B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idC90270667F7B4EC1B8DCA6B39F1359F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id70DFEFEA35624BE2B9CCAF25E1661E3F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>2 members shall be appointed by the minority leader of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4BAB4FEE3E2D424F8C38C7858762A623"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>Members of the Commission shall be appointed to the Commission from among individuals, or representatives of institutions or entities, who possess—</text><paragraph id="id081728E7991F470C903C9365B8EF7FC0"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph id="id8B84E8F3935E4D74BCBB913CF243BAED" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a demonstrated commitment to the research, study, or promotion of LGBTQ+ history, art, political or economic status, or culture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id7B8A73C2B1CB41C9A3B726C150AB2EE4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause id="idD703F1A4A1FA41478D7CDDC645722762" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>expertise in museum administration;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" id="id31E6912649B34394BAC870FA73C58BD0" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>expertise in fundraising for nonprofit or cultural institutions;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="idE6943918C15F4DA588B8D7A9DF46CD72"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>experience in the study and teaching of American LGBTQ+ history;</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id1FAE5030198A430B8ADCEEE53C188F63"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>experience in studying the issue of the representation of LGBTQ+ Americans in art, life, history, and culture at the Smithsonian Institution; or</text></clause><clause display-inline="no-display-inline" indent="up1" id="id6AD493C2CDBC4EC39847DA6D279AEF69"><enum>(v)</enum><text>extensive experience in public or elected service;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idDBAE373255B64154B8EEA611D18E1457"><enum>(2)</enum><text>experience in the administration of, or the planning for, the establishment of museums; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id56121E041FB9459A9EC253CB70519954"><enum>(3)</enum><text>experience in the planning, design, or construction of museum facilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id47526D9FD10844659973D8FCD87C4679"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Deadline for initial appointment</header><text>The initial members of the Commission shall be appointed not later than the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="id2B912FD8055346058B4B1524AAFA46EC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Vacancies</header><text>A vacancy in the Commission—</text><paragraph id="id4BC6E7E9C29F49A994289182CD37156B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not affect the powers of the Commission; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id773268702D8C4594966C869CD5FE002D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall be filled in the same manner as the original appointment was made.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idF01E1E5C96104F56BE7367ACE73BFABB"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Commission shall, by majority vote of all of the members, select 1 member of the Commission to serve as the Chairperson of the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="idE6164B19EBF9424E96D23666C6016745"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No employee of the Federal Government may serve as a member of the Commission.</text></subsection></section><section id="idC1A4060DF11F4873976F5FBC9BE011E0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Duties of the Commission</header><subsection id="id8496AC121C3C4E4E9F3C3E725297D1BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="idC6FF4695EB09497FB58BDC4AC5CBE67E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan of action</header><text>The Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report containing the recommendations of the Commission with respect to a plan of action regarding the feasibility of establishing and maintaining a National Museum of American LGBTQ+ History and Culture (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Museum</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id83996BBEC5A046E4A6A765E80B590208"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report on issues</header><text>The Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report that addresses the following issues:</text><subparagraph id="idE94776BC49644C83BA2CFA5AA2F3743C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The availability and cost of collections to be acquired and housed in the Museum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4A8D417746F34144AF17F5AC0157C987"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The impact of the Museum on existing American LGBTQ+ history-related museums.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id4038E6CCAF3C43B7BD7CDEBC2E9132DB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>In consultation with the Smithsonian Institution, develop criteria for evaluating possible locations for the Museum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idD0773F8B13CC413CAFC4B72EDFAFCE31"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The feasibility of the Museum becoming part of the Smithsonian Institution, taking into account the Museum’s potential impact on the Smithsonian’s existing facilities maintenance backlog, collections storage needs, and identified construction or renovation costs for new or existing museums.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA64C05C88679457A9CA3637D36BB4D5D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The governance and organizational structure from which the Museum should operate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idA5807C635D4C49B4A5F2E80BA72014FD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Best practices for engaging LGBTQ+ Americans in the development and design of the Museum.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id555A40AF6BA54FF9A323107569703F8D"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The cost of constructing, operating, and maintaining the Museum.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0FFCDEC47C7144909C14C954B7EE90E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text>The reports required under paragraphs (1) and (2) shall be submitted not later than the date that is 18 months after the date of the first meeting of the Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id045D441B7BF648A7968C996B8E0FF849"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Fundraising plan</header><paragraph id="idD5F098762A35473AA38A0C3565B91060"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall develop a fundraising plan that will address the ability to support the establishment, operation, and maintenance of the Museum through contributions from the public.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id07066E157F37406FB9E0260EF3CC18C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In developing the fundraising plan under paragraph (1), the Commission shall consider issues relating to funding the operations and maintenance of the Museum in perpetuity without reliance on appropriations of Federal funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idB8F9D4286247492D83CE945BD4DB0A34"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent review</header><text>The Commission shall obtain an independent review of the viability of the plan developed under paragraph (1) and such review shall include an analysis as to whether the plan is able to achieve the level of resources necessary to fund the construction of the Museum and the operations and maintenance of the Museum in perpetuity without reliance on appropriations of Federal funds.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id04DA6D1559034EBDB7396D6632794333"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>The Commission shall submit the plan developed under paragraph (1) and the review conducted under paragraph (3) to the Committees on House Administration, Natural Resources, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Rules and Administration, Energy and Natural Resources, and Appropriations of the Senate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id6B2791A8417E453086CEE9EC7C193F7F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Legislation To carry out plan of action</header><text>Based on the recommendations contained in the report submitted under paragraphs (1) and (2) of subsection (a), the Commission shall submit for consideration to the Committees on House Administration, Natural Resources, and Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Committees on Rules and Administration, Energy and Natural Resources, and Appropriations of the Senate recommendations for a legislative plan of action on the feasibility of establishing and constructing the Museum.</text></subsection><subsection id="idD5A929D9BEC743EFA7D162A64D05E55D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National conference</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date on which the initial members of the Commission are appointed under section 2, the Commission may, in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this section, convene a national conference relating to the Museum, to be comprised of individuals committed to the advancement of the life, art, history, and culture of LGBTQ+ Americans.</text></subsection></section><section id="id2DC58A77B88C4A9C98955615324CA708"><enum>4.</enum><header>Administrative provisions</header><subsection id="id777ED3D5EECE4394AAC33A6DBC98AC91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation</header><paragraph id="id054F471B77874A9FB984E3E29EB06E8D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A member of the Commission—</text><subparagraph id="idB6842D3D2B9D4F159B2F7D15CADEE94F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall not be considered to be a Federal employee for any purpose by reason of service on the Commission; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idB6AD101498F1430CACF6F2DF35AB6BBA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall serve without pay.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idA7CEE2F566AC48689B46E0BFDEF0E291"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Commission shall be allowed a per diem allowance for travel expenses, at rates consistent with those authorized under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4BF053182A8C4FC2938E8AE4A75B3A90"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Gifts, bequests, and devises</header><text>The Commission may solicit, accept, use, and dispose of gifts, bequests, or devises of money, services, or real or personal property for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="idA0488FB0BD40408CB58715F4AC9CEDD4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Commission shall not be subject to the Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id257F27EBF22B40CD9FA0FB96288CB070"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate on the date that is 30 days after the date on which the final versions of the reports required under section 3 are submitted.</text></subsection><subsection id="id96DA74CC3A2242E1BD8542A513F3FFDC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><paragraph id="id3C1B791F567343FD89D5FCFD88BC0707"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall be solely responsible for acceptance of contributions for, and payment of the expenses of, the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id0B3187DAC2514EFBA391784FB12E641E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No Federal funds may be obligated to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="idC087AB5AFC9E47D891A17CA121469088"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Director and staff of Commission</header><paragraph id="idCBAD63EBF5F4443DA9843DF975418325"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Director and staff</header><subparagraph id="id9C3E6548B34E46C88383651D942C3CF3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission may employ and compensate an executive director and any other additional personnel that are necessary to enable the Commission to perform the duties of the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id2E3BC4ADB7C74E4FB587BF2764CF043D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rates of pay</header><text>Rates of pay for persons employed under subparagraph (A) shall be consistent with the rates of pay allowed for employees of a temporary organization under section 3161 of title 5, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id5027DDA0390B4ACE8EBBFB8DDE91EC85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Not Federal employment</header><text>Any individual employed under this section shall not be considered a Federal employee for the purpose of any law governing Federal employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id78C193BD3DF94A74BD869550E54E7194"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><subparagraph id="id7F2CABA2283A4338B3396E1CF5EA5E65"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), on request of the Commission, the head of a Federal agency may provide technical assistance to the Commission.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id7756D9AFB90942D586B2AB8A00AA0EDF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No Federal employees may be detailed to the Commission.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="id4CA5FAB3B8874ACBB1F66842E740D2FE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the House Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

