<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HD64FC958ABDA410B9E082C0A855D20F1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6032 RH: Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam Sacred Lands Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 496</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6032</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–679]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20211118">November 18, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on November 18, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To take certain Federal lands located in Siskiyou County, California, and Humboldt County, California, into trust for the benefit of the Karuk Tribe, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HF90F283B168A46F0BCCAC9558677AAE1"><section section-type="section-one" id="H72B3691E87B64BD6AEF6B728438E5750"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam Sacred Lands Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H7B4B4EBCA8EA4EE5A3BAA39C11B20D7A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Land held in trust for the Karuk Tribe</header><subsection id="H85E99BFEA9DC4565860F83983F5E86AF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text>Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H96EFC82655CA477EB03B56E224E58F39"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land is located in the ancestral territory of the Karuk Tribe; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H041E6AB8F1BE47528F8F11143D2E6F13"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Karuk Tribe has historically used, and has an ongoing relationship with, the Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77AA93B73F72403E91F8ADC2270FF6DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB59D89C408414BA1B0AF06F1AEDB6A40"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land</header><text>The term <term>Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land</term> means the approximately 1,031 acres of Federal land, including improvements and appurtenances to the Federal land, located in Siskiyou County, California, and Humboldt County, California, and generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Area</quote> on the map of the Forest Service entitled <quote>Katimiîn Area Boundary Proposal</quote> and dated August 9, 2021. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0395F7166647BCA2E5B6A4AE717CB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCCC2909001FC4690BEF1CF3EF7E6FC62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administrative transfer</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administrative jurisdiction of the Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land is hereby transferred from the Secretary of Agriculture to the Secretary, subject to the condition that the Chief of the Forest Service shall continue to manage the component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System that flows through the Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2617CA0F6C1546B59C83888D89764A7C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Land held in trust</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land is hereby taken into trust by the Secretary for the benefit of the Karuk Tribe, subject to—</text><paragraph id="H041C7798A2BF49068790D2BD04D06EA9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">valid existing rights, contracts, and management agreements relating to easements and rights-of-way; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62E57E09A346402BB00012EDD90C2AC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>continued access by the Chief of the Forest Service for the purpose of managing the component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System that flows through the Katimiîn and Ameekyáaraam land.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H876DC79F26574B88A32BFCAEB5E6B5AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Agriculture shall provide to the Secretary a complete survey of the land taken into trust under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H9A9991ACF21E460194A9DB38BA87E5B1"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of land</header><paragraph id="H7D481BFA8D9A4949915EB0CFA152C4F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Land taken into trust under subsection (d) may be used for traditional and customary uses for the benefit of the Karuk Tribe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93A3CF5C03D844AAB7DD72C1AB903745"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Gaming</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Class II and class III gaming under the Indian Gaming Regulatory Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2701">25 U.S.C. 2701 et seq.</external-xref>) shall not be allowed on the land taken into trust under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4395660939C84975830FF8300A938001"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Wild and Scenic Rivers management</header><paragraph id="H273CBBAD1A9D471C80D1E1A06EB5489E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the status or administration of any component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System, including any component that flows through the land taken into trust under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H612C682233F04DC99A812914073744A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Memorandum of understanding</header><text>The Secretary of Agriculture shall enter into a memorandum of understanding with the Karuk Tribe, consistent with the obligations of the Secretary of Agriculture under subsection (c), to establish mutual goals for the protection and enhancement of the river values of any component of the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System that flows through the land taken into trust under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221230">December 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

