<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDF3C98521A6B4373BBB3D4F5BA1D7285" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9433 IH: Social Enterprise Ecosystem and Economic Development Commission Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9433</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221206">December 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the establishment of a Commission on the Advancement of Social Enterprise, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9893FEE875A446549BFBFECD315B866D" style="OLC"><section id="HB53F5415C7644B8D9DAF533D4224CA74" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Social Enterprise Ecosystem and Economic Development Commission Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or as the <quote><short-title>SEEED Commission Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H95238E594B6C45E8A67F39B5554F9F10"><enum>2.</enum><header>Commission on the Advancement of Social Enterprise</header><subsection id="HF3DC4655E0154DA4BE0FF789067A41F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a commission to be known as the Commission on the Advancement of Social Enterprise (referred to in this section as the <term>Commission</term>). </text></subsection><subsection id="H16D9908DDFED4937B51F179257C8E0F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Federal Advisory Committee Act</header><text>The Federal Advisory Committee Act (5 U.S.C. App.) does not apply to the Commission.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6F632988269F4C40950C0A001FDA5967"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Members</header><text>The members of the Commission shall be each of the following or their designees:</text><paragraph id="H9234A0DC03F741F68FC0EF49DB5A5FD7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Small Business Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75E79B2195204A2A896C6CBC0762B3FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Administrator of the Economic Development Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFD8EB5BCC74DD69A4A3685DD4BE4FB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H324E0DA13659497592A9FEB2409A343D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Commissioner of Internal Revenue.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70431A61E41A4B9787E7FC0926E1B36A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4D99540F0446EBB422294DC69396BE"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Director of the National Economic Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30ED5D0F5B4249819657B8B2F418D993"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Chair of the Council of Economic Advisors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87446D4A9EDD460FB872552BF82E9E10"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA708D10E11A4130B31ED6B9E09FE995"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBB1A59184494342A18BB8C2B1B2B96F"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Secretary of Housing and Urban Development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CDC91712CB6436C85665C1C97BA9B6D"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chair of the Securities and Exchange Commission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2DB6803D168C44B687A0E151D0C24F08"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Operation</header><paragraph id="HAC85DBC3A7404AE7AECAF92287463026"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chair</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Domestic Policy Council shall serve as the Chair of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H501A766AB8834E38AAB2AB547D005D61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Meetings</header><subparagraph id="HDF01B0EB32BC48DCAD10CB0BAB8D7823"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall meet at the call of the Chair.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4841F9846414B4E83F61349352DC710"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The initial meeting shall take place not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAACE8C4861A46C1855362A44A1D8627"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Commission shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9C3C3295FA14259951DD56C77F653F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rules</header><text>The Commission may establish, by majority vote, any rules for the conduct of Commission business, in accordance with this Act and other applicable law.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC085470E52C34D9B9306D47196046138"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Duties</header><paragraph id="H78FA045CA19748BB8D5BB42D3CF22E8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall examine and make recommendations with respect to ways the Federal Government can support and utilize the transformative power of social enterprises. </text></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE60B44273F3E4560ACF3250939C36425"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defining social enterprise</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the initial meeting of the Commission, the Commission shall establish criteria for identifying social enterprises, which may include nonprofit and for-profit organizations, for purposes of Federal programs. The Commission shall consider research and scholarship on social enterprise and the input of practitioners and policy experts within the social enterprise field.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B4DAA9F62C9475C8FD98DA11E194A38"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Study activities</header><subparagraph id="HFF05663A645F4C5BA1D0F38B27FD7139"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall identify opportunities for the Federal Government to more effectively engage social enterprises in creating jobs and strengthening local economies while achieving optimal outcomes in addressing policy challenges at the national, State, and local level. The Commission shall receive and consider reports and testimony from individuals, government departments, State and local elected officials, community-based organizations, nonprofit organizations, faith-based organizations, foundations, and other public and private organizations statewide and of national significance on the following:</text><clause id="HCF2AEA18FF884DC2B5D0D8208FF0BE3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>How social enterprise can accelerate progress on social and environmental issues.</text></clause><clause id="HFEC6D9F84AF342E5B6FFDD204D28D1B7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>How social enterprises work in a cross-sector manner.</text></clause><clause id="H8485F12DE67143699B8FEB7CD971A061"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>How social enterprise can advance social and economic development goals.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5477AEA79ED4AECB5E12E6943F97CCE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Areas of study and recommendation</header><text>The areas studied and potential recommendations offered by the Commission under this paragraph shall include the following:</text><clause id="H0A2709D2715E4C67B970A721ECF735F4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The role of social enterprises in the United States economy.</text></clause><clause id="HE421A81131074471AC23167962CABB97"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The role of social enterprises in addressing economic, social, and environmental policy challenges across all levels of government.</text></clause><clause id="H9286A25A3B3D4862B116E72C036254BD"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The role of social enterprises as community support and development entities.</text></clause><clause id="HA4EF54D4EC604960B2BEAA2B3E1EC6A3"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>A statistical and qualitative examination of social enterprise within the United States and the contribution of social enterprise to the social and economic development of the United States.</text></clause><clause id="H90A833884D7E483A9653D64E604A9731"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Means through which the Federal Government can assist in enhancing the capacity of social enterprises.</text></clause><clause id="HB4CDF25AAA944A27834523E3F846F9E8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Corporate legal structures that foster or impede the development of social enterprises or the ability of organizations that are not social enterprises to partner with social enterprises.</text></clause><clause id="HB64807A96E60483D8A4CF69F36866CC8"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>How to reform the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to reduce obstacles that social enterprises face when addressing social issues and creating economic value through innovative methods.</text></clause><clause id="H73B9E5BC50854490B25B72E2920EDB20"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How to encourage impact investing, including reforming Federal securities laws and fiduciary duty for financial relationships.</text></clause><clause id="H6C6C9453654E4294A1BF8D7460F12E46"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How to use financial tools, financial instruments, and financial institutions to promote the development and growth of social enterprise.</text></clause><clause id="HA9DE2EE65CDB485FAE523445CC264AA8"><enum>(x)</enum><text>How the Federal Government can make use of community development financial institutions programs to benefit social enterprises.</text></clause><clause id="HFB727FE6F4A14E45931CD3B149B87ED4"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>How various sectors (including philanthropic, for-profit, and nonprofit sectors) and levels of government interact with social enterprises.</text></clause><clause id="H69D3B0DB24784BB58DB2544B384D8077"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Review of the process through which social enterprises (for-profit and nonprofit organizations) obtain Federal loans, grants, and contracts and offer recommendations for improving these processes in light of the special needs and contributions of social enterprises.</text></clause><clause id="H8C155627876240E697DD794FAF5DECB7"><enum>(xiii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Review of the process, policies, and procedures through which social enterprises (for-profit and nonprofit organizations) access Federal contracting opportunities and offer recommendations for improving the access of social enterprises to such opportunities.</text></clause><clause id="H39F215917A1044A8BF731667AD9F380D"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>How the Federal Government can play a role in developing a purchasing directory of social enterprises within the United States that can be supported by citizens, businesses, and government.</text></clause><clause id="HB11C4B40486A4BBA8948D7972F782855"><enum>(xv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunities for the Federal Government to develop and expand research and the collection and analysis of longitudinal data on social enterprises.</text></clause><clause id="H4AE7A27F8D244E5882BF502B2BA49A60"><enum>(xvi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barriers to social enterprise growth.</text></clause><clause id="H06111C7D41CF4310A5A14CDED386A6F3"><enum>(xvii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Opportunities for the development of an entity or initiative to support intermediaries that will promote and invest in social enterprise.</text></clause><clause id="H23865CE71C2941038885C39D4B4ED95C"><enum>(xviii)</enum><text>Identification of the appropriate entity within the Federal Government—</text><subclause id="H5E2284A832264DBF86C9ED0DE33C14F2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to prepare and submit to Congress an annual report on the impact of social enterprises in the United States and the extent to which the Federal Government interacts with, supports, and invests in social enterprises; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8F13FB70A63B40049850DFABBF010622"><enum>(II)</enum><text>where appropriate, to monitor and update the areas of study listed in this subparagraph.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H63F76A2A8B9E4989BE4D8CFF7CA0F9C7"><enum>(xix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Barriers that prevent corporations or organizations that are not social enterprises from operating like social enterprises and what incentives or structures would encourage them to operate more like social enterprises.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB288E52E20824196A4A4F7CBA0F630E3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Powers of the Commission</header><paragraph id="H524B30F027534FFAA4443EB0430E811E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Commission may hold such hearings and collect such information as appropriate for carrying out this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H16BE4E133B3B453F87D1BEEC0C16637C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information</header><text>Except as otherwise prohibited by law, the Commission may secure directly from any agency information the Commission considers necessary to carry out this section. Upon the request of the Commission, the head of the agency shall furnish information requested under this paragraph to the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H674B7DA4720F482E8CCDB36F7E444E78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract authority</header><text>The Commission may enter into contracts for research to inform the deliberations of the Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36EF3A711E8C44D29B0652249CAF760C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Mails</header><text>The Commission may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other agencies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E5F62E5960F4579977AFC59820B0CAC"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Advisory council</header><text>The Commission may establish an advisory council of relevant nonprofit organizations and for-profit organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FD08D52CEC144CBA854995EF2A27401" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Commission personnel matters</header><paragraph id="H3C013B7E4D864E8184039E73B750437D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Detail of Federal employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the affirmative vote of <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the members of the Commission and the approval of the appropriate head of the agency, an employee of the Federal Government at GS–13 level or higher may be detailed to the Commission without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status, benefits, or privileges.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64AA468D50F6470E9B763A3F832F441A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Staff</header><subparagraph id="H8413B3A689CB4B3DA9611CA2F02863D9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><clause id="HA990222AB0384BEE938D7CFE65381FB4" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Appointment and compensation</header><text>The Chair of the Commission, in accordance with rules agreed upon by the Commission, may appoint and fix the compensation of a staff director and such other personnel as may be necessary to enable the Commission to carry out its functions, without regard to the provisions of title 5, United States Code, governing appointments in the competitive service, and without regard to the provisions of chapter 51 and subchapter III of chapter 53 of such title relating to classification and General Schedule pay rates, except that no rate of pay fixed under this subsection may exceed the equivalent of that payable for a position at Level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of title 5, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="H71613DCEBF614ABC8558F3AE4B16F3C0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Personnel as Federal employees</header><subclause id="H4544BB4C29324416A093B5E5A5B6AE5C" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any personnel of the Commission who are employees shall be employees under section 2105 of title 5, United States Code, for purposes of chapters 63, 81, 83, 84, 85, 87, 89, and 90 of that title.</text></subclause><subclause id="H049222F6ACF145F18BE9DC569C5BE0EB" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Members of the Commission</header><text>Subparagraph (I) shall not be construed to apply to members of the Commission.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD99B4A286B6B49DABE503C498D5C0E49" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Volunteer services</header><text>Notwithstanding section 1342 of title 31, United States Code, the Commission may accept and use voluntary and uncompensated services as the Commission determines necessary. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H471D2D04B9A940E597A45DFCA09C70BC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Contracts for research</header><paragraph id="H879190CF34374CE48F5BD03C14D22066"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Researchers and experts</header><text>On an affirmative vote of <fraction>2/3</fraction> of the members of the Commission, the Commission may select nongovernmental researchers and experts to assist the Commission in carrying out the duties of the Commission under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDB35D914363742E6954FAD983854E4CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other organizations</header><text>Nothing in this subsection limits the ability of the Commission to enter into contracts with any other entity or organization to carry out research necessary to carry out the duties of the Commission under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H85C0E90B7D1E4B3B9784025C7DD69097"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the Commission establishes criteria by which to identify social enterprise, the Commission shall submit to the President and Congress a report on the findings, conclusions, and recommendations of the Commission. The report shall identify the Federal programs recommended and shall include—</text><paragraph id="HD53639890E084BCEAE36B9E57BFAA3B6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reports on all matters described in subsection (e); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C6BCF4C44C6499085F131FE619D860A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>how existing Federal Government programs can be expanded to take advantage of the social and economic benefits of social enterprises.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1AB2B9D62FBC4630937760815C58CC9D"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The Commission shall terminate 90 days after the date on which the Commission submits the report of the Commission under subsection (i).</text></subsection><subsection id="HF604D1035D1749C9A93788DB788E4D2C"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H7E46B1CB096F45E59ED0F56AAF3AF8B7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Agency</header><text>The term agency has the meaning given that term in section 551 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0537DC26E24C89A8C0831671E4B3B7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Impact investing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>impact investing</term> means investing made with the intention to generate positive, measurable, social, and environmental impact alongside a financial return. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9CD45EF25615470D804282C64719F3DC" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Nonprofit organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>nonprofit organization</term> means an organization described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB406242A34B14480A1022BCF0002A59B" commented="no"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Commission such funds as are necessary to carry out its duties under this section. Such funds shall remain available until the date on which the Commission terminates pursuant to subjection (j).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

