<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H89EEE1F5EED6485B92D65B6F691EF10C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8298 IH: Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps Expansion Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8298</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to develop a plan to ensure reasonable access to the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5CCDC6FE90EA43A5B3015073A1FEF3F4" style="OLC"><section id="H26511C88B5D84DD18490F9146B227CAF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps Expansion Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H131EF7C523EA4D1D8797050699BCE607" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Plan to ensure reasonable access to the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps</header><subsection id="HA4BC88389F0D445285236C39B5D05434"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, shall develop a plan to increase the total number of units of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps to ensure that there is reasonable access to such units in each geographic region of the United States by not later than September 30, 2031.</text></subsection><subsection id="H512DF9966F5E4EE682CB376D36EA25FE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The plan required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HAC6FCDC959AE4FA4966C2A1900A6C67E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposal to increase the total number of units of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps to ensure reasonable access for students throughout the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8814F11D0F8243128F0E3A43EBC1FB17"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The estimated cost of implementing the proposed increase in the number of such units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F50C4B61A1F4D88AFB2FEB5C257F6CC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A prioritized list of the States and regions in which the Secretary proposes adding additional units.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E52A2174B6A44D0939D268B58C94470"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Actions the Secretary expects to carry out to ensure adequate representation and fair access to such units for students in all regions of the United States, including rural and remote areas and in underrepresented States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A06A147F67444BBB75C1A739922C2BD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>To the extent appropriate, modifications to the requirements for such units, including the requirements applicable to instructors, to accommodate units in rural areas and small schools.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1BDD31AC6F741CD859B7E761909DC19"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to increase school and community awareness of Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps programs in underrepresented areas.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD2201DA653A428E85DED8202033C808"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives a report that includes the plan developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6B9D56BD484E40799FB79459BA4B8933"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reasonable access defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>reasonable access</term>, when used with respect to units of the Junior Reserve Officers’ Training Corps, means a level of access determined by the Secretary of Defense to be reasonable taking into account the demand for student participation, the availability of instructors, and the physical distance between units.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

