<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC68CB3DD62424202BD439B63A606C580" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6579 IH: Teamwork for Employees and Managers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6579</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220203">February 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000372">Mr. Allen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000061">Mr. Garcia of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000478">Ms. Tenney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To enable an employer or employees to establish an employee involvement organization to represent the interests of employees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1050D83665DC4555A413B978D42993CF" style="OLC"><section id="HFAA391AFE9D44F22BAA36BEE3A55849E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teamwork for Employees and Managers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H575CB59021B7454ABAA321CEF9A11A54"><enum>2.</enum><header>Employer exception</header><subsection id="H8A303EAA6DC94201848FC1F4E9C8C8FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 8 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBF53C35E86BE484B98299D618F1D2EFC"><subsection id="H75F5FAFF0E6D44B4A10709071B16F6F1"><enum>(h)</enum><text>It shall not constitute or be evidence of an unfair labor practice under subsection (a) for an employer to establish, assist, maintain, or participate in an employee involvement organization, as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Teamwork for Employees and Managers Act of 2022</short-title>: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That this subsection shall not apply in a case in which a labor organization is the representative of the employees of the employer in accordance with section 9(a).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H51D140DF03B44A71B0C57B6D9592D61B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception from labor organization definition</header><text>Section 2(5) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, except that the term shall not include an employee involvement organization as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Teamwork for Employees and Managers Act of 2022</short-title></quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDCCCC0755AC94D968287EFC47DC887AA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HB8B5A84BCD63451AB65AE79375932A44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2673967556345DA9E9673DEBFF2F423"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employee involvement organization</header><text>The term <term>employee involvement organization</term> means an organization or entity established by the mutual consent of an employer and any number of employees of the employer—</text><subparagraph id="HA9061FB20443451BBF1BE471AC4393C1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which may be initiated by the employer, the employees, or both;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCACBFC08FEF45BCBBCFB10EBB4BC7E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which may be dissolved—</text><clause id="HCF884057BC6E4061A97A301ECAE01D1F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>except as described in clause (ii), at any time, and without regard to cause, by the employer, the employees, or both; or</text></clause><clause id="H108B70E4369C451D81977AD28C18E476"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an employee involvement organization for a large employer and employees of the large employer, only in accordance with section 4(b)(2);</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6A832F154564451CB5E0DF4506337020"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in which employees and supervisors participate to address matters of mutual interest, including issues of quality of work, productivity, efficiency, compensation, benefits (including related to education and training), recruitment and retention, grievances, child care, safety and health, and accommodation of the religious beliefs and practices of employees; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC3F1AAD06D40CD929EEC68310AB252"><enum>(D)</enum><text>that does not have, claim, or seek authority to—</text><clause id="HF2EEC1111AE144C0B9404E0A8F5750D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be the exclusive collective bargaining representative of the employees participating in such organization or entity; </text></clause><clause id="H0F6B2EA64103457189B969E29D5880BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>negotiate or enter into a collective bargaining agreement with the employer on behalf of such employees;</text></clause><clause id="H03E14DC8FBFF47108832807B1BE65F96"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>amend any collective bargaining agreement between the employer and any labor organization; or</text></clause><clause id="H970F3D9075D945DE8B490C83DC3A30B0"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>preclude such employees from designating or selecting a labor organization as the representative of such employees, as provided in section 9(a) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159(a)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3CEA405F4449E9923E78C7A8DFFDD9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Employer</header><text>The term <term>employer</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FC181C594B04B3194590B65B75E55C7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Large employer</header><text>The term <term>large employer</term> means an employer that—</text><subparagraph id="HCECFEEA811694F8E946EE9DE6127851F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>had more than $1,000,000,000 in annual gross revenues for the most recently completed fiscal year prior to the date of certification under section 4(b)(1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC49A63DEAD944891801DA7D9D6A856E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>employs more than 3,000 employees on such date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4C11E2EF564F56BD35944767B43CC1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Workforce committee</header><text>The term <term>workforce committee</term> means a committee of the board of directors of an employer that—</text><subparagraph id="H3C1516219E724BABAF84087A5AD466FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>oversees the policies of the employer on quality of work, productivity, efficiency, compensation, benefits (including related to education and training), recruitment and retention, grievances, child care, safety and health, and accommodation of the religious beliefs and practices of employees;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3628340F6BB044C2B21D5566A364AFDE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a substantially equivalent source of authority with respect to authorizing provisions in the article of incorporation or bylaws of the employer as the compensation committee of the board of directors or an equivalent committee of the board of directors; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H101AC211B73A4D6CBF07D760C1FC3867"><enum>(C)</enum><text>may be the compensation committee of the board of directors or an equivalent committee of the board of directors, if such committee meets the requirements of this paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H8FB0A57752034A4AB3FD9A90F26CE2B7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requirements for employee involvement organizations at large employers</header><subsection id="H80FC1AADDAB34637AFBFA7F1D6961D80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>This section shall apply to each employee involvement organization for a large employer and employees of the large employer.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC0CD684006614206ABC99824D4851953"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment of an employee involvement organization for large employers</header><paragraph id="H863F25C27187417F9214615C9CCCA090"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Certification</header><text>A large employer shall certify each employee involvement organization for the large employer on the date of formation of such employee involvement organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C85D835221D46D886F9FAAD9CD74BDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procedures</header><subparagraph id="H98EA9EEA3B274114B1C73262F560BA3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employee involvement organization established under paragraph (1) shall have reasonable procedures regarding—</text><clause id="H49CD6ACE32BA492F8BD4A51081FC23E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>how an employee may join or leave such employee involvement organization; and</text></clause><clause id="H367062D8E606457C92C099DA3AA7F447"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>dissolution of the employee involvement organization.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFD585007609A4A6C996ACFBD6CCB6D17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Dissolution for cause</header><clause id="H639B855B97F14AF688043B693193AEB2"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an employee involvement organization that has been certified under paragraph (1) for not less than 5 consecutive years, a large employer may only dissolve such employee involvement organization with cause. </text></clause><clause id="HC9C5CAE2EF6C439687A984A7D0D89DF8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Cause</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the term <term>cause</term> means a reasonable business purpose for dissolution, as determined by—</text><subclause id="HA054B544A7A84DD693910198976E0B86"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the independent business judgment of the board of directors of the business of the large employer; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H18D82C0830B44FF9893084AD8C36F4E3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the business of a large employer does not have a board of directors, the substantial equivalent of the board of directors.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1ACF33F83A4C46868EA2E943F029B5C3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cooling-off period</header><text>Unless otherwise specified in the certification under paragraph (1), an employee involvement organization may not be established at a large employer prior to 2 years after—</text><subparagraph id="H72E7C1829B274BC3B5E292F1FC711849"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a large employer for which a valid election was held under section 9(c)(1) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159(c)(1)</external-xref>) in which a majority of the employees voting in such election voted against representation, the date of such election; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A6B675827B340A0A5B8C1FDAAA94459"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of a large employer for which a valid election was held under section 9(e) of such Act and a majority of the employees voting in such election voted in favor of rescission of the authority of a labor organization to make an agreement described in section 8(a)(3) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158(a)(3)</external-xref>), the date of such election.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFFD450E231E744E18F8C2C7C4CABC4D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Employee representative of an employee involvement organization</header><paragraph id="H8B4F5F4DF0E4475C81A88407A59AF887"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Employees participating in an employee involvement organization established under subsection (b)(1) may, subject to the requirements in paragraph (2), elect through reasonable means an employee representative of the employee involvement organization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA609EEBFCF94466961984A7802DA27E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election process</header><subparagraph id="H033707C74BC34B14B6C97C4DCF1B943A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>An election of an employee representative of an employee involvement organization for the large employer—</text><clause id="HBE533308D73F4F03BF0D85EA58A9E56C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall be through a secret ballot of the employees participating in the employee involvement organization who are employed by the large employer on the date of such election and who are United States citizens or reside primarily in the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="H173A04337FC04866ADDBE846EAFEDB61"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may not be funded through funding sources external to the employee involvement organization, including any labor organization, nonprofit, or business other than the employer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4C13FF353D341A4804913CFFD08095F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Default rules regarding election process</header><text>Unless otherwise specified in the certification under subsection (b)(1) by the large employer of such employee involvement organization, an election of an employee representative of an employee involvement organization for the large employer—</text><clause id="H13D547D43EA243CE8B6B155BC2CCB0AD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may be funded through employer-provided funding; and</text></clause><clause id="HCD6390CEE36040B4842EEC8991AB21CD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall occur within the same time period and with the same regularity as the election of the board of directors of the large employer.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8653C7B31E5A4CB98542CE3F5612136B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligibility requirements</header><subparagraph id="H4A35364A4DA6408ABB6D84E6DB29CCD8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each individual elected to be a representative of an employee involvement organization for a large employer shall be an employee who—</text><clause id="H234059CB078743C19F11636088E86B64"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is eligible to vote under paragraph (2)(A)(i); and </text></clause><clause id="HC46C3E0929464B1AAFAA83A6B16AF8FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except in a case in which the large employer has operated for less than the 5 calendar years immediately preceding the date of the election, has been employed by the large employer for not less than the 5 calendar years immediately preceding the date of the election.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BE9C4564EBD4865909D74C48F39C495"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Ineligibility; term limits</header><text>An employee representative of an employee involvement organization elected under this subsection shall not—</text><clause id="HED6B42260B79434A802B98F3D08DA4EE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be employed by the employer at the time of such election as a supervisor; or</text></clause><clause id="H29C0BBA23BF14E5E9ABB3EC107573362"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>at any time during the 5 calendar years immediately preceding the date of such election, be employed by the employer in a position related to human resources.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H279909DC2A0341E78E44CE1AAFB41600"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Representation by employee representative on board of directors of large employer</header><subparagraph id="H0ACD5AE3B86749D2A7EC0408DF4496DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Board representation</header><text>Subject to the limitation under subparagraph (B) and, as relevant, the procedure under subparagraph (C), an employee representative of an employee involvement organization elected under this subsection shall—</text><clause id="HD265227180224FA0B1E89423A419A9D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be a nonvoting member of either or both of—</text><subclause id="HBE449C93B9504CBCBFC7B28C81438714"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the board of directors of the employer; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H6ABC2626AA844AD79D20A545EBFB8AEF"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a workforce committee of the board of directors of the employer;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC5DA2CB15A7A41389080D32E7024EDAF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be permitted to attend any regular meeting of such board or committee, as applicable; and</text></clause><clause id="H5DCC10276BD04EAD85FA0F0A11E2A97B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>receive equal access to information relevant to the purposes of the employee involvement organization as any other member of the board or committee, as applicable.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F37E74A3F344BC9BBF6CE551A70C768" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>Unless otherwise specified in the certification under subsection (b)(1) by the large employer of such employee involvement organization, an employer may exclude an employee representative from attending any meeting of any committee of the board of directors of the business of such employer (or the substantial equivalent of any such committee) called for purposes unrelated to the purposes of such employee involvement organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H618DEC0EC6CE445EBEDF701867B0C970" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Special procedure for an employer with more than 1 employee involvement organization</header><text>In a case in which 2 or more employee representatives in total are elected for a large employer under paragraph (1), the employer and each employee involvement organization that elects such an employee representative shall, by reasonable procedures which provide for the input of each such employee involvement organization, ensure that only 1 employee representative for the employer at any time exercises the powers described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC2F30237AB2A44DF8A7AE46499DCFDAF" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Safe harbor for violation of rules due to the fault of an employee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 8 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB4B25F3C16564A4E9287CBE5528B6B7E"><subsection commented="no" id="HB26F8C602D6B4278B62D740A05986707"><enum>(i)</enum><text>It shall not constitute or be evidence of an unfair labor practice under subsection (a) for an employer to establish, assist, maintain, or participate in an organization which purports to be an employee involvement organization, as defined in section 3 of the <short-title>Teamwork for Employees and Managers Act of 2022</short-title>, but which fails to comply with the requirements of such Act due to the fault of an employee: <proviso><italic>Provided</italic></proviso>, That this subsection shall not apply in a case in which a labor organization is the representative of the employees of the employer in accordance with section 9(a).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H97618CA906574C07A184845B93FAEC02"><enum>6.</enum><header>Limitations</header><subsection id="H7E672510C2AE41CA8833EC1B3CAF2B27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Labor organization rights</header><text>This Act shall not prevent or affect the rights provided to labor organizations under section 9 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H87F318F84B42437BA878188CC7F84888"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Employee rights</header><text>This Act shall not affect the rights and responsibilities of employees under the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>), except with respect to the amendments made to section 2(5) and section 8 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/152">29 U.S.C. 152(5)</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158</external-xref>) by sections 2 and 5 of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H057DAD776D964A0F9E0ED3946CE53731"><enum>7.</enum><header>Enforcement by the National Labor Relations Board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 6 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/156">29 U.S.C. 156</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H117203A6298F408F9898E72C28E56845"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Board</quote> and inserting <quote>(a) The Board</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF52B20C3062420787571BDEFADA4916"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA471DCF1D2474938A573BF98A678D53F" style="OLC" act-name=""><subsection id="H37A6B93FA4534EA68D5A6B49F04B6CE1"><enum>(b)</enum><text>The Board shall not have any authority for enforcement, or adjudication, under this Act or the <short-title>Teamwork for Employees and Managers Act of 2022</short-title> with respect to an employee involvement organization, as defined in section 3 of such Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

