<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H85F4EE52759B4C9B8E48D099C14160FF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6363 IH: Genetic Sequencing Accountability Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6363</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220110">January 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001275">Mr. Bucshon</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Comptroller General of the United States to conduct a study on funding to entities utilizing such funding for human genomic sequencing or genetic services.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDC97A78C58CC4CF0B6ABC4DCA0FF9988" style="OLC"><section id="HC7AA50DBCD0646DBBCEA90EDA1A733B2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Genetic Sequencing Accountability Act</short-title></quote> .</text></section><section id="H7995B1DBAB2C40FF8728861201C2C1D8"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO Study</header><subsection id="H45D57CA57A80486CA293CEDC9667FC95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Comptroller General of the United States (referred to in this section as the <quote>Comptroller General</quote>) shall conduct a study to assess the extent to which the Department of Health and Human Services (referred to in this section as the <quote>Department</quote>) utilizes or provides funding to entities that utilize such funds for human genomic sequencing services or genetic services (as such term is defined in section 201(6) of the Genetic Information Nondiscrimination Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ff">42 U.S.C. 2000ff(6)</external-xref>)) provided by entities organized under the laws of a country or countries of concern, in the estimation of the Director of National Intelligence or the head of another Federal department or agency, as appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H81CF585B31A54F81AE1560A86B7DD4C6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In carrying out the study under this section, the Comptroller General shall—</text><paragraph id="H4071D4EC2EC24958B0B5BA05804F01F3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consider—</text><subparagraph id="H4FAF218A5F1D47958EE7DA43DB4EE1C6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>what is known about the extent to which the country or countries of concern could obtain human genomic information of citizens and residents of the United States from such entities that sequence, analyze, collect, or store human genomic information and which the Director of National Intelligence or the head of another Federal department or agency reasonably anticipates may use such information in a manner inconsistent with the national security interests of the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FE7018F74A04A20B64018D5BC28872C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the Department or recipient of such funds from the Department sought to provide funding to, or to use, domestic entities with no such ties to the country or countries of concern for such purposes and any barriers to the use of domestic entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB90926C5D6564BD2A7B93A0C69967CCD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the Department has processes in place to ensure that data use agreements, data security measures, and other such measures taken by the Department or recipient of such funds from the Department are sufficient to protect the identifiable, sensitive information of the people of the United States and the national security interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7807400829E8426496FF13A94D3CD5E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make recommendations to address any vulnerabilities to the United States national security identified, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA407B1BEA65E47BBA9D33C09E68E002B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Estimation</header><text>In conducting the study under this section, the Comptroller General may, as appropriate and necessary to complete such study, investigate specific instances of such utilization of genetic sequencing services or genetic services, as described in subsection (a), to produce estimates of the potential prevalence of such utilization among entities in receipt of Departmental funds. </text></subsection><subsection id="HF1035DAB4226493588B58BD27479A51C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit a report on the study under this section to the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives. The report shall be submitted in unclassified form, to the extent practicable, but may include a classified annex.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

