<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H0A0C6B6A2C3E441FA0AFDF8B1754D8C8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7636 RH: Bulb Replacement Improving Government with High-Efficiency Technology Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 441</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7636</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–610]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221208">December 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 40, United States Code, to require the Administrator of General Services to procure the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting products and to issue guidance on the efficiency, effectiveness, and economy of those products, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="HB98EE1EA55AD470EA37F0EE6648DFDF4" style="OLC"><section id="H4CC3F7EBFFA54FD589F4456B3F21A350" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bulb Replacement Improving Government with High-Efficiency Technology Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>BRIGHT Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDD544CA8229B4FED803597272A3073B7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Guidance</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of General Services shall—</text><paragraph id="H8C0AEBBFB2C34AB39567D9524AA8DD7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue guidance to Federal agencies for the procurement and use of the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems (as determined in accordance with section 3313 of title 40, United States Code) to increase the efficiency, effectiveness, and economy of the Federal Government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA2A50639E144BEB927859EA2B2FD04D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>publish on the internet or otherwise make available to State, local, and Tribal entities information on ways to improve efficiency, effectiveness, and economy by procuring and using the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems (as determined in accordance with section 3313 of title 40, United States Code).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H041492BABD5A4DABBE4142CE18A55CD1" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Procurement of life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems</header><subsection id="H38775784D4E64CE284AAD5D49AE1CC08"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3313 of title 40, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H61844C68CB8F4D3C851B3995E2C054A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsection (h);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE7D8CBDDFE148D7868268B881DBB65C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (d) through (g) as subsections (f) through (i), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB6BF6CBDC994C0B996EDF332E377314"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking the section designation and heading and all that follows through the end of subsection (c) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4F8D49EA02924A908EEF0BD6551DFFCF" style="USC"><section id="H13DE65C693D044149CA8CC863F2DF279"><enum>3313.</enum><header>Procurement of life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems</header><subsection id="HF6296E94B375477487EEABDB60741D53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H8D73F1671AD6408CBE4ADFAF4EBF957C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of General Services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E0913EB20BB4E3B808089D85D082DB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Lighting system</header><text>The term <term>lighting system</term> means the elements required to maintain a desired light level, including lamps, light fixtures, fixture distribution, sensors and control technologies, interior design elements, and daylighting sources.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A7DB3D4B6D543BBB7650682EEA5218D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Procurement</header><paragraph id="HAD7F1070C50A47849E9558EC7B88709B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Administrator shall—</text><subparagraph id="H94C5E6666BC5403EA2D3B15F7ABA2148"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procure the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H710A00AEFCC542A6AE738D02E5FB58B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensure that procurements after the date of enactment of the <short-title>BRIGHT Act</short-title> of lighting systems or the individual components of lighting systems maximize life-cycle cost effectiveness and energy efficiency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85DBC9A16FC3457B9BB1A189F34DDF97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public building constructed, altered, acquired, or leased by the Administrator shall be equipped, to the maximum extent practicable as determined by the Administrator, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems for each application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2CA4761ECB124789AB678340ED0AA886"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maintenance of public buildings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each individual component of a lighting system, including a lamp or fixture, that is replaced by the Administrator in the normal course of maintenance of public buildings shall be replaced, to the maximum extent practicable, with the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system possible for the application.</text></subsection><subsection id="H62027C0A63024EA1A5405CCBF91521AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Considerations</header><paragraph id="H9D86DB8082B54DC8B407C7D4C06C8F9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Contracting options</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out this section, the Administrator shall consider appropriate contracting options for the procurement of the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF6D3F75DD5849978C3E0BE38F545109"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Procurement and use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a determination under this section concerning the practicability of procuring and installing the most life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting system, the Administrator shall consider—</text><subparagraph id="H37DAA803B7C24420AC9561F15B611405"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the compatibility of the lighting system with existing equipment, including consideration of a cost effective retrofit;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D61810B5EC5433EBB1BFC96F71FA7BF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">whether procurement and use of the lighting system could result in interference with productivity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1579448FCB7A45ADB880E4AE2C52C739"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the aesthetics relating to the use of the lighting system; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33966495908B4F25B54B48D30D1785D2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such other factors as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1768C10B30FA4EC795289D75BDF8BEAC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Life-Cycle cost effective</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall use the procedures and methods established under section 544(a) of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8254">42 U.S.C. 8254(a)</external-xref>) in determining whether a lighting system is life-cycle cost effective.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H50183CEE2DE2495FA9CAFACD2D3571D6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (f) (as so redesignated)—</text><subparagraph id="HFCC3C0BEB05C40C7A84EA5A3706B2060"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>lighting fixture or bulb</quote> and inserting <quote>lighting system</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD9B24F69A56471C85F734175BB73FE1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>the fixture or bulb is</quote> and inserting <quote>the lighting system or the individual components of the lighting system are</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85814CEAB85E4AF2B453CC87DEF9411E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>fixture or bulb</quote> and inserting <quote>lighting system</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3B75925330447F496D4FBC27A014666"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (g) (as so redesignated), by inserting <quote>procurement and</quote> before <quote>use in public buildings</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50763ED13EA74A8A82EBB5CBDFC5BFDA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>in subsection (h) (as so redesignated), by inserting <quote>procurement and</quote> before <quote>use of energy efficient</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4CE862B45F745FB9001749A9FCFF75F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 3313 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H659542257FB74D17890B4242DD2470AD" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="section">3313. Procurement of life-cycle cost effective and energy efficient lighting systems.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221208">December 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

