<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFD464383F9834E0BA28A2264DE6E7237" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8884 IH: Medicare Opioid Use Disorder Outreach Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8884</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide outreach and reporting on opioid use disorder treatment services furnished by opioid treatment programs under the Medicare program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94C66A3B8AF8415581F1395305E99CDB" style="OLC"><section id="HB405C8867093489BB0CCC2D008FC7C23" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Medicare Opioid Use Disorder Outreach Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB852347A70D44F879DED4174F405686D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Outreach and reporting on opioid use disorder treatment services furnished by opioid treatment programs</header><subsection id="H3B2F3E8E5D1A43FBBDC160087253F88E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Outreach</header><paragraph id="H4FC424BF34E2411A8E990CF37585106A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Provider outreach</header><text>The Secretary of Health and Human Services (in this section referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall conduct outreach to physicians and appropriate non-physician practitioners participating under the Medicare program under title XVIII of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to opioid use disorder treatment services furnished by an opioid treatment program (as defined in section 1861(jjj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(jjj)</external-xref>)). Such outreach shall include a comprehensive, one-time education initiative to inform such physicians and practitioners of the inclusion of such services as a covered benefit under the Medicare program, including describing the requirements for billing and the requirements for beneficiary eligibility for such services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7CCAED28C4E4D109ABB4E6F56BDFB40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Beneficiary outreach</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall conduct outreach to Medicare beneficiaries with respect to opioid use disorder treatment services furnished by an opioid treatment program (as defined in section 1861(jjj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(jjj)</external-xref>)), including a comprehensive, one-time education initiative informing such beneficiaries about the eligibility requirements to receive such services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B939D2391EA44F39338210A48DC0F59"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reports to congress</header><paragraph id="HAAE7D33F07B24A50A7D583BC7CABB083"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Outreach</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the completion of the education initiatives described in subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the outreach conducted under such subsection. Such report shall include a description of the methods used for such outreach.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90B8B0208FA84C5C88E5BFB7CA89490D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Utilization rates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the completion of the education initiatives described in subsection (a), and two years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Ways and Means and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate a report on the number of Medicare beneficiaries who, during the preceding year, were furnished opioid use disorder treatment services by an opioid treatment program (as defined in section 1861(jjj) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x(jjj)</external-xref>)) for which payment was made under title XVIII of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395">42 U.S.C. 1395 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

