<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1BAF753DBD4D4E6587CDD94DCECC5F4C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9399 IH: Protect Our Waters and Expand Renewables on Our Reservoirs Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9399</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221201">December 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require assessments of opportunities to install and maintain floating photovoltaic solar panels at Corps of Engineers and Bureau of Reclamation projects, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6BC38DC0BAC4CE4832B5615B5380BD1" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H274BAB01BEA34C43B56F4571820DF1F0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protect Our Waters and Expand Renewables on Our Reservoirs Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>POWER Our Reservoirs Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H48F0FF81850C4FEE9BA7283C81B8CCB2" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Floating solar energy at Corps of Engineers projects</header> <subsection id="H04CD399CD4B042A7BB6DAF24DADF5267"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header> <paragraph id="H2C974391EA8848808527B4CF830F2B6B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief of Engineers shall, at Federal expense, conduct an assessment, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, of opportunities to install and maintain floating photovoltaic solar panels at Corps of Engineers projects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H01D93E7E1516490BA2C314E6BEDD0413"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Chief of Engineers shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA21DA6A9764C453590F08627DC4F410A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the economic, environmental, and technical viability of installing and maintaining, or contracting with third parties to install and maintain, floating photovoltaic solar panels at Corps of Engineers projects;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5F08EDC4FFA94BA0B7594CEC21082539"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify Corps of Engineers projects with a high potential for the installation and maintenance of floating photovoltaic solar panels, and whether such installation and maintenance would require additional authorization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H77C9365686C043BEABCF5E7D058F936A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>account for potential effects on Corps of Engineers projects, and the authorized purposes of such projects, of installing and maintaining floating photovoltaic solar panels at such projects, including potential effects related to evaporation suppression, energy yield, dam safety, recreation, water quality, and fish and wildlife;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAECAE3E61B6C4B20A065D850FB43333F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>account for potential damage to floating photovoltaic solar panels from weather, water level fluctuations, and recreational and other uses of the Corps of Engineers projects; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20293E34D5AD482296D0A121A5DF830C"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for the availability of electric grid infrastructure close to Corps of Engineers projects, including underutilized transmission infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HFC3D3BF016DD4AA8B4E785BC4E917732"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chief of Engineers shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available (including on a publicly available website), a report containing the results of the assessment conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA2DA93BC41204636894BFE3C080DA368"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Sustainability reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Chief of Engineers shall include renewable energy from floating photovoltaic solar panels as part of any Sustainability Report and Implementation Plan of the Corps of Engineers.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H1AC2FF28F31F46A196DE51C798B297ED"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pilot program</header> 
<paragraph id="H2298476E53D54103890AA6F5916FC9F7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, if supported by the results of the assessment conducted under subsection (a), the Chief of Engineers shall establish a pilot program for the deployment of floating photovoltaic solar panels at Corps of Engineers projects identified under paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection with respect to which any applicable non-Federal interest for the project—</text> <subparagraph id="HB4ED5C735D684000BC30D8587DFC4CB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agrees to invest in and deploy floating photovoltaic solar panels; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED0CAF82F44A421CB1BA3AA486E3E349"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the authority to enter into agreements, including through public-private partnerships, for the purpose of carrying out such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H488F8EA9A0444B8E98594C5D9B081A0E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text>In carrying out a project under this subsection, the Chief of Engineers may cover up to 100 percent of the cost of such project.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9A5886449DEA43548994E192E97A60E2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Chief of Engineers $12,000,000, to remain available until expended, to carry out this section.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAF311348D35A4FAAA7BAC62EA174FFFC"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No effect on project purposes</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the authorized purposes of a Corps of Engineers project.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HF5A863B3B3C8490A8EE9C6AD7AE2C694"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HFF4D04495D6645B982DC9C4EE785E13F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chief of Engineers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Chief of Engineers</term> means the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBE9685008BFE4261A1A41E46E692B857"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Corps of Engineers project</header><text>The term <term>Corps of Engineers project</term> means any water resources development project constructed by the Chief of Engineers or for which the Chief of Engineers has financial or operational responsibility.</text> </paragraph> </subsection></section> <section id="H755DD26AAFB64D8F99FDD66C20CFF91A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Floating solar energy at Bureau of Reclamation projects</header> <subsection id="HE0044886A1DE43BBB46B0B13B2BE845C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assessment</header> <paragraph id="HEDBE298860A84AE5A1F06B9F8EFA7461"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commissioner shall, at Federal expense, conduct an assessment, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, of opportunities to install and maintain floating photovoltaic solar panels at Reclamation projects.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8808D1A6B02C44128B7D81649AEF2C4D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out paragraph (1), the Commissioner shall—</text> <subparagraph id="HA79FF1EC067B46AAB3048731F720C4A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the economic, environmental, and technical feasibility of installing and maintaining, or contracting with third parties to install and maintain, photovoltaic solar panels at Reclamation projects;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H94925DCA75FC40938B7FAAB2286BF49C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify Reclamation projects with a high potential for the installation and maintenance of floating photovoltaic solar panels, and whether such installation and maintenance would require additional authorization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9A5E3D67A7C94FC8994D931000C29B60"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for potential effects on Reclamation projects, and the authorized purposes of such projects, of installing and maintaining floating photovoltaic solar panels at such projects, including potential effects related to evaporation suppression, energy yield, dam safety, recreation, water quality, and fish and wildlife;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF39282EEED6B4EDBA6F5291ECBFA8AE7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>account for potential damage to floating photovoltaic solar panels from weather, water level fluctuations, and recreational and other uses of the Reclamation projects; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H961F534087FD43F399F81F8B197DEFC4"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">account for the availability of electric grid infrastructure close to Reclamation projects, including underutilized transmission infrastructure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7CD33B253EB64C10A76B0380C125F026"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commissioner shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available (including on a publicly available website), a report containing the results of the assessment conducted under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB96820A9ED4742318CDF959FB806C199" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Pilot program</header> <paragraph id="H20D707D26BB142CEA822B5FC45A29C8F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, if supported by the results of the assessment conducted under subsection (a), the Commissioner shall establish a pilot program for the deployment of floating photovoltaic solar panels at Reclamation projects identified under paragraph (2)(B) of such subsection with respect to which any applicable non-Federal entity for the project—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HEAB6931856CF4EDE83AF0BF95DC8260E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>agrees to invest in and deploy floating photovoltaic solar panels; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H087EA1F7DCD34A7B922719113077437F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has the authority to enter into agreements, including through public-private partnerships, for the purpose of carrying out such activities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC4019B9BF915421F82C8F34099F246B1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out a project under this subsection, the Commissioner may cover up to 100 percent of the cost of such project.</text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HBC94D458E708402B85DB7DF9B75274AA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Commissioner $12,000,000, to remain available until expended, to carry out this section.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6C846E54C35F415299511C76A26D3C63" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(e)</enum><header>No effect on project purposes</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the authorized purposes of a Reclamation project.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H06A7ACA78EB8439BA61CBF9073317214"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9A2690B7570541A9A2E8309037BD5F8C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commissioner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commissioner</term> means the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Commissioner of Reclamation. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD7EA4A467A5D492B94583C170484D7E8" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reclamation project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Reclamation project</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H636C69C2C8EB4CBBBB54D30398A5F52A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any reclamation or irrigation project, including incidental features of the project—</text> <clause id="HA66D35C25AA3438297539CEFD454187C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is authorized by the Federal reclamation laws;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4BA6AFEAFE1848CA9E4540D29BE253AD" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is constructed by the United States pursuant to the Federal reclamation laws; or</text></clause> <clause id="H35428D96F00C477E87887494E13C39A6" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in connection with which there is a repayment or water service contract executed by the United States pursuant to the Federal reclamation laws; or</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H71815E4A7C114B8280F10E46E5C84313" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any project constructed by the Secretary of the Interior for the reclamation of land.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

