<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H480F6FE182F44FA69D85F4155EDAF6B1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9119 IH: Targeting and Offsetting Existing Illegal Contaminants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220930">September 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for a program within the Forest Service to remediate the environmental damages caused by trespass cannabis cultivation, amend the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act to include criminal penalties for illegal pesticide application on Government property, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H873150BD8A544577B8AA56E4FEE92BC0" style="OLC"><section id="HFFDF82ECDF544E02919CEF83849617C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Targeting and Offsetting Existing Illegal Contaminants Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HCC115A95F3694DA6B19B21053D38DB38"><enum>2.</enum><header>Trespass cannabis cultivation site restoration program established</header><subsection id="H452ADFD2A13742A0AE192D64D565B690"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Trespass cannabis cultivation site restoration program</header><paragraph id="HE7AE29E748EE417E9E25E19C854C3C9D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of the Agriculture shall carry out a program of environmental restoration on land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service. The program shall be known as the <quote>Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Program</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B0C23B4197F4534B61C71E60A310CD7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application of section 120 of CERCLA</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities of the program described in subsection (b) shall be carried out subject to, and in a manner consistent with, section 120 (relating to Federal facilities) of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EF7D4B0622248E5B74DA510AC88EBC8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation with EPA</header><text>The program shall be carried out in consultation with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H32956C76F5B845569C7FB8561F6F061F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Administrative Office within the Department of Agriculture</header><text>The Secretary shall identify an office within the Forest Service which shall have responsibility for carrying out the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF4360BBF3F8445EC8A93092B7BAF8C6B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program goals</header><text>The goals of the program shall include the identification, investigation, research, and development of solutions to, and remediation of, contamination resulting from the cultivation of cannabis on land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="H815386AA5F5A4629A378955358F9D754"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Responsibility for response actions</header><paragraph id="HF4558AE357EE48A29C0BC9B51E3BA7E5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Basic responsibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, with respect to releases or threats of releases of hazardous substances, pollutants, contaminants, improper pesticides or other wastes resulting from the cultivation of cannabis, carry out (in accordance with the provisions of this Act and CERCLA) all response actions at each facility or site which is under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service or any site which was under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service at the time of such cultivation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H08A89B85F9ED4DF7B89F7F278ED63782"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other responsible parties</header><text>Paragraph (1) shall not apply to a removal or remedial action if the Administrator has provided for response action by a potentially responsible person in accordance with section 122 (relating to settlements) of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9622">42 U.S.C. 9622</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2154854F8C75430687BC0AB63E39A637"><enum>(3)</enum><header>State fees and charges</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall pay fees and charges imposed by State authorities for permit services for the disposal of hazardous substances, pollutants, contaminants, improper pesticides or other wastes on lands described in paragraph (1) to the same extent that nongovernmental entities are required to pay fees and charges imposed by State authorities for permit services. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to a payment that is the responsibility of a lessee, contractor, or other private person.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9AAFDE584352489481BD13BE89C56A6E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Services of other entities</header><paragraph id="H953BD3CFA45A434CA80C70DA48E9D80F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary may enter into agreements on a reimbursable or other basis with any other Federal agency, any State or local government agency, any Indian tribe, any owner of covenant property, or any nonprofit conservation organization to obtain the services of the agency, Indian tribe, owner, or organization to assist the Secretary in carrying out any of the Secretary’s responsibilities under this section. Services which may be obtained under this subsection include the identification, investigation, and cleanup of any hazardous substances, pollutants, contaminants, improper pesticides or other wastes resulting from the cultivation of cannabis on land described subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88671B208735494D9543BD148A5E7DE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cross-fiscal year agreements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement with an agency under paragraph (1) may be for a period that begins in one fiscal year and ends in another fiscal year so long as the period of the agreement does not exceed two years.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C4F601F40244C6DAEF190AC00510A0A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Limitation on reimbursable agreements</header><text>An agreement with an agency under paragraph (1) may not provide for reimbursement of the agency for regulatory enforcement activities. An agreement under such paragraph with respect to a site also may not change the cleanup standards selected for the site pursuant to law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56B515BEFF5D46099576EFF92D298752"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="HD8595E3A958C4206BAF7A99BBF9AC351"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The term <term>Indian tribe</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA43E7D8CB91448B9A526ACF54963E8C4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The term <term>nonprofit conservation organization</term> means any non-governmental nonprofit organization whose primary purpose is conservation of open space or natural resources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF00FF4A1B03A4479B6DE2E9E42C27B06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The term <term>owner of covenant property</term> means an owner of property subject to a covenant provided by the United States in accordance with the requirements of paragraphs (3) and (4) of section 120(h) of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620(h)</external-xref>), so long as the covenant property is the site at which the services procured under paragraph (1) are to be performed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEBE55638DBF1496C9F018DC31F4850C3"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects the applicability of section 120 of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9620">42 U.S.C. 9620</external-xref>) to the Department of Agriculture or the obligations and responsibilities of the Department of Agriculture under subsection (h) of such section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7516A0ADD6534E7FBB713F37A72D35EF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Response action contractors</header><text>The provisions of section 119 of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9619">42 U.S.C. 9619</external-xref>) apply to response action contractors (as defined in that section) who carry out response actions under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H04ADC7C322934906B22765E5728C5631"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Use of appropriated funds at former department of agriculture sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations available to the Department of Agriculture may be used on land described in subsection (c)(1) for remediation of damages described in such subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H49C0B93E64D34BAD9E3265F5966D7CDA"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Surety-Contractor relationship</header><text>Any surety which provides a bid, performance, or payment bond in connection with any direct Federal procurement for a response action contract under the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Program and begins activities to meet its obligations under such bond, shall, in connection with such activities or obligations, be entitled to any indemnification and the same standard of liability to which its principal was entitled under the contract or under any applicable law or regulation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H56358E5CD20145F98CFE0F318E22DA53"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Surety bonds</header><paragraph id="HF7705357839740DF93EABD440A98E2CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicability of sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40</header><text>If under sections 3131 and 3133 of title 40, United States Code, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Program and are not waived pursuant to section 3134 of title 40, the surety bonds shall be issued in accordance with sections 3131 and 3133.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBE94E83E7A2D4C10B50F970757E51492"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation of accrual of rights of action under bonds</header><text>If, under applicable Federal law, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Program, no right of action shall accrue on the performance bond issued on such contract to or for the use of any person other than an obligee named in the bond.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D14CDBB483A4492B148AA661E996723"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Liability of sureties under bonds</header><text>If, under applicable Federal law, surety bonds are required for any direct Federal procurement of any response action contract under the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Program, unless otherwise provided for by the Secretary in the bond, in the event of a default, the surety’s liability on a performance bond shall be only for the cost of completion of the contract work in accordance with the plans and specifications of the contract less the balance of funds remaining to be paid under the contract, up to the penal sum of the bond. The surety shall in no event be liable on bonds to indemnify or compensate the obligee for loss or liability arising from personal injury or property damage whether or not caused by a breach of the bonded contract.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F812149072942DB9DA3CE05F4FEAE37"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Nonpreemption</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as—</text><subparagraph id="H88EEC24083114AF09AFBD60B2145278D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>preempting, limiting, superseding, affecting, applying to, or modifying any State laws, regulations, requirements, rules, practices, or procedures; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE79E99D226364B2BA8CE9563AD6FB474"><enum>(B)</enum><text>affecting, applying to, modifying, limiting, superseding, or preempting any rights, authorities, liabilities, demands, actions, causes of action, losses, judgment, claims, statutes of limitation, or obligations under Federal or State law, which do not arise on or under the bond.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81A3B6F1245A4B32B1DF450FB40B51A1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Applicability</header><paragraph id="H00F6D17FAADF49AD8FD07EA4C69A0A6E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bonds executed before December 5, 1991</header><text>Subsections (g) and (h) shall not apply to bonds executed before December 5, 1991.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CEF83B4C1EF48BCB962152373273B9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Other bonds</header><text>Subsections (g) and (h) shall not apply to bonds to which section 119(g) of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9619">42 U.S.C. 9619(g)</external-xref>) applies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A7F0941C5384FD2A863A35281A182FA" commented="no"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Establishment of accounts</header><paragraph id="H6D5DC5EC844B49D1AC8E836645735364" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="HBBA8A5C537214ABE849B5E96918A0C79" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Account, Agriculture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby established in the Treasury of the United States an account to be known as the <quote>Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Account, Agriculture</quote> which shall consist of, with respect to land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service— </text><clause id="H62E7D70D1A3E4E0BA40A932579CAF599" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>amounts appropriated with respect to such land under subsection (m); </text></clause><clause id="H96080C99AF874EE580C68B8AE22173CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>amounts recovered from trespassers for response actions on such land under CERCLA; and </text></clause><clause id="HA654D38328484F57A739109663A6118D" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other amounts recovered from a contractor, insurer, surety, or other person to reimburse the Department of Agriculture for environmental response activities on such land.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74709C8B84C94AD7A7CC18A5A39511C6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Account, Formerly Used Agriculture Sites</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An account to be known as the <quote>Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Account, Formerly Used Agriculture Sites</quote> which shall consist of, with respect to land formerly under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture—</text><clause id="H771B8E7AF5D0412F9F791CDECF58647C" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>amounts appropriated with respect to such land under subsection (m); </text></clause><clause id="H36D19281E48E40EEA5201BEEECA42531"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>amounts recovered from trespassers for response actions on such land under CERCLA; and </text></clause><clause id="H574B3E1EFC594EC8A728972D11794387" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other amounts recovered from a contractor, insurer, surety, or other person to reimburse the Department of Agriculture for environmental response activities on such land.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9098C95B5AD436FA8DBD1C9C86DA0F1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Obligation of authorized amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds authorized for deposit in an account under paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HA2BDD07BD6504225A9D470951289CEE4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may be obligated or expended from the account only to carry out the environmental restoration functions of the Secretary of Agriculture; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6B446DE26A94D6E9D2D4AD68561B0B6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall remain available until expended.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB938A6388C8543F9A5E60DF02B1AE9E6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payments of fines and penalties</header><text>None of the funds appropriated to the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Account, Agriculture, or to the Trespass Cannabis Cultivation Site Restoration Account, Formerly Used Agriculture Sites, may be used for the payment of a fine or penalty (including any supplemental environmental project carried out as part of such penalty) imposed against the Department of Agriculture unless the act or omission for which the fine or penalty is imposed arises out of an activity funded by the environmental restoration account concerned and the payment of the fine or penalty has been specifically authorized by law.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6FD00029421402B8A83D843EEA3B76F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Sole source of funds for operation and monitoring of environmental remedies</header><text>The sole source of funds for all phases of an environmental remedy on land under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service or land formerly under the jurisdiction of the Forest Service shall be the applicable environmental restoration accounts established under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59360679B0364AE5B89E8FF71B6EEC70" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Environmental remedy defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>environmental remedy</term> has the meaning given the term <term>remedy</term> in section 101 of CERCLA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B01792596294F7ABAB1955628129AAE"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Budget reports</header><text>In proposing the budget for any fiscal year pursuant to section 1105 of title 31, United States Code, the President shall set forth separately the amounts requested for environmental restoration programs of the Forest Service.</text></subsection><subsection id="H227DA88FC8C848D497452BD738DB6F84"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H31F6230237674CABAE4EABAD120853C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>CERCLA</header><text>The term <term>CERCLA</term> means the Comprehensive Environmental Response, Compensation, and Liability Act of 1980 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/9601">42 U.S.C. 9601 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C49C0A74F4E4D0AAC7DEB6C9CA497BF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Improper pesticide</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>improper pesticide</term> means a pesticide that is—</text><subparagraph id="H1211B9CCC6BF4603B77B288BCE2E2CC8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at the time of application, cancelled by the Secretary of Agriculture under the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCA88C644C9B497AAA174667A03E62C4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improperly applied. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FD964941F1C46C2846476AD9128D6DC"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $250,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="H17D95708BC5C4370808C1635B4962F65" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Criminal penalties for illegal pesticide application</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 14(b)(2) of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136l">7 U.S.C. 136l(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE8C8BA36F1174349B515D371ABF8BAD4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H5B24D476F86549F89D465C9C6C20EF74"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Private applicator</header><subparagraph id="H76DEDDE248D049C5B47BC96D09A49900"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any private applicator or other person not included in paragraph (1) who knowingly violates any provision of this Act shall be guilty of a misdemeanor and shall on conviction be fined not more than $1,000, or imprisoned for not more than 30 days, or both.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAED5C27DC54548B5BCC3F2962EB7470B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>During the commission of a Federal offense</header><text>Any private applicator or other person not included in paragraph (1) who knowingly violates any provision of this Act during the commission of a Federal offense under section 1361 of title 18, United States Code, shall, in addition to the punishment provided under such section, on conviction be imprisoned for not more than 10 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H18447C1EB0124DC9AF309C3E0FA06E73"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protection of National forests; rules and regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Act of June 4, 1897 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/551">16 U.S.C. 551</external-xref>; 30 Stat. 35) is amended by inserting <quote>Any violation of the provisions of this section, the sections referenced in the preceding sentence, or such rules and regulations, which involves the illegal cultivation of cannabis on public lands using pesticides which are not in compliance with the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/136">7 U.S.C. 136 et seq.</external-xref>) shall be punished by a fine of not more than $250,000 or imprisoned for not more than 20 years, or both.</quote> before <quote>Any person charged</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

