<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H010F9729493E461CA3E0DC35C270BA94" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9661 IH: VA Caregiver Continuity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9661</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221221">December 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to conduct certain outreach to legacy participants in the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0D39D17E196744858E6C793E6DA01E86" style="OLC"><section id="H8CE865FADFF941D98D9D0DCE41FFF3BF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>VA Caregiver Continuity Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HCCCB05AE3D99481394301C67B5DF71FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Outreach to legacy participants in Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers</header><subsection id="H83D87ADBD84C42AFA31DEDB67D3A9377"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the Secretary of Veterans Affairs should not discharge any legacy participant within the priority group specified in section 1705(a)(1) of title 38, United States Code, from the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers, or reduce the support received by any such legacy participant under such program, on the sole basis of the final rule of the Department of Veterans Affairs relating to <quote>Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers Improvements and Amendments Under the VA MISSION Act of 2018</quote> (85 Fed. Reg. 46226, as in effect on October 1, 2020), or any related successor rule.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8D7A9EC6FB2049B7ACB8B280732BA159" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Outreach requirements</header><text>The Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall—</text><paragraph id="H27DB04ABB9834C4186B11D9DC221FB32" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify each legacy participant that has been sent a notification from the Department of Veterans Affairs that the individual may be subject to a discharge from, reassessment of eligibility for, or reduction of benefits under, the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers on the sole basis of the final rule specified in subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90E464C8700746ED854201EEC62E20C7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to each such legacy participant information regarding continued eligibility for such program under the interim final rule of the Department of Veterans Affairs relating to <quote>Extension of Program of Comprehensive Assistance for Family Caregivers; Eligibility for Legacy Participants and Legacy Applicants</quote> (issued on September 14, 2022), or any related successor rule; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD4A330519FE47AFB3A54EA65EBBABC9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">take such other steps as may be necessary to ensure that legacy participants receive the most up-to-date information regarding eligibility for such program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC857167873BC495D9E3E12A063DDB275"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization of priority group one veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the outreach requirements under subsection (c), the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall prioritize the provision of information to legacy participants within the priority group specified in section 1705(a)(1) of title 38, United States Code.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4EA31BC1099149F3A3BA4E4F1019B1A6"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H10E8A4A6687C4B00BD33B8160C9A09EC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>family caregiver</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 1720G(d) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1E9CBBE34B4CF2BF3F5E6FBA1F072A"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>legacy participant</quote> means, with respect to the program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers, a veteran, or family caregiver thereof, who was a participant in such program as of September 30, 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64B8191F85B8427589916A68E675815C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>program of comprehensive assistance for family caregivers</quote> means the program of the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1720G(a) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

