<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA2CB1E214DAA4B31808D150B12E5723F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9498 IH: Teachers are Leaders Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9498</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221212">December 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000483">Mr. Trone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000459">Mr. Fleischmann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to provide for a teacher leader development program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE988C8A13D42436BA9FE03915491B49F" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HDAB500DB60A74DE5A743C302FAB3AE30" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Teachers are Leaders Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HDFF40F2B0188413DAE70F28508B2B910"><enum>2.</enum><header>Teacher leader development program</header> <subsection id="H51B282B461774438B98E350AE19FBC51"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (f) of section 202 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1022a">20 U.S.C. 1022a</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="HC49A437C45BE44EF9A7F161834AB2906" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="H48DB3C2CF1B148C49F1D0723B6F217C0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Teacher leader development program</header> 
<paragraph id="HDE3B364509F345A3A7EF4753FA6E346A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A teacher leader development program carried out with a grant awarded under this section shall provide for the professional development of teachers, as described in paragraph (2), who maintain their roles as classroom teachers and who also carry out formalized leadership responsibilities to increase the academic achievement of students and promote data-driven instructional practices that address the demonstrated needs at the elementary schools and secondary schools in which the teachers are employed, such as—</text> <subparagraph id="HC1588C77FE094CB5A52E5E73FCDE255B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>development of curriculum and curricular resources;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB72758296FB4654B0248017194BF0E1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitating the work of committees and teams;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H875909E5FCF4434391CC549F58A28EDB"><enum>(C)</enum><text>family and community engagement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D14CF119FDB42F887DAE7A47C134C17"><enum>(D)</enum><text>school discipline and culture;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF3458A919D81442FB1E4EBBD4AAC6207"><enum>(E)</enum><text>peer observations and coaching; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA99142701BEF4B5B9AEC005BDEC3F509"><enum>(F)</enum><text>dual enrollment instruction; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB7018F9B24324C34A5AB3D17908D858E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>cultural competencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1A0834B416FB404CB348434E779EE255"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Professional development</header><text>The professional development of teachers in a teacher leader development program carried out with a grant awarded under this section shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="H5FF6F0C918B642949A7FDC7592496766"><enum>(A)</enum><text>one year of professional development, training, and support that may—</text> 
<clause id="H893AC37F0F834FB6A4924D1A004235ED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>include—</text> <subclause id="HF8241B35E0154499B3FC1E7E19042849"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the engagement of teachers in rigorous coursework and fieldwork relevant to their role as a teacher leader, including available teacher leader standards; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD47ACCD2AF864C2EBC294CE5DE30C583"><enum>(II)</enum><text>regular observations and professional support from—</text> <item id="H2076D8309C5A42CB890B36930E28C96F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a principal, vice principal, or a designated instructional leader of the school;</text></item> 
<item id="H451730D6C70E4E669330454B87756DD8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a representative from the institution of higher education that is a partner in the eligible partnership;</text></item> <item id="H0B266164FDFF4BED8A0C034E1E8741B9"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a representative from another entity that is a partner in the eligible partnership; and</text></item> 
<item id="H6F1CFC46350F4FD58D69E12E6F7BC8F0"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>another member of the teacher leader cohort, if applicable, or a peer teacher; and</text></item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H98E2F151AEB540B3BC7B55C677201DA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>result in the awarding of a credential in teacher leadership; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H05333661914C4158B849F35D9D5C3838"><enum>(B)</enum><text>one or 2 additional years of support from a principal, vice principal, or a designated instructional leader of the school, a representative from the institution of higher education that is a partner in the eligible partnership, and a representative from another entity that is a partner in the eligible partnership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H778DD7FC9DBD4E71BAEAB33C8CCCFE02"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Teacher leader development program plan</header><text>In carrying out a teacher leader development program under this section, an eligible partnership shall develop a plan that shall describe—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0E8AD1AC30E84C54879F23A7DE3CA32D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>how the work hours of teacher leaders will be allocated between their classroom responsibilities and responsibilities as a teacher leader, which shall include a description of whether the teacher leader will be relieved from teaching duties during their participation in the teacher leader development program;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAE359D4DDC44410A88E6C4069F3A76D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>how the partnership will support teacher leaders after the first year of professional development in the program; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H918836727EA84DFD874D7052AE4A4D16"><enum>(C)</enum><text>how teacher leader activities could be sustained by the eligible partnership after the program concludes, which may include a description of opportunities for the teacher leaders to assist in the educator preparation program at the institution of higher education in the partnership.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H30C20A2E0812471FA4E8077EBAA8DCE1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Selection of teacher leaders; use of funds</header><text>In carrying out a teacher leader development program under this section, an eligible partnership—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H994E32A98AA54184A81E8E4A70A3CCE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall select a teacher for participation in the program—</text> <clause id="H57352F8322854CF58CDCF24452043C08"><enum>(i)</enum><text>who—</text> 
<subclause id="H94F57FD9D0A042049F499353DE492DE3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is fully certified to teach in the State of the high-need local educational agency that is a partner in the eligible partnership;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H66793FD781544C7184BBD76331D57A06"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is employed by such high-need local educational agency;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HAB209809152A400CAC413E7362B65496"><enum>(III)</enum><text>has not less than 3 years of teaching experience; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="HCFD3DC060F79415BBC3F3BA7466F0276"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>submits an application for participation to the eligible partnership; and</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H855D88DC87C54465843F2454CD25C923"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>based on selection criteria that includes—</text> <subclause id="HA1E39BBD4A734098AB232977E31C251D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>demonstration of strong content knowledge or a record of accomplishment in the field or subject area the teacher will support as a teacher leader; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HD32E4DB0210D48A4924125FFC39A80D1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>demonstration of attributes linked to effective teaching that is determined through interviews, observations, artifacts, student achievement, or performance assessments, such as those leading to an advanced credential;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD59B5525791C4505A12B3C1751FBFFA1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may develop admissions goals and priorities for the teacher leader development program that—</text> 
<clause id="HA64B9000FB0D4C189030DC3986B3924D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are aligned with the demonstrated needs of the school or high-need local educational agency in which the teacher is employed;</text></clause> <clause id="H888333012A834944ACF27615CA05B89A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>considers cultural competencies that would make the applicant effective in the applicant’s teacher leader role; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H0451F5597E044A81A691CB87B02BDB64"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>considers whether the teacher has substantial teaching experience in the school in which the teacher is employed or in a school that is similar to the school in which the teacher is employed;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HECACC2EF810E45569CCDF5F736FA10BE"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall use the grant funds to pay for costs of training and supporting teacher leaders for not less than 2 years and not more than 3 years;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BB67EB3E8504EB285BD77287DF1E686"><enum>(D)</enum><text>may use the grant funds to pay for a portion of a stipend for teacher leaders if such grant funds are matched by additional non-Federal public or private funds as follows:</text> <clause id="H83D53644015845A1ACB63D9C5EEA8089"><enum>(i)</enum><text>during each of the first and second years of the grant period, grant funds may pay not more than 50 percent of such stipend; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5E0B077F868D4CE399CDD9DDBEB47693"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>during the third year of the grant period, grant funds may pay not more than 33 percent of such stipend; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0182E059404E46A29B1225A0CFFF67E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may require teacher leaders to pay back the cost of attaining the credential described in paragraph (2)(A)(ii) if they do not complete their term of service in the teacher leader development program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H24679C6102C74DC19F88F867D72A02D7" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Teacher leader defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>teacher leader</term> means a highly effective educator who carries out formalized leadership responsibilities based on the demonstrated needs of the elementary school or secondary school in which the teacher is employed, while maintaining a role as a classroom instructor who— </text> <subparagraph id="HB6E608E1962B49D7A12ACE44D388B4E9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is trained in and practices teacher leadership; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF3F20F0F0FB747F59D01C3776151E188" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>fosters a collaborative culture to— </text> <clause id="HF86BDDADDCD240E28071B08FADC6239A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support educator development, effectiveness, and student learning; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HA33A46EE05D94F3EA48E663461370587" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>support access and use research to improve practice and student learning; </text></clause> <clause id="HAABD4383FEC244DF9A9FCF4B35940A17" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promote professional learning for continuous improvement; </text></clause> 
<clause id="H68BAB06D8FD948829BEF70C9B70B784C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>facilitate improvements in instruction and student learning; promote the appropriate use of assessments and data for school and district improvement;</text></clause> <clause id="H371C1BC416E349D6AF2F75FBD2DA0BCA" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>improve outreach and collaboration with families and community; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HD9607F5F985C4DF6B4AF409D3CBFF604" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>advance the profession by shaping and implementing policy; </text></clause> <clause id="HAE3932987D1842C3978BDA8E412FC51A" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>advocate for increased access to great teaching and learning for all students; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H56026D15225F4EE8AC30BA8B8BF963ED"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>demonstrate cultural competencies and provide instruction and support as such.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> <subsection id="HB9686EADE66448F08DEF95809D531EBB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 202(c)(2) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1022a">20 U.S.C. 1022a</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>leadership development program</quote> and inserting <quote>teacher leader development program</quote>. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA05090229DBD4ED6B5A2C4AAB4DEF354"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 209 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1022h">20 U.S.C. 1022h</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>for fiscal year 2009 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the two succeeding fiscal years</quote> and inserting <quote>for fiscal year 2023 and such sums as may be necessary for each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years</quote>. </text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

