<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H78FB30A392CC4742BE298356F2A87EAE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8782 IH: Protecting Our Homeland from Chinese Espionage Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8782</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220909">September 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001086">Mrs. Harshbarger</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require disclosure by Department of Homeland Security contractors of contracts with Chinese entities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H111ACEE0FA7D4E8191F8090AF6FF9A4E" style="OLC"><section id="HF8D39F2867B445FF8D362CA0FA4BEA88" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Our Homeland from Chinese Espionage Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H347640E23BB54DBF93D7F80B50773F72" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement for Department of Homeland Security contractors to disclose contracts and ties with People’s Republic of China entities</header><subsection id="HA14CE2D5D45F453F9DE074450E9E6C29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirement</header><paragraph id="HC77F01AF2723422C853651E39E8C0660"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial disclosure</header><subparagraph id="HF359639C5C0E4C2C8D6AB5A61CFE5079"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 12 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall amend the Homeland Security Acquisition Regulation to require that a contractor with the Department of Homeland Security shall, as a condition of being awarded a contract for the procurement of goods or services, disclose to the Department covered information related to any contracts or other relevant commercial ties with a covered entity such contractor, including the immediate owner of such contractor, the highest-level owner of such contractor, and all first tier subcontractors of such contractor with respect to the contract to be awarded—</text><clause id="H817587FC8BB44EB9928B0560318EC283"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has that are in effect at the time of contract award;</text></clause><clause id="H8897340F108D46339F7E5050C81B04F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has had within the three years immediately preceding such time of contract award; and</text></clause><clause id="H42726DBA0CB744289F4854D59B1147B2" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>enters into at any time during the period of such contract award.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9CB02A9E6AC749288507D7925FE228CE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives of disclosures described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H278EA88D7ACF4F03854382AC52A72A44"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Updated disclosures</header><subparagraph id="HEC75978549DF4728AE5F70172ADDF787"><enum>(A)</enum><header>New or renewal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contractor awarded a contract with the Department of Homeland Security in accordance with the amended Homeland Security Acquisition Regulation pursuant to paragraph (1) shall update disclosures made to the Department in accordance with such paragraph not later than 30 days after such contractor, including the immediate owner of such contractor, the highest-level owner of such contractor, and all first tier subcontractors of such contractor with respect to such contract, enters into or renews a contract with a covered entity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6C09392CEBA455385D52B29FC7FF018"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Annual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A contractor awarded a contract with the Department of Homeland Security in accordance with the amended Homeland Security Acquisition Regulation pursuant to paragraph (1) shall annually update disclosures made to the Department in accordance with such paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC64EECF2988B41D197850BE278CE2C9F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall notify the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives of updated disclosures under subparagraphs (A) and (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H63100012DCAF4974A4C0D761C6F35218"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>Disclosure and notification requirements under this section shall not apply in the case of any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HED949FC40CD54C5DB2F16E1C821437F5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the procurement that is the subject of the contract at issue is in an amount at or below the simplified acquisition threshold, as that term in defined under section 134 of title 41, United States Code, and adjusted for inflation under section 1908 of such title. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0439AFD79FE74C2FB923250A9A546C12"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any supply or service contract the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Chief Acquisition Officer, Chief Procurement Officer, and Chief Security Officer of the Department of Homeland Security, determines to be low risk.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H469372FE6A614A37B3932EAE8171432F"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the procurement that is the subject of the contract at issue is already under investigation by the Department of Homeland Security or another United States Government agency and with respect to which such a disclosure or notification would compromise the integrity of such investigation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAAF9ADD638314808A30DEA679D56938F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Database of Federal contractor contracts with covered entities</header><paragraph id="H7C93DABFDFF44B93A54A36F998B24EFF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish a public database containing the information concerning contracts with covered entities disclosed pursuant to subsection (a). Upon the termination or completion of such a contract, the contractor with respect to such a contract, including the immediate owner of such contractor, the highest-level owner of such contractor, and all first-tier subcontractors of such contractor, shall be eligible for removal from such public database.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FE6D142501B45FF9928E881D24EB209"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraph (1) shall not apply in the case of contracts with respect to which compliance with such paragraph would compromise national security or if information otherwise subject to disclosure is classified pursuant to Executive Order 13526.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H792FF47C14A0424B98E86FA7D97F2ABE" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To withhold or terminate contracts</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall terminate an existing contract if the Secretary determines based on a disclosure made by the contractor, the immediate owner of such contractor, the highest-level owner of such contractor, or a first-tier subcontractor of such contractor, that continuation of such contract violates Federal law or is not in the public’s interest.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB77EF8D2FB7D421386999977F6063393"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Suspension and debarment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Based on information disclosed pursuant to this section, the Secretary of Homeland Security may refer a contractor, the immediate owner of such contractor, the highest-level owner of such contractor, or a first-tier subcontractor of such contractor, as appropriate, to the Suspension and Debarment official of the Department of Homeland Security for suspension or debarment, to initiate a suspension or debarment proceeding, as such official determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6E1EC6E0C798409EBB55DE353BDAC99A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1EFFD417FF904B4289FEC490715751BA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered entity</header><text>The term <quote>covered entity</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H53C1CD5FB6DB4DBA8949C8528FED44F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Government of the People’s Republic of China;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBED86A95A56C4110AFDC8435BBD98738"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Chinese Communist Party (CCP);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5437B3ABED4F4E60B4412C16073B0F4C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Chinese military;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H346404FECA834C3BBB10ED226AD53D9F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>an entity owned, directed, controlled, financed, or influenced directly or indirectly, through separate contracts or otherwise, by the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the CCP, or the Chinese military, in which the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the CCP, or the Chinese military has majority ownership or control or has minority ownership greater than ten percent of such entity, including any entity for which the Government of the People’s Republic of China, the CCP, or the Chinese military has the ability, through ownership of a majority or a dominant minority of the total outstanding voting interest in an entity, board representation, proxy voting, a special share, contractual arrangements, formal or informal arrangements to act in concert, or other means, to determine, direct, or decide for an entity an important matter;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFC25448058D4EA9BC7E1270E823563C"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a parent, subsidiary, or affiliate of an entity described in subparagraph (D); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25209A3B826846A5913786EEA351C68E" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an China-based entity with a majority ownership or control or with minority ownership greater than ten percent by a covered entity, substantively involved in People’s Republic of China economic or industrial policies or military-civil fusion, including by accepting funding, performing services, or receiving subsidies, or with responsibilities for overseeing economic development projects, including Made in China 2025 and the Belt and Road Initiative.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F851A12FD8947B3A67F3AF9B50E503F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered information</header><text>The term <quote>covered information</quote> means information relating to—</text><subparagraph id="H849D73F000474546869B9060042DA4FE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the covered entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE3F46BDFA7485EB29A572E86D37C14"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the covered entity has the ability to act in concert or to determine, direct, or decide an important matter for a contractor, including the immediate owner of such contractor, the highest-level owner of such contractor, and all first tier subcontractors of such contractor under the awarded contract, through ownership of a majority or a dominant minority of the total outstanding voting interest, board representation, proxy voting, special interest share, contractual arrangements, or other formal or informal arrangements;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE86ADF3295D34B12A38DB62BEE88B59E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the date such contract was entered into; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A45C9AFC18F451985FBDD34FF437366"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the duration, including any extensions, of such contract.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9E380743DC140F1A2B6AA2CB7D26DB3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Immediate owner</header><text>The term <quote>immediate owner</quote> means an entity, other than a contractor, that has direct control of the contractor, including through one or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H93F75A3223474083A9AF7C1D723CBCED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ownership or interlocking management.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6539DAD71A8B4A57B832E0C51BBE9101"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identity of interests among family members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ABC6233023147ECB5DC21F69B9CE947"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Shared facilities and equipment.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3992B68FF4324E58A74191AC2CA9D4C1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Common use of employees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF4779E37674982ABE00A670F879F68"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Highest-level owner</header><text>The term <quote>highest-level owner</quote> means an entity that owns or controls an immediate owner of a contractor, or that owns or controls one or more entities that control an immediate owner of a contractor, and that is not owned or controlled by any other entity.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

