<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1780103A998C4999A245D51E2DAD7F6E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8787 IH: ZZZ’s to A’s Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8787</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220909">September 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Education to conduct a study to determine the relationship between school start times and adolescent health, well-being, and performance.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEC2D5D7C70FD4839ADD2C3B4DDCDC1BA" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H0E9FEE5248114CFF8836BCE32DEABF0B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>ZZZ’s to A’s Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H935913B887AD4DED981929E137700219"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="HDE762F6CFEB34D8A9E9AD0124676135F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Secretary of Education has not formally issued policy guidance on school start times.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9053442B4C9F41278D278C897A0AE933"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The American Academy of Sleep Medicine recommends 8 to 10 hours of sleep per day for teenagers aged 13 to 18 years, but early school start times are contributing to lack of sleep among adolescents.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCB4E3C34393B4A7D91AD78D36267150C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Despite the shift in biological rhythms during puberty, which causes adolescents to sleep later at night and wake later in the morning, 82 percent of public high schools and 79 percent of public middle schools in the United States started before 8:30 a.m. in the 2017–2018 school year.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H45C80E70DAB34711BDD714109A8C33BF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The State of California became the first State to enact a law to move back school start times beginning in the 2022–2023 school year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1815DE9F0E5341D6A587ADE24873DC52"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Numerous local educational agencies across 46 States have also recently changed or are considering changing school start times in an effort to improve adolescent health, well-being, and performance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDCBA742E6C1E4A8B8B5CB1D354104891"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The American Academy of Pediatrics has strongly supported efforts to optimize sleep in students by delaying school start times since 2014.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD5BEF7A6DEC644DDB91705F054AD6E77"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Later school start times are associated with—</text> <subparagraph id="H335BC09CA52845078C39F758E95842ED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improvements in academic performance, including attendance rates, grade point averages, and test scores;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4C8A2DC234DD48F4B8BBC11DEB99C8F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improvements in mental and physical health, including reduced risk of depression and obesity; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8502FCBC4B7E467799B7EDAB2C09A5F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>improvements in public safety, including reduced risk of automobile accidents.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB83924B56EC841109BCE403442074185"><enum>(8)</enum><text>A universal delay in school start times would be a cost-effective policy measure.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7B26E02C4BC4C3689D134A5382B3434"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The mission of the Department of Education is to promote student achievement and preparation for global competitiveness by fostering educational excellence and ensuring equal access.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H64B87078A82146EF96F17C15F43B6B10"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study and report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Education shall—</text> <paragraph id="H4C7238B0F9F54D4787895BA39313193B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study, directly or through the award of a grant or contract, to examine the relationship between school start times and adolescent health, well-being, and performance that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H36FA8B408C08478490758EFA559A2541"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provides a comprehensive review of the scientific evidence relating to school start times and adolescent health, well-being, and performance;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3509EA832E9741388CCBE2BA1E58E05C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">compares adolescent health, well-being, and performance among local educational agencies with different school start times; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H47A8D6F0B87341FDB5EC3AEAA9CBDE56"><enum>(C)</enum><text>evaluates factors that contribute to or affect school start times; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDE0EF047BE1040E3B28AAE39025CA2AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submit to Congress a report that describes—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HFCB1D1AD6B78461BB277FC2F7E094D7C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the findings of the study; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4861D3DBDED4A12A5D54FAACED56F57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any recommendations of the Secretary based on such findings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE8AB2474E1B341139123FD2F0716DF88"><enum>4.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H3020D70C27DF4EC9ACBDF85B87524B94"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Local educational agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>local educational agency</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8F6672FBC331491CBACFB2EF0E73E685"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Performance</header><text>The term <term>performance</term> means a measurement of how well an individual achieves a desired task, and may include academic performance and cognitive performance.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body></bill>

