<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDA886523E0AB4A2C83E0E1CA1571BDAB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6372 IH: Tribal Medical Supplies Stockpile Access Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6372</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220111">January 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001053">Mr. Cole</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To ensure that facilities of the Indian Health Service, facilities operated by an Indian tribe, tribal organization, or inter-tribal consortium, and facilities operated by an urban Indian organization receive items from the strategic national stockpile and qualified pandemic or epidemic products directly from the Department of Health and Human Services.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H000DE8DA81D642E590A9EAF1FDCE890A" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8D0B795B5B4D482F8F0C5CE991545910" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Medical Supplies Stockpile Access Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H95097DCFFA89456FBB85CE6FACF080EF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Provision of items to Indian programs and facilities</header> <subsection id="H05B76B5E857744CB9319693F571086BD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Strategic national stockpile</header><text>Section 319F–2(a)(3)(G) of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 247d–6b(a)(3)(G)) is amended by inserting <quote>, and, in the case that the Secretary deploys the stockpile under this subparagraph, ensure that appropriate drugs, vaccines and other biological products, medical devices, and other supplies are deployed by the Secretary directly to health programs or facilities operated by the Indian Health Service, an Indian tribe, a tribal organization (as those terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)), or an inter-tribal consortium (as defined in section 501 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5381">25 U.S.C. 5381</external-xref>)) or through an urban Indian organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act), while avoiding duplicative distributions to such programs or facilities</quote> before the semicolon.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H8EAADA34CDF04D6BBD57D086542D18A5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution of qualified pandemic or epidemic products to IHS facilities</header><text>Title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/241">42 U.S.C. 241 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 319F–4 the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9CD86F433ED4C34AD10ABD3F58F4AF9"> <section id="H312BCACF938C4981BDCFDAAAC2AEA711"><enum>319F–5.</enum><header>Distribution of qualified pandemic or epidemic products to Indian programs and facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In the case that the Secretary distributes qualified pandemic or epidemic products (as defined in section 319F–3(i)(7)) to States or other entities, the Secretary shall ensure that, as appropriate, such products are distributed directly to health programs or facilities operated by the Indian Health Service, an Indian tribe, a tribal organization (as those terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>)), or an inter-tribal consortium (as defined in section 501 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5381">25 U.S.C. 5381</external-xref>)) or through an urban Indian organization (as defined in section 4 of the Indian Health Care Improvement Act), while avoiding duplicative distributions to such programs or facilities.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

