<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB842585837144D419E098B3DCF7B1497" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8077 IH: Closing the Digital Divide for Students Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8077</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220615">June 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. C&#225;rdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000590">Mrs. Lee of Nevada</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To include reasonable costs for high-speed internet service in the utility allowances for families residing in public housing, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H58FEDE0FDF0B4A6786F516F72E21C9A2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H786FEC115E124C8A93EF9E048B439137" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Closing the Digital Divide for Students Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H18C40F92E3B24047A0018554CBAD145C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inclusion of high-speed internet service in public housing utility allowances for certain families</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 3 of the United States Housing Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1437a">42 U.S.C. 1437a(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H46E79736C8E848CBA3A54ED66091578C" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<paragraph id="H3202BF6E33C044849657B682B8578D5B"><enum>(14)</enum><header>Utility allowance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A utility allowance under this Act for public housing shall include costs for high-speed internet service, including the cost of renting or purchasing equipment necessary to access such service and a one-time installation fee, subject to the following limitations:</text> <subparagraph id="H5FC5EA5DEDEB4DEE82123CCFE2827BC3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Cost</header><text>The cost included in a utility allowance for a public housing dwelling unit pursuant to this paragraph for monthly internet service shall not—</text> 
<clause id="H2D0B17567F994D7BB20C6D123CCB1336"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exceed the lowest cost available in the area of such housing for such monthly high-speed internet service; and</text></clause> <clause id="H9200470A48024CDD8014AB2E6429BFFE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>include any costs for cable or satellite television service or telephone service.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7CE70DAD9EA74B4BA2CB7AA86C2BFF5E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Family choice</header><text>Subparagraph (A) may not be construed to prohibit a household in public housing from subscribing to—</text> <clause id="H6C38E7EDA07E49CD916C0BAD9B66AAED"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a high-speed internet service the cost of which exceeds the cost described in subparagraph (A)(i); or</text></clause> 
<clause id="HB39BEEF029AB404F8EAE8130BB113972"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any joint package for internet service together with cable or satellite television service or telephone service, or both.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E978A35DCD34B92845B265C7550835F"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Qualified families</header><text>Costs for high-speed internet service may be included in a utility allowance only for a household that incurs such costs and includes children who qualify for free and reduced price lunch pursuant to section 9 of the Richard B. Russell National School Lunch Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1758">42 U.S.C. 1758</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF2BE720B2A7540DBAADB61FE54E92AF2"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Protection of minors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs for high-speed internet service may be included in a utility allowance for a household only if the internet service provider, upon initial provision of such service for a household, provides the household with a specific technology capable of blocking or filtering internet access to visual depictions described in section 254(h)(5)(B)(i) of the Communications Act of 1937 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254(h)(5)(B)(i)</external-xref>) that provides a level of protection against access by minors to such depictions through the internet that is at least as great as the level of protection provided by a technology protection measure (as such term is defined in paragraph (7) of such section 254(h)) that meets the requirements for certification under such paragraph, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

