<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1350A93D7A654F4CB0BA25AF35C0BB1C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9493 IH: Homeland Security Export Subpoena Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9493</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221212">December 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001077">Mr. Higgins of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 to reauthorize the export administrative subpoena authority and other authorities under that Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H277217FFEBA24EA48A662E2742C9F9D7" style="OLC">
<section id="H557FE9D18D3B43CD94B5F0A762678A20" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Security Export Subpoena Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H68118EBEAB544353804F62DC5E7EDD2C" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reauthorization of export administrative subpoena authority and other authorities under the Export Control Reform Act of 2018</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1761(k) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4820">50 U.S.C. 4820(k)</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4549097668DE4EC48F1985A55DD8DE97" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<subsection id="HC76EEDBF2FFF44D1BC479DCBBC5363DC"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Authority of the Department of Homeland Security</header> 
<paragraph id="H5264C197360C42AABD13CDA2DBED93CF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subtitle shall be construed to limit or otherwise affect the enforcement authorities of the Department of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6BC41B71D9864BCC9DB22578937CEE51"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Customs officer authorities</header> <subparagraph id="H953219145C70458DBB8E4B68B39AEFA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement and U.S. Customs and Border Protection may take appropriate action to ensure observance of this subtitle as to the enforcement of export controls. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H19755C86D86D4AB383B8FBC9A707B5D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement may make investigations into violations of this subtitle both within and outside of the United States, and may obtain such information from, require such reports or the keeping of such records by, make such inspection of the books, records, and other writings, premises, or property of, and take the sworn testimony of, any person. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4C5E8ECCAFF3446EA0BFBA56EF3C7BFA"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement special agents and U.S. Customs and Border Protection officers may administer oaths or affirmations, and may by subpoena require any person to appear and testify or to appear and produce books, records, and other writings, or both, and in the case of contumacy by, or refusal to obey a subpoena issued to, any such person, a district court of the United States, after notice to any such person and hearing, shall have jurisdiction to issue an order requiring such person to appear and give testimony or to appear and produce books, records, and other writings, or both, and any failure to obey such order of the court may be punished by such court as a contempt thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </section> 
</legis-body></bill>

