<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1F0F0E10BE2C40DD90E4EE368A223EE3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8027 IH: To establish within the Executive Office of the President a Technology Competitiveness Council.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8027</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220613">June 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. C. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish within the Executive Office of the President a Technology Competitiveness Council.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H04D241CBB2814AF18BE9C4ECB06CCB7C" style="OLC"><section id="H56AF4C8F6B794AE699EDDFA3CDFD0BCE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Technology Competitiveness Council</header><subsection id="H46BF4B6D80CB4DC1859FA48EEEE80F0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6601">42 U.S.C. 6601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEDD1B2D821FD4B2D880545C006CDEB29" display-inline="no-display-inline"><title id="HEBE0F594548946A1902114E9F72DF102"><enum>VII</enum><header>Technology Competitiveness Council</header><section id="H18E2077407564369BFC95824F9E38525"><enum>701.</enum><header>Establishment of Council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President shall establish within the Executive Office of the President a Technology Competitiveness Council (in this title referred to as the <quote>Council</quote>).</text></section><section id="H830D1E6A77B1429DB2AE3C6FE354C32B"><enum>702.</enum><header>Membership of Council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Council shall be composed of the following members:</text><paragraph id="H8149FD6C014D4540B98A6059E64FA700"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Vice President, who shall be Chair of the Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H496BC0A1E2EB4C41AB3BC3A500944A31"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The following executive branch officials:</text><subparagraph id="H01B4C72A7848483C8F39F24086EF511D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H07B31F22C9954F1CBBBA17A33256C662"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H792A802A48754CFBB0EDF1288F3AF14A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0887CBCFE55D4DE0B0CB2264E4455CB6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Attorney General.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9234B00CFAB04A70A96A932F6A8D8FF6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Secretary of Commerce.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4E64D5A36F446648CD0AE45B0F6332C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>The Secretary of Energy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H368919C870CC4D74A2BA4DE49D325278"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD616C169224547DF8002101D151D5188"><enum>(H)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Management and Budget.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H24197CDA771F41A79576376088802158"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for Technology Competitiveness.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C5AF574DD13489B9D4305E4E0496064"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for National Security Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67CA980DC7A041ECAF5ACE79319CBC57"><enum>(K)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for Science and Technology.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41F9988E819549C49B433904F4A13B72"><enum>(L)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for Economic Policy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1294503898824E0BB3B2B6538D9B5C5F"><enum>(M)</enum><text>The Assistant to the President for Domestic Policy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3772429B0EAE4656834F86F0D5C5A49E"><enum>(N)</enum><text>The United States Trade Representative.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB1F5D521D084BADB54723ABC432A287"><enum>(O)</enum><text>The Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A32ADEE01745C6BC426BA795EDA02E"><enum>(P)</enum><text>The heads of such other executive departments and agencies and other senior officials within the Executive Office of the President, as may be determined by the Chair of the Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H5A018305CB174516AAB1D90EDB0115E2"><enum>703.</enum><header>Operation of Council</header><subsection id="H89DC6EB46B6545C6A996917765977A52"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Responsibilities of the chair</header><paragraph id="H428AF7A6FCDB4FDDA9870AE240ABBC7C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Chair shall convene and preside over meetings of the Council and shall determine the agenda for the Council.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCDD0FBE25D84E118709E99B1EE670D7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Committees</header><text>The Chair may authorize the establishment of such committees of the Council, including an executive committee, and of such working groups, composed of senior designees of the Council members and of other officials, as he or she deems necessary or appropriate for the efficient conduct of Council functions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9485BE6C8D784D5BB81FAA2E4EC64A3C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>The Chair shall report to the President on the activities and recommendations of the Council. The Chair shall advise the Council as appropriate regarding the President’s directions with respect to the Council’s activities and national technology policy generally.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7302FEE35A5B47D69029E2615847D607"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HB1BBD340CB204F69A7C91D7B6C6CCAAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall have a staff, headed by the Assistant to the President for Technology Competitiveness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5A10D1C6A1D43B3AFC932C103B01E69"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Personnel, funding, and administrative support</header><text>The Office of Administration in the Executive Office of the President shall provide the Council with such personnel, funding, and administrative support, as directed by the Chair or, upon the Chair’s direction, the Assistant to the President for Technology Competitiveness, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FA23D8CD7CF477CB91CBFDAC26E3AA7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Resources</header><text>Subject to the availability of appropriations, heads of agencies serving on the Council shall make resources, including but not limited to personnel and office support, available to the Council as reasonably requested by the Chair or, upon the Chair’s direction, the Assistant to the President for Technology Competitiveness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD894509C2CA49FFADB5B70B521780F6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Information and assistance</header><text>The heads of agencies shall provide to the Council such information and assistance as the Chair may request to carry out the functions described in section 704.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33E295B6398446758BFF9F261D8DBAF5"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Council shall coordinate with the National Security Council on Technology Policy and Strategy matters relating primarily to national security to ensure that the activities of the Council are carried out in a manner that is consistent with the responsibilities and authorities of the National Security Council.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H76ACDCF74569430D80EE05011325C572"><enum>704.</enum><header>Functions of council</header><subsection id="H57C03E890D814108B17E3BD8BA80109C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall be responsible for—</text><paragraph id="H998D0DBCE4D348FAB606067BAFFA377F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>developing recommendations for the President on United States technology competitiveness and technology-related issues, advising and assisting the President in the development and implementation of national technology policy and strategy, and performing such other duties as the President may prescribe;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H366F49610CB14B76968BC3F8ABF56F36"><enum>(2)</enum><text>developing and overseeing the implementation of a National Technology Strategy as described in subsection (b);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0ADC561E18443D6983722A46A535DAB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>serving as a forum for balancing national security, economic, and technology considerations of United States departments and agencies as they pertain to technology research, development, commercial interests, and national security applications;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB27BA58AAE13438C825C9E64E2E490F5"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coordinating policies across Federal departments and agencies related to United States competitiveness in critical and emerging technologies and ensuring that policies designed to promote United States leadership and protect existing competitive advantages are integrated and mutually reinforcing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H174C181B44C9441982C3B83EC6D5F15D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>synchronizing budgets and strategies, in consultation with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, in accordance with the National Technology Strategy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9A4AB24381F740C4B83590B5C7BFC16E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National technology strategy</header><paragraph id="H57BCFB7324F24E18A9D9560C7435CF00"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council shall be responsible for developing and annually submitting to the President a National Technology Strategy designed to maintain United States leadership in critical and emerging technologies essential to United States national security and economic prosperity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB437E8F092984C53BFEC64A28B6B51B5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The National Technology Strategy required by paragraph (1) shall contain at least the following elements:</text><subparagraph id="H949FB2F874E74C9BB7734144854CB086"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of the United States Government’s efforts to preserve United States leadership in key emerging technologies and prevent United States strategic competitors from leveraging advanced technologies to gain strategic military or economic advantages over the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC112C7EE03024DEEB8D85D17A68BFECA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A review of existing United States Government technology policy, including long-range goals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE3760307D8C4AA686C0B43F14EAC430"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An analysis of technology trends and assessment of the relative competitiveness of United States technology sectors in relation to strategic competitors.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA71225A46D541A7A98B55CBD4DA6C40"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Identification of sectors critical for the long-term resilience of United States innovation leadership across design, manufacturing, supply chains, and markets.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEB66185D2335453CAACB0EF286651005"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Recommendations for domestic policy incentives to sustain an innovation economy and develop specific, high-cost sectors necessary for long-term national security ends.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7F8B8F2C8E9491788C2E7521F7C64F3"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Recommendations for policies to protect United States and allied leadership in critical areas through targeted export controls, investment screening, and counterintelligence activities.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98FE779FA90541E6BD40430D07B4E383"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Identification of priority domestic research and development areas critical to national security and necessary to sustain United States leadership, and directing funding to fill gaps in basic and applied research where the private sector does not focus.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H223447D784B04745A1CED7B530A53706"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Recommendations for talent programs to grow United States talent in key critical and emerging technologies and enhance the ability of the Federal Government to recruit and retain individuals with critical skills into Federal service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H97E103362C1146F7829FCBD4740F0D0E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Methods to foster the development of international partnerships to reinforce domestic policy actions, build new markets, engage in collaborative research, and create an international environment that reflects United States values and protects United States interests.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H81A32E70F0AB45FFB4F003790857CE1D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial National Technology Strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The National Technology Council established pursuant to section 701 of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976, as added by this Act, shall provide the first National Technology Strategy required by section 704(b) of such Act, not later than the date that is 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

