<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA2DCA38235494C3BAD539845274265C6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6883 IH: To prohibit certain aircraft associated with the Russian Federation from operating in the national airspace system.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6883</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220301">March 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit certain aircraft associated with the Russian Federation from operating in the national airspace system.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB8E645CE473C4C8394BD97996AD2E603" style="OLC"><section id="H0A40E9535A154F1CB8C5DA7317AD4B14" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Prohibition on Russian air carriers</header><subsection id="H43F3789923F2459D85FCFE887DA78C0A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the Secretary of Transportation shall ensure that the following aircraft may not operate in the national airspace system:</text><paragraph id="H520C83A93B8143FFB3F076BB91ABCBF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A private aircraft listed by the Secretary of State pursuant to subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2972A1F5CA464FB2ABB26166A905C8B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any aircraft of a foreign air carrier, as such term is defined in section 40102 of title 49, United States Code, owned or operated by an entity organized under the laws of the Russian Federation, or any jurisdiction within the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8055F152DA7549BE98CC4F1AF7889606"><enum>(b)</enum><header>List of prohibited aircraft</header><text>The Secretary of State shall compile a list of private aircraft that are—</text><paragraph id="HB1A2EA51A9CE4CC0A6A844248F43AB7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>owned by a citizen of the Russian Federation that is considered to be an oligarch, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC99589532364BF290C0168468BCAE19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>registered in a country other than the Russian Federation. </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

