<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H598AC4984B0B4D7CB6B3DBD6B97ABE4D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6941 IH: Territorial Representation in the Senate Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6941</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001204">Mr. San Nicolas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000610">Ms. Plaskett</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To provide for a nonvoting delegate to the Senate to represent American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands of the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H0526672F01494AE0882E7031878B236E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H636F160A9AC040648FDFAFBB6FDD00D9" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Territorial Representation in the Senate Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HBBFF9F57FA8E4743A47042C0138F21E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Delegate to Senate from each Territory</header> <subsection id="H753378F1273D40BAAF39ADF185FA0162"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Nonvoting delegate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to local legislative approval in accordance with subsection (b), each Territory shall be represented in the United States Congress by a Delegate to the United States Senate. The Delegate shall be a nonvoting Delegate in the Senate, elected as provided in this Act.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H9CD8BE9F784744A28C6469D38A5BF5E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Local legislative approval</header><text>The local legislature of each Territory shall—</text> <paragraph id="HECC23EBE246940C5956BF39AAA929015"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determine whether the Territory will be represented by a nonvoting delegate as authorized by this Act; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB4B5D3FD49804828BE4A7BAD9CDA24DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>establish such procedures as the legislature may deem appropriate to modify the determination described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H77F6303CA4034C21B1FFC6CFF3956B13"><enum>3.</enum><header>Election of delegate</header> <subsection id="HBDA318244C404BE38146A69650DF676B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Electors and time of election</header><text>The Delegate for a Territory shall be elected—</text> 
<paragraph id="HA736933B781C4C9B88EBD6A45DC9D53D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by the people qualified to vote for the popularly elected officials of the Territory;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H34638449C6A64A998626615E5787B410"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at the first Federal general election occurring at least one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and at each Federal general election every 6 years thereafter; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H39A736BBBBB54FF5A52BF1C990527F5D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>at a special election, if required due to a mid-term permanent vacancy.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H845EDECA064C4558B7194E7D97863C29"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Manner of election</header> <paragraph id="H9122B76B9E7146B69A1914C65EBC76CB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Delegate shall be elected at large and by a plurality of the votes cast for the office of Delegate.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H283EAEAA07EB40489AC9B4A0A84CFAB4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of establishment of primary elections</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1), if the Government of the Territory, acting pursuant to legislation enacted in accordance with the Constitution or Organic Act of the Territory, provides for primary elections for the election of the Delegate, the Delegate shall be elected by a majority of the votes cast in any general election for the office of Delegate for which such primary elections were held.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3D241EAD5FAF40569F5EA79E13269BD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Vacancy</header><text>In case of a permanent vacancy in the office of Delegate, the office of Delegate shall remain vacant until a successor is elected and qualified.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDE204EF5C89E49C2A52F26FA56321434"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Commencement of term</header><text>The term of the Delegate shall commence on the 3rd day of January following the date of the election.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB516A9DEFDC24F399951E7451C669916"><enum>4.</enum><header>Qualifications for office of delegate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">To be eligible for the office of Delegate a candidate shall—</text> 
<paragraph id="H245A1C26F86E40A6B6F272F8C7E1540E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be at least 30 years of age on the date of the election;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE8AC0EB39EA74B79A031FEA9DE56D4AE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>have been a citizen of the United States for at least 9 years prior to the date of the election;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86805390571E4B51BA9705445A905F36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be a resident and domiciliary of the Territory prior to the date of the election for a period to be determined by the Government of the Territory;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H218BC55950C74832980313037C1F83ED"><enum>(4)</enum><text>be qualified to vote in the Territory on the date of the election; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF669B784067F4C3D9F1C2A0DD6D6B045"><enum>(5)</enum><text>not be, on the date of the election, a candidate for any other office.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H03CBE3D88ED140F4BC9AE60E9D319686"><enum>5.</enum><header>Determination of election procedure</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Acting pursuant to legislation enacted in accordance with the Constitution or Organic Act of the Territory, the Government of the Territory may determine—</text> 
<paragraph id="H290D31D7C7EA413D9430F8DEF484AFA5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the order of names on the ballot for election of Delegate;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDB2F5947730C42BE93E8E1B0A9DF2313"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the method by which a special election to fill a permanent vacancy in the office of Delegate shall be conducted;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC6E9E7B2617E49CD83F09E5BB7F7EF88"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the method by which ties between candidates for the office of Delegate shall be resolved; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5195011CF9E4263817B952F424E8A99"><enum>(4)</enum><text>all other matters of local application pertaining to the election and the office of Delegate not otherwise expressly provided for in this Act.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section commented="no" id="H6DD5B8D119534987AEEB501AEAAC33B9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Compensation, privileges, and immunities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Until the Rules of the Senate are amended to provide otherwise, the Delegate from the Territory shall receive the same compensation, allowances, and benefits as a Member of the Senate, and shall be entitled to whatever privileges and immunities are, or hereinafter may be, granted to any other member of the Senate, except that a Delegate shall be nonvoting on final Senate votes.</text></section> <section id="HF610A6C3CB0F49578886829C6BECB496"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act, the term <term>Territory</term> means, individually, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, Guam, Puerto Rico, and the Virgin Islands of the United States.</text></section> 
</legis-body>
</bill> 

