<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE49631F23D044C94BC384511B9101D97" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7662 IH: My Child, My Choice Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7662</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001214">Mr. Steube</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001116">Mr. Clyde</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit Federal education funds from being provided to elementary schools that do not require teachers to obtain written parental consent prior to teaching lessons specifically related to gender identity, sexual orientation, or transgender studies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H29D71057A43443F69AEF5A42DC83B118" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4B550FE85EA942F78B1656198F70EA25" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>My Child, My Choice Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H42407074907A4849AF439449F72E60C9" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Written parental consent required for teaching of information related to gender identity, sexual orientation, or transgender studies</header> <subsection id="H500FF0F26BE641589573B59FC56BCB95"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No funds under an applicable program may be provided to an elementary school determined by the Secretary of Education under subsection (c) to not be in compliance with subsection (b). </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA1A65ED2DEEC484B86F46FD6459C68E7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Written parental consent</header> 
<paragraph id="H7CD5497535BC4E28961456E64EADADA1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consent required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A teacher employed by an elementary school shall, prior to teaching a lesson specifically related to gender identity, sexual orientation, or transgender studies, request written consent from the parent of each student enrolled in the class in which the teacher plans to teach such lesson. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFFB761696547432CB921A307DD144D58"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header> <subparagraph id="H86B5B296A4BB4D21A2127698859B3DE5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A teacher shall request the written consent required under paragraph (1) not later than 30 days prior to the date on which the teacher plans to teach such lesson.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5868B64F696649ECA628D62970A3CBBA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration of consent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A teacher shall request such written consent each such time the teacher plans to teach such lesson.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3C02C5A8E79245FD85D1134B9C85B5A4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission</header><text>A parent providing written consent shall submit such written consent to the principal of the school not later than the date described in paragraph (2)(A).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H32E789DE5760482B8742992204D2CA67" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consent not obtained</header> 
<subparagraph id="H5FD6ED7008E04ADEB36DD3BCFEB82E1F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a student whose parent does not submit written consent under paragraph (3), the school shall provide such student with an alternative period of learning or study hall.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4F78D6F08E754E9C9BA0A48FE0C829F5" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>50 percent required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the principal does not receive written consent from the parents of at least 50 percent of the students enrolled in the class in which the teacher plans to teach such lesson, the teacher may not teach such lesson.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H61395D0D65EF4BB9BC869E9655BEBD26" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ensuring compliance</header> 
<paragraph id="HC9E99884BD284B20BB39FA4281638324" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Students enrolled in an elementary school, parents of such students, and teachers employed by an elementary school may submit, to the Secretary, a report that such school was not in compliance with subsection (b).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HE034843861B846F88CD0E9BC200E2E8C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Review</header><text>The Secretary shall review each such report and make a determination with respect to whether the elementary school identified in such report is in compliance with subsection (b).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF1792B0CDFBE40D184DA53CB939AF70A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of compliance</header><text>If the Secretary makes a determination that the school is not in compliance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H9A205DE2A3A04871AD4804DC04654BCD" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>notify the school of such determination; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2BD2B6DC529D48F88EE723694401EB3A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide a period of 15 days after such notification for the school to—</text> <clause id="HC7CD35943FE34272B7FF49284CAF2FC8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>comply with subsection (b); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H274AA0775E494CB4A3FEFF38FD7B2762"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Secretary a written confirmation of compliance with subsection (b), which shall include—</text> <subclause id="HB041EEABE1CC4C6E8B91E5ACF3F3408C"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of each requirement of subsection (b) with which the school was not in compliance; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HC4257073B21341CFAC2C8AE89C4FBAD7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the plans and actions the school is taking to ensure that the school continues to be in such compliance; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H760AE8D717CE4BD6BEBE65744B9DF9EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluate the written confirmation submitted under subparagraph (B)(ii) and make a final determination with respect to whether the school is in compliance with subsection (b).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD4B864C2F49B41E68271BB69410B316D" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Federal funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Secretary makes a final determination under subsection (c)(3)(C) that an elementary school is not in compliance with subsection (b), no funds under an applicable program may be provided to such school for the school year immediately following the school year in which such school is determined to be out of compliance.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="HC1390BC5EDA14C138E50DFAA9F24B66D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="H73CB134BB65C4074885592B5EF21D958" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable program</term> has the meaning given the term in section 400(c) of the General Education Provisions Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1221">20 U.S.C. 1221(c)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3214D310BF314FC483F6FE4351F12CCA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Biological sex</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>biological sex</term> means the biological indication of male or female in the context of reproductive potential or capacity, including sex chromosomes, naturally occurring sex hormones, gonads, and nonambiguous internal and external genitalia present at birth.</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCF324D2CEDE44EEB9825EFF6FEE2F48A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>ESEA terms</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term> and <term>parent</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEDCFCDE145334AF1B35426A9BE0401BA" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gender identity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gender identity</term> means an individual’s perception of their own gender or claimed gender, regardless of the biological sex of the individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3B10AC64AC54B3EA3E8AA9F8A3FEB15"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lesson</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>lesson</term> means a planned and structured period of learning. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBCEAA8CC0E9405DB8EA5B25C277517B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education. </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9A985315AAF647519C889B2B0C47490C"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Sexual orientation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>sexual orientation</term> means an individual’s actual or perceived romantic, physical or sexual attraction to other individuals, or lack thereof, on the basis of gender.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB772C4467DFD4B58850BC15A713D42F4"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Transgender individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>transgender individual</term> means an individual whose gender identity or behavior does not conform to that typically associated with the biological sex of the individual.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55B9A75651764E3FADFC18BDFDF62A44"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Transgender studies</header><text>The term <term>transgender studies</term> means the study of transgender individuals. </text> </paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

