<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H858630B4B5074C0B9BDE5F4954C6C854" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7206 IH: Protecting Communities from Harmful Algal Blooms Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7206</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220324">March 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. C. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act to include algal blooms in the definition of a major disaster, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H294BD742792E4D4B8922E831550CE6F6" style="OLC">
<section id="HDC0CCDA1778B4779821A7E430F3301BC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting Communities from Harmful Algal Blooms Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2B1E0ED4E8C44DCF82BFA019EEB8B720" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Algal blooms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 102(2) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5122">42 U.S.C. 5122(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>or drought</quote> and inserting <quote>drought, or algal blooms</quote>.</text></section>
<section id="HB5B87FCEBB79484994692E79FC9C29AF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Impacts of algal blooms on air quality</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 365 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention shall submit to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, the Committee of Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate, the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate, the Committee on Oversight and Reform of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives a detailed study relating to the health effects of exposure to cyanotoxins in the air that result from algal blooms.</text> </section> </legis-body></bill>

