<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72E93482EEA44908B500962FDC8D2DEB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8596 IH: Biochar Research Network Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8596</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Committee on Agriculture</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a national biochar research network, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA3D2524570544EC791C047386DD1029D" style="OLC"><section id="H071CF66B97B3451C94DCEC676C0EC015" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Biochar Research Network Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H68F1D2FE1717457584C61290BD76B5E5"><enum>2.</enum><header>National biochar research network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title IV of the Agricultural Research, Extension, and Education Reform Act of 1998 is amended by inserting before section 404 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/7624">7 U.S.C. 7624</external-xref>) the following new section: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7F711297592F49FB8BFE52B6901E4960" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H3B31043F913C4040BF76F3035ACA3751"><enum>403.</enum><header>National biochar research network</header><subsection id="H9007CC77BE9241FD960DB878B0FB58B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a national biochar research network of not more than 20 research sites to test the full range of biochar types across soil types, soil conditions, application methods, and climatic and agronomic regions to—</text><paragraph id="HCB8554BB45534B7495CAA6B1640B4AB0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the soil carbon sequestration potential of biochar;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H406F42EDB2384524B8D6AD660887B732"><enum>(2)</enum><text>understand how to use biochar productively to contribute to climate mitigation, crop production, resilience to extreme weather events, ecosystem health, and natural resource conservation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE454F98FA6E441DFB18B6526AB5F8010"><enum>(3)</enum><text>deliver science-based, region-specific, cost-effective, and practical information to farmers, ranchers, foresters, land reclamation managers, urban land managers and other land and natural resource managers and businesses on sustainable biochar production and application.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H97BE5FFC8A0646968C0AC1926D598B9A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The national biochar research network established under subsection (a) shall encompass agriculture, horticulture, rangeland, forestry, and other biochar uses and a broad range of feedstocks, production processes, and application treatments. The research conducted shall include—</text><paragraph id="HA1EE270339F5462AB39B298E5D5EA17D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cross-site and mechanistic experiments to—</text><subparagraph id="H6ED3F06549B74B979EF9E40DFE08E79B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fill critical knowledge gaps and gain a more complete understanding of the impact of various types of biochar in varying site conditions on soil properties, plant growth, greenhouse gas emissions, and carbon sequestration in different soils, climates, and other natural and agronomic conditions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H754030F2254B4AA6B104BAD31341BD62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provide mechanistic and techno-economic insights on thermochemical conversion processes in biochar production and the co-production of biochar and bioenergy, including interactions of feedstock properties with reactor conditions and processes on the relative proportions and properties of biochar, bio-fuels, and value-added co-products, as well as process efficiency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C5CB9EA2AA84BD1A4532EF1175CD4D8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>generate data to develop, calibrate, and validate robust mechanistic models to predict the full life cycle of greenhouse gas, crop response, and related agronomic and environmental implications of particular applications of biochar; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4C5D9EFA8CE416694AE303539429D0E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>generate data to help guide the design of new, more-efficient biochar and bioenergy production reactors and biorefineries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A8A70B67E1840578951481C9C1555DB"><enum>(E)</enum><text>generate data to develop, calibrate, and validate testing methodologies for biochar to identify potential contaminants or other factors that may cause unintended consequences;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB6A8AE52689458F926C3FCBF27F4B6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">site-specific farm and forestry systems assessments and pilot-scale biochar production and application systems to—</text><subparagraph id="H4FFE37F8FBC548A8A765D1EE559C6734"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">refine the most promising soil-based uses, sources, and methods of producing and applying biochar in particular regions to enhance productivity, increase profitability, scalability, and portability, reduce greenhouse gas emissions, improve ecosystem health, and strengthen resilience to extreme weather events, and explore soil, crop, climate, management, and biochar interactions;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAAE6C5B7B2314B4687AFC0DBE1C83CB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop new knowledge to support decisions on sustainable production and use of biochar;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F53767A86924FE18DC94855037764E8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>collect relevant data needed for full life cycle greenhouse gas and economic analyses and complete such analysis; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEC5C10B02D5423DB405AFA6A01DBEFA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>predict plant-response, soil health, soil carbon sequestration, ecosystem health, water quality, greenhouse gas, and economic outcomes for specific implementations of biochar technology; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H698753C55BEC4EC1A2F4010C63B4DBC9"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide data to evaluate local biomass feedstocks, support selection of sustainable biochar production methods, and address biochar production issues; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DE21C9774E64393A6FF45C3C3891FC6"><enum>(F)</enum><text>share research results to inform farmers, horticulturalists, ranchers, foresters, urban biochar users, extension agents and specialists, and technical assistance providers on the most advantageous ways to use biochar to increase profitability, raise productivity, lower costs, improve soil and plant health, and enhance resilience to extreme weather events while contributing to carbon sequestration and greenhouse gas reductions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4162EF79257345AAA6B8ACCCAF8AEAB8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity is eligible to be selected to conduct research funded under this section if such entity is—</text><paragraph id="HE54496A3896648EEA68532F86E18061B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a State agricultural experiment station or a State forestry experiment station;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3079B215A2BC4BC0A0C15E0ACD790FD9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a research facility of the Agricultural Research Service, the Forest Service, or any other agency of the Department of Agriculture that the Secretary determines is appropriate; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF4DD6D0C4C5484CB03CC7DCF9B8F0DA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a research facility of the Department of Energy, the Department of Commerce, or the Department of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD81861E057C449BBBF3BBDB5ED82AC7B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HD73EF447A92046859519F49FB7F7F250"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The research network established under subsection (a) shall be administered by the Administrator of the Agricultural Research Service, in partnership with Chief of the Forest Service, the Director of the National Institute of Food and Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of the Interior, and, as determined by the Secretary of Agriculture, other agencies of the Department of Agriculture.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18B480CC9FBD4C1C9EF37DFA15265541"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conservation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Natural Resources Conservation Service—</text><subparagraph id="HB3634FC7E26B418DB551DBBFEDE0A09D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may develop a practice standard informed by the research; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CDF0166E94B4D0A9FC2B823514D9237"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall coordinate the activities of the research network established under subsection (a) with—</text><clause id="HBD100DF9623A40B3940FF7BACAECC3F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the development and refinement of a biochar conservation practice standard; and</text></clause><clause id="H510549B136BE4D9CB6EF99F9CF25FC45"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>improvements and expansion of conservation program technical and financial support for biochar production and application.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE1D67342B12A43DBB0D19F2D7E51020D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $50,000,000 for each fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

