<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H51DE9BDEC5E7446DB806D97B2F3574B6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8901 IH: To direct the Secretary of Defense to submit a report regarding the provision of water alternatives to communities affected by PFAS contamination, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8901</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to submit a report regarding the provision of water alternatives to communities affected by PFAS contamination, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAEF4CC1EA27F45AF8DCA5A21623E7A6D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H9314327D713143279C3EFCD0BFF58E45" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Report on Department of Defense provision of water alternatives to communities affected by PFAS contamination</header> 
<subsection id="H26832AC3A6724F21B629CAE6E42879B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than December 1, 2022, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report containing an outline of the plan of the Department of Defense to provide (or continue providing, as the case may be) alternative water sources to affected communities surrounding military installations with levels of perfluoroalkyl substances that have been determined to be above the lifetime health advisory for contamination for such substances as issued by the Environmental Protection Agency and printed in the Federal Register on June 21, 2022.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H40322562B33D403298F29025704207B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Matters</header><text>The report under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H9026B9FB2A8E43A185025718D3AC30EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of any military installations previously classified as requiring <quote>no further action</quote> with respect to perfluoroalkyl substances contamination that, as of the date of the report, require additional investigation with respect to such contamination.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H79923D7315A74976873927DDC559BDB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A list of any military installations with previous tests results of perfluorooctanoic acid or perfluorooctane sulfonic acid at concentrations above 0 but less than 70 parts per trillion, and a description of the timeline and processes by which the Secretary has provided, and continues to provide, alternative water sources to affected communities surrounding such installations.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H955D64FCB67746E196A06A9EA5C078A7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any guidance issued by the Secretary to update the processes and procedures of the Department in accordance with the lifetime health advisory issued by the Environmental Protection Agency and printed in the Federal Register on June 21, 2022.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA31C87F1FCC446A8953D875A93BBB00D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any plans of the Department for community engagement with respect to affected communities referred to in subsection (a).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFB3D93B6F4FF4D4281901A0E9BF8282C"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of any additional resources necessary for the Secretary to address the needs of such affected communities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H17987ADFEA994B1CA172CA24C61C5775"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the testing methods for perfluoroalkyl substances, and the levels of detection associated with such methods, currently available to the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD36BE5689FF1484FB29470EDB611B17E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Alternative water source defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <quote>alternative water source</quote> means a source of water uncontaminated with perfluoroalkyl substances.</text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

