<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8ECAFB5A3200423DB5184F95FC5580F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6508 IH: Family Plus Health Care Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220125">January 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act to extend group health plan and health insurance coverage to parents of enrollees if such parents are not eligible to enroll in the Medicare or Medicaid program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H921135F8EF794724A70D47E2E79BF5FC" style="OLC"><section id="H2F57AE5F6FA94424BE7F811101391E73" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Family Plus Health Care Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H15F00E4998D2468193A114FBED442266"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension of coverage to parents of enrollees who are not eligible to enroll in the Medicare or Medicaid program</header><subsection id="H4E0F03DEC383420295AD02D411A55B09"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Extension of coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg">42 U.S.C. 300gg et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 2714 the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H3D6839862BFE4D538DB2F62761EDDDB6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HFDEDCCE2269E4F698B66701082926C1B"><enum>2714A.</enum><header>Extension of coverage to parents of enrollees who are not eligible to enroll in the Medicare or Medicaid program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A group health plan or a health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage that provides dependent coverage of children shall extend coverage under such group health plan or such health insurance coverage, at the option of an individual enrolled in such group health plan or such health insurance coverage, to a parent of such individual if such parent is not entitled to benefits under part A, or eligible to enroll under part B, of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and not eligible to enroll under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of such Act.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0BB13FBA7AB4450EA256B898AA4F6FB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tax treatment of expenditures for health insurance of non-Dependent parents</header><paragraph id="HD5EA771F38F54CFC93F899D55D285217"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Tax treatment</header><subparagraph id="H913704E2C92143A89EDC32D405CF8B02"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exclusion of amounts expended for medical care</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/105">Section 105(b)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7971D0575A4C4553B386547E0449A63C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HF08D48CBD90B4734AA34BFBF7CFBE9B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts expended for medical care</header><paragraph id="HD17DE1E9BBA640ADB2D7D67FEEC1EF06"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except in the case of amounts attributable to (and not in excess of) deductions allowed under section 213 (relating to medical, etc., expenses) for any prior taxable year, gross income does not include amounts referred to in subsection (a) if such amounts are paid, directly or indirectly, to the taxpayer to reimburse the taxpayer for expenses incurred by him for the medical care (as defined in section 213(d)) of the taxpayer, his spouse, his dependents (as defined in section 152, determined without regard to subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), and (d)(1)(B) thereof), any child (as defined in section 152(f)(1)) of the taxpayer who as of the end of the taxable year has not attained age 27, and any parent of the taxpayer who (during the calendar month in which such amounts are incurred) is not entitled to benefits under part A, or eligible to enroll under part B, of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and not eligible to enroll under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of such Act. Any child to whom section 152(e) applies shall be treated as a dependent of both parents for purposes of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85D9DCC3E2AC4E12A33E2C6E8B119253"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Parent defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>parent</quote> includes a biological parent, a stepparent, and a parent by adoption.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD79DB23565D4F1893EB99AEA12CB4E0"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Self-employed health insurance deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 162(l)(1) of such Code is amended—</text><clause id="H59442EFB67764A59A9DF52F2ABCB3CE7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end,</text></clause><clause id="H92BEB81B14854718AB5A89BF06F42A9F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>, and</quote>, and</text></clause><clause id="H4AB403E555914B65A61B54EA980DFD1B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H820AD8C7EA2C464EAEBD496FB5A2EC51" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HF600C288F625474B868FA87FF7B7F635"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any parent (as defined in section 105(b)(2)) of the taxpayer who, during the calendar month in which such amounts are incurred, is not entitled to benefits under part A, or eligible to enroll under part B, of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and not eligible to enroll under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of such Act.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA2F754BAD24A4067BAED962C4D9FC0CB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Coverage under self-employed deduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 162(l)(2)(B) of such Code is amended by inserting <quote>or subparagraph (E)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (D)</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A08381D86E94C8C864BDC5C394D581B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Medical and other benefits for retired employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 401(h) of such Code is amended by striking <quote>age 27.</quote> and inserting <quote>age 27 or who is a parent (as defined in section 105(b)(2)) of a retired employee who (during the calendar month in which such contributions are made) is not entitled to benefits under part A, or eligible to enroll under part B, of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and not eligible to enroll under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of such Act.</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA1AEB9D0917477AB779E6A385B7C653"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Treatment of parent as dependent for purposes of certain sick and accident benefits</header><text>Section 501(c)(9) of such Code is amended by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>or who is a parent (as defined in section 105(b)(2)) of a member who (during the calendar month in which such payments are made) is not entitled to benefits under part A, or eligible to enroll under part B, of title XVIII of the Social Security Act and not eligible to enroll under a State plan (or waiver of such plan) under title XIX of such Act.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C7969A9754E41029DDBFA7109BB8EC7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this subsection shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

