<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4E8319C256E8479883C67D248F28260D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9262 IH: To make improvements to cybersecurity acquisition policies of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9262</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221103">November 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make improvements to cybersecurity acquisition policies of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC094460A59C143EBBBC63462DF8B24D4" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H39EAACFA0F6249DFA8D9881E3840D189" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Curricula on software acquisitions and cybersecurity software or hardware acquisitions for covered individuals</header> 
<subsection id="HEAF9B45B12114881A111642B76B4A718"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Curricula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President of the Defense Acquisition University shall develop training curricula related to software acquisitions and cybersecurity software or hardware acquisitions and offer such curricula to covered individuals to increase digital literacy related to such acquisitions by developing the ability of such covered individuals to use technology to identify, critically evaluate, and synthesize data and information related to such acquisitions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE2FAB47FFAD24DD28AC7B47C6E8AD483"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>Curricula developed pursuant to subsection (a) shall provide information on—</text> 
<paragraph id="HFD9A562CD81C4DA58C2553FCB83F0A91"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cybersecurity, information technology systems, computer networks, cloud computing, artificial intelligence, machine learning, and quantum technologies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCE453E48E7124DB8A4AF20766EB6BA47"><enum>(2)</enum><text>cybersecurity threats and capabilities;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7CEFC98A45B643ADB92D6760F66F4298"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operational efforts of United States Cyber Command to combat cyber threats;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H96844C3DBB804721AD56902661A7E4A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">mission requirements and current capabilites and systems of United States Cyber Command;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFD17BF29E9274B11B4BB35B8D81C06E6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">activities that encompass the full range of threat reduction, vulnerability reduction, deterrence, incident response, resiliency, and recovery policies and activities, including activities relating to computer network operations, information assurance, military missions, and intelligence missions to the extent such activities relate to the security and stability of cyberspace; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H567ADA1232E245A19DFBB3BCC59B41B4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">industry best practices relating to software acquisitions and cybersecurity software or hardware acquisitions.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H530EDE3233E846DE9D78770D068878B0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the President of the Defense Acquisition University, shall submit to Congress a comprehensive plan to implement the curricula developed under subsection (a). Such plan shall include a list of resources required for and costs associated with such implementation, including—</text> <paragraph id="HB14EDEFB34144E4DB297B75BFE6BE130"><enum>(1)</enum><text>curriculum development;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6733E9A9805B4E348E31814F1B7E08E8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>hiring instructors to teach the curriculum;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB80F133FF1274D4E9C8370523A7970DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>facilities; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34186CF36C284183A7D43FF74C49FEAA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>website development.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H91356F2FCD884E3E8611015FE3E8BC3C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the plan described in subsection (c) is submitted to Congress, the President of the Defense Acquisition University shall offer the curricula developed under subsection (a) to covered individuals. </text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA6ECD1BD3B2E44FE82BA9FB4B340E533"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date on which the plan described in subsection (c) is submitted to Congress, the Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the President of the Defense Acquisition University, shall submit to Congress a report assessing the costs and benefits of requiring all covered individuals to complete the curricula developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection> <subsection id="H4093B71762F54EE2A148FB3180388B1B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Covered individuals defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered individuals</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD29E2DB23A2B45CCA22CDB8181B74191"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a contracting officer of the Department of Defense with responsibilities related to software acquisitions or cybersecurity software or hardware acquisitions; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H046704EE46AD4B72A266FF5732912689"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a individual serving in a position designated under section 1721(b) of title 10, United States Code, who is regularly consulted for software acquisitions or cybersecurity software or hardware acquisitions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HF4A6F4BA7D204DB89C6DEDA6167A9260"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on streamlining of information assurance and cybersecurity approval processes in software acquisitions</header> 
<subsection id="HD0F88EEEC8D54D7D87ABCD75F59C8024"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to Congress a report detailing a plan to streamline approval processes related to information assurance and cybersecurity for software acquisitions.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H544425290CFB441C8250EE90C6563701"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall include the following in the plan required by subsection (a):</text> 
<paragraph id="H576C1A36ABF54EDDA31617E647E0DF18"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Areas of duplication or overlapping processes and methods to streamline such processes.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H83E0196EFA344AC8A1237B127C1EAB68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Recommendations on how to adapt requirements processes to be more iterative to meet the needs of modern software acquisitions.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB0804C87FA004B4CA44FBBCB70C164ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Recommendations for modifying the requirements processes to become a threat-focused process.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEE79824816554E788CA181F54DC680A2"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An annex with information on staffing and funding levels and the impact on the efficiency of approval processes related to information assurance and cybersecurity for software acquisitions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

