<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H60D7B703688A455F8F87724AF1931736" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9626 IH: Report on DoD Practices to Distinguish Between Civilians and Combatants Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9626</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221220">December 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000305">Ms. Jacobs of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require an independent report on Department of Defense practices for distinguishing between combatants and civilians in United States military operations, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H501D22EE0BDB4E63902E4A3A0B1DFA73" style="OLC"><section id="H562D9814D3E9418F91433DF6E259F0F8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Report on DoD Practices to Distinguish Between Civilians and Combatants Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H60BCB92C6DF34E00BC91AD56A3A3F0AB" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Report on Department of Defense practices regarding distinction between combatants and civilians in United States military operations</header><subsection id="H97B2A529D45F436CAED926BC645BC7A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into an agreement with a federally funded research and development center to prepare an independent report on Department of Defense practices regarding distinguishing between combatants and civilians in United States military operations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFF8790CCA1A4412BAF002E469E91D256"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following matters:</text><paragraph id="HD993786087E24EB5A01125F62E09410A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of how the Department of Defense and individual members of the Armed Forces have differentiated between combatants and civilians in both ground and air operations since 2001, including in Afghanistan, Iraq, Syria, Somalia, Libya, and Yemen, including—</text><subparagraph id="HCA0098A483004387BCB61912CEA5DFA8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant policy and legal standards and how these standards were implemented in practice;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B8EA3A90AE9428EBD4F018D81965C88"><enum>(B)</enum><text>target engagement criteria; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BB06A7C346A43C4BB99FB9B35586DB5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether military-aged males were presumptively targetable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FB3109BC914448686FD9424E4886DA9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how the Department of Defense has differentiated between combatants and civilians when assessing allegations of civilian casualties since 2001, including in Afghanistan, Iraq, Syria, Somalia, Libya, and Yemen, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1E528A5C9E274F0593ECF240BCD0EA80"><enum>(A)</enum><text>relevant policy and legal standards and the factual indicators these standards were applied to in assessing claims of civilian casualties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H347BA1BA401741ECA5CD3C91C346F5E6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any other matters the Secretary of Defense determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91BC630DCF2545F69AC7DB1EC40C62A0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Submission of report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees a report setting forth an unaltered copy of the assessment under this section, together with the views of the Secretary on the assessment.</text></subsection><subsection id="H07E0E83008C44FC0AC5DED46B93BE3BB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition of United States military operation</header><text>In this section, the term <term>United States military operations</term> includes any mission, strike, engagement, raid, or incident involving United States Armed Forces.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

