<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H63BC6AB2B829491788F050E7464D9A2B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7593 IH: Access for All Communities Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7593</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Commerce to establish a clearinghouse to assist economic development activities in capacity-constrained communities.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H11903A7941034B1E95F02A6E018C8CB7" style="OLC"><section id="HED42AE414FB34A149E1A2B3C03E47C09" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Access for All Communities Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H0798DB07730347989392F4450F5B7E27"><enum>2.</enum><header>Establishment of Economic Development Resource Clearinghouse</header><subsection id="HEF8FD23914204B71B37BD85DC0E18EC6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Secretary of Commerce, acting through the Economic Development Administration, shall establish, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Commerce, a clearinghouse to be known as the Economic Development Resource Clearinghouse (hereinafter referred to as the <quote>Clearinghouse</quote>) for the purpose described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H177E154F92FD4D528BC5C1A83ECF21E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Clearinghouse shall be to increase awareness of Federal and State programs, grants, loans, loan guarantees, and other assistance that the Secretary determines can assist economic development activities in capacity-constrained communities.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCAA8C93BC7D941D2AED9C3461BF665C2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><paragraph id="HA22D1D90F9394C33B3E3EC23597B2C07"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall, as appropriate, maintain the Clearinghouse established under subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B287239FDC6403DA4DF803448C405BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Periodic updates</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In maintaining the Clearinghouse, the Secretary shall, not less than once per calendar year and as often as is necessary to reflect up-to-date information, update the Clearinghouse to address changes to available resources and changes to the needs of capacity-constrained communities, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5076FC53716F4E958C02D960E0B248FF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In establishing and maintaining the Clearinghouse, the Secretary shall consult with such Federal agencies as considered appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H34EF423DDE3C431A88ADB231B01D18FE"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available, a report on—</text><paragraph id="HD7D0980D38534D1FA5D51C51D58BF3F6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the availability of resources for capacity-constrained communities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4CE940017A34C3F8BF6731CFD294960"><enum>(2)</enum><text>efforts to publicize the Clearinghouse for capacity-constrained communities and the results of those efforts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA371FC07576242ADBC19F8ED07D5C64B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations on policy action to coordinate and facilitate strategic economic development, regional planning, capacity building, and technical assistance in capacity-constrained communities.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

