<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H338A7A8CEDF544C195D51A3CCBA3B822" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7575 IH: Green Jobs and Opportunity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7575</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220426">April 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and Secretary of Education, to submit a report on current and future trends and shortages in the clean energy technology industry to achieve a clean energy economy, and to provide grants to establish and enhance training programs for any occupation or field of work for which a shortage is identified, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H600C2FE329BC4C1087A6C95580B4C4EC" style="OLC"><section id="H1FB0356C8A0A440FA7F07DB542B2B593" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Green Jobs and Opportunity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H263267C5B3F84B11B4F9F05318A9DB19"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings and purpose</header><subsection id="HEEE4766DB4164D3FA6220F632B56B964"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H40A59606ECED4D41A1F1EB137212D333"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The 21st century has some of the highest recorded temperatures in known history.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A20230B09E449F0B4F77ECF318432D0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Scientists have high confidence that global temperatures will continue to rise for decades to come, largely due to greenhouse gases produced by human activities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5D020BC0DA3448AB29E00E673A02CD2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>According to the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change (IPCC), which includes more than 1,300 scientists from the United States and other countries, there will likely be a temperature rise of 2.5 to 10 degrees Fahrenheit over the next century.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD117126764046179DF2D9244B9F49B0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>With only around 4.4 percent of the Earth’s population, World Bank studies have found that the United States is the second largest contributor of carbon dioxide emissions at 14.6 metric tons of CO<subscript>2</subscript> per capita.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E0A8081087947299CBCD89A26560D0E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>When the world gets hotter, it can fuel the proliferation of drought, typhoons, hurricanes, wild­fires, and general habitat change, and can affect the availability of food and water, among other issues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04E0EE1A25CC4CD5ACED9BDB52E1396C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>IPCC findings have revealed that the United States is projected to lose more than $500,000,000,000 in annual economic output by the year 2100 from global warming.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H625C5D4BA3D24B2FAAF50D46EDA9E7CF"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Additionally, the IPCC discovered that to avoid the most severe impacts of a changing climate, net-zero global emissions by 2050 will be required.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5050D9DF76184A55B1A5973CC90CF98E"><enum>(8)</enum><text>According to the Brookings Institution, a clean economy would encompass a vast array of industries and jobs directly involved in producing goods and providing services with an environmental benefit.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA26E54F7C2F244A3BD5F66577F6E228B"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Under the 2019 Clean Jobs America report by E2 (Environmental Entrepreneurs), it is estimated that 3.26 million workers are currently employed in, or are engaged in closely related activities, to the clean economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCABC401B366A4E8F9DB1AAEEE114909C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>According to the International Labor Organization, by 2030, it is projected that over 24 million new clean energy jobs will be needed globally to transition to a clean economy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H248C9763C4844DAEBDFD0FF69F6E6C3D"><enum>(11)</enum><text>To meet this clean energy agenda, investing in job training will be crucial to ensuring the United States has a readied workforce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD76E5E612F3F4BA19936C0DB3F3E5B8F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of this Act is to ensure the current United States workforce is prepared to transition to a clean energy economy.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE68A3ADD0D8646A6ADF5F96FA2D65E62"><enum>3.</enum><header>21st century workforce trends and shortages</header><subsection id="H5EDD19E1CF7041AF813716E8263B4F0C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Monitoring</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Labor, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy, shall collect data to monitor current and future trends and shortages within the clean energy technology industry, which includes skilled technical personnel, electric power engineers, transmission engineers, and other occupations or fields of work under—</text><paragraph id="H4942E94D0E08481AA0145EE62C438696"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the agriculture and forestry industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10EC8959168A43C79DB01ED461D73E80"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the electric utility industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB706FEEF46064A53A39A3B1D634E6B61"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the manufacturing industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00EA5231014E402EBAFF0C6880E3273B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the wholesale trade industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D13445BCCA24FC3B637D09C6B3B7E96"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the professional and business services industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BFE084503824B13956287306AD4DBCC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the manufacturing and operation and maintenance industries for component parts of clean energy technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4EF9DA621B0144618174C84AD3D36E06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on current and future trends and shortages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and on a quarterly basis thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, based on the data collected under subsection (a), a report on—</text><paragraph id="H2892A75A91B04D59B2D3E98E8B0B2BB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">trends and shortages as of the date of such report and trends and shortages projected in the next 10 years;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B211C0AD3B845C3A684FD4B21E5EDAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>recommendations to prepare the workforce to address such trends and shortages to meet the demands of a clean energy economy, or prepare the workforce to meet such demands; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A1743C72FEF4BF4AF6116490B5F06E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other recommendations the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4DD2099C21C44EA3999914F32FF5CDA5"><enum>4.</enum><header>Workforce training grants</header><subsection id="H9A2E7AE3342645D2B0093DDC3D8792A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Grants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of Education, shall provide grants to eligible entities described in subsection (b) to establish workforce training programs (including distance learning) for any occupation or field of work for which a workforce shortage is identified or projected under subsection (b) or (c) of section 3.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF9B196458AE145E1B333834EACCC3542"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an entity shall be—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H01B7444899FA4DB1833D9895F10DF409"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an institution of higher education (as such term is defined in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>)), including a junior or community college (as such term is defined in section 312(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(f)</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD5C9D0AFD9FE4429B910A77B9ACF5E9F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a postsecondary vocational institution (as such term is defined in section 102(c) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002(c)</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H6848BB8DE93C4D57984A29750A7C3B1F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an elementary school (as such term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDC8C990BD24E45EDB4052E0F1305D396"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a secondary school (as such term is defined in section 8101 of the Elementary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB07C93D5232B41A193D5FD952CD71FC6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a Bureau-funded school (as such term is defined in section 1141 of the Education Amendments of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/2021">25 U.S.C. 2021</external-xref>));</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5D51C52FF6F8406F9E4A8380A2139A75"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a labor organization or joint labor-management organization;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA7023BA031B94FB8A5A4E75B54F11C65"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an entity that is registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>) that pays all participants of an apprenticeship program compensation at least the higher of $15 an hour or the applicable Federal, State, or local minimum wage in the location of the program; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HCBC4C9AE7D8247B6A88F07265C871CB2"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an area career and technical education school (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Carl D. Perkins Career and Technical Education Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/2302">20 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F2FAD5D16B94446A1C2A2AE6EF80A58"><enum>(9)</enum><text>an education and training provider that is listed as an eligible provider of training services for a program under section 122(d) of the Workforce Innovation Opportunity Act (29 U.S.C. 3152 (d)) that pays all participants of an apprenticeship or on-the-job-training program compensation at least the higher of $15 an hour or the applicable Federal, State, or local minimum wage in the location of the program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HF08BEFD9DDAF46C39BC9F09AEEA3878A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant from the Secretary under this section, an entity shall submit an application to the Secretary containing such information as the Secretary may require, including but not limited to—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H90B8840A988144BDA038E3CCF5C1A1DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the training the entity would provide with funds from such a grant, how such training fulfills the workforce needs described in subsection (b) or (c) of section 3, and that the workforce need being met is in an industry or occupation in the region in which the training is conducted;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HE2D82C968CF342CA9F5C52EF3334D598"><enum>(2)</enum><text>evidence of experience in conducting training programs in the clean energy technology sector;</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H58EA4336A4A748D7B804B99A83EF843A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>evidence that the program funded by such a grant will aid a participating individual in finding new or more advanced employment or training opportunities in the clean energy technology sector and that such employment or training will help the individual achieve economic self-sufficiency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4110FE0DD3734689AFBDEC47119FBE8D"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the entity and any relevant partnerships with the Federal Government, other worker training entities, employers or employer-sponsored organizations, State or local agencies, labor or joint labor-management organizations, institutions of higher education, community-based organizations, or faith-based organizations.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8FF2069EB9224D43965141CF04391382"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority</header><text>In awarding grants under this section, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities that, in carrying out training programs under this section, give priority to the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H1E6EE7DCA9DA49C5A51B9A7CCD6E85C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Displaced workers (particularly workers from the fossil fuel industry).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H16EEB2BA0E6B4846AE440EE4169C5793"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Individuals with a barrier to employment (as such term is defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1C659EE131244D78A7B9D5649B3ED2B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Veterans, members of the reserve components of the Armed Forces, or former members of such reserve components.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA8F9B866CB904CA29EC5344F48225978"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Members of underrepresented populations.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H5A38891CACDC4BB6814F7A0781554F5E"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Frontline and vulnerable communities.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7A85901B2E134D38B74CB451A2404D54"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other identified group the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB586B8C9501F43DD98FA79E7C815DC80"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Grant period and amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant awarded under this section shall be awarded for a one year period and may not exceed $2,500,000.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC46CD4F9A75D485DB298852DDF733BEE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit a report to Congress on the grant program carried out under this section, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="HD595E6B12C7142EB908B4B43049A11C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of each eligible entity awarded a grant under this section;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4968F1586BC1402DB50CFE83E868E781"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of each such grant;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1374D0693F14CDE9F3465B8420F7E14"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the activities for which such grant was used;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B2DB2BA703B41BBAA764963C33E6F9A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">policy recommendations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A692C29AF4C46F58E8821A6865C322C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any other information the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H317B419571DF434DBE99C524DF054B1C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Secretary’s National Advisory Committee</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish a National Advisory Committee on the Clean Energy Technology workforce, referred to in this section as the <quote>Advisory Committee</quote>, to meet the objectives of this Act.</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HEA309DE3F1224A208B4139A0D32C1A53"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall have—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD952EDF870BD4A229BBCE4084CEE4AF4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>24 voting members appointed by the Secretary, composed of—</text><clause commented="no" id="H58B576E2328A4C1FA50954AB916E0713"><enum>(i)</enum><text>6 representatives of employers who participate in the clean energy technology industry, including employers who participate in a registered apprenticeship program in the clean energy technology industry sponsored by a joint labor-management partnership;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H77469F21FFAB46DCB9C06B126CA16F76"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">6 representatives of labor or joint labor-management organizations who represent workers in the clean energy technology industry;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HB6B4B16AD8A14CD29D5EBB9800DD2DAA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>6 representatives of institutions of higher education, postsecondary vocational institutions, public high schools, an entity that carries out programs registered under the Act of August 16, 1937, and other education and training providers that are listed as an eligible provider of training services for a program under section 122(d) of the Workforce Innovation Opportunity Act; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE05781795FF94DAC97F3BD6850034815"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>6 representatives of environmental and clean energy community organizations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H013D2D44EA064EFFBEB94BDC79AA3F1A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>members who are ex officio nonvoting representatives from the Departments of Labor, Education, and Energy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H1D04C798793C4E908B95F36D39466126"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Qualifications</header><text>The members shall be selected upon the basis of their experience and competence concerning workforce development and training in the clean energy technology industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD47536DB539543C0A7594845C71EF93A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Terms</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint the members for terms of 3 years.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB39EE34994474983A63A8815A4F08131"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary shall designate one of the members of the Advisory Committee to serve as Chairperson of the Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD62E72153D154B9AB29A7FC7744D727B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Meetings</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall hold not fewer than 2 meetings during each calendar year. All meetings of the Advisory Committee shall be open to the public. A transcript shall be kept of each meeting and made available for public inspection.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HA938442FBE674133B745C4B878A86366"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall advise, consult with, and make recommendations to the Secretary on matters relating to the administration of this Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HDD9DEFF5454E40E7B0CC239181B4D32F"><enum>6.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act, $260,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025.</text></section><section id="H5764A8A67C5640A9A7D5063FCF3E0AF0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HBFB7A8FFE9234A9FBE401BEEF0DD0202"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as otherwise provided, any term used in this Act that is defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>) shall have the meaning given the term in such section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H34C2EEFB4AC64CE58F787B475075D8C0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clean energy economy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>clean energy economy</term> means United States energy production resulting in net-zero carbon emissions in accordance with the timeline described in the IPCC Report to limit global warming to 1.5 °C above pre-industrialized levels.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA2FDB35D76CB49EBA2ED1DF49FF27444"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clean energy technology industry</header><text>The term <term>clean energy technology industry</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H978D7482B95741EE998B85A6B938283F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the renewable, clean, and low-carbon electric power energy generation sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78FE1B342A51415BB8E6F75037945AC8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the electric transmission sector;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7B069544C254DAE88F067B8CA5FDFF1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the energy storage sector; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC26D96ACA5AC4A60A77CC418BB91BAB7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the energy efficiency sector.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H71046BA6F3A148F4BCC46BD70DC66581"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <term>Department</term> means the Department of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3669900BA034AE79EDA402FA179D079"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Distance learning</header><text>The term <term>distance learning</term> means the transmission of educational or instructional programming to geographically dispersed individuals and groups via telecommunications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF91D2AD1BD24D9AA834372EEA1C9B4D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Frontline and vulnerable communities</header><text>The term <term>frontline and vulnerable communities</term> means deindustrialized communities, depopulated rural communities, and communities where indigenous people, people of color, migrants, low-income workers, women, the elderly, people with disabilities, and the youth are disproportionately impacted.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD530E3C6E98E4C908BA48A7D8A57690B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>High school</header><text>The term <term>high school</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD9EC4C794E68450BAC9E20068B540314"><enum>(8)</enum><header>IPCC Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>IPCC Report</term> means the report entitled <quote>IPCC, 2018: Global warming of 1.5 °C. An IPCC Special Report on the impacts of global warming of 1.5 °C above pre-industrial levels and related global greenhouse gas emission pathways, in the context of strengthening the global response to the threat of climate change, sustainable development, and efforts to eradicate poverty</quote> published by the Intergovernmental Panel on Climate Change on October 8, 2018.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99898EFC156B40258BAC13E2688AE751"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BD28616548B4270A8A2651C2C101E92"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Shortages</header><text>The term <term>shortages</term> refers to when workforce demand exceeds supply within an occupation or field of work.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33EAD9D660254D24BBAF4A45AABAB150"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Skilled technical personnel</header><text>The term <term>skilled technical personnel</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HA6C0A48BD98F4319BF9B0ADD8893F120"><enum>(A)</enum><text>journey- and apprentice-level workers (including such workers who work in full supply chain and manufacturing, and operation and maintenance), who are enrolled in, or have completed, a registered apprenticeship program under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3207878C63DD4F169570B53DD93CFED6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other skilled workers in the clean energy technology industry, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8DF4801A257647F48A78C1C12E499F62"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Trend</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>trend</term> refers to jobs being created, jobs being eliminated, lifespan of jobs, required competencies of jobs, skill gaps of jobs, geographical locations of jobs, ongoing training for jobs, cleanliness of jobs (based on greenhouse gas reductions), current job openings, projected job openings, current wages of jobs, projected wages of jobs, unionization rates of jobs, and other information the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H543276C39B684216B1CD2C15A5A28195"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Underrepresented populations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>underrepresented populations</term> is a group of individuals (such as a group of individuals from the same gender or race) that comprises less than 25 percent of the individuals employed in each occupation or field of work within the clean-energy technology industry.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

