<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAF0AC5F573114CD7BE1946E315AA8A9A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9198 IH: To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to limit fiduciary consideration of non-pecuniary factors in investment decision-making.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9198</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221018">October 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M001205">Mrs. Miller of West Virginia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001183">Mr. Schweikert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001199">Mr. Smucker</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to limit fiduciary consideration of non-pecuniary factors in investment decision-making.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H104C232AB5D34CA6B19203943F2C5D77" style="OLC"><section id="H166FF699807B41A4AE48734B6B727126" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Fiduciary responsibilities relating to certain non-pecuniary objectives</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 404(a) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1104">29 U.S.C. 1104(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5FDC4C5966494339A8B4A42565F5248F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HEEE3F36DB9E242139EBE154E2C209FD7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Interest based on non-Pecuniary factors</header><subparagraph id="H98741E6F9ADD4977B0424935D5BD3C28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), a fiduciary of a plan shall be considered to act solely in the interest of the participants and beneficiaries of the plan with respect to a plan investment or investment course of action only if the fiduciary’s action with respect to such investment is based only on pecuniary factors. The fiduciary may not subordinate the interests of the participants and beneficiaries in their retirement income or financial benefits under the plan to other objectives and may not sacrifice investment return or take on additional investment risk to promote non-pecuniary benefits or goals. The weight given to any pecuniary factor by a fiduciary should appropriately reflect a prudent assessment of the impact of such factor on risk-return.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD02E37F1D6A940A9928F65F16F04EBE4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Investment alternatives for participant-directed individual account plans</header><text>In selecting investment options for a pension plan described in subsection (c)(1)(A), a fiduciary is not prohibited from considering or including an investment option on the basis that such investment option promotes non-pecuniary benefits or goals, provided that the fiduciary—</text><clause id="H1A9DBEE44EA14371942CD74F91BF612F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>satisfies the requirements of paragraph (1) and subparagraph (A) in considering or including any such investment option; and</text></clause><clause id="H4844C2AD2C5E44979302E14A46E93BA4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not consider or include such investment option as a default investment (as defined in the regulations issued by the Secretary under subsection (c)(5)(A)), or a component thereof.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E9DA56108B548038360657C9A525C36"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Pecuniary factor defined</header><text>For the purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>pecuniary factor</quote> means a factor that a fiduciary prudently determines is expected to have a material effect on the risk and return of an investment based on appropriate investment horizons consistent with the plan’s investment objectives and the funding policy established pursuant to section 402(b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HB3C40B37903E417A9B41455FAAC01713" section-type="subsequent-section" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Requirement that retirement plans continue to offer investments based solely on pecuniary factors</header><subsection id="H1E0F59472AF34A1D86B4BE663D80E8A2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/401">Section 401(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7D2A8C18BBBA439CB653F5F258883A84" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H7975F5EEB86442AD8E85BFEBEDB5842A" commented="no"><enum>(39)</enum><header>Defined contribution plan investment option requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a trust forming part of a defined contribution plan which includes investment options based on non-pecuniary factors (within the meaning of section 404(a)(3) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974), such trust shall not constitute a qualified trust unless the plan includes investment options not based on any such factors.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA4C52155737E4175B72B0BD905F03C02" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header><enum-in-header>403(b)</enum-in-header> plans</header><text>Section 403(b)(7) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBAB5A498936346C0B0952161ED2BE814" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HCBF66953B1C64D53B8191A55BC410B25" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Investment option requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subparagraph (A) shall not apply to an amount unless under the custodial account meets investment option requirements similar to the requirements of section 401(a)(39).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H4DA9F0E706CD42DF9B9933787F4767E5" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header><enum-in-header>457(b)</enum-in-header> plans</header><text>Section 457(e) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HAE808ECB0A884F9F8EA84B0533E77C1E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6423E8BF346A452D86F78087A599CDA8" commented="no"><enum>(19)</enum><header>Investment option requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an employer described in subsection (e)(1)(A), a plan shall not be treated as meeting the requirements of this section unless such plan meets investment option requirements similar to the requirements of section 401(a)(39).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HFD586B5EDFAE4C2890ED5A9B449BA184" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to plan years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

