<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9803C9A8C6BC4EB789185EB79529F9C2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7822 IH: Baby Formula Emergency Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7822</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220518">May 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000590">Mr. Green of Tennessee</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C000059">Mr. Calvert</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To allow for duty-free importation and sale of infant formula that is lawfully marketed as such in its country of origin, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC8E8B421996847CAA2E4E95B955C7DCC" style="OLC"><section id="H297054AA727F40689E46B008FB379D68" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Baby Formula Emergency Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H0E05153B5A194769AA49F0358C6C48A6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Removal of limitations on importation</header><subsection id="HDD0B0E00E16F434A984E663E6B859456" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a determination by the President that there is a shortage or potential shortage of the supply of infant formula (as defined in section 201(z) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/321">21 U.S.C. 321(z)</external-xref>)) in the United States, the President may, notwithstanding any provision of Federal law, suspend any duty imposed with respect to the importation of any article of infant formula that meets the criteria specified in subsection (b) on or before the date on which the President submits the notification described in the second sentence of subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H39B5226183D64D198F79FBD789EAF041"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for importation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any provision of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/301">21 U.S.C. 301 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other provision of Federal law, the President may allow, without restrictions, the production, manufacture, distribution, marketing, prescribing, sale, or dispensing of any infant formula during the period in which a shortage or potential shortage, as determined under subsection (a) exists, if—</text><paragraph id="HF1013D5CA96B4107BFEF3CA98A02024D"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H1F7573C458154541A291E8D6168D0B97"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the manufacturer of such infant formula certifies to the Commissioner of Food and Drugs that the infant formula meets the nutrition requirements under section 412(i) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/350a">21 U.S.C. 350a(i)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB137574E34F74C298A2260DB1CC92BD4" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the infant formula is lawfully marketed as infant formula in its country of origin;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD668D58D6714B5AA1981532C797D182"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States has not imposed sanctions with respect to the actions of the government of the country of origin of such infant formula, including a ban on the importation of some or all products of such country as a result of such actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67721E243DC44A2DA4D95A5A7C991DEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States has not imposed any sanctions with respect to the manufacturer of such infant formula (including by listing such manufacturer on the List of Specially Designated Nationals and Blocked Persons maintained by the Office of Foreign Assets Control of the Department of the Treasury); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H78E5DF7EDF4D490D80AFF6A270270368"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the Commissioner of Food and Drugs has not determined that such infant formula is unsafe.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6F43F72B4A54E27B9FD6E39A405BAE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon a determination referred to in subsection (a) with respect to a shortage or potential shortage of the supply of infant formula, the President shall notify the Committee on Energy and Commerce and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor and Pensions and the Committee on Finance of the Senate of such determination. The President shall notify such committees upon any determination that the shortage referred to in such subsection no longer exists. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

