<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5A2BF0733B61475CA6762BD507CD2578" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8209 IH: Supporting Opportunities to Build Everyday Responsibility Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8209</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220623">June 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000301">Mr. Johnson of South Dakota</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Attorney General to establish a grant program with respect to 24-7 sobriety programs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB538D24D27314569969E54D8D08D4ABC" style="OLC"><section id="H1C62E2D5BBF642F9943A36FD30670424" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Supporting Opportunities to Build Everyday Responsibility Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SOBER Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9FA9618F5B914048B7FC98EAE5264B21"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grant program with respect to 24-7 sobriety programs</header><subsection id="H16648047526F4D8EB69262B89AE4E7EC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall establish a grant program (in this Act referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>), within the Office of Justice Programs, to provide funding to 24-7 sobriety programs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF9759FF464724B9098EBB2EB85C4756F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the Program, the Attorney General may award a grant to an eligible recipient that submits an application for the Program. </text></subsection><subsection id="H1564A17E4B2C42D3A2C7F8DC6614A5E9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Eligible recipient</header><paragraph id="H6CFDEBD046C04898A6F3F1B46F963334"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Grants awarded under the Program may be awarded to a State, Tribal government, or an agency, office, or a group of such agencies or offices of the State or Tribal government for the purpose of administering an eligible project under subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51D60EE3FF2341B7AFF896FF9EAB71DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subgrant</header><text>An eligible recipient awarded a grant under the Program may distribute subgrant of funds awarded under the program to any local government office or agency, or group of offices or agencies, for the purpose of administering an eligible project under subsection (e).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB88ABA920A9B4C149A8D82B9BA83BF61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under the Program, an eligible recipient shall submit to the Attorney General an application at such time, in such manner, and containing or accompanied by such information as the Attorney General may reasonably require.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB85B592A0FD24B3B95243BB34A3B7BC6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Eligible projects</header><text>Grant funds awarded under the Program shall be used to defray administrative costs of an existing 24-7 sobriety program, or costs associated with implementing a new 24-7 sobriety program. Such costs may include—</text><paragraph id="H67D4B87D95684611BDDF12837783AC61"><enum>(1)</enum><text>hiring staff; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9653322353B41B8A64BBA4E62BBE2AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>purchasing and maintaining equipment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H736E80A058614E6AA62CC3C4C3A893D7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>data collection; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73463B77446948A4BF603903ACD22561"><enum>(4)</enum><text>helping a participant meet the financial obligations of being a participant in a 24-7 sobriety program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD10D8B8B567B40C6A51FD4AF6B8DA1EB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>other administrative costs.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8B40F0E57DB4355844B071F8022D97A"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Federal share</header><text>The Federal share of the cost of a project assisted with a grant under the Program shall not exceed 100 percent. </text></subsection><subsection id="H91A5BEF3E61A41249FC141F68E28CBF9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Report by eligible recipient</header><text>Not later than 365 days after disbursement of funds to an eligible recipient under the Program, an eligible recipient shall submit to the Attorney General a report including, for each 24-7 sobriety program funded by the eligible recipient—</text><paragraph id="H1E1CCE6AEF2D47EEA4FFFD6F314EAC3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on eligibility and participation in the 24-7 sobriety program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF861667AA68E4D498E98342C023A6646"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">data with respect to the consumption of alcohol or other controlled substances by 24-7 sobriety program participants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H951B3E6FF2EF4FE38E766F9762F0C5D5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>data reflecting any criminal charges and convictions among participants during and up to five years after such participant participated in the 24-7 sobriety program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE59E0942FC384920AED82D799C0A3F08"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data regarding programmatic outcomes, including technical violations of the 24-7 sobriety program and sanctions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H87595227043C4FC0A2B2503D8A84979E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>categorized expenses incurred for the administration of a 24-7 sobriety program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3D3F7E82C3754FFD9DA0418B4016C224"><enum>(h)</enum><header>National Institute of Justice evaluation and report to Congress</header><paragraph id="HA2858D22E1AF4C449C035CAD5180262D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, and every two years thereafter, the Director of the National Institute of Justice shall conduct an evaluation to identify policies and procedures used by eligible recipients to reduce crime, recidivism, and incarceration attributed to use of alcohol or controlled substances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD270C94333864CFBBDF27F1014612586"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress and the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration</header><text>Not later than 30 days after completion of the evaluation under paragraph (1), the Attorney General shall submit to Congress and the Administrator of the National Highway Traffic Safety Administration a report including—</text><subparagraph id="H5CA580FA78604682ADFF41BC2C186D94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the results of the evaluation conducted under paragraph (1) by the National Institute of Justice; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01B6728F1961458C8D4B8268A1D027FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information reported by each eligible recipient under subsection (g).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H13D6043661744FDBA518456D22908C2E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HF9266A31402842B3ADE36FC4932F25B6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the Program $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31E834B076BA40F0A2E5896FEE8E1BAE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New program implementation</header><subparagraph id="HC0D3DA19D3E24FD9B6440E6724CADA30"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>At least 15 percent of funds awarded under the Program, on an annual basis, shall be awarded to an eligible recipient to implement a new 24-7 sobriety program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB37E98D5104D48A2B389E41BDDB88E5E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New program</header><text>An eligible recipient awarded funds under subparagraph (A), shall be ineligible for further grants under this Program if no such 24-7 sobriety program has been implemented two years after the distribution of Program funds under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H03CF4B7010EE4B3EB845C281379A48AA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance</header><text>At least 1 percent of annual Program funds shall be awarded to an eligible recipient under the Program for training and technical assistance related to the administration of 24-7 sobriety programs. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAEABD35CF5284D869A035C4154FF4DAB"><enum>(j)</enum><header>24-7 sobriety program defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>24-7 sobriety program</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 405(d)(7)(a) of title 23, United States Code. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

