<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D1228B7B4BF4C6E9460C4A89BAB750A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7642 IH: Transportation Assistance for Olympic Cities Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7642</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220503">May 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide assistance for surface transportation projects relating to international Olympic, Paralympic, and Special Olympics events.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC55DC6C024A74F918887231EA35D94A8" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H683B8B3878CE43A89E7767D135D5BEEC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Transportation Assistance for Olympic Cities Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H98FA3BE9739C4F3E902B7935C5C701B1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Transportation assistance for Olympic, Paralympic, and Special Olympics cities</header> <subsection id="H8B7BCFD5BC7441268A5BE2CEDE974A6D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of this section is to prioritize and support State and local efforts on surface transportation issues necessary to obtain the national recognition and economic benefits of participation in the international Olympic, Paralympic, and Special Olympics movement by hosting international Olympic, Paralympic, and Special Olympics events in the United States.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H0C29FE5D32FF431091043E74349E2817"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H1EB2576D973545AFAC1F158314A4E042"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered event</header> <subparagraph id="H2699883B85C7498C8069968D5808CDC2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered event</term> means an international Olympic, Paralympic, or Special Olympics event held at a site that has been selected to hold such event. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H03E3F84167D345C9B8938BD55E42D2BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>covered event</term> does not include activities relating to preparing or submitting a bid to be selected to hold an international Olympic, Paralympic, or Special Olympics event. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H800BD485B0B440F488AB3000A3F679CE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Transportation. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H811952DD46AC4ADD94E6F66583F66F53"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority for transportation projects relating to Olympic, Paralympic, and Special Olympics events</header> 
<paragraph id="HEEA91985DFF84DABA8886338E9F56FEE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, in providing grants for surface transportation projects described in paragraph (2), the Secretary may give priority to a surface transportation project relating to a covered event.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H315C78178F9D40F994505EB95E1DD765"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants described</header><text>A grant referred to in paragraph (1) is a discretionary grant for a surface transportation project—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE59E193CC1AB4D05A28FF415165CB43B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under title 23 or 49, United States Code, beginning on the date of enactment of this Act; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4FF3A5AEA01B44D88CC7C40D8D23B898"><enum>(B)</enum><text>otherwise administered by the Secretary for surface transportation projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H44AD8B7833CA467CB680C34F446F51CF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Transportation planning activities</header><text>The Secretary shall take all reasonable efforts to provide assistance to a covered event, including—</text> <paragraph id="H94B5F89EC2FB494198B2BA72F12B77F1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by providing assistance for planning activities of States and metropolitan planning organizations under sections 134 and 135 of title 23, United States Code, for surface transportation projects relating to a covered event;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC9154D3F0A094DE28FB25DFC8CEE1E6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by developing intermodal transportation plans in coordination with States and local transportation agencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50FC6AFDA5AE4ADE8367EA6BBF31AD41"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by expediting review and comment of any required submissions to the Secretary relating to a covered event; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H049E35F0A8CD4C988A7E519DF49142C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by providing technical assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HBC440DCB4B4C452499E22949C2550990"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Transportation projects relating to Olympic, Paralympic, and Special Olympics events</header> <paragraph id="HEA2482608AC24CEA9A349C30DDD33273"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may provide assistance, including planning, capital, and operating assistance, to a State or unit of local government in carrying out surface transportation projects relating to a covered event.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H78B9B1812BDD4900A695CB7802FBD6C5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, any funding provided in accordance with this section may be used for any temporary facility, equipment, operations, and maintenance that meets the extraordinary surface transportation needs associated with hosting a covered event. </text></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HBB49E081A84348EA95C3C1408D5FC27D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding</header> <paragraph id="H88DB2D56D056424DA885B7C51E259DB1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as are necessary for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2034.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H84D9DECD79534DD0B3F07D3824EC609F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Any amounts provided to a State or unit of local government in accordance with this section shall be in addition to any Federal funds otherwise available to the State or unit of local government for the surface transportation project.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HEF4B7417DCC84FDA87DBA6BE22F82C5F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>The authority provided by this section shall terminate on September 30, 2034. </text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

