<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H0206A0D891134FE7B4979037B3527FBE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8281 IH: Military Housing Affordability Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8281</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220701">July 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001189">Mr. Austin Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001159">Ms. Strickland</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 37, United States Code, to extend the authority to temporarily adjust the basic allowance for housing in certain areas.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB48FE72DC7134D4C84C4BE652C81F54C" style="OLC"><section id="H4E5B9E9B7BF74DC88C7C14B73D459A19" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Military Housing Affordability Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2AEEA584D17144B7A11A117D00A6B7B4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H0181D0257AC84A03BDC8923C7F84B016"><enum>(1)</enum><text>In April 2022, the median price for existing home sales increased 14.8 percent from the previous year and 2021 saw year-over-year median price increases as high as 23.6 percent, according to data from the National Association of Realtors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7F16417E53E84AA197713EE083BB1114"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Military Times, in July 2021, reported, <quote>A number of service members [are] being forced to pay hundreds of dollars more in rent per month than their housing allowance covers.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA33B6F8419C0416D9DDA81E3AC89BAF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In September 2021, the Department of Defense exercised its authority to temporarily adjust basic allowance for housing rates in 56 housing markets for members of the uniformed services who incurred increased housing costs above their current basic allowance for housing rate, in order to <quote>help ease the financial burden of rising housing costs facing Service members moving to new duty stations or signing new leases</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3371953DCDB04519ADFBFED8CB0334D7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In November 2021, the Secretary of Defense approved a temporary basic allowance for housing increase for members in locations where rental prices rose at least 10 percent in 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H082007760173407CBF155724D5F7FCB8"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense’s authority to temporarily adjust basic allowance for housing rates in a military housing area, if the actual costs of adequate housing for civilians in that military housing area differs from the basic allowance for housing rate by more than 20 percent, is set to expire on September 30, 2022. </text></paragraph></section><section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HEBAEBF9158D34662A21AAEC554CD0CF6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Extension of authority to temporarily adjust basic allowance for housing in certain areas</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 403(b) of title 37, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>2022</quote> both places it appears and inserting <quote>2024</quote>.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

