<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H5E5EEB13004E4C82BD85AEB0C39068AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4685 RH: Trading Isn’t a Game Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 165</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4685</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–231]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210726">July 26, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</cosponsor> and <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 26, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Government Accountability Office to carry out a study on the impact of the gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques used by online trading platforms, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HF7EA0D2B036E42689AE384C135200F9B"><section id="HD850BCAF30824AC9BACFF765CDB45E53"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Trading Isn’t a Game Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H733709C7D90E4F5994DC967616BFC274" section-type="section-one"><enum>2.</enum><header>GAO study on the gamification of investing</header><subsection id="H392CFE08AC164624BD04BFB12F79A148"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall carry out a study on the impact of the gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques of online trading platforms, including the following:</text><paragraph id="H52966D116DE5473FAAAC27176FAEC983"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How, and to what extent gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques are being used by online platforms in ways that are detrimental to investors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0006B8740B4487EB9E5FCBF88AA0C29"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How, and to what extent gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques are being used by online platforms in ways that empower, inform, and educate investors.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5E5A5EA18BB4734A9E900E43B9F74D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The various ways brokers use gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques in marketing strategies that attempt to attract retail customers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0163DF2FD47246BD9E205C5189BBC450"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> The various ways investment advisers or <quote>robo-advisers</quote> use gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques in marketing strategies that target or include retail customers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA8B21C7BAD849BBB068F0DC056BF8DE"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The various ways in which brokers, investment advisers, or <quote>robo-advisers</quote> incorporate <quote>game-like</quote> features and designs in their online trading applications used by retail customers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H485006DCE925484D91221B51962F59E0"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether certain platform use of gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques, including <quote>game-like</quote> features, may constitute investment advice or recommendations under Federal securities laws and regulations, including Regulation Best Interest (17 C.F.R. 240.15l-1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DD180E8BF474EFCAC4E850D4A1A3246"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A comparison between the investment activity, habits, and risk tolerance, including a comparison between the stated preference of retail investors and their actual trading activity, of—</text><subparagraph id="H6C6BD0CCFD7B44499B8A306E09386473"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retail customers of firms that use gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques in marketing, or that incorporate <quote>game-like</quote> features and designs in their online trading applications; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3BB8293BF16B466FB11FFE97D697E8F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">retail customers of firms that do not use, or have limited use of, gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques in marketing and that do not incorporate <quote>game-like</quote> features and designs in their online trading applications.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD0D7C2DC2DC4B9FA4CB4F064D1BDD1C"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">How, and how prominently, brokers, investment advisers or <quote>robo-advisers</quote> that use gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques in marketing strategies that target or include retail investors, or that incorporate <quote>game-like</quote> features and designs in their online trading applications, are disclosing the risks associated with leverage, complex products, or excessive or frequent trading.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9384F7B6F63F4D8892800170E8BC87F1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The various customer demographic categories (including age, net worth, and investment experience) of brokers or investment advisers, or <quote>robo-advisers</quote> that use gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques in marketing strategies that target or include retail investors, or that incorporate <quote>game-like</quote> features and designs in their online trading applications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03F16FDA797940629E290B467812D06E"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The relationship between (and any correlation between) zero commission trading and gamification or investor susceptibility to <quote>game-like</quote> features.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E77C78959D64C8E906532E63E11606F"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The degree to which the types of retail trading activity that is incentivized by gamification (including the specific asset classes promoted via gamification) benefits, harms, or otherwise affects other market participants, and an analysis thereof.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71515B7F5C4746D89F31A09E1D7A3E13"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The degree to which Securities and Exchange Commission’s Form BD and Form ADV can be revised to help the Commission better identify which registered firms use gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE582F2C69054CC9BF118C4861FF6F09"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Whether gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques have created investment activity or interest in the capital markets by women and minority groups.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C3D16CD3D684DB2AEFFC304EFA254B4"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether gamification, psychological nudges, and other design techniques have targeted women and minority groups or created particular risks for them.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6D2202A3D004F0BBF86F9FF7A6ADBEE"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any data or legal challenges (e.g., so-called proprietary practices) that the Comptroller General encounters in preparing the report.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B45C7979CF54180BE8CE921C840E38D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Investor testing authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Investor Advocate of the Securities and Exchange Commission is authorized to carry out investor testing as part of the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEF447BA0232244888BB581C0B331D5ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>GAO report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the end of the 270-day period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall issue a report to the Securities and Exchange Commission, the Investor Advocate of the Commission, and the Congress containing all findings and recommendations made in carrying out the study required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="HD903EB460CF34F6AB1CAA89640C11DE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the study required under subsection (a), the Comptroller General shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="HA92BBBFDB86B47859B0AF7DAF05A64A8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Securities and Exchange Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DD67E52B60B428794829AE3025588FC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Investor Advocate of the Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A3B36228A0F4ABE9B057C42566AEFC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Director of the Office of Investor Education and Advocacy of the Commission;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD4CD005E694FB4B584864F744C5C44"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the North American Securities Administrators Association;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD04CCFA2383F4728B1C86D4FEB173F7E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the Financial Industry Regulatory Authority;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC24EBDB3AFBF49DF9F1961706B8AF751"><enum>(6)</enum><text>academics, including gamification and behavioral psychology experts; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC90167AA8FDB499D97D57E7875B2CC46"><enum>(7)</enum><text>investor advocacy organizations and experts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7A641FBDFEB420B8884AD82F7E7C978"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report and recommendations of the Investor Advocate</header><text>Not later than the end of the 90-day period beginning on the date that the Investor Advocate of the Commission receives the report issued under subsection (c), the Investor Advocate shall—</text><paragraph id="H34C152D9F998443380FE987533760D5E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>review the report; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD69E33CB4E924CBFB4B5EE63F1153F6C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>issue a report to the Congress containing any regulatory (including rules and policies of Financial Industry Regulatory Authority and the Municipal Securities Rulemaking Board) or legislative recommendations the Investor Advocate may have.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0FB42DD335224AD2AD1FD2867C4CEA05"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Gamification defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>gamification</quote> means tactics or strategies used to engage customers and incentivize or nudge them to transact and spend time on an investment platform, including increased use of notifications, prizes, use of ladders and leader boards, psychological tools, and design elements to incentivize customers to spend more time on an investment platform, to increase rapid trading, and to increase the number of trades.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

