<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEE00BBD19ADB4BF0A4B3D4132D37007C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7268 IH: Downeast Maine National Heritage Area Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7268</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220329">March 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Downeast Maine National Heritage Area in the State of Maine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9D139A4AA05D4CC2989CAAB30DE53237" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H529A205672914B98957ECF440F4F01F7"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Downeast Maine National Heritage Area Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF45DD9BB31A6460BBF63F17E7A4CE988"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="HFA62F6293EDF4110AC4CED08AD7E9872"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the area in Maine known as <quote>Downeast Maine</quote> embodies a nationally important story of the longstanding human dependence on natural resources to survive and thrive;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF6B6B4B3C5C49C382FC7CE58A4CC777"><enum>(2)</enum><text>dramatic changes have occurred on many levels over the last several centuries in Downeast Maine, but even after 10,000 years—</text><subparagraph id="HDBFBDB0BE01C4679A369E7C28D1C14F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the economy and well-being of Downeast Maine depends on the same natural resources that have existed for centuries; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3266E37192C144A5B991E212D8DDF5A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the culture of Downeast Maine continues to be shaped by those resources;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC6BE12ECD834AEF9229F1C555DC4F34"><enum>(3)</enum><text>dependence on the natural resources in Downeast Maine for economic, community, and environmental health has led to habitat conservation and species restoration initiatives that allow natural systems and cultural associations to remain intact in Downeast Maine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA39A028A5D1F4013977EC5A4F1356D16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>coastal fisheries, forest products, agriculture, wild blueberries, subsistence harvests, outdoor recreation, tourism, and habitat conservation are the heart of the culture and economy of Downeast Maine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H804A5F42B7FF41C5848AB6E40B0D5EC0"><enum>(5)</enum><text>traditions of trade and culture from the past can be experienced firsthand in Downeast Maine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5CF37E912654C5A910B1F6D8FA696AC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the Downeast Maine way of life is visible—</text><subparagraph id="HB97B153BA76746079476F004D600168D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in historic districts, working waterfronts, and community festivals in Downeast Maine; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58F3C6A809334F469A9D16F3ECE8E887"><enum>(B)</enum><text>at the 51 historical societies and museums located in Downeast Maine;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D2B194C9D2442519253F95F8D2C725F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Passamaquoddy language and arts and traditions from the fishing, logging, maritime, and wild blueberry industries are preserved in audio and photographic collections in Downeast Maine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF2FE77865EB415AB114EE03BD0B5CC2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>markets and galleries in Downeast Maine showcase arts, foods, and utilitarian products created with the natural resources of the area that can be purchased directly from the producer;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DB5D3426FC44D5BA5F28B2086E5BFE6"><enum>(9)</enum><text>community festivals in Downeast Maine celebrate the nature-based culture of Downeast Maine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64620A84DC614A5EA4AD97F8729852B9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>lighthouses and watercraft dominate the coastal scenery in Downeast Maine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBA12A08F4AF41388554019A02B3893B"><enum>(11)</enum><text>the scenic byways and network of land and water trails in Downeast Maine provide a physical experience of unique geologic features, waterways, wildlife, and working landscapes, such as wild blueberry fields and forests. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H774BB95B553E405596CCB2F2323395B8"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HD6AE9B458E01402B9EEF959E5AAD6803"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Heritage area</header><text>The term <term>Heritage Area</term> means the Downeast Maine National Heritage Area established by section 4(a). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BB84EA202D94DA6B7912AECD9BA86BC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text>The term <quote>local coordinating entity</quote> means the local coordinating entity for the Heritage Area designated by section 5(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H357934C065FA46288CA203039406D7DB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Management plan</header><text>The term <term>management plan</term> means the plan developed by the local coordinating entity under section 6(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB7A315935FC48078578CCB28980E39E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90EB1F7915344BA5AEFC5E398881E466"><enum>(5)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means the State of Maine.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1E7AB64AA0F240D980F3BE8AEEB2B55F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Downeast Maine National Heritage Area</header><subsection id="H5CC101B33E6A4715949CE0DDE275373E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the Downeast Maine National Heritage Area in the State.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE407A3D4D7064F09AD2F8E8A50905164"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><text>The Heritage Area shall consist of Hancock and Washington Counties in the State.</text></subsection></section><section id="H970FF0D62FEC474CAFA097A5A344658E"><enum>5.</enum><header>Designation of local coordinating entity</header><subsection id="HF3BD8E0B0A884AE9B6E8A9D511010A77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Local coordinating entity</header><text>The Sunrise County Economic Council shall be the local coordinating entity for the Heritage Area. </text></subsection><subsection id="HFDC09E96AB754099BF72B68FAE2F8B22"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorities of local coordinating entity</header><text>The local coordinating entity may, for purposes of preparing and implementing the management plan, use Federal funds made available under this Act—</text><paragraph id="H25B5D3CDE36E4FED866057E879ED7F5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prepare reports, studies, interpretive exhibits and programs, historic preservation projects, and other activities recommended in the management plan for the Heritage Area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8B5E3E27718423AA1C6D3812681FC35"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to make grants to the State, political subdivisions of the State, nonprofit organizations, and other persons;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB933C7C683F041AAB1D6FF697BBDB17B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to enter into cooperative agreements with the State, political subdivisions of the State, nonprofit organizations, and other organizations;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0B4081B804436E997757F3BEB3508E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to hire and compensate staff;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA821B1449214449ABDFA880B2DCFD454"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to obtain funds or services from any source, including funds and services provided under any other Federal program or law; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H58EB5E60D5C04655A13F745D32A832A7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to contract for goods and services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB67846A5A5241D188BDDF55D2B79E9A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties of local coordinating entity</header><text>To further the purposes of the Heritage Area, the local coordinating entity shall—</text><paragraph id="H0F5FACB54FCE4A7E9D4B4182AB35109A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>prepare a management plan for the Heritage Area in accordance with section 6;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79A9CD49690143748D815CAD9DB40B0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>give priority to the implementation of actions, goals, and strategies set forth in the management plan, including assisting units of government and other persons in—</text><subparagraph id="H8ED1476A3A1941DB9BF3A86B1690EC39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carrying out programs and projects that recognize and protect important resource values in the Heritage Area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C4384352A954589BE19294FB135AAC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encouraging economic viability in the Heritage Area in accordance with the goals of the management plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47BF6203131A45FABB477BA377065228"><enum>(C)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining interpretive exhibits in the Heritage Area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C7D5E52872403C8AC35633EB080411"><enum>(D)</enum><text>developing heritage-based recreational and educational opportunities for residents and visitors in the Heritage Area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE696130D35F2426293A49012E867B25B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>increasing public awareness of and appreciation for the natural, historic, and cultural resources of the Heritage Area;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE73F87D9C2C04936826A387EABCCF790"><enum>(F)</enum><text>restoring historic buildings that are—</text><clause id="H399B72FE79F34E3B919AC66AADEA24C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>located in the Heritage Area; and</text></clause><clause id="H4E35266D6EDD4062B3A22AD8BF6B23E9"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>related to the themes of the Heritage Area; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE385C7C4F827490CA0AE23A2CBE36C92"><enum>(G)</enum><text>installing throughout the Heritage Area clear, consistent, and appropriate signs identifying public access points and sites of interest;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AB84F3C3FFA44C1911EAF40827376C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>consider the interests of diverse units of government, businesses, tourism officials, private property owners, and nonprofit groups within the Heritage Area in developing and implementing the management plan;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H40B8AE1E248B432E8673BDBC3EB6039E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>conduct public meetings at least semiannually regarding the development and implementation of the management plan; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0CB0B04AC774EA3909007352891552D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>for any fiscal year for which Federal funds are received under this Act—</text><subparagraph id="H6F82EEFECB8046EE840B873959FF8F6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>submit to the Secretary an annual report that describes—</text><clause id="H907F688631E54679A5997B373BF36E6A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the accomplishments of the local coordinating entity;</text></clause><clause id="HA4573EF5685242C18C01B9C0B1DEE6CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expenses and income of the local coordinating entity; and</text></clause><clause id="H1DA7D4179A5F407E83445A9AE9C3D0CA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the entities to which the local coordinating entity made any grants;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3081C30C6DCA40D5868F910ADD6B4C96"><enum>(B)</enum><text>make available for audit all records relating to the expenditure of the Federal funds and any matching funds; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84141C75B21849B98EF85FFAA5EDD9D9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>require, with respect to all agreements authorizing the expenditure of Federal funds by other organizations, that the receiving organizations make available for audit all records relating to the expenditure of the Federal funds.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB3522DBBB6C840068E9CCBEE551467F7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Management plan</header><subsection id="HA831069DFE9141F28DA8DFDC9F9D2E45"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to carry out this Act, the local coordinating entity shall prepare and submit to the Secretary a management plan for the Heritage Area.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD75675A2449D4335BCB27356E63D3748"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The management plan for the Heritage Area shall—</text><paragraph id="H8E1DD1379997432D86E6E2F41543B3B3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include comprehensive policies, strategies, and recommendations for the conservation, funding, management, and development of the Heritage Area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C14C60517A84755A6F2B1EFAB78EDB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take into consideration existing State and local plans;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE55FA76C21234CEE83E0FD11043B5047"><enum>(3)</enum><text>specify the existing and potential sources of funding to protect, manage, and develop the Heritage Area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H453F0EDCFF7E4FF4AA4D9F7A1B92E3F8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>include an inventory of the natural, historic, cultural, educational, scenic, and recreational resources of the Heritage Area relating to the themes of the Heritage Area that should be preserved, restored, managed, developed, or maintained; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA758789EA44430C8F3CEA19F2F32DD4"><enum>(5)</enum><text>include an analysis of, and recommendations for, ways in which Federal, State, and local programs, may best be coordinated to further the purposes of this Act, including recommendations for the role of the National Park Service in the Heritage Area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF74510827A13425B9AECFA1882060B59"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disqualification from funding</header><text>If a proposed management plan is not submitted to the Secretary by the date that is 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to carry out this Act, the local coordinating entity may not receive additional funding under this Act until the date on which the Secretary receives the proposed management plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA6D934C307C241768E8608031F307D0D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Approval and disapproval of management plan</header><paragraph id="H7E862A7C35584FCDBEB87C68A82F23C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date on which the local coordinating entity submits the management plan to the Secretary, the Secretary shall approve or disapprove the proposed management plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2136F5F0846749E28B870952DA3C29BD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In determining whether to approve or disapprove the management plan, the Secretary shall consider whether—</text><subparagraph id="H29AD739A0A7A4E9F8C8E4D7A49E4518D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the local coordinating entity is representative of the diverse interests of the Heritage Area, including governments, natural and historic resource protection organizations, educational institutions, businesses, and recreational organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE73997401FAA4787904DF763F8673F20"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the local coordinating entity has provided adequate opportunities (including public meetings) for public and governmental involvement in the preparation of the management plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A3F9D59CCBB4CEE8558C76C8B0B5BA8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the resource protection and interpretation strategies contained in the management plan, if implemented, would adequately protect the natural, historic, and cultural resources of the Heritage Area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51497433439C4D06902C922E48E1742A"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the management plan is supported by the appropriate State and local officials, the cooperation of which is needed to ensure the effective implementation of the State and local aspects of the management plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7683ABA9B67497284B454608E38ED5F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disapproval and revisions</header><subparagraph id="H7758A3A44A8448A792C53C50A8F76021"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Secretary disapproves a proposed management plan, the Secretary shall—</text><clause id="H138774ACEEB64463AE662A84A80D86C8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>advise the local coordinating entity, in writing, of the reasons for the disapproval; and</text></clause><clause id="HBA72C395D9074E05B8C47C9054827D2B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>make recommendations for revision of the proposed management plan.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0878EBFD9ED41C6908C46E30D58C8E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Approval or disapproval</header><text>The Secretary shall approve or disapprove a revised management plan not later than 180 days after the date on which the revised management plan is submitted.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H124453445441414F836658123BB2E9B6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Approval of amendments</header><paragraph id="HE4BD9DF0A50F47DCA0DF25D5C69DF692"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall review and approve or disapprove substantial amendments to the management plan in accordance with subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88C1F4D5089F4E1183BBB245B6751783"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>Funds appropriated under this Act may not be expended to implement any changes made by an amendment to the management plan until the Secretary approves the amendment.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4B193404FCF14BBAA148D046C2B64CD0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Relationship to other Federal agencies</header><subsection id="H4F1A987AEEBB406999E6C6C4E5BDE1CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Nothing in this Act affects the authority of a Federal agency to provide technical or financial assistance under any other law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7A50249216E745C1BED65F8E144C8B99"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>The head of any Federal agency planning to conduct activities that may have an impact on the Heritage Area is encouraged to consult and coordinate the activities with the Secretary and the local coordinating entity to the extent practicable.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCDE772DCFF224E839EC62B209DF464C1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other Federal agencies</header><text>Nothing in this Act—</text><paragraph id="HD94B89A8B278468186330FA92783686B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any law or regulation authorizing a Federal agency to manage Federal land under the jurisdiction of the Federal agency;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0704BEE7438242A3A562A0C1FB3ADB2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limits the discretion of a Federal land manager to implement an approved land use plan within the boundaries of the Heritage Area; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA40A187406204B95AA791BA49788888A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>modifies, alters, or amends any authorized use of Federal land under the jurisdiction of a Federal agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H83DB70CDD9914B9F97570197BFCE89B9"><enum>8.</enum><header>Private property and regulatory protections</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act—</text><paragraph id="H978D91D17E984ED881810E72CB09BDEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>abridges the rights of any property owner (whether public or private), including the right to refrain from participating in any plan, project, program, or activity conducted within the Heritage Area;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE72895F4209B4367A40EE6EBBA4BA096"><enum>(2)</enum><text>requires any property owner to permit public access (including access by Federal, State, or local agencies) to the property of the property owner, or to modify public access or use of property of the property owner under any other Federal, State, or local law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED339D0A8E95452093CAAAEBC85BA796"><enum>(3)</enum><text>alters any duly adopted land use regulation, approved land use plan, or other regulatory authority of any Federal, State, or local agency, or conveys any land use or other regulatory authority to the local coordinating entity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H815198BF7E8043B58FD81B4623773B24"><enum>(4)</enum><text>authorizes or implies the reservation or appropriation of water or water rights;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H920AA70F2FDB47D6B2D968DD07A15433"><enum>(5)</enum><text>diminishes the authority of the State to manage fish and wildlife, including the regulation of fishing and hunting within the Heritage Area; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5266DF22B9B24653B91A9FA5386952BC"><enum>(6)</enum><text>creates any liability, or affects any liability under any other law, of any private property owner with respect to any person injured on the private property.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3A6A7A64CF064C9DAD2A16730253ED13"><enum>9.</enum><header>Evaluation; report</header><subsection id="H73CEE314870F450CA930AEE5E1E360F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In General</header><text>Not later than 3 years before the date on which authority for Federal funding terminates for the Heritage Area, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HF5C70B39AA2E45D689C18E6413D31C01"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct an evaluation of the accomplishments of the Heritage Area; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7246DAD9C6B64F7CAB3B4BABD0566FB8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prepare a report in accordance with subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE1BBF33AB9147DE8401D86F683B3189"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>An evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1) shall—</text><paragraph id="H01A3B24A6BC0451BB52ECDC190724EF2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>assess the progress of the local coordinating entity with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="HEEA131200B95427CA07D53312D28D6FF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accomplishing the purposes of this Act for the Heritage Area; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7DC8B9E8A924AEC9BE95189D1A9FF11"><enum>(B)</enum><text>achieving the goals and objectives of the approved management plan for the Heritage Area;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD3D9109EC6944DB8BAC02654599AFFF9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyze the Federal, State, local, and private investments in the Heritage Area to determine the leverage and impact of the investments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H716F2AAA845B4B59810767648F3A28D0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review the management structure, partnership relationships, and funding of the Heritage Area for purposes of identifying the critical components for sustainability of the Heritage Area.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A347CF27465434684078646E7F33FF7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="H492B5E76808A4E568E65057D7DB739E0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Based on the evaluation conducted under subsection (a)(1), the Secretary shall prepare a report that includes recommendations for the future role of the National Park Service, if any, with respect to the Heritage Area.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC15848C455B4652AA3B18C2D0F29211"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Required analysis</header><text>If the report prepared under paragraph (1) recommends that Federal funding for the Heritage Area be reauthorized, the report shall include an analysis of—</text><subparagraph id="H82258EDBC15444FE8E20455AF00B4BAE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ways in which Federal funding for the Heritage Area may be reduced or eliminated; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3421BDB0D34B4A6B8EC4242D1EB15854"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the appropriate time period necessary to achieve the recommended reduction or elimination.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EA3FAD526184FF8AAC234FA33A77E37"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Submission to congress</header><text>On completion of the report, the Secretary shall submit the report to—</text><subparagraph id="H1C258B9B09CF431F92BE0571E5B084DF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7889F44B430482C954BCC9E7AE5E4A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF4A35268548B4091A5C19FBCCC854F00"><enum>10.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="H29D7FBFDBA384FA1811B6CB555B850BE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this Act $10,000,000, of which not more than $1,000,000 may be authorized to be appropriated for any fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF29784D1421B49B894B89C6EF0D63A3A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts made available under subsection (a) shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD27CA64700044CCDBB2D2DC9FBF79A20"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Cost-Sharing requirement</header><paragraph id="H8D8536A37E7840E0A9867C652DCFDFF7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out using funds made available under this Act shall be not more than 50 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96A10AAFE40149328144F08DA65EE7B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The non-Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out using funds made available under this Act may be in the form of in-kind contributions of goods or services fairly valued, cash, or a combination thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section" id="H8E8B3E49C1FD46BB928C1C0A949130B8"><enum>11.</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority of the Secretary to provide financial assistance under this Act terminates on the date that is 15 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

