<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7871D7F282AC43958632C64EE54D89AB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6702 IH: Safeguarding Women’s and Children’s Health Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6702</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220209">February 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000813">Mrs. Walorski</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000564">Mr. Lamborn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001114">Mr. Curtis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000446">Mr. Feenstra</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000302">Mr. Joyce of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. C. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000470">Mrs. Fischbach</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000569">Mr. Luetkemeyer</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require more accurate reporting of abortion drug prescribing and related adverse events, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5582535A9636464496AEB82176180409" style="OLC"><section id="HF469FE7712564797A8EB975686BD6422" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Safeguarding Women’s and Children’s Health Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4AFE234BFF5A4ED9A6D2DB865D31E688"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H5E2233D5A1914B93B3B39B4424B3D5DD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Many data limitations affect the accuracy of statistics related to chemical abortions in the United States, and there is no central database tracking this information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6542AC6E1B242EF944A85FB2839CE62"><enum>(2)</enum><text>States may voluntarily choose to share abortion data with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), but the Guttmacher Institute, which directly surveys abortion providers, consistently documents 30 to 40 percent more abortions than the CDC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFB8BFA200B146048CC0D7227138B02A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Some States with high volumes of abortion, such as California, do not report to the CDC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEECFADF2C894C87963B10449561B196"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Only 28 States require abortion providers to report complications, but there is rarely an enforced penalty for noncompliance. Only 12 States require other physicians, coroners, or emergency rooms to report complications or deaths for investigation, and frequently these facilities and physicians are unaware of these reporting requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A90E31A4EEA4C41BDD595AFC65D9EC1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>These data problems are a significant limitation to United States studies on abortion complications.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H590BDF3881AA496782F173EE4C30BAD1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Women experiencing complications will often present to an emergency room rather than return to the abortion provider, and researchers frequently ignore the difficulty in obtaining accurate International Classification of Diseases coding in emergency rooms due to search engine failure to discover induced abortion codes, which leads to miscoding and frequently attributing induced abortion complications to spontaneous abortions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE850EA380CE94FA5B7DCB85144C24C0F"><enum>(7)</enum><text>When compared to surgical abortions, chemical abortions are over 50 percent more likely to result in an abortion-related visit to an emergency room, and by 2015, 60 percent of chemical abortion-related emergency room visits were incorrectly coded as miscarriages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H56478F2B5F734435BC0CE5054485C3D9"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Better quality, international records-linkages studies, and meta-analyses document far higher rates of complications and mortality from abortion, casting doubt on the validity of the reported data by which United States public health decisions are made.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE41F0692F42442E78B0976CB19A3D7AF"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Independent systematic analysis of adverse event reports submitted to the Food and Drug Administration (FDA) between 2000 and 2019 revealed approximately 3,000 United States adverse events out of an expected 185,000 adverse events based on the known and published complication rate after mifepristone misoprostol abortions. Thus, the Adverse Event Reporting System of the FDA captured only 1.7 percent of the actual adverse events occurring in United States women, the majority of which occurred prior to 2016 when mifepristone prescribers were required to report adverse events as part of the risk evaluation and mitigation strategy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6179BF0398B14027B5AE27B42377CFC7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In 2016, the FDA relaxed the gestational age dispensing from a limitation of 7 weeks gestation to a limitation of 10 weeks gestation, and at the same time the FDA no longer required mifepristone prescribers to report adverse events other than death. These simultaneous changes ensured that there would be no way to capture the increased adverse events resulting from the relaxation of the gestational age requirements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F7914CB0738436E9910144DC3EBD445"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In order to fulfil the statutory requirement of the FDA to oversee and evaluate the safety of mifepristone use as an abortifacient, substantial changes in the adverse event reporting for mifepristone must be implemented to obtain an accurate evaluation of the impact of mifepristone-related adverse events on United States women.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0B5A6D0994ED43759682146606C49856"><enum>3.</enum><header>Accurate reporting on chemical abortion and related adverse events</header><subsection id="HE67B1CE277CE4857A14822567772F737"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall require any abortion drug, including any abortion drug approved by the Food and Drug Administration before the date of enactment of this Act, to have a risk evaluation and mitigation strategy requiring that—</text><paragraph id="H38935E8E6E084F4F980E0EFEEC6C4917"><enum>(1)</enum><text>within 15 days of becoming aware of any death or other adverse event in a patient associated with the use of such abortion drug, a health care provider shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2E6ED65903D644DBA006B3D5744B7CF8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>report such death or adverse event to the Food and Drug Administration and to the manufacturer of such abortion drug; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H23E347A2963240D7B41001F5BED49E9E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify in such reporting the patient by a nonidentifiable reference and the serial number from each package of such abortion drug if available; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H327BE80F8F70485F83C986F1D44BA353"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a health care practitioner who prescribes, dispenses, or administers such abortion drug shall—</text><subparagraph id="HCF274E3264BF4AA1934EFD5B3221993C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>within 15 days of such prescribing, dispensing, or administering, report the action to the Food and Drug Administration and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDE28B7399DC4D3EAB2E0F72997D8895"><enum>(B)</enum><text>exclude from such reporting any individually identifiable patient information.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9767565537A14DF98225C44E80E3CF09"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Portals</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall—</text><paragraph id="H10863AA4C9BF4F8FA56BA1A3F6B2CCDD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish and maintain an online portal that allows health care practitioners to easily, confidentially, and securely report to the Food and Drug Administration and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention by means of online transmission the information required by subsection (a) to be reported; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1431CE73405D43FB8AB8A6F2A759FC4E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish and maintain an online portal that allows patients to easily, confidentially, and securely self-report to the Food and Drug Administration and the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention by means of online transmission any adverse events the patients have experienced that are associated with use of an abortion drug.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB70A739960624298BD03EFEF5083E4E4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2333CFA6F7614B178A5B6AE769CD4C7F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>abortion drug</term> means any drug, substance, or combination of drugs or substances that is intended for use or that is in fact used (irrespective of how the product is labeled)—</text><subparagraph id="H828BF590B94B457A901CAD0BE11636E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE98E0DAB14AE4D23A8CDAF6E1902D9BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text><clause id="HA3637D6EEC6743A48B325E4D2742159C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to produce a live birth;</text></clause><clause id="HA2EE1315EAEC43AFA177EE26412F1724"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child; or</text></clause><clause id="HF92B379D2BC44CFB884A2ED36C4C5F29"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to treat an ectopic or molar pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF6B69DFFBF7647D3BBE59F66F42B93B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>adverse event</term> means any untoward medical occurrence associated with the use of a drug in humans, whether or not considered drug-related.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H792C1211B69343DE869B706C5FD9396A"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unborn child</term> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in section 8(b) of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6A4C521472344E89B742B6B80AE06416"><enum>4.</enum><header>Improved reporting of data related to chemical abortions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act is amended by inserting after section 317U of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247b-23">42 U.S.C. 247b–23</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H419090FB8B2F4638A461AAEA2131F401" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H14013D47165843F487E1A50E1B22A73C"><enum>317V.</enum><header>Improved reporting of data related to chemical abortions</header><subsection id="HF6439465BCB54449B2D6AD72B27D61B2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, shall—</text><paragraph id="H3CFF318E9EB04E379212FCBF7D00646C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>collect and aggregate in a standardized format information that is reported pursuant to section 3 of the <short-title>Safeguarding Women’s and Children’s Health Act of 2022</short-title> with respect to abortion drugs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8D351B06A5E4DE7BA6BFB9527E8B555"><enum>(2)</enum><text>make such information available in accordance with section 552 of title 5, United States Code; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA9D1EE20C4842F88CE402336B6941D3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>annually publish—</text><subparagraph id="H72857FEE5421479EB487379C9C6DC3E2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of abortion drugs prescribed in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE97667FCDBCB4A868F4DBAA19A847609"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of abortion drugs that are shipped directly to prescribers and to patients;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H523A0AFC55FD4E0D8E676A2DCFCA51EC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the total number of deaths that occurred within 120 days of ingestion of an abortion drug, regardless of causal attribution, and the cause of death;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6F5DD90409C44060A066A19867908BC2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of serious adverse events that occurred within 120 days of ingestion of an abortion drug;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CCF6E453D3647DA83ED61553B418508"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of times each such serious adverse event occurred;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1EF68E4F2DA04C81B1D023A3F44467F1"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of all adverse events that occurred within 120 days of ingestion of an abortion drug, stratified by the Common Terminology for Coding Adverse Events (or any successor publication) criteria for severity grading; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7120587D85A846298F69ECE649BAD7B2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the number of times abortion drug ingestion resulted in an incomplete abortion.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF99B9CD93197449FBC7DD86B80E4B043"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>The Secretary shall provide technical assistance to facilitate and improve the reporting of data for purposes of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBBEDBED956574C108106F11C8709018D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual reporting</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H668ED95422C844D5AE570A5EB363D0AB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>annually publish a report on the data collected and aggregated pursuant to subsection (a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H590321A9E07540B59C6D746B70669C1D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>post such report on the public website of the Food and Drug Administration.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H84A608CD9B694065993BAF9E715C5AB0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HCA5413C461E9413B89DE9AC9C93F8446"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>abortion drug</term> means any drug, substance, or combination of drugs or substances that is intended for use or that is in fact used (irrespective of how the product is labeled)—</text><subparagraph id="H4BA3144FF06B4F92997D3E9A964CBCA3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to intentionally kill the unborn child of a woman known to be pregnant; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA11F1175E0A340B1A2692E76CEDA43BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to intentionally terminate the pregnancy of a woman known to be pregnant, with an intention other than—</text><clause id="HC3A12868792B443B926CC9F73AA32DEE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to produce a live birth;</text></clause><clause id="H967C5FD74A87476A80510F7870E3AB37"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to remove a dead unborn child; or</text></clause><clause id="H7C644E5CC6D24716ABFED98881E454C8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>to treat an ectopic or molar pregnancy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5BFDF8D1AA44C69BF5BB91551E465EF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>adverse event</term> means any untoward medical occurrence associated with the use of a drug in humans, whether or not considered drug-related.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H397ADF8542DB43C59E39472B9E693F6D"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>serious adverse event</term> means an adverse event that meets Common Terminology for Coding Adverse Events criteria (or any successor publication) for level 3 or above.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H126D36C3E55249B7825A03E97593B331"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The term <term>unborn child</term> means an individual organism of the species homo sapiens, beginning at fertilization, until the point of being born alive as defined in section 8(b) of title 1, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

