<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HE8D0EF4EAFFF45019BEEB37AED8C106C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4042 RH: Aviation Funding Stability Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 484</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4042</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–665, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210622">June 22, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221223">December 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000593">Mr. Perlmutter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000559">Mr. Langevin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000190">Mr. Norman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000593">Mr. Levin of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000602">Miss Rice of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000468">Mrs. Fletcher</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000576">Mr. Ruppersberger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001305">Mr. Budd</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001185">Mr. Sean Patrick Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001056">Ms. Herrera Beutler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000376">Mr. Allred</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001052">Mr. Harris</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000454">Mr. Foster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000591">Mrs. Luria</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000392">Mr. Kustoff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000469">Mr. Fulcher</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221223">December 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221223">December 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for funding from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for all Federal Aviation Administration activities for a certain period in the event of a Government shutdown, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H7861A44F59474AD6BADDBCDB4E93AC39" style="OLC"><section id="H2752FF1A419B428CB034B6D335DF354A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Aviation Funding Stability Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H14244D05EB6F4B24A759B7A76F6FB781" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Funding for the Federal Aviation Administration in the event of a lapse in appropriation</header><subsection id="HA727DE02490F49C6ABDE4CCF1E0C791F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, with respect to the Federal Aviation Administration, an appropriation measure for a fiscal year is not enacted before the beginning of such fiscal year or a joint resolution making continuing appropriations is not in effect, amounts in the Airport and Airway Trust Fund not otherwise appropriated shall be available to the Administrator for continuing programs, projects, or activities (including the costs of direct loans and loan guarantees) that were conducted with amounts made available for the Federal Aviation Administration, including for the accounts <quote>Federal Aviation Administration—Operations</quote>, <quote>Federal Aviation Administration—Facilities and Equipment</quote>, <quote>Federal Aviation Administration—Research, Engineering, and Development</quote>, and <quote>Federal Aviation Administration—Grants-in-Aid for Airports</quote> in the preceding fiscal year—</text><paragraph id="H236CF5B004C245F1A6F7E217EB594B14"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the corresponding appropriation Act for such preceding fiscal year; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB54F32E5BB64EAEAA632EFA18963C9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the corresponding appropriation bill for such preceding fiscal year did not become law, then in a joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H624E5092F90B4DF68F9CF145858F01F5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rate for operations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available, and authority granted, for a program, project, or activity for any fiscal year pursuant to this section shall be at a rate for operations not greater than—</text><paragraph id="H70E1DCD862C1445CA93EA4242652FA97"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the rate for operations provided for in the regular appropriation Act providing for such program, project, or activity for the preceding fiscal year; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED7787DFA82C4517A47DE2C176789426"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the absence of such an Act, the rate for operations provided for such program, project, or activity pursuant to a joint resolution making continuing appropriations for such preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB1F7CBDA00848DAA54BBD3769B2593F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Appropriations and funds made available, and authority granted, for any fiscal year pursuant to this section for a program, project, or activity shall be available for the period beginning with the first day of a lapse in appropriations and ending with the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HD155AB890E59478BAE656D29BDC85233"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which—</text><subparagraph id="H6E73F11C6FD6450F8D9184AAB0A0A3EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the applicable regular appropriation bill for such fiscal year becomes law (whether or not such law provides for such program, project, or activity); or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE0AD748E6CBD48619DA1D40BBE92381D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a joint resolution making continuing appropriations becomes law; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1142F7BEA114390A8710D7A5DFB8E32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date that is 30 days after the first day of a lapse in appropriations. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA2FF076F9CF845DDAE235D656CF36C92"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An appropriation or funds made available, or authority granted, for a program, project, or activity for any fiscal year pursuant to this section shall be subject to the terms and conditions imposed with respect to the appropriation made or funds made available for the preceding fiscal year, or authority granted for such program, project, or activity under applicable law on the first day of the applicable lapse in appropriations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H695BA5A798CE4E6189CB697668A9122B"><enum>(e)</enum><header>End of fiscal year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If this section is in effect at the end of a fiscal year, funding levels shall continue as provided in this section for the next fiscal year.</text></subsection><subsection id="H87896D87BADB46BD883B3A2A1BEFAFB3"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Expenditures and obligations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Expenditures and obligations made for a program, project, or activity for any fiscal year pursuant to this section shall be charged to the applicable appropriation, fund, or authorization whenever a regular appropriation bill or a joint resolution making continuing appropriations until the end of a fiscal year providing for such program, project, or activity for such period becomes law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7B4F736471A9470492CDC82DFB6098C5"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Expenditure authority</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9502">Section 9502(d)(1)(A)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting <quote>or the Aviation Funding Stability Act of 2021;</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H40B22897A6534E9398F9F20736822F22"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section shall not apply to a program, project, or activity during any portion of a fiscal year if any other provision of law (other than an authorization of appropriations)—</text><paragraph id="H0A3758A274244F4FA4623116B4AB4E6B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">makes an appropriation, makes funds available, or grants authority for such program, project, or activity to continue for such period; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F625E04BABA43F19C74F7174CAD44C1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">specifically provides that no appropriation shall be made, no funds shall be made available, or no authority shall be granted for such program, project, or activity to continue for such period.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20221223">December 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc><action-date date="20221223">December 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

