<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H8C127841814146D6B4D3CFB88BBD7885" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9709 IH: Protecting the Safety of Air Traffic Control and the Aviation System Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2023-01-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9709</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20230103">January 3, 2023</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000577">Mr. Graves of Louisiana</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to issue regulations, policy, and guidance to ensure the safety of the aviation system, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6C105E314B8048B3A9511AFDC1350D9F" style="OLC"><section id="H80B28B8755AE4C878CDE1296007AF2C5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Protecting the Safety of Air Traffic Control and the Aviation System Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H61DA06D813EE4B9B9B468D2520F9B807" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HD7CAF1D89B134F40BB4FF9B6B306AEEF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Since its establishment in 1958, the Federal Aviation Administration, originally named the Federal Aviation Agency, has been responsible for—</text><subparagraph id="H2F5E3FD6D2E54C3F92944BF833F53AD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>promoting the safe flight of civil aircraft in air commerce;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67063EF424E04BEEBF25F7D92FBFB9FB"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensuring the safe, secure, and efficient use of the national airspace system and provision of air navigation services; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H596B6E0791864658B14EE019EC085350"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">overseeing the certification and continued airworthiness of aircraft and other aeronautical products.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98EA3B1AD51742649C7E27536AA61900"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress has repeatedly tasked the Federal Aviation Administration with responsibility for securing the national airspace system, including the air traffic control system, airspace management, civil aircraft, and aeronautical products and articles through safety regulation and oversight. These mandates have routinely included protecting against associated cyber threats affecting aviation safety or the Administration’s provision of safe, secure, and efficient air navigation services and airspace management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9C1B1261EBC4B6191D64B7706B89CAA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2003, Congress passed the Vision 100—Century of Aviation Reauthorization Act, which directed the Federal Aviation Administration to develop and submit a report on an integrated plan to ensure that the Next Generation Air Transportation System meets future air transportation safety, security, mobility, efficiency, and capacity needs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2E2428961A14A17959A621BE7E8B975"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 2012, Congress passed the FAA Modernization and Reform Act of 2012, which directed the Federal Aviation Administration to develop a NextGen Implementation Plan with a detailed description of how the agency is implementing the Next Generation Air Transportation System, and contingency plans for dealing with the degradation of the System in the event of a natural disaster, major equipment failure, or act of terrorism.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AF23E9450184623A78B207284C2D103"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2016, Congress passed the FAA Extension, Safety, and Security Act of 2016, which established requirements for the Federal Aviation Administration to enhance the national airspace system’s cybersecurity and included mandates for the Administration to—</text><subparagraph id="H732F9C86D9194851B18DFE3914C39B39"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a cybersecurity strategic plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF721A4E21F245959227752DFBE6C429"><enum>(B)</enum><text>coordinate with other Federal agencies to identify cyber vulnerabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA758439614E0462885B4FC58DD826225"><enum>(C)</enum><text>develop a cyber threat model; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5DF87D540AF473B828E4BC1D54AB7BC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>complete a comprehensive, strategic policy framework to identify and mitigate cybersecurity risks to the air traffic control system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAB728F6CBFF4819813CE46774A4C185"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 2018, Congress passed the FAA Reauthorization Act of 2018 which—</text><subparagraph id="H7F38326E1CB54C5DB39E768472306D3D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">authorized funding for the construction of Federal Aviation Administration facilities dedicated to improving the cybersecurity of the national airspace system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C45277E77F5411EB03F660B4D65049A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">required the Federal Aviation Administration to publish a 5-year roadmap for the introduction of civil unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system with an update on the advancement of technologies needed to integrate unmanned aircraft systems into the national airspace system, including decision making by adaptive systems and cyber physical systems security;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H54BB0EB9D9C148FD870C66425F715ED2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>required the Federal Aviation Administration to develop a plan to allow for the implementation of unmanned aircraft systems traffic management services, including an assessment of cybersecurity protections, data integrity, and national and homeland security benefits of such a system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31A232E82979468880730C3CE562C650"><enum>(D)</enum><text>mandated that the Federal Aviation Administration consider revising Federal Aviation Administration regulations regarding airworthiness certification to address cybersecurity for avionics systems, including software components and to require that aircraft avionics systems used for flight guidance or aircraft control be secured against unauthorized access and that avionics systems be protected from unauthorized external and internal access;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE8A4982FABA41CE81A9CD832775A75F"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">required the Federal Aviation Administration to review and update its comprehensive, strategic policy framework for cybersecurity to assess the degree to which the framework identifies and addresses known cybersecurity risks associated with the aviation system, and evaluate existing short- and long-term objectives for addressing cybersecurity risks to the national airspace system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF84059CDF4D4A1581874E3FEA85BC8C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>created a Chief Technology Officer position within the Federal Aviation Administration to be responsible for, among other things, coordinating the implementation, operation, maintenance, and cybersecurity of technology programs relating to the air traffic control system with the aviation industry and other Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9722BC3FB8664D61B0A89E9186012A01"><enum>(G)</enum><text>directed the National Academy of Sciences to study the cybersecurity workforce of the Federal Aviation Administration in order to develop recommendations to increase the size, quality, and diversity of such workforce; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAA6A12E3BEB4EDD9EACA1734A9E3C52"><enum>(H)</enum><text>required the Federal Aviation Administration to develop a comprehensive plan to attract, develop, train, and retain talented individuals in the fields of systems engineering, systems architecture, systems integration, digital communications, and cybersecurity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC93417C5278C43A48805BFAA5E6CB006"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Congress has tasked the Federal Aviation Administration with being the primary Federal agency to assess and address the threats posed from cyber incidents relating to United States Government-provided air traffic control and air traffic management services and the threats posed from cyber incidents relating to civil aircraft, aeronautical products and articles, aviation networks, aviation systems, services, and operations, and the aviation industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCC9EF86F5F240C5B0A3A830267019E4"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Since 2005, the Federal Aviation Administration has been addressing cyber vulnerabilities in civil aircraft and aeronautical products and articles during the safety certification process.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEE4C539110E470C9A41D910341E20A3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Congress has received and reviewed testimony, briefings, and documentation on the potential risks of cyber incidents relating to Federal Aviation Administration-provided air navigation services and airspace management, civil aircraft, aeronautical products and articles, aviation networks, aviation systems, services, and operations, and the aviation industry. This testimony and documentation demonstrate the complicated and increasingly interconnected relationship between aviation safety; the safe, secure, and efficient provision of air navigation services; and cybersecurity for both Federal Aviation Administration-provided air navigation services and airspace management, and civil aircraft, aeronautical products and articles, aviation networks, aviation systems, services, and operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72411D7F78284206BBB98D1F89918F3B"><enum>(10)</enum><text>This testimony and documentation also demonstrate the need for the Federal Aviation Administration to issue specific regulations, policy, and guidance that are standardized and harmonized, where appropriate and consistent with the interests of safety in air commerce and national security with key international partners and International Civil Aviation Organization.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HBA2F1267FE5642A497A9472B176EEB46"><enum>3.</enum><header>National airspace system, air traffic control, and airspace management safety</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 106(f)(2) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2A2F08E203A14BA9B8D5F720E6AE9630"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)(ii) by striking <quote>and maintenance</quote> and inserting <quote>maintenance, and security (including cybersecurity)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBD54105206546A1A0AEB9022D6AF13D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D) by inserting <quote>or any other Federal agency</quote> after <quote>Department of Transportation</quote>.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEDCE513AB5D8441CB2FB9CCFD0299A96"><enum>4.</enum><header>Aviation product safety</header><subsection id="HC2E92D94805E4C3F8B62E39C8591BFAD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Cybersecurity standards</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44701(a) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA04BC9504ACB46C8A22BD89A9E0414FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by inserting <quote>cybersecurity,</quote> after <quote>quality of work,</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C838FD3277C45A3ACFD310A7F42CB9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5)—</text><subparagraph id="H162D22060BFF42778A0169A176E479E1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>cybersecurity and</quote> after <quote>standards for</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1C6B1A2696B14F40809D31C0BB4E8AB9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>procedure</quote> and inserting <quote>procedures</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF81364D609C4505B61A4EE99B52DC28"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exclusive rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44701 of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H9EB1B5A476EF491D9610E3EE5C6585CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HCCE8F5BBD4B44DD7A0DB2AD95FA5CD36"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Exclusive rulemaking authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law and except as provided in section 40131, to the extent that a provision of law authorizes any Federal agency that is not the Department of Transportation, or component thereof, to issue regulations under such provision for purposes of assuring civil aircraft, aircraft engine, propeller, and appliance cybersecurity, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall have the exclusive authority to prescribe regulations subject to such provision.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H6C85BF443AC94009B782FBEA981BC842"><enum>5.</enum><header>Airports</header><subsection id="HDDE8FE8E339342A8A4D0A33B9A3FB4CB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44706(b) of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HBF4B69920D4A4072854B1C89EBC92EE4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1) by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8962956611542858BEE74EE68D44BF1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2) by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4449ACF2EE474694B5C2E6287CB5DA36"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5DBCABCA8E784F839836AAB63F6FB22B" style="USC"><paragraph id="HA8BB461EBD624ED286DD5E19E3AA3760"><enum>(3)</enum><text>such cybersecurity standards as the Administrator may prescribe.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED4E1C9B3A4F41A3AC8C57AF34A5672E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Classification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation shall revise section 15.5 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, to classify information about cybersecurity standards for airports holding an airport operating certificate issued under section 44706 of title 49, United States Code, as sensitive security information.</text></subsection></section><section id="H19982EB6E22344839D01078B4898BDD0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Federal Aviation Administration regulations, policy, and guidance</header><subsection id="H5EFDB840BCE54794A868B851AA9B4B6E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/401">Chapter 401</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H43E97D65E3084757BE60DCC78D9B3B23" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HC9127F4CDA004FDAB388B0417A62B9A8"><enum>40131.</enum><header>National airspace system cyber threat management process</header><subsection id="HE69A33BBBC1F456F9751ED630754F91C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall establish a national airspace system cyber threat management process to protect the national airspace system cyber environment, including the safety, security, and efficiency of the airspace management services provided by the Administration.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2FBA8B71BB6D43B5BC27F51B52715047"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Issues To be addressed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing the national airspace system cyber threat management process under subsection (a), the Administrator shall, at a minimum—</text><paragraph id="H42CFD9B0EE624B82A41FE68053A71426"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor the national airspace system cyber environment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED469B22E24403584E92C514CB8B9D2"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in consultation with appropriate Federal agencies, evaluate the cyber threat landscape for the national airspace system, including updating such evaluation on both annual and threat-based timelines;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5189E988027448FB87BAF5CABE9EBA4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct national airspace system cyber incident analyses;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB77579F28FFA4FC29568966F44DFAD9B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">create a cyber common operating picture for the national airspace system cyber environment;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0383A1EAF4B24F67BE96893B374DD21A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>determine whether, and if so how, to conduct active cyber defense;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A0CE084D75F4F9088DA8128D784DB39"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate national airspace system cyber incident responses with other appropriate Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A312E04A37B43F0B6030C7A8EDC5076"><enum>(7)</enum><text>track cyber incident detection, response, mitigation implementation, recovery, and closure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA505F737BF934158B277548FD0F364ED"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a process to collect relevant national airspace system cyber incident data from internal and external stakeholders; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64D05692387A4B3CBB2A51061AC60E25"><enum>(9)</enum><text>any other matter the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3E2477550E5C45449B409D6036BA7083"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the following definitions apply:</text><paragraph id="H078384DDB8FD4B3BB50FD2401B792A45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Active cyber defense</header><text>The term <term>active cyber defense</term> means the use of cyber enforcement capabilities that actively interdict the movement or processing of data to mitigate a cyber threat.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00E647AC844544BFA55C172792023F6D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cyber common operating picture</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cyber common operating picture</term> means the correlation of a detected cyber incident or cyber threat in the national airspace system and other operational anomalies to provide a holistic view of potential cause and impact.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D121866A7C45D99D5DAA035CA270C2" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cyber environment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cyber environment</term> means the information environment consisting of the interdependent networks of information technology infrastructures and resident data, including the internet, telecommunications networks, computer systems, and embedded processors and controllers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H369DA9E481384E5B80E1C4A02552C70C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cyber incident</header><text>The term <term>cyber incident</term> means an action that creates noticeable degradation, disruption, or destruction to the cyber environment of—</text><subparagraph id="H6DFC3E99C6B741C68F28B793BFD4BF8E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the national airspace system;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50B08A6223564C479D12A430D51FE3B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>civil aircraft information, data, networks, systems, services, operations and technology; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53A2901C95B846AF88CFBE9A70C9AC3C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>aeronautical products and articles.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1F14C715A054288A9506F7C363FE7D9"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Cyber threat</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>cyber threat</term> means the threat of an action that, if carried out, would constitute a cyber incident, an intentional unauthorized electronic interaction, or an electronic attack.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABC19D3450104F519942F36E4CCA0B34"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Electronic attack</header><text>The term <term>electronic attack</term> means the use of electromagnetic spectrum energy to impede operations in the cyber environment, including through techniques such as jamming or spoofing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6826D378AA1042D0A2EE7833BA04FD29"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Intentional unauthorized electronic interaction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>intentional unauthorized electronic interaction</term> means an intentional and unauthorized attempt to cause a safety or other negative impact on aircraft operations by—</text><subparagraph id="HA039054A15E9407DA066F7A3C37C08C7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>modifying an aeronautical database;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61D1DF856CA44F95ABF08F97A613A38F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>corrupting software; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78BC6C7251C54592B85F9E19C4882A4B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">accessing an aircraft or aeronautical system using an internet connection or other form of electronic connection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2E6E35452BC41F6A31B27366E85603D"><enum>(8)</enum><header>National airspace system cyber environment</header><text>The term <term>national airspace system cyber environment</term> means the networking and computing technology infrastructures and data used to perform air navigation services (including air traffic control and air traffic management services), including the internet, telecommunications networks, computer systems, and embedded processors and controllers.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HEF8DA9C1DC4340D588EBDA643853397A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/401">chapter 401</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H4342124968614B9B8474E6BB2C8D7022" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">40131. National airspace system cyber threat management process.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HC72A85AB515E4D84B6B9DAF7D50DD0D3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Civil aircraft cybersecurity aviation rulemaking committee</header><subsection id="H438C2FB7019E4B508B9F19F90499C9BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall convene an aviation rulemaking committee on civil aircraft cybersecurity to conduct a review and develop findings and recommendations on cybersecurity standards for civil aircraft, aircraft ground support information systems, and aeronautical products and articles.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE153834564414A1986427BE632133EBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Administrator shall—</text><paragraph id="H3CFDD3839D1C41AABB72AE3A8F7B958F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, submit to Congress a report based on the findings of the aviation rulemaking committee convened under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2D53A29F065407CBDFC4A9BF5F2AAAC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not later than 180 days after the date of submission of the report under paragraph (1), issue a notice of proposed rulemaking based on any consensus recommendations reached by such committee.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H828BC2CA9F764EEA907D11F8059DAA79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Composition</header><text>The aviation rulemaking committee convened under subsection (a) shall consist of members appointed by the Administrator, including representatives of—</text><paragraph id="H0A739AA6F8104C27A886C628976224C8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>aircraft manufacturers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3C7830779D14756AD521B2E0E0BE676"><enum>(2)</enum><text>air carriers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5223C5DEA7BB4CBBACABA4DA7B6CC295"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Aviation Administration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF46DEDE4DF664E8C8502FF496AFFE926"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">such Federal agencies as the Administrator considers appropriate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4BBB075802D4A72AF45E71928DED245"><enum>(5)</enum><text>aviation safety experts with specific knowledge of aircraft cybersecurity.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD4D0D25A69F6404CAF3CC5D2F9F59023"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Member access to sensitive security information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of a member’s appointment under subsection (c), the Administrator shall determine if there is cause for the member to be restricted from possessing sensitive security information. Upon a determination of no cause being found regarding the member, and upon the member voluntarily signing a nondisclosure agreement, the member may be granted access to sensitive security information that is relevant to the member’s duties on the aviation rulemaking committee. The member shall protect the sensitive security information in accordance with part 1520 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2DC7DFFDDE0A44A8A95EEAAFC673B845"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition on compensation</header><text>The members of the aviation rulemaking committee convened under subsection (a) shall not receive pay, allowances, or benefits from the Government by reason of their service on such committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H327FF7A81D8C46DC94D3D7DCA5EAE064"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>The Administrator shall direct such committee to consider—</text><paragraph id="HC0CD6AD15A31470FA837ABCED0F01702"><enum>(1)</enum><text>existing cybersecurity standards, regulations, policies, and guidance, including those from other Federal agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA166E125CF86496CA6ACD331AA012E04"><enum>(2)</enum><text>threat- and risk-based security approaches used by the aviation industry, including the assessment of the potential costs and benefits of cybersecurity actions;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B98796BB2E14E60A752C34B238B8E44"><enum>(3)</enum><text>data gathered from cybersecurity reporting;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67AB0B338CA24C81970A86E27F85AAD1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data gathered from safety reporting;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD99893A35324002A5BCE304CC22E5EA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the need to accommodate the diversity of operations and systems on aircraft and amongst air carriers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H868DD11A6F9E478DA5122F90FE3EF2ED"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the need to harmonize or deconflict proposed and existing standards, regulations, policies, and guidance with other Federal standards, regulations, policies, and guidance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD645EFC671754F42A8105DFFDC995C37"><enum>(7)</enum><text>design approval holder aircraft network security guidance for operators;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA40B78DB0C74CA480B1E3E10FC817AB"><enum>(8)</enum><text>the need for such standards, regulations, policies, and guidance as applied to civil aircraft information, data, networks, systems, services, operations, and technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86A4EF5B4F8E496494D56C67DE8BBEF3"><enum>(9)</enum><text>updates needed to airworthiness regulations and systems safety assessment methods used to show compliance with airworthiness requirements for design, function, installation, and certification of civil aircraft, aeronautical products and articles, and aircraft networks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE0CD839767D43DF870271F93841D4D6"><enum>(10)</enum><text>updates needed to air carrier operating and maintenance regulations to ensure continued adherence with processes and procedures established in airworthiness regulations to provide cybersecurity protections for aircraft systems, including for continued airworthiness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77BC33AF2B004693826D2C9D51AFA96F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>policies and procedures to coordinate with other Federal agencies, including intelligence agencies, and the aviation industry in sharing information and analyses related to cyber threats to civil aircraft information, data, networks, systems, services, operations, and technology and aeronautical products and articles;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H696C50B1BCCE450893A226E7A1B91E5D"><enum>(12)</enum><text>the response of the Administrator and aviation industry to, and recovery from, cyber incidents, including by coordinating with other Federal agencies, including intelligence agencies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E25E6F807904BC0AC114A570A09BAC2"><enum>(13)</enum><text>processes for members of the aviation industry to voluntarily report to the Federal Aviation Administration cyber incidents that may affect aviation safety in a manner that protects trade secrets and sensitive business information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C75FFAB81C84636969EF1905FCADC21"><enum>(14)</enum><text>the unique nature of the aviation industry, including aircraft networks, aircraft systems, and aeronautical products, and the interconnectedness of cybersecurity and aviation safety;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4F881AA2012414BA8FF02F38C15C296"><enum>(15)</enum><text>appropriate cybersecurity controls for aircraft networks, aircraft systems, and aeronautical products and articles to protect aviation safety, including airworthiness;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DD1B46260204CA280F659E977CCA483"><enum>(16)</enum><text>minimum standards for protecting civil aircraft, aeronautical products and articles, aviation networks, aviation systems, services, and operations from cyber threats and cyber incidents;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88DCCE3FF1544BB89B3B5BA419264309"><enum>(17)</enum><text>international collaboration, where appropriate and consistent with the interests of aviation safety in air commerce and national security, with other civil aviation authorities, international aviation and standards organizations, and any other appropriate entities to protect civil aviation from cyber incidents and cyber threats;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3A3E3B48229484A9E9AB5C516616C82"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recommendations and implementation of the Aircraft System Information Security/Protection report of the aviation rulemaking advisory committee submitted on August 22, 2022; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC3997F7CBF640B1ADD26402708CF472"><enum>(19)</enum><text>any other matter the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H99165DF4184D4582B593252EFE6E8E3F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The definitions set forth in section 40131 of title 49, United States Code (as added by this Act), apply to this section. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

