<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE2F3DC0CC9764A0EBDC8982281150F17" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6779 IH: Grid Resilience and Infrastructure Depot Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6779</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="G000588">Mr. Gonzalez of Ohio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a program to reduce the vulnerability of the electric grid to physical attack, cyber attack, and other events, including by ensuring that large power transformers and other critical electric grid equipment are strategically located to ensure timely replacement of such equipment as may be necessary, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HCD57D04B76F34B128FB39B28EC557A05" style="OLC">
<section id="H5092872837C0424DB506E9F474FBE3BA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Grid Resilience and Infrastructure Depot Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>GRID Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="H2C4BC84230534DDDA00BD87E3DDC49B2" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategic transformer reserve and resilience program</header> <subsection id="H645D05B34191442BAEB5EC66F74ED84C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a program to reduce the vulnerability of the electric grid to physical attack, cyber attack, electromagnetic pulse, geomagnetic disturbances, severe weather, climate change, and seismic events, including by—</text>
<paragraph id="H009CB7EA262B4CF6844492D394AA21E4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensuring that large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment are strategically located to ensure timely replacement of such equipment as may be necessary to restore electric grid function rapidly in the event of severe damage to the electric grid due to physical attack, cyber attack, electromagnetic pulse, geomagnetic disturbances, severe weather, climate change, or seismic events; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC3B58516072C40F1ACDE10FF8FB7DC80" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establishing a coordinated plan to facilitate transportation of large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA3249A989DAB424D98A76BE8CBB56351" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transformer resilience</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8F60785ADAA44FADA1C2FECBB30D44BD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improve large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment by reducing their vulnerabilities; </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEE53B31C09274F9FB5A5C813E5147E56" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop, test, and deploy innovative equipment designs that are more flexible and offer greater resiliency of electric grid functions; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H22717FC8BAA44033A3FE753AED8ED143" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinate with industry and manufacturers to standardize large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF2DCD1AEC9C4C339370AFB44555AD0E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">monitor and test large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment that the Secretary determines may pose a risk to the bulk-power system or national security; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0B1727C561344F26888F58DF8F1D0293" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the domestic manufacturing of large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment through the issuance of grants and loans, and through the provision of technical support.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HEADCE69EB9BD42A4A42EDCA7E73C6807" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Strategic equipment reserves</header>
<paragraph id="HA41AD61D7BCF4DC7952B67B0F2C8F3C2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>In carrying out the program established under subsection (a), the Secretary may establish one or more federally owned strategic equipment reserves, as appropriate, to ensure nationwide access to large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, and other critical electric grid equipment. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5ED3714064D74DA2AC6E14A9DEA67BAD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In establishing any federally owned strategic equipment reserve, the Secretary may consider existing spare transformer and equipment programs and requirements established by the private sector, Regional Transmission Organizations, Independent System Operators, and State regulatory authorities. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA4F1B1FF202E4723BEC56C4FAFB230E0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Iron and steel</header>
<subparagraph id="HDED6DBE17F9F4131AD4BCC6B2B642A28"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In establishing any federally owned strategic equipment reserve, no Federal funds shall be used for the purchase of large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, or other critical electric grid equipment unless all of the iron and steel products used in such equipment are produced in the United States.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3EB0054D112C4C3C838D665BE4BC0CFE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Waiver</header> <clause id="H71CD971B25C0483B9422AA294EE8F40D"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall waive application of subparagraph (A) in any case or category of cases in which the Secretary finds that—</text>
<subclause id="H3537620BFC41406DA4946D5858FCAE53"><enum>(I)</enum><text>applying subparagraph (A) would be inconsistent with the public interest;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4E095E9FEAF84CA49EED19C2E7B52CFB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>iron and steel products are not produced in the United States in sufficient and reasonably available quantities or of a satisfactory quality; or</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H41EFB7EF7E334D78AE90C8FDEC42B70A"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">inclusion of iron and steel products produced in the United States will increase the cost of the applicable large power transformers, generator step-up transformers, power conversion equipment, or other critical electric grid equipment by more than 25 percent.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H2C256771134F4DFA924FD9128FD86990"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Process</header><text>Before issuing a waiver under this subparagraph, the Secretary shall—</text>
<subclause id="H008DFB21F2554B1CA8034F96808ED8AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>make publicly available in an easily accessible location on a website designated by the Office of Management and Budget and on the website of the Department of Energy a detailed written explanation for the proposed determination to issue the waiver; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3B613319A90240A49FDE8EB1502C4F67"><enum>(II)</enum><text>provide a period of not less than 15 days for public comment on the proposed waiver.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H75418DEEF69444A69239C9A1F3414FFD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>International agreements</header><text>This paragraph shall be applied in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0A110646E47E45E79B68CF00C460DBDD"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph—</text>
<clause id="H125DD3C164574E0E9748312911142866" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>iron and steel products</term> includes electrical steel used in the manufacture of—</text> <subclause id="H025CB9F1E0F6422AB095EE6DBA952CF1" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>transformers; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H90DBCDE78BC44FFD80253B646F67E0F2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>laminations, cores, and other transformer components; and </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HE169F03DF96D46EABCCF0A5A18A22664"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of iron and steel products, the term <term>produced in the United States</term> means that all manufacturing processes, from the initial melting stage through the application of coatings, occurred in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA4AB6489C42E4230A4B326ADE9C8B682" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The program established under subsection (a) shall be carried out in consultation with the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission, the Electricity Subsector Coordinating Council, the Electric Reliability Organization, manufacturers, and owners and operators of critical electric infrastructure and defense and military installations. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HC3B4EC53145D4E8A8E00FAABC961BF2F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prevailing wages</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any laborer or mechanic employed by any contractor or subcontractor in the performance of work funded directly, or assisted in whole or in part, by the Federal Government pursuant to this section shall be paid wages at rates not less than those prevailing on work of a similar character in the locality, as determined by the Secretary of Labor under subchapter IV of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly referred to as the Davis-Bacon Act). With respect to the labor standards in this subsection, the Secretary of Labor shall have the authority and functions set forth in Reorganization Plan Numbered 14 of 1950 (64 Stat. 1267; 5 U.S.C. App.) and section 3145 of title 40, United States Code. </text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1E44758C2536465EB9247211ED237633" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $75,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, and such amounts shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HC1E809BE08084B0AAC1D441DBE640B4C" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="HE9FEB7B13ECF4070B1E090DEB0E77E5A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bulk-power system; Electric Reliability Organization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>bulk-power system</term> and <term>Electric Reliability Organization</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 215 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824o">16 U.S.C. 824o</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB566F68D48A844308C23F361EEDE04E5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Critical electric infrastructure</header><text>The term <term>critical electric infrastructure</term> has the meaning given such term in section 215A of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824o-1">16 U.S.C. 824o–1</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9C36CE3B0D45429394BC076BBFDE15AB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Independent System Operator; Regional Transmission Organization State regulatory authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The terms <term>Regional Transmission Organization</term>, <term>Independent System Operator</term>, and <term>State regulatory authority</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 3 of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/796">16 U.S.C. 796</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H44B6852C202D4E93A464DD050DA6D817" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy. </text></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


