<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2B692054A6FC47ACB00C44397DBA75F9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7714 IH: Outlease Reform in Public Buildings Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7714</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 40, United States Code, to establish requirements for outleasing certain Federal buildings, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDA576D55E80E463498AD05684749FB57" style="OLC"><section id="HE3BF0E1302384D6B81DD34D645026A5E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Outlease Reform in Public Buildings Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>OUR Public Buildings Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H72A4826B3EB54C588865BDD269973A62" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Outleasing Federal buildings</header><subsection id="H4A3DF8FA5CD240AC933D4FC4423504E9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter V of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HBBE7342638154985B5546229E7B1842C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HA6613D771F9A41D4B2D37AB236A136FC"><enum>594.</enum><header>Outlease of Federal buildings</header><subsection id="H93CEC6BBE5124C92ABAB6C08D953FEEE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="HE3B0A43E1B204722BEBF8D2266477893"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this section, the Administrator of General Services shall develop and require the use of standard clauses to use in covered outlease agreements.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H763EA1B9772A4AD1BCCB381BEAE20E11"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The covered outlease agreements shall contain a provision authorizing the Administrator and the inspector general of the General Services Administration to audit the covered outlease.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H11D21DC2EBA248F2A1417C658817560D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conditions on covered outleases</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any covered outlease agreement entered into by the Administrator shall require the lessee to submit a form disclosing any foreign ownership interest in such covered outlease.</text></subsection><subsection id="H11A96777129842E38CB86A5F81C0CF18"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prohibition on certain outleases</header><paragraph id="HDD65B9E91D41422AA3F4FB3B040E4FB1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not enter into a covered outlease with the President of the United States, the Vice President of the United States, the head of an Executive agency, or a Member of Congress. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0EF6EC89D2D44C9943C8AA278D9710E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Certification of covered outlease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may only sign a covered outlease agreement if the Office of General Counsel of the General Services Administration has certified in writing that the lessor is not the President of the United States, the Vice President of the United States, the head of an Executive agency, or a Member of Congress. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB068D10D5B7F43C68DA2FB6E463599E4"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional review</header><paragraph id="H3C8E52F6D0674A6495E288371D545B3A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before a covered outlease takes effect, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate, and Congress a copy of such covered outlease.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B6F42C0038D4675A20FE7E1375AEFBC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date of outlease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered outlease submitted under paragraph (1) shall take effect on the latest of—</text><subparagraph id="H9475A4709DCF4DF6B1B587B4C29EE167"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date that is 180 days after the date on which a copy of a covered outlease is submitted under paragraph (1); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BE32CF3BE424FD5AAA03051C7F2F67B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if the Congress passes a joint resolution of disapproval described in paragraph (4) relating to the covered outlease, and the President signs a veto of such resolution, the earlier date—</text><clause id="H43B6CE62579E4509A6720C5E37773D26"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">on which either House of Congress votes and fails to override the veto of the President; or</text></clause><clause id="H328913FA51C947D59857234CE3E34FC2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">occurring 30 session days after the date on which the Congress received the veto and objections of the President.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF34E92722045495C9D34C7B5115B5106"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Congressional rejection of outlease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (2), a covered outlease submitted under paragraph (1) shall not take effect if Congress enacts a joint resolution of disapproval of the covered outlease pursuant to paragraph (4) and such joint resolution is signed by the President.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C042A0D560D4AA080202C053C0AB012"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Disapproval resolution</header><subparagraph id="HA002A81485BA4F2DA54C949737A5B8A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>joint resolution</quote> means only a joint resolution introduced in the period beginning on the date on which a covered outlease described in paragraph (1) is received by the Committees described in such paragraph and Congress and ending 60 days thereafter (excluding days either House of Congress is adjourned for more than 3 days during a session of Congress), the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the outlease submitted by the Administrator of General Services relating to the outlease of ____, and such outlease shall have no effect.</quote> (The blank spaces being appropriately filled in).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C9697C8F2404651AFFDC3185FB6EB9E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Referral of joint resolution</header><text>A joint resolution described in subparagraph (A) shall be referred to the committees in each House of Congress with jurisdiction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H641B728721844431B1B6EF190C8A7457"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H1347F10951144BD0919A3FF3D46298FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Beneficial owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>beneficial owner</quote> means each natural person who, directly or indirectly, through any contract, arrangement, understanding, relationship, or otherwise—</text><subparagraph id="HBB6261C420CB401796A512C58B4F79BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>exercises control over the building for which a covered outlease is entered into under this section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE5F1EBB8B9C4FEE96AE4D72CBC56FAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has a substantial interest in or receives substantial economic benefits from the such building.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3512AC68A1A14CDB9C5CBD5E333D4DA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive agency</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Executive agency</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 101 of title 5, United States Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88935955AAE1432FAF76CE1A3B90770E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Member of Congress</header><text>The term <quote>Member of Congress</quote> means a Member of the Senate or House of Representatives, a Delegate to the House of Representatives, and the Resident Commissioner from Puerto Rico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6687559392A94B689C37BD8D51A53BCA"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered outlease</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered outlease</quote> means a lease that—</text><subparagraph id="HB373885C27DA4794AA625C5F843EB14A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is for a public building that is at least 150,000 gross square feet;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F09BFA4AC1F4D158265757A477C2A6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is entered into by the Administrator of General Services and a private entity;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H527211CB85264456AF90A20A76E10598"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for which the leased space totals at least 51 percent of the usable square feet of the building; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48726CF598BF4D549F1614D207EAD156"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for which the term of the lease, including options, is in excess of 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H462D8D308E8041EB987496381FC74ECB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/5">chapter 5</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/40/593">section 593</external-xref> the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HCDEE950DC29F468B90ABBC6AE573A37F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">594. Outlease of Federal buildings.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

