<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H58671D6D0F584617987A1E84FB0A4F55" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8312 IH: To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a Natural Disaster Grid Mitigation Map that identifies critical electric grid infrastructure that is vulnerable to natural disasters, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8312</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish a Natural Disaster Grid Mitigation Map that identifies critical electric grid infrastructure that is vulnerable to natural disasters, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE89F9F6A35D44CCD8605161826136546" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HF5ED233DA2F14A7FA79A791AEEC7F5E6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Natural Disaster Grid Mitigation Map</header> 
<subsection id="HBB4C1AFB17634224B6E5DD1C48486BA5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish and maintain a Natural Disaster Grid Mitigation Map that identifies critical electric grid infrastructure in each State that is vulnerable to natural disasters.</text> </subsection> <subsection id="H6ED8F8078D11467AB4835EAEE40EBA3C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header> <paragraph id="H75A391A7E31E4B15BB75CD3312263A1C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary shall develop a report that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HE3B784F403D5484ABA24BEE2E417D33B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyzes how vulnerable critical electric grid infrastructure in each State is to natural disasters; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9CF496B5DC8249D0B6FA934FAD454B0C"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identifies parts of such critical electric grid infrastructure that are high risk for energy disruptions caused by natural disasters.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57A7FECE77D74750ACC4183C3CE2CC95"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>The Secretary shall make the report developed under paragraph (1) available to other relevant Federal agencies to consider when funding disaster mitigation and resiliency efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H23D6CBF66DA2454FBE67B5AF9DDB5A43"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> 
<paragraph id="HA7C17A8DCAEE46AF822238DBBE1EE59E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Critical electric grid infrastructure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>critical electric grid infrastructure</term> includes transmission lines of 66 kilovolt-amperes and above and other infrastructure, as determined by the Secretary. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC2E4F2D6DB94499A9F7120C5A4EA3666"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Natural disaster</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>natural disaster</term> means a wildfire, hurricane, tornado, extreme temperature, storm, flood, earthquake, volcanic eruption, or other natural occurrence of such magnitude or severity so as to be considered disastrous, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13F037C2828C40559A6E5C9E1EA721CA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAF335F0FCE26462A82D5A5A4AE817C3D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, any territory or possession of the United States, and any federally recognized Indian Tribe.</text> </paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

