<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA9DFD3CA2AA0444A976ABC264518B20A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9192 IH: Good Documentation and Enforcement of Estate Deeds Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9192</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221018">October 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish a grant program to address deed fraud, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H00C8E7AA0AE1455498CB8821C85668A4" style="OLC"><section id="H5FA075EFEB914F6EA8FCA79EAE38E9AA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Good Documentation and Enforcement of Estate Deeds Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Good DEED Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE172BE9EF09E4C1AA80988122E74E14C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Deed fraud grant program</header><subsection id="H713A9DE66F52400D877C47F0B15F89F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development shall establish a program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) to award grants, on a competitive basis, to address deed fraud in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E364117162A41CAA3662D431943C3A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><paragraph id="HBF2CCE6D47EC41C889B55F3A84ED9217"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>In carrying out the Program, the Secretary may award a grant to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2AB36F9E2DC345F7AE2BEAD193517860"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A State.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4675A57ED7F54BDF9332413459731142"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A political subdivision of a State with a population of 200,000 or more individuals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1F08C5017CE4FCBB55D602F8206E4D3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applications</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the Program, an entity specified in paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H690337A73AFA4D70AACFA5AD332C8760"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fingerprint requirement</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under the Program, an entity specified in paragraph (1) that is a State shall require that if a document to be notarized is a written instrument transferring an interest in real property, any notary public preforming an in-person notarization shall—</text><subparagraph id="HC378BCBD6712406A98D7FB8F80A48D70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>if a print notary journal is used, require the party signing the document to place his or her right thumbprint or other finger print as appropriate in a sequential notary journal entry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H916935A885D0483DB3EF289BE6FE81D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>if an electronic notary journal is used—</text><clause id="H35B52ADBB5AD49AF8CC216C97E7CB884"><enum>(i)</enum><text>save to such journal a picture of the signing party’s face; or </text></clause><clause id="H47BE478798F742CCA14CEFBB6BC4BB32"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>save to such journal a video of the signer during the act of signing.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B577F414D4942F09D2847C8731BC5B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Recording retention requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To be eligible to receive a grant under the Program, a State shall require any notary public performing remote notarization using audio-visual technology with respect to a written instrument transferring an interest in real property to submit an audio and visual recording of the notarization to a repository approved by such State where such recording shall be retained for not less than 10 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA822285144A747B3B917BCF187AD564E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A grant recipient under the Program may only use grant amounts to fund the following activities carried out by the recipient or a covered organization:</text><paragraph id="HDA68946DC0EF46539616D19B4F929F38"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Legal assistance related to deed fraud for a low-income individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE53CA3F35D44B3D8A12404082679944"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coverage of costs associated with clearing a title for a low-income individual.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H611F9A77FE234F8AB17B0161A9D3C3B9"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Acquisition, upgrade, or implementation of technology that—</text><subparagraph id="H7C3A94FB81054D808D7AE6E55DDBCE6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>assists in preventing or detecting or responding to deed fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD6F24C8E568149ADACD80A580E83BE30"><enum>(B)</enum><text>facilitates communication in response to the detection of deed fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC22DE7920374544A663288C164FE826"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"> assists in the creation of websites relating to deed fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67C34A0629D84C98B1DE6AE07AD3BAF8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>assists in the creation and use of public notification systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4981443C95148E2B05A97B95A99A69F"><enum>(E)</enum><text>allows for geospatial information system mapping of deed fraud report locations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA61785798514459B60EDDDF0FAD534D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>enhances the indexing of information relating to deed fraud; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7A3EBFCDE5340D08F2B5A1125347340"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improves the exchange of data relating to deed fraud; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A9E8E28A060452DB8220B1FB161C049"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduces notarial fraud or mistake in the performance of notarial acts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9AB747655AC406D962D85168014B130"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assistance in the prevention, detection, investigation, and prosecution of deed fraud, including through the provision of—</text><subparagraph id="H279A2DEEF7DF4A83B0A82E18AF72DF43"><enum>(A)</enum><text>education and training;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB0EAE3648B7C486EB74E79491654BBFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>information sharing and partnership facilitation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H81388EB0777F4298A6E9ABD0E5241B3D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>research support and other assistance supportive of intelligence-focused policing; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF5211D7C556E4D8D9C1FF27A8C34A27B"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">investigative support, including support staff, detectives, and prosecutors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC8E99A7A52940C19026FBE4B6EBB329"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection criteria</header><paragraph id="H902FA60FA3234A4EAEC663CDD8F88992"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In awarding grants under the Program, the Secretary shall give priority to grant applications that propose to assist an area with a high actual or potential risk of deed fraud affecting title, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H082920E863354E0CBDD21F17E0482EB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Minimum allocation for legal services</header><text>At least 35 percent of the amounts awarded by the Secretary under the Program shall be used to provide legal assistance described in subsections (c)(1) and (c)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10D8AEB51C2244D485A84197313A54BF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report on the Program, including—</text><paragraph id="HA8315F88BCF74003B1597BC1BFC0E69E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of activities funded under the Program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B24ACDC67D743E789D7956F30BCBC0C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of factors that increase and decrease the likelihood of deed fraud, which shall include the impact of state laws; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB01111AFB7D4DC1834A0854B5CFB4EB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the effectiveness of the Program in assisting victims of deed fraud affecting title.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H125611DAA75841E2AB148C6419F9EB6D"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Uniform crime reporting program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigations shall, not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, add a categories for deed fraud to the Uniform Crime Reporting Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="H16E64F8A3F8749D29386F8EB692573D9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>United States Sentencing Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States Sentencing Commission, shall, not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act promulgate guidelines or amend existing guidelines to provide sentencing enhancements for offenses that involve deed fraud.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F7FA543B5024AFA93C4861E4E0D3872"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1BFB39F85813430C9BD5C23EFA6AC70A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA4A1F10234424481B9787C7903A6464F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered organization</header><text>The term <term>covered organization</term> means each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H6ECF35AB884F4A2B984449BA5C4B2F20"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A legal services organization;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H000AA01CAEE940B88E87B831E6F5DEC2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a non-profit organization, or a State, Tribal, or local government agency that develops laws, policies or programs designed to prevent, detect, deter and remedy deed fraud and related issues; and </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB73511EFAAA948A69F67BD5AB6E963B6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Journal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>journal</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4A3298C0D4F4430EAD1990705CCDD914"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a record of notarial acts that is created and maintained by a notary public; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7CC4632C6B0A44B79E5D8FCD5AEA3F04"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all journals of notarial acts created and maintained by a notary public. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A6FABF24FE44860ACF3C64903EE34D2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Legal services organization</header><text>The term <term>legal services organization</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H00D64BF0F51F43F1A36180ECC02EE23B"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an accredited law school;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H575E5F699753490E99474C1203935BCD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a public provider of legal aid or legal services; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H758FCFECF6BE4F3585D660ED6F4E59D2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a nonprofit provider of legal aid or legal services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H036E0799DB0F4D65A97EAC1ED88D32C2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Low-income individual</header><text>The term <term>low-income individual</term> means an individual with a household income that does not exceed 80 percent of the median income of the area in which such individual resides, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H564F6982D3D74902B73513DC8E155375"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Deed fraud</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>deed fraud</term> means forgery, impersonation, or willful misrepresentation of authority in connection with the execution of a written instrument transferring an interest in real property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD7FEA78385841A7AD1ED24A54F10971"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Written instrument transferring an interest in real property</header><text> The term <quote>written instrument transferring an interest in real property</quote> includes any deed, mortgage, satisfaction of mortgage, contract of sale, assignment or termination of any of the foregoing, or any other instrument which does or may evidence, create, transfer, terminate or otherwise affect a legal right or interest in real property, or is required for the filing of a deed, including a notarial certificate, with an agency of a State or any political subdivision, public authority or public benefit corporation of a State.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

