<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6FE7AF62E1E5412FA2CECF3DF7EBC5F1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6533 IH: Regional Clean Energy Innovation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6533</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220201">February 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to establish an Office of Advanced Clean Energy Technologies to manage a network of Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes to advance clean energy technologies, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H03A638D0BB8C49E0978B6EF29B946C5E" style="OLC"><section id="H5AA9D195571647A28948C6897C159822" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regional Clean Energy Innovation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H684182DD8DA34261B97A152755235297"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H8DAFACC152764B5CACEDCA75CE927142" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clean energy technology</header><text>The term <term>clean energy technology</term> means a technology, production process, or methodology that—</text><subparagraph id="HF23F2FE0A3F3409D95CAE9B46C85EE85" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>produces energy from solar, wind, geothermal, biomass, tidal, wave, ocean, or another renewable energy source (as defined in section 609 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/918c">7 U.S.C. 918c</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69AFA9F5F7FF459BBB0A5192EDE2450D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>more efficiently transmits, distributes, or stores energy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC34DC766DC24D488EE4BEB613FEE6F4" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhances energy efficiency for buildings, manufacturing processes, and industry, including combined heat and power;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H70B63F32BACE4F81BFC283C1345DD1F8" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enables the development of a Smart Grid (as described in section 1301 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17381">42 U.S.C. 17381</external-xref>)), including integration of renewable energy sources and distributed generation, demand response, demand side management, and systems analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE3EAF846B52148A6AE3B260DC1E6844B" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>produces an advanced or sustainable material with clean energy or energy efficiency applications; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44BC494AB87B4062B792F353CCD726DB" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>improves energy efficiency for transportation, including electric vehicles.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40553EFADBBA4321AD2CC5084A31FEFF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Director</header><text>The term <term>Director</term> means the Director of the Office of Advanced Clean Energy Technologies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD90085855A0143C4903960501DC67939" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a State, a unit of local government, a Tribal government, an institution of higher education, a business, a National Laboratory, a labor organization, and any other entity the Secretary determines appropriate. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64FE0C4654274924BC39D3F7283B435B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National Laboratory</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>National Laboratory</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2(3) of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801(3)</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HECC6F1F25F7543119404225F41EEF461" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Office</header><text>The term <term>Office</term> means the Office of Advanced Clean Energy Technologies established under section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8BD297B809224760A4591413292050F7" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute or REIDI</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute</term> or <term>REIDI</term> means a partnership—</text><subparagraph id="HC2BADC267D9149228C802557CF94072A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of at least 2 eligible entities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8CCF9876503F46D78CA9AC2AC6F54D87"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is designated by the Director under the program established under section 3(e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA46ABAB74DB54B419190FF635EBB13BE"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF0961138EE3E4FF5B19E3EB3E3B1E711"><enum>3.</enum><header>Office of Advanced Clean Energy Technologies</header><subsection id="H3B3FC8E117A24FE68B1CE8F5F4FABD0D" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall establish an Office of Advanced Clean Energy Technologies within the Department of Energy.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD03D4216B8964D08B32603344BBB63A9" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purpose of the Office is to advance mid-stage and late-stage innovation, development, demonstration, and commercialization of clean energy technologies, in accordance with regional capabilities and market needs, in order to further regional net-zero greenhouse gas emissions pathways.</text></subsection><subsection id="H86CCE0A26BD1472B8DA7C15C902382C9" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Director</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Office shall be headed by a Director who shall be appointed by the President, with the advice and consent of the Senate, and shall report to the Secretary.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0F3925DA7F874A1BB80719289437C7E0" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The duties of the Director shall include—</text><paragraph id="HCB755FB1468B4F0A885680A40018C721" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assessing regional capabilities to develop and utilize, and market needs for, clean energy technologies; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H538CFDD9867945BDA6A6A90CE9C88680"><enum>(2)</enum><text>analyzing region-specific pathways to decarbonization and net-zero greenhouse gas emissions to inform the designation of Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C1ECEFC4AA54842AD2E71416E2450BC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>establishing and carrying out the program described in subsection (e); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7568EA328E846BFB7102674C2BBAE39" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establishing and maintaining a staff with sufficient qualifications and expertise to enable the Office to carry out its duties in conjunction with other operations of the Department of Energy; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8B5222C673A449FBF81DA0CA56C17DF" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">coordinating with National Laboratories and other Federal agencies, offices, and programs, including the Economic Development Administration, to avoid duplication of effort and to work together to address gaps in mid-stage and late-stage innovation, demonstration, deployment, and commercialization of clean energy technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1C7BD2AAC23F4730B6ADBE98311A44FB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program To designate and support REIDIs</header><paragraph id="H9646CC37C1CD47A4A2B3E688E48AACE7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall establish and carry out a program to designate, and provide financial assistance and other support to, Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes in accordance with this subsection. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23C1DAADE26948099F2952A22A66FE38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Program contents</header><text>In carrying out the program established under paragraph (1) the Director shall—</text><subparagraph id="HE857E1912E8A4C1BB0833DEDF32A868F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish goals for Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes and publicize the goals to eligible entities; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H165E654F99184790BEAFC97F4E4B3B78" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>support the creation and development of Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes by providing incentives to eligible entities to organize as partnerships and address specific targeted clean energy technologies and market intersections; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F085F4F3CB34B8783A20775066A7F1C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide assistance to partnerships of eligible entities in applying to be designated as Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAE739578199C491D9E0401E2720326BB" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">designate partnerships of eligible entities as Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes, taking into consideration—</text><clause id="H9994D8BC98D24723948719B50E496D3E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an appropriate balance of geographical interests;</text></clause><clause id="H46F0EFCD22B14590B2AAAC230CEA52CA" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>existing clean energy technology innovation efforts, including innovation efforts of National Laboratories, and other resources;</text></clause><clause id="HDFE11259D7BA4B808F0F710F495854DA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">regional variations in energy supply and demand and in resilience of energy supply and demand; </text></clause><clause id="H8F6252415CF143F5B9D032F841B6BEFE"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the potential for job creation in the area to be served by the proposed Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute from mid-stage and late-stage innovation, demonstration, deployment, and commercialization of clean energy technologies; and</text></clause><clause id="H2F2E9E508E174863B53CBF9220504D7B" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the extent to which the proposed Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute will address environmental justice and energy issues for rural and low-income households, communities of color, Tribal communities, and communities that are disproportionately vulnerable to the effects of climate change and greenhouse gas emissions; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE6E0BCE6E554890A61685D3D1D1A72A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote collaboration and resource sharing among Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9134D579ECC44A99B97BD1C00314D4E3" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in collaboration with National Laboratories, provide technical assistance to Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DBCB33435684ACF92F4724B3FC504D6" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide financial assistance to Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes to carry out activities described in paragraph (3);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H76188C0D3C5F4E38AAE1DF53F420CC3B" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">share best practices for establishing and operating Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FFA264E0DFB4FD2A3C7B7FA35C28EAC" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>support Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes in the navigation of regulatory processes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA0A9D59540949648E09CE9786832DEF"><enum>(J)</enum><text>assess the success of the Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes through the establishment of technical milestones, which shall be used to determine whether to terminate the designation of Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institutes that are not achieving such milestones. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6C50F9F042E47A094C317E044A9BEA5"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute may use financial assistance provided under the program established under paragraph (1) to carry out activities that advance mid-stage and late-stage innovation, development, demonstration, and commercialization of clean energy technologies, in accordance with regional capabilities and market needs, in order to further regional net-zero greenhouse gas emissions pathways, including activities that—</text><subparagraph id="H589152FBA33149AD9AAD909D4981DFE5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate commercialization of clean energy technologies through collaboration with relevant regulatory authorities and identification of regulatory structures that create obstacles to deployment and commercialization of clean energy technologies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC12CD8651A2467E89F0FC0165C3A06F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">connect eligible entities that are partners in the Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute to technical resources, modeling, and test beds; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H63BAA05153DA420D990E57DD3CC140CC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>foster mentorship, business development, education, and research and development investments relating to clean energy technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E69C833FB5C4B158CBCC423E7FEBB1A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">design and implement initiatives to stimulate market demand for clean energy technologies that will substantially contribute to regional net-zero greenhouse gas emissions pathways. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7267565A2214E47A41D71C96F6E3CB0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Cost share</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal share of the cost of any activity carried out by a Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute shall be not more than 50 percent. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA14678E25434887AE6D9EECBDB21650" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To apply for designation as a Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute, and for financial and other assistance, under the program established under paragraph (1), a partnership of eligible entities shall submit an application to the Director that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H6433328EE8314305B91F9885817860DF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the eligible entities in the partnership;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA948ED2117F4C33A9222A1726776AE9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the geographical region that will be represented by the Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BE19B470B3745D7A33B14F2BFBE74DF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan for and description of the activities to be carried out by the Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute with Federal funds, including a description of how such activities will—</text><clause id="HC84F3967D9C4418C817C75CBE523F9EC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>align with State, local, regional, and Tribal policies;</text></clause><clause id="HB4DA2B8398AD4B6781AA30AB74DD44F5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contribute to job creation; </text></clause><clause id="H6D6B28E592AD4556A70CDA33D167D1A8"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>contribute to regional net-zero greenhouse gas emissions pathways and reductions in greenhouse gas emissions; and</text></clause><clause id="H10C9F9BF77A7412CB3C7C88F6C725824" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">address market need in deployment, and increase market competitiveness, of clean energy technologies; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8B2D0A5648194A62A16EE7643B992319" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the clean energy sectors that will be served by the Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute, and how such sectors were identified in relation to regional market needs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEF0B13D48DA94A83871B07A4A73F9DA6" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the non-Federal funding sources to be utilized in carrying out the activities of the Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H111C37595F1C40B8B2E79AD4E51C8418" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>such other information as the Director may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9D5BC924D50546B19AD8166D7776459C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports and plan</header><paragraph id="HC8F36560003E495EA72AA5CA0AED8439" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall annually submit to Congress, as part of the Department of Energy’s annual budget submitted for a fiscal year, a report describing activities conducted by each Regional Energy Innovation and Development Institute during the previous fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E4EEC25F8CD423198F7E44EDEF1C486"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Strategic Plan</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of enactment of this Act, and at least once every 5 years thereafter, the Director shall submit to Congress a strategic plan for the Office for the following 5 years that includes a plan for how the Office will advance mid-stage and late-stage innovation, development, demonstration, and commercialization of clean energy technologies, in accordance with regional capabilities and market needs, in order to further regional net-zero greenhouse gas emissions pathways.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDDA0AA1257614102A9DE5179B1A39F21" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated, for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, $150,000,000 to carry out this section, of which not more than $25,000,000 shall be for the administrative expenses of the Office each fiscal year.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

