<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA9E2CB532A54447BB0DCADC267B0078" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8516 IH: Wildfire Response Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-26</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8516</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220726">July 26, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to conduct a review of the benefit cost analysis criteria for mitigation projects under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H69B0B309CEDE4434A0D2365489DCFB17" style="OLC"><section id="H1DDD99750D8749E583991D979EB50F5E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Wildfire Response Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H528F15A920D146F1BF085408C70C843E" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Fire management assistance program policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update the categories of eligibility and timelines for the fire management assistance program under section 420 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5187">42 U.S.C. 5187</external-xref>) to be, to the maximum extent practicable, the same as such categories and timelines under the public assistance program under section 406 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5172">42 U.S.C. 5172</external-xref>). </text></section><section id="HA0AE1325AE99489A9A13E992A9CE0B0F"><enum>3.</enum><header>Changes to public assistance policy guide</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall issue such regulations as are necessary to update the Public Assistance Program and Policy Guide of the Federal Emergency Management Agency to include guidance on the wildfire-specific challenges, including debris removal, emergency protective measures, and the resulting toxicity of drinking water resources.</text></section><section id="H6FB2C6BAC6134A748D145A273060C93F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Mitigation benefit-cost analysis</header><subsection id="HA616A5AA9010408EBD014AD543B426B8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall conduct a review of the benefit cost analysis criteria for mitigation projects under sections 203 and 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>; 5170c) to consider a broader range of factors, including—</text><paragraph id="H834BDA7D6DFD488C99EBA84FB5D968EA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the establishment of a benefit cost analysis pre-calculated benefits critereon for common defensible space mitigation projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3538FCD5963D4EA6A5A77AF0E31CCB45"><enum>(2)</enum><text>projects that use nature-based infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53D5D1E941F7426F8052184186025325"><enum>(3)</enum><text>considerations for ecological and societal health;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H090F1DE4AC944B9592CFA042B1976A29"><enum>(4)</enum><text>carbon sequestration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE47A8450AD04E06A1DC3EAB2EEE4194"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improved water quality; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F2C02FD6F25430699E2D0CDC95F26F6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>lessening disaster impact on traditionally underserved communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD884D56DC21740768333C20AC0D0AF27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updated criteria</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall issue such regulations as are necessary to—</text><paragraph id="HFEBF8E2ED6CD4967B143214E6CF088C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>update the benefit cost analysis criteria for mitigation projects under sections 203 and 404 of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5133">42 U.S.C. 5133</external-xref>; 5170c) based on the results of the review conducted under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HADDE545131F7489EB6D039FE58BDCDF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>prioritize projects under such sections based on the benefit cost analysis criteria updated under paragraph (1). </text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

