<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE6494CE07D27486B94D1BA8C717D9B8A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7820 IH: Travel and Tourism Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7820</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220518">May 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Commerce to identify the resources, regulatory changes, and private sector engagement needed to achieve annual travel and tourism goals, including a travel and tourism recovery strategy from COVID–19, and to prepare a strategy to address potential future pandemics, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H31F571CD66D24746A27048EBC97826F1" style="OLC"><section id="H93EA3CDAA8264730B41B87C52E0E0AB8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HDFBF68AA8D364A5DA0F7FACC30E207A9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text>This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Travel and Tourism Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H081A43FB381046EAAFF00F7B3EAF3ACA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H93EA3CDAA8264730B41B87C52E0E0AB8" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF8332F9C6B6142ACAE4102CA94D47D4F" level="section">Sec. 2. Responsibilities of the Secretary of Commerce.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDC147A48FC7545BB82C0CE73BA1D85DB" level="section">Sec. 3. Travel and tourism strategy.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEAF0A7661C934D4F9E38FC607A981A14" level="section">Sec. 4. United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H99112776DC3147958B69EDB6300D8C10" level="section">Sec. 5. Data on domestic travel and tourism.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HCD2F5C02FE4347EDB2240C2DAB8D8C54" level="section">Sec. 6. Defined term.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HF8332F9C6B6142ACAE4102CA94D47D4F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Responsibilities of the Secretary of Commerce</header><subsection id="H77ED0AD33B9347B8875C42FA07E2B2F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Visitation goals</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce shall—</text><paragraph id="HF7E4008AE6B44024A1986B20FA820304"><enum>(1)</enum><text>establish an annual goal, consistent with the goals of the travel and tourism strategy developed pursuant to section 3(1), for—</text><subparagraph id="H9265631E4BE34092BDD79A595F53E57C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of international visitors to the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6691644904642F39F3A742C287E6609"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the value of travel and tourism commerce;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H64A7A16D51874F61A817D694A7FF9A33"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop recommendations for achieving the annual goals established pursuant to paragraph (1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2212D8D8585B478496F0EBD3BBDF869A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that travel and tourism policy is developed in consultation with—</text><subparagraph id="H7A5C876FABB14CCE9B182549177DB02C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Tourism Policy Council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF828D8426560466A86AA1FE6F688B3E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the National Travel and Tourism Office;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E5E46D0C23E43BCBC5DAA66A4C9C7AD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Brand USA;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H02C1F91AA2334E348D2D3C968C010465"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45E6F7CA5E4141AC90708E484028B15C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>travel industry partners, including public and private destination marketing organizations, travel and tourism suppliers, and gig economy representatives from these industries;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A713EDBDE6A4AF9A95EFD2083279713"><enum>(4)</enum><text>establish short, medium, and long-term timelines for implementing the recommendations developed pursuant to paragraph (2);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD938F48C7C5B4E0EAD19110AD53CB52A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>conduct Federal agency needs assessments, in consultation with the Office of Management and Budget, to identify the resources, statutory or regulatory changes, and private sector engagement needed to achieve the annual commerce goals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD59C6084DA614A669191324DC591A91C"><enum>(6)</enum><text>provide assessments and recommendations to—</text><subparagraph id="HEA6E4F459DCD431F9C7CFFDF2CF9E017"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE3A04570700456ABE0BE6BD1C7E5043"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3E1C074DFBF4FFF90204DAE107F7929"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the public through a publicly accessible website.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFB86E75165104660B3DE350C657C169C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Domestic travel and tourism</header><text>The Secretary, to the extent feasible, shall—</text><paragraph id="HE1265DCC121144768B1A73C6E198D183"><enum>(1)</enum><text>develop recommendations and goals to support and enhance domestic tourism, separated by business and leisure; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B8C3339F353421FA91D7CD926D919DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>engage public and private stakeholders to support domestic tourism.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF8C0ABC827AB4F06AA01BDA9EBF27A62"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Workforce</header><text>The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HBEDB619FC3324A25BB86F97BC9F102C4"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with the Secretary of Labor to develop strategies and best practices for improving the timeliness and reliability of travel and tourism workforce data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D469A77B4D4BA49CDC2057EB80045D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with the Secretary of Labor and the Bureau of Economic Analysis to improve travel and tourism industry data;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA55C55AB18449CAAF7B9F8527021644"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide recommendations for policy enhancements and efficiencies; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90D9670574EA4EFCBA79D71E3CC06775"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provide recommendations for policy to support and grow the gig economy as it relates to travel and tourism.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B8D1C22D69843EFAF5835AF1870BA77"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recovery strategy</header><paragraph id="H411F1666249F4FBD8B68D2B588F4FE15"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial recovery strategy</header><text>Not later than 1 year after amounts are appropriated to accomplish the purposes of this section, the Secretary, in consultation with public and private stakeholders identified in subsection (a)(3) and public health officials, shall develop and implement a COVID–19 public health emergency recovery strategy to assist the United States travel and tourism industry to quickly recover from the pandemic.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CB5EE7A47744517896C89AB3865B9F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Future recovery strategies</header><text>After assisting in the implementation of the strategy developed pursuant to paragraph (1), the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate public and private stakeholders, shall develop additional recovery strategies, including but not limited to a public-private partnership, for the travel and tourism industry in anticipation of other unforeseen catastrophic events that would significantly affect the travel and tourism industry, such as hurricanes, floods, tsunamis, tornadoes, terrorist attacks, and pandemics.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CD4ED758948427EB6D052A8BF415A8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost-benefit analysis</header><text>In developing the COVID–19 public health emergency recovery strategy under paragraph (1) and additional recovery strategies for the travel and tourism industry under paragraph (2), the Secretary shall conduct cost-benefit analyses that take into account the health and economic effects of public health mitigation measures on the travel and tourism industry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBE9B3B9CC2E4CF6BBD6624F21154A65"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting requirements</header><paragraph id="HFD1B8D5D85AC424794BDE62F4CD7C3E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Forecasting report</header><text>The Secretary shall produce an annual forecasting report on the travel and tourism industry, to the extent feasible, which shall include current and anticipated international inbound volume and spending, taking into account the lasting effects of the COVID–19 public health emergency and the impact of the recovery strategy implemented pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAE377DD622D4F6D828AEA670D96D29F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Bureau of economic analysis</header><text>The Director of the Bureau of Economic Analysis should annually update, to the extent feasible, the Travel and Tourism Satellite Accounts, including State level travel and tourism spending data.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HED10F5F7C5234AE9A73B123C08A0E9DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>National travel and tourism office</header><text>The Director of the National Travel and Tourism Office—</text><subparagraph id="H19A6F99C2C8B42DDB8C4E817603E4E93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in partnership with the Bureau of Economic Analysis, shall report international arrival and spending data on a regular monthly schedule, which shall be made available to the Travel and Tourism Advisory Board and to the public through a publicly available website; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0785511CF2E449FA888219A4AF873E6F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall include questions in the Survey of International Air Travelers regarding wait-times, visits to public lands, and State data, to the extent applicable.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HDC147A48FC7545BB82C0CE73BA1D85DB"><enum>3.</enum><header>Travel and tourism strategy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not less frequently than once every 10 years, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board, and the Tourism Policy Council, shall develop and submit to Congress a 10-year travel and tourism strategy, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H3998F713560C4AC8A55149950AE6AF00"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the establishment of goals with respect to the number of annual international visitors to the United States and the annual value of travel and tourism commerce during such 10-year period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F761AC9A45C4ABD89BDDB690AF3D290"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the resources needed to achieve the goals established pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1FE89FCEC324A06ABD9B8B8D3DC5E5F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>recommendations for statutory or regulatory changes that would be necessary to achieve such goals.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HEAF0A7661C934D4F9E38FC607A981A14"><enum>4.</enum><header>United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to encourage travel in the United States, and for other purposes</quote> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1546">15 U.S.C. 1546</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC8DABF07C49E4AFC8D51BFEC8A872B7B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by amending the section heading to read as follows: <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="OLC">United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board; advisory committee</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEC33D15E0194C3BA78816C4958BFE08"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>The Secretary of Commerce is authorized</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0862C9AC50894E9BAACA4793D62FA3C9" style="OLC"><subsection id="HE0EAE2CE8EDB49728C9541254726F303"><enum>(a)</enum><header>United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board</header><paragraph id="H634ECDCF4A144BAB9C730E06EF0D5542"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the United States Travel and Tourism Advisory Board (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Board</quote>), the members of which shall be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce for 2-year terms from among companies and organizations in the travel and tourism industry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88384F70A7B64CBD8478F47F144EE334"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Executive director</header><text>The Assistant Secretary for Commerce and Economic Development shall serve as the Executive Director of the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H581C2360309B4531B972AFA4DDEE3D61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Executive secretariat</header><text>The Director of the National Travel and Tourism Office of the International Trade Administration shall serve as the Executive Secretariat for the Board.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H240FFE14C2A745B493B0CF950ADA9F01"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Board’s Charter shall specify that the Board will—</text><subparagraph id="HF7F5723E8D344B2DA997B47C68F640FC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>serve as the advisory body to the Secretary of Commerce on matters relating to the travel and tourism industry in the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD84E2839AE344EA29F42B298F318BAA2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advise the Secretary of Commerce on government policies and programs that affect the United States travel and tourism industry;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC2CA77164A94B68B54645A172DCAE51"><enum>(C)</enum><text>offer counsel on current and emerging issues;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8380E3D8A16B4D46BFA45C160550E1D1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>provide a forum for discussing and proposing solutions to problems related to the travel and tourism industry; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08AE58E2A5AD4676B89062D646F2DD33"><enum>(E)</enum><text>provide advice regarding the domestic travel and tourism industry as an economic engine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6AD7CCD68F514BDA9BAD331D13863429"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory committee for promotion of tourist travel</header><text>The Secretary of Commerce is authorized</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H99112776DC3147958B69EDB6300D8C10"><enum>5.</enum><header>Data on domestic travel and tourism</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce, subject to the availability of appropriations, shall collect and make public aggregate data on domestic travel and tourism trends by individuals traveling between points within the United States.</text></section><section id="HCD2F5C02FE4347EDB2240C2DAB8D8C54"><enum>6.</enum><header>Defined term</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>COVID–19 public health emergency</term>—</text><paragraph id="HC509AC2D67FD402F99DD16B3E1229689"><enum>(1)</enum><text>means the public health emergency first declared on January 31, 2020, by the Secretary of Health and Human Services under section 319 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>) with respect to COVID–19; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99202120E01D4F04A9C571719DF0D2D7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>includes any renewal of such declaration pursuant to such section 319.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

