<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC80E21D361BF49759BE4E4C84B9FD84C" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8448 IH: No Tax Breaks for Union Busting (NTBUB) Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8448</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220720">July 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000394">Mr. Kim of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000581">Mrs. Lawrence</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000378">Mrs. Axne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000588">Mr. Lamb</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000179">Mrs. Napolitano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001215">Ms. Stevens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001168">Mr. Sarbanes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001281">Mrs. Beatty</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000040">Ms. Underwood</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000482">Mrs. Trahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000607">Mr. Pocan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001207">Ms. Sherrill</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001127">Mrs. Cherfilus-McCormick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001313">Ms. Brown of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001278">Ms. Bonamici</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001201">Mr. Suozzi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000577">Mr. Ryan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001097">Mr. Cárdenas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to end the tax subsidy for employer efforts to influence their workers’ exercise of their rights around labor organizations and engaging in collective action.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H60598F9DEA5E422D89DBB3CB18B082DC" style="OLC"><section id="H188947722BD44AFCAC9DAAFE479159DB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>No Tax Breaks for Union Busting (NTBUB) Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H48DECB1C2B2D4676BE3EF498B1A197C1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="HCEE357785586403EBA543405B95C0CC9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) declares that it is the right of employees to form, join, or assist labor organizations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF16C6EADF2C54E84BA0C79FFCD9EAF24"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The National Labor Relations Act further declares that it is <quote>the policy of the United States to eliminate the causes of certain substantial obstructions to the free flow of commerce and to mitigate and eliminate these obstructions when they have occurred by encouraging the practice and procedure of collective bargaining and by protecting the exercise by workers of full freedom of association, self-organization, and designation of representatives of their own choosing . . .</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7FB5659EE874D35A67E6552E489E659"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Despite Congress’ intention to give workers full agency in these matters, many employers regularly choose to involve themselves, lawfully or unlawfully, in the decisions of their employees about whether to avail themselves of their rights under the National Labor Relations Act and the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H179ED1EE99CA4B3597BD0D2D73DFF678"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Employers frequently violate labor laws around organizing and collective action. The Economic Policy Institute finds that in approximately 4 of 10 labor organization elections in 2016–2017 employers were charged with committing an unfair labor practice. Among larger bargaining units of 61 employees or more, over 54 percent of elections have an unfair labor practice charge.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18A853397B7D489FB804E9032B29EB96"><enum>(5)</enum><text>In practice, these unfair labor practices often include charges such as employees being illegally fired for labor organization activity, refusal to bargain in good faith with labor organizations, or coercion and intimidation. Employers also frequently use captive audience meetings, workplace surveillance, and other lawful or unlawful tactics to sway labor organization elections.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43E6918D46C64BAF9DB836E80806E282"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Whether or not there are charges of unlawful behavior, employers spend millions of dollars to sway the opinions of their employees with respect to whether or how to exercise their rights under the National Labor Relations Act and the Railway Labor Act. According to the Economic Policy Institute report, companies spent $340,000,000 yearly on outside consultants to sway their workers' opinions about labor organization activities. This and other spending interfere with the United States goal of <quote>encouraging the practice and procedure of collective bargaining</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H500DA4AC0287482FA6555BD77921FE75"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Internal Revenue Code of 1986 has long recognized that spending by businesses with the purpose of influencing the general public with respect to elections, while it may be lawful, is not tax deductible. Congress should extend that principle to spending done by employers to influence workers’ elections and collective bargaining decisions. These free choices to exercise the rights to engage in collective bargaining, labor organization representation, and other lawful collective activities should be made without taxpayer subsidies of undue outside influence from employers. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HCB86EDB94F8A457892D35916ACE71E80"><enum>3.</enum><header>Denial of deduction for attempting to influence employees with respect to labor organizations or labor organization activities</header><subsection id="H9D1AD63610D042A58760A550C0C9C33D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/162">Section 162(e)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C), by striking the period at the end of subparagraph (D) and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HFFDE76649A184E1AB30093A0D43CA940"><subparagraph id="HCBA05360CF97496B96034ACEAE288ACE"><enum>(E)</enum><text>any attempt to influence the taxpayer's employees with respect to labor organizations or labor organization activities, including with respect to the opinion of such employees regarding such organizations or activities.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8003C40DDCAE4925957E1D68599A517D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Labor organizations; labor organization activities defined</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/162">Section 162(e)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating paragraph (6) as paragraph (7) and by inserting after paragraph (5) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H6A92D67F9B4546059B976F4694056948" display-inline="no-display-inline" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H65A45D7F2E6042E888C3E89C66BF0109"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Labor organizations and labor organization activity defined</header><text>For purposes of this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="HA62DE25A02794E90ABA9D9E89B7E931F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Labor organization</header><text>The term <term>labor organization</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/402">29 U.S.C. 402</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39537479CF714723AD69584D53954418"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Labor organization activity</header><clause id="H94E701779B7C45E4909AB00131464B81"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>labor organization activity</term> includes labor organization elections, labor disputes, and collective actions.</text></clause><clause id="H3FBFE54F3AF24F06AB118C0F1E9337C4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other terms</header><text>For purposes of clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H888C98DC603245B8A464510BCE37FB0F"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Collective action</header><text>The term <term>collective action</term> means any action, including collective bargaining, described in section 7 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/157">29 U.S.C. 157</external-xref>) or any action that is a right of employees or labor organizations under the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="HBB20AA5AE905499485418D703087C101"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Labor dispute</header><text>The term <term>labor dispute</term> has the meaning given such term under section 3 of the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/402">29 U.S.C. 402</external-xref>). </text></subclause><subclause id="H0A4F41DBC8414CB2B60725999957A3E7" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Labor organization election</header><text>The term <term>labor organization election</term> means any election described in section 9 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159</external-xref>) or section 2 of the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/152">45 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB825AB25AD084AE3A5DF1AA9AB724BC8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rules</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/162">Section 162(e)(4)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA52CC2A868F44E9F80B8C2DC045A836E"><subparagraph id="HED5AC5B0A2AA431B8BD908F66B24D046"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Expenses relating to labor organizations or labor organization activities</header><clause id="HFBB3F8710839454F8E814A244AC43592"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1)(E), amounts paid or incurred in connection with attempting to influence the taxpayer's employees with respect to labor organizations or labor organization activities include—</text><subclause id="HE8093CB79590492DABE37D078F10FC7A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any amount paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with an action that results in—</text><item id="HC63D63F2CC8A498787D47CBB52F752DB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a complaint issued under section 10 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160</external-xref>) against the taxpayer for an unfair labor practice under section 8(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158(a)</external-xref>), unless an order of the National Labor Relations Board related to such complaint is set aside in full in accordance with subsection (e) or (f) of section 10 of such Act,</text></item><item id="HD619A8598882487D827E726615C62404"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a settlement offer related to an investigation by the National Labor Relations Board of a charge of an unfair labor practice under section 8(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/158">29 U.S.C. 158(a)</external-xref>) that results in a settlement of such charge without issuance of a complaint under section 10 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/160">29 U.S.C. 160</external-xref>), or</text></item><item id="H3317F6127F4044B2AFABF73C3ED7AF91" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a finding of interference, influence, or coercion by a Federal court under section 2 of the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/152">45 U.S.C. 152</external-xref>),</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HD3CFBDA1AB7F44649A1FFD1E8ADAD498"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any amount paid or incurred (including wages) in producing, conducting, or attending any meeting or training—</text><item id="HFA057436F01B49F18DD3543BD2C589E0"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>which includes employees of the taxpayer who are or who could become bargaining unit members or members of a craft or class under the Railway Labor Act, and </text></item><item id="H97A82BC77EA04AB38C037CA86877FF88"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>at which labor organizations or a labor organization activity is discussed, and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H2843452733FC489C8D00E20DACE4C688"><enum>(III)</enum><text>any amount which is required to be reported under the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/401">29 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H232D31B9BFEC4788961E840861CF643E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The following amounts shall not be treated as amounts paid or incurred in connection with attempting to influence the taxpayer's employees with respect to labor organizations or labor organization activities under paragraph (1)(E):</text><subclause id="HD6CB6C8EE3F64AA4AAF0B3944F8E7BBF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for communications or negotiations directly with the designated or selected representative of the employees of the taxpayer described in section 9(a) of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159(a)</external-xref>) or under the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="H6A1CD790386447368829491017FAF27D" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for communications directly with shareholders, as may be required under section 13 of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78m">15 U.S.C. 78m</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="H982BDBD23D234EE28C496D716CC63E01"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for communications or consultations by the taxpayer in the process of voluntarily recognizing a labor organization as a representative in accordance with section 9 of the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/159">29 U.S.C. 159</external-xref>).</text></subclause><subclause id="H0673682195ED4F5F89335FA8379035C3"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for communications or consultations related to the operation of a labor-management partnership described in a collective bargaining agreement in effect between a representative of employees of the taxpayer and the taxpayer.</text></subclause><subclause id="HFB597BA6AA0E40A09605C8086878BDDD"><enum>(V)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for communications or consultations related to the operation of a grievance procedure described in a collective bargaining agreement in effect between a representative of employees of the taxpayer and the taxpayer. </text></subclause><subclause id="H36854E1014924D02920BDB6D48AC9AFB" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred by a labor organization.</text></subclause><subclause id="H31DB60B588044660B65E88D511BFB19B" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>Amounts paid or incurred for communication materials, including visual or audio media, required to be posted for, or provided to, employees of the taxpayer by law, including under the National Labor Relations Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/151">29 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Railway Labor Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/45/151">45 U.S.C. 151 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HE204E8DBDCF9451C8991829FE1842BDA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information reporting</header><paragraph id="HA67C1A885C044F679E19EB20DB0D8C39"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart A of part III of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/61">chapter 61</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting after section 6039J the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HECE16DA314124CF99446C1B2DA5A6E0F"><section id="H5D267830B38E486B9249323F5F030BC2"><enum>6039K.</enum><header>Information with respect to certain employer activities relating to labor organizations</header><subsection id="HBA9016C565664A3D9D1E6D096B1512AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any employer who attempts to influence the employer's employees with respect to labor organizations or labor organization activities as described in section 162(e)(1)(E) shall file a return (at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may by regulations prescribe, not more frequently than each quarter in which such an attempt occurs and not less frequently than each year in which such an attempt occurs) which includes the information described in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H13A0D90D4C1D4E0898E3D7428EE5A705"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information To be provided</header><text>Information required under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="HE7F41FECAFF44E76982B293AB9A9F8A1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the dates that such activities described in subsection (a) took place,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5184A24C3F72495FAEA524C72FB37703"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a statement indicating whether the activity was an activity described in item (aa), (bb), or (cc) of section 162(e)(4)(D)(i)(I),</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7BB65DB422242CFAAF58CBDB9D65E54"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the amounts paid or incurred for such activities,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D996B5CDCE44F228C5F22050F89CC50"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a copy of any disclosures which are required to be reported under the Labor-Management Reporting and Disclosure Act of 1959 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/401">29 U.S.C. 401 et seq.</external-xref>), and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC98F8EEFBFFF41F296728A981E4A122D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>such other information as the Secretary may prescribe.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HE2BD4F0BADCE4D919FD0AA2391DD6616"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Penalty</header><text>Subparagraph (B) of section 6724(d)(1) of such Code is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H4702ED8AE24344818211EA40B3ED7219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking the comma at the end of clause (xxvii), as added by the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act, and inserting <quote>, or</quote>, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H769B04D7025646D49C121DAD82B1D499"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2FDB8BB371E147868A6678E875632EE6"><clause id="H1DF19996BCC84E898D0C3A95E366EB4A"><enum>(xxviii)</enum><text>section 6039K (relating to information with respect to certain employer activities relating to labor organizations), and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H40CA411D2EF147108316ADE0E3F9D098"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart A of part III of subchapter A of chapter 61 of such Code is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 6039J the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7488E7AB08FE4EE3AEEB4CB21121630A"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H5D267830B38E486B9249323F5F030BC2">Sec. 6039K. Information with respect to certain employer activities relating to labor organizations.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H26658A74DAB34D68BD1917F4D5218121"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HEF62B4DA6765413F9549A6C15B61198F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The heading for subsection (e) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/162">section 162</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">and political expenditures</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subsection">, political expenditures, and labor organization expenditures</header-in-text></quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H88AEBAF04800435D8470E26A23CF0829" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The heading of subparagraph (C) of section 162(e)(4) of such Code is amended by striking <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">and political activities</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text style="OLC" level="subparagraph">, political, and labor organization activities</header-in-text></quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCCFBD6E41CC2448387446FCAFA921793" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

