<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H505CC4FE61834F8C84AC0F43D367A255" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>116 HR 6748 IH: Midland Over Moscow Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6748</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001299">Mr. Banks</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001120">Mr. Crenshaw</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To impose sanctions with respect to the Nord Stream 2 pipeline and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H90DB5CE3B4834AABB7FD26300114C225" style="OLC"><section id="H331751E2C8CE41A088F33E770AC79803" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Midland Over Moscow Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4A896B3B33534FC98BA887A87FD93686"><enum>2.</enum><header>Strategy to strengthen energy independence</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Treasury, the Secretary of Commerce, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of Defense, and the Secretary of the Interior shall, within 180 days, submit to the appropriate congressional committees, a strategy detailing the use of diplomatic, financial, and economic means to strengthen United States energy independence, and work with NATO, and other allies and partners, to make countries in the European continent less dependent on Russian oil and gas. The strategy shall have the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H8C1D9E7D79B543558BAF91B7F431CE0E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of how the reduction of regulatory barriers to domestic energy production could assist in these objectives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7C819EE3AE0848B4B40E2DCA11CBF73B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of how economic sanctions can be utilized to counter the Russian Federation’s attempts to make Europe dependent on Russian oil and gas, including a description on how the President will end waivers provided pursuant to the Protecting European Energy Security through Sanctions Act (PEESA) in connection with the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6B8B2890747B42C3BC6D2A0D8A1B40F6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of how sanctions on Russia’s financial sector, including on multiple major banks and financial systems within the Russian Federation, could be utilized to counter Russia’s energy exports to Europe.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37B05705335744328B3B02D3C69772FB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of how the President will use economic sanctions to permanently and irreversibly stop the Nord Stream 2 pipeline, prevent its construction, and punish all persons and entities responsible for its attempted construction, operation, or development.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65CD5A6D6C124EACAA86260DBF4A4326"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of how diplomatic efforts could be utilized to bring together our European and NATO allies, including Germany, to permanently and irreversibly stop the Nord Stream 2 pipeline.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59E90DFAF24343F3936F75464C1D6E73"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of how Russia’s growing relationship with China and Iran in the energy sector effects United States security interests.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8EC6C581B9FF40FA954899D24BE3AA5C"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how the President will end the moratorium on oil and gas leases on public land. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27C1E50F79944EC8BFA0C360E3EDD8A4"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how diplomatic efforts could be utilized to promote dialogue within the European Union on their efforts to diversify their natural gas supply through the Southern Gas Corridor.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA03450A7C4234777B7A6E24E13F4986A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions related to Nord Stream 2</header><subsection id="H06C481C1069341D4BEFAD66E350D027C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Not later than 10 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall impose sanctions under subsection (b)(1) with respect to—</text><paragraph id="HF2A3F640FD104AD19C80BA5B43D8C62F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any entity responsible for planning, construction, maintenance, technical assistance, engineering assistance, financing, or operation of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline or a successor entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE959751205340E4AE63302E39FF61F5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other corporate officer of or principal shareholder with a controlling interest in an entity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HACB2507C9BC4483DA7B0D0988B171DC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><paragraph id="H0007C7ED5AE24B03BA45C4AB85A14E0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The sanctions described in this subsection are the following:</text><subparagraph id="HF08A28EB3BE54C54ABBAD87433A1604A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Blocking of property</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted to the President under the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AF0BAD1F1694B45AC4FAC4F20259278"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aliens ineligible for visas, admission, or parole</header><clause id="H4491EA57974A49E4A39EEC823781234E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>An alien who the Secretary of State or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) knows, or has reason to believe, has knowingly engaged in any activity described in subsection (a) is—</text><subclause id="HBE93F3DF571A440BBDD6118EE54B344F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF1C3FF98E2254C1784C5D4BA5683379A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H57598E9833EC4683ADF29B49D7FA614F"><enum>(III)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H052C6AEE0C25425CB21B70435FFC537E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><subclause id="H53C6BF4A78B441228F929C6E54D98B8E"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The issuing consular officer, the Secretary of State, or the Secretary of Homeland Security (or a designee of one of such Secretaries) shall, in accordance with section 221(i) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1201">8 U.S.C. 1201(i)</external-xref>), revoke any visa or other entry documentation issued to an alien described in clause (i) regardless of when the visa or other entry documentation is issued.</text></subclause><subclause id="HDA041B46EBF2423DACFA665E4838554C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Effect of revocation</header><text>A revocation under subclause (I) shall take effect immediately and shall automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD7FDD7C5C2A4927A25D91E4BA2E5C26"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><subparagraph id="H7AF6ED59C4764A60954E7F68DA6859A4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>United nations headquarters agreement</header><text>The sanctions described under paragraph (1)(B) shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBBABB6105A542B7B32148D1ED12FD67"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence, law enforcement, and national security activities</header><text>Sanctions under paragraph (1) shall not apply to any authorized intelligence, law enforcement, or national security activities of the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFDE198312F95420D8A7A68254C469D36"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><clause id="H91AF73970A2B4804837426CDBAE8EF87"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the authorities and requirements to impose sanctions under this section shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></clause><clause id="H06407662813B43CEBBAA9AC6043F6039"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <quote>good</quote> means any article, natural or man-made substance, material, supply or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB52C5BE0C2364DED92A3FF8B52F31559"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>The penalties provided for in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) shall apply to a person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of regulations promulgated to carry out this section or the sanctions imposed pursuant to this section to the same extent that such penalties apply to a person that commits an unlawful act described in section 206(a) of that Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E80EA7873614726A3D728B92C1E83AB"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation authority</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) for purposes of carrying out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7945200DDA6941458137A62901FD0E3A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulatory authority</header><text>The President shall, not later than 10 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, promulgate regulations as necessary for the implementation of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5D395F944093444C89C604C0E2697EEA"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Repeal of national interest waiver under Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019</header><text>Section 7503 of the Protecting Europe’s Energy Security Act of 2019 (title LXXV of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/116/92">Public Law 116–92</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/9526">22 U.S.C. 9526</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H5E4CEA88129044B6BA08A6EA70096A8A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)(C), by striking <quote>subsection (i)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (h)</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCA1C4BD69B824066B8A0A5DF1A342367"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA90FAFD1FCB4829905951C18ACA59F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (g) through (k) as subsections (f) through (j), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H884DC43099A245BCB81D47FDA1E51309"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (i), as redesignated by paragraph (3), by striking <quote>subsection (h)</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (g)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H000D39D0B39E48EFA56FBEB033F5909B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Natural gas exports</header><subsection id="HDF12C166E39C435CABDFADBB9DF60180"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text>Congress finds that expanding natural gas exports will lead to increased investment and development of domestic supplies of natural gas that will contribute to job growth and economic development.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB1EB8D9069CE476DA93343B6EBA89337"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Natural gas exports</header><text>Section 3(c) of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b(c)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HD6D196C2F42B43FF942255F63289BD2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>or any other nation not excluded by this section</quote> after <quote>trade in natural gas</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF7A2DA490CBD410EBBF441DBF1964904"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(c) For purposes</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H8EE82A4E663D4D3B99C17AF7AC18ADA9" style="OLC"><subsection id="H27B99B4881104130B51AD6B38D37E409"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited application and approval process</header><paragraph id="HC07F33974AD34C93B5731E6C3C315CF9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1882998F2FB47039F1916A003F111E9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HD29FDDB5565E4808BF4A0DE4AAA9AE50" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HF207A8FC613E4F3CAAD84E4233C7FDDA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><subparagraph id="H8729D3BA4E664CAD964E3F5D0FCB21D3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any nation subject to sanctions or trade restrictions imposed by the United States is excluded from expedited approval under paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6676CA1450CA45BCAF7850FE531D4735"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Designation by president or congress</header><text>The President or Congress may designate nations that may be excluded from expedited approval under paragraph (1) for reasons of national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CD9E0629ECA4BF6BB0DE32ADA28C6AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Order not required</header><text>No order is required under subsection (a) to authorize the export or import of any natural gas to or from Canada or Mexico.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

