<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H796A2C22C8924CF5A1B966D307DB9421" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7875 IH: Emergency Infant Formula Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7875</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001135">Ms. Manning</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000627">Mrs. Demings</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the expedited and duty-free importation of infant formula that may be lawfully marketed in the European Union, Canada, Japan, or the United Kingdom, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H2F82AE684F0F4D058BCE5917D52D324F" style="OLC"><section id="H7CD3BB719E274C0D96F667B4A337420D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Infant Formula Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9618E8C23FEF435D87CBEABFA869A41B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Expedited importation of infant formula</header><subsection id="H79518B15CC15428D95D1D7335C90C167"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorization for importation and sale</header><paragraph id="H8F94E24FA221446CB6E178277F10F1DD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Declaration of shortage</header><text>The President may declare, in consultation with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and through Executive order, that a shortage exists in the United States of infant formula with respect to any period specified in such order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE111D61DD8D644BF8DC377FDE519B21C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization for importation and sale</header><text>The President, in consultation with the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, may authorize the importation, distribution, and sale of any covered infant formula, notwithstanding the provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/201">21 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>), if the applicable brand, manufacturer, or manufacturing plant, or the specific infant formula product, is included in the Executive order promulgated pursuant to the authority provided by paragraph (1). Such Executive order may further specify, with respect to such authorized products, specific requirements with respect to the labeling or usage guidance to be eligible for importation, distribution, and sale pursuant to the authority provided by this paragraph.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H323A3028365145329609226FF3DE33FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Labeling requirements</header><subparagraph id="H43F7E47B17624E3CA01F898E5526D942"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Exemption from United States labeling requirements</header><text>Any provision of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/201">21 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) relating to labeling requirements for infant formula products imported into the United States shall not apply with respect to such products imported pursuant to the authority provided by paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA807A7FD6E52456E9F3A010EEE1007E7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement with respect to foreign marketing eligibility</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (A), the Commissioner of Food and Drugs shall require any retailer of covered infant formula imported subject to the authority provided by paragraph (2), including an online retailer, to include in an appropriate and conspicuous place next to the product or description of the product, as applicable, a label—</text><clause id="HB0740EE916764D9BA97E60CE6229D96E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that indicates that such product has not been approved for importation, distribution, or sale by the Commissioner of Food and Drugs and is authorized for sale only subject to the provisions of this Act; and</text></clause><clause id="HDD82C44D19964178BAF0E2E248D112CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that may additionally indicate the foreign country or countries where such product may be lawfully marketed.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C1135FEF0264B92A184C8B32E288455"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Termination of shortage</header><text>The President may, upon determining that a shortage no longer exists in the United States of infant formula, terminate a declaration described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCB1158D7A5047448F6C4E6329FF948E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duty-Free treatment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, the President may, during any period in which an infant formula shortage is declared in accordance with subsection (a)(1), reduce or suspend any duties imposed—</text><paragraph id="HC16B3EAC85754B2FA36F8521823202D0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>with respect to the importation of covered infant formula; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54B470FC9B6E46B19BA90D1A708DCCBF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with respect to any other article used in the production of infant formula that the importer certifies is being imported for such production.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF5800BB8D45C46DA944076EBAB26D50C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Priority handling of entries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During any period in which an infant formula shortage is declared in accordance with subsection (a)(1), the Commissioner of U.S. Customs and Border Patrol shall give the highest priority and take any steps as may be necessary to expedite the processing of all entries of covered infant formula and articles used in the production of infant formula (as described in subsection (b)(2)).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2942F3DF002444679327ACFAC40A3EFC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HDB674D7B74B84B3581440ED0D19C1BF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered infant formula</header><subparagraph id="H62BF990CEB644BB6855E40E2B66BD336"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>covered infant formula</term> means any infant formula that is lawfully marketed in the European Union, Canada, Japan, the United Kingdom, or any country the President determines to have sufficient health and safety standards with respect to infant formula.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE5EAE7E524874D78A8207501DF3A2122"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may exclude from the definition of the term <quote>covered infant formula</quote> products whose label—</text><clause id="HB37516F9B7814DE7ADD0F202567AE30E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not in English or another language specified by the President;</text></clause><clause id="HF71F39D81FBC48A3805379427BE17482"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>does not include instructions for the use of the product which incorporate the imperial system of measurement; or</text></clause><clause id="HFE818B5E2780494C8B671CD793D1B0C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>does not identify all potential allergens that are contained in the product and appear on a list of potential allergens identified by the President.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0368D4C3E55476B89F20C2F1BBF6289"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Infant formula</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In paragraph (1), the term <term>infant formula</term> has the meaning given to such term in section 201 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/201">21 U.S.C. 201</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAC65BA8B9C3E4D77BF1F86A2E51D9464"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Sunset</header><text>This Act shall cease to be effective on the date that is 5 years after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

