<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC4608649EFD44D60B30FA316228D9DB1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7211 IH: Small State and Rural Rescue Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7211</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220324">March 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000591">Mr. Guest</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act, review a final rule of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H68968CAEAB3C4EC8A78FB42D5B4C906C" style="OLC"><section id="HFF924721FCEB49E4AD18FD96A0F7DE49" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small State and Rural Rescue Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HC05BC9AA102749E7903F0E8BF3B6F473"><enum>2.</enum><header>Designation of small State and rural advocate</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 326(c) of the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/5165d">42 U.S.C. 5165d</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA5D0A64D6CFC4F8A9F25A984362A69C9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of paragraph (2); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF3FB947416494DD594DB6CEF03306805"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A6B837205A54E15867BF2A3E5DDC918"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC15784C914CB49288EA919B5516045AF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H1083EA1B9C88423FBC2F1BA97C9BCD15"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist States in the collection and presentation of material in the disaster or emergency declaration request relevant to demonstrate severe localized impacts within the State for a specific incident, including—</text><subparagraph id="HBD54923C430440F59ED1C1B4A44D9000"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the per capita personal income by local area, as calculated by the Bureau of Economic Analysis;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC1D5B2A67AD4FB79418F690B8E5D289"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the disaster impacted population profile, as reported by the Bureau of the Census, including—</text><clause id="H1D90E05A5ABC4CCFBE80A0BAFD2962B3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the percentage of the population for whom poverty status is determined;</text></clause><clause id="H9CF1E0CCE786405497B5514EE7E67940"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of the population already receiving Government assistance such as Supplemental Security Income and Supplemental Nutrition Assistance Program benefits;</text></clause><clause id="H99E15C6D01E347CC932315BE0E99EDA4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the pre-disaster unemployment rate;</text></clause><clause id="H9BCF81AF32D84D508EA85047A64411FB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the percentage of the population that is 65 years old and older;</text></clause><clause id="H29769E9DCFF745CF96D4A152A8F69546"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the percentage of the population 18 years old and younger;</text></clause><clause id="H9446F9B7D5A94B49BB9F02034A731DAA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the percentage of the population with a disability;</text></clause><clause id="HB7EFC3AD3C9840DF92B1E0A27E2B7099"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the percentage of the population who speak a language other than English and speak English less than <quote>very well</quote>; and </text></clause><clause id="H64CA1ABCAAC94D5ABB99C290C4E09920"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>any unique considerations regarding American Indian and Alaskan Native Tribal populations raised in the State’s request for a major disaster declaration that may not be reflected in the data points referenced in this subparagraph; </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC73D160A49ED41B5BBA8086130A3AFD7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the impact to community infrastructure, including—</text><clause id="H482CEB69ECFD4933BD356EE31B021737"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disruptions to community life-saving and life-sustaining services;</text></clause><clause id="H0F356CAD33184960AD61687E92DEFCCD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disruptions or increased demand for essential community services; and</text></clause><clause id="HCE90662164C240EF84E7383CA0E16859"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>disruptions to transportation, infrastructure, and utilities; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF1F687A093C34E14B9D9A2C8A34D7056"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other information relevant to demonstrate severe local impacts. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HB62F16ECCD8F4213B529CE68B0E4AB30"><enum>3.</enum><header>GAO review of a final rule</header><subsection id="H790B91C08D6545D39A4530E2008A1E1C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General shall conduct a review of the Federal Emergency Management Agency’s implementation of its final rule, published on March 21, 2019, amending section 206.48(b) of title 44, Code of Federal Regulations (regarding factors considered when evaluating a Governor's request for a major disaster declaration), which revised the factors that the Agency considers when evaluating a Governor’s request for a major disaster declaration authorizing individual assistance under the Robert T. Stafford Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act (42 U.S.C. 5121 et seq).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3278517CC2BC4614B0B5B1A281C2A683"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The review required under subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H065BF657A5584E62A4D6FBC4AD6A8FCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An assessment of the criteria used by the Agency to assess individual assistance requests following a major disaster declaration authorizing individual assistance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D1E9ADAD26B441C8041BF70F9790BF4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the consistency with which the Agency uses the updated Individual Assistance Declaration Factors when assessing the impact of individual communities after a major disaster declaration. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5247C288E7C74A5FA0687DC115B46E95"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of the impact, if any, of using the updated Individual Assistance Declaration Factors has had on equity in disaster recovery outcomes.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB931D3013B92426D9BF9DF887850D708"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Recommendations to improve the use of the Individual Assistance Declaration Factors to increase equity in disaster recovery outcomes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A033291FC92433B9FE146F15A5B078B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report on the review required under this section. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

