<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3A828A2341694449866D871C3F0E34F1" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6601 IH: Saudi Arabia Legitimate Self Defense Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-04</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6601</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220204">February 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000376">Mr. Allred</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for the prohibition on issuance of licenses authorizing exports of certain defense services to Saudi Arabia, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3B9FE2F266454872AF05B5B3C4E01A65" style="OLC"><section id="H172BA43DCABD4AE08A7805D665EA894A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Saudi Arabia Legitimate Self Defense Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H6703D91CB7E44516AFA8D0D661532D1D"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that, for purposes of compliance with and implementation of section 502 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2302">22 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>; relating to utilization of defense articles) and section 4 of the Foreign Military Sales Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2754">22 U.S.C. 2754</external-xref>; relating to purposes for which military sales by the United States are authorized)—</text><paragraph id="H15B907FCDE3547AD9D7AC13D949ED13A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">officials from the Department of State and Department of Defense who oversee security cooperation with the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia have an obligation to be alert to and report to the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of State any indication that United States-origin defense articles are being used against anything other than legitimate military targets; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H192ED5D7B66E48428334351C7E018B53"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Department of State is responsible, under United States law and consistent with United States policy, for investigating such incidents of potential misuse and imposing restrictions, as appropriate, on the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia in instances in which it is suspected of not utilizing United States-origin defense articles consistent with United States law.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H267BF362B65D4F6C8D31E5DAB63ECEB0"><enum>3.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It shall be the policy of the United States that—</text><paragraph id="HF6C3D7F384CD4AFDA85EF00DFEAC18E5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of compliance with section 502 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2302">22 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>; relating to utilization of defense articles) and section 4 of the Foreign Military Sales Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2754">22 U.S.C. 2754</external-xref>; relating to purposes for which military sales by the United States are authorized), offensive strikes on Houthi (Ansar Allah) ground forces in Yemen by the armed forces of the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia do not constitute “legitimate self defense”, “internal security”, nor “preventing or hindering the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or the means of delivering such weapons”; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0169CD46F0D4AE4B30D6DFA45E96A8F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consistent with section 3(g) of the Foreign Military Sales Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2753">22 U.S.C. 2753(g)</external-xref>; relating to unauthorized use of articles), the United States retains the right to verify credible reports that Saudi Air Force aircraft have been used for purposes other than those authorized under contract terms consistent with the Arms Export Control Act.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF96FE3F256994C59BF6DBE52C29DA9F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report</header><subsection id="H791E577E23CE49B2904A2389B7C5482D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of compliance with section 502 of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2302">22 U.S.C. 2302</external-xref>; relating to utilization of defense articles) and section 4 of the Foreign Military Sales Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2754">22 U.S.C. 2754</external-xref>; relating to purposes for which military sales by the United States are authorized), the Secretary of State shall, not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report that includes the following:</text><paragraph id="HCEF67FA1E79E4CDE9C26697431C38392"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strikes by the Saudi Air Force in Yemen, from 2015 to the present, that the United States Government considers <quote>legitimate self defense</quote>, <quote>internal security</quote>, and <quote>preventing or hindering the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or the means of delivering such weapons</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36259F240933445E832EC5F8CB857C84"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of strikes by Saudi Arabia in Yemen, from 2015 from present, that the intelligence community assesses do not constitute “legitimate self defense”, “internal security”, and “preventing or hindering the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or the means of delivering such weapons,” consistent with the statement of policy described in section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H244D8ADFA89F44099C924A1FBAF1C345"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of the investigations that the United States Government carried out relating to the strikes described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2099FF9E13BB41BA852BEF2433EABD6A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any violations of the terms of sale for United States Munitions List-listed aircraft to Saudi Arabia for purposes of compliance with 3(c)(2) of the Foreign Military Sales Act that the investigations described in paragraph (3) found.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98CD6B303B55448780726CF1D2338D2A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A copy of the Department of State’s standing guidance to all personnel, including those operating under Chief of Mission supervision at United States embassies, for reporting any indication that United States-origin defense articles are being used by Saudi Arabia in Yemen against anything other than legitimate military targets.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEE4F461D2244D3EB5C1B5C3724E6B37"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A copy of the Department of State’s procedures for investigating and reporting to the Secretary of State on the outcome of any investigations of any indication that United States-origin defense articles are being used by Saudi Arabia in Yemen against anything other than legitimate military targets. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3152D84A69C0405586EDA8052F5A8703"><enum>(7)</enum><text>A certification from the Secretary of State that the guidance described in paragraph (5) is being faithfully and consistently implemented by all Department of State personnel, as required by United States law and policy.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H03852226B8554AB6AA4963CC3DB1ADC7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="H76D638A385F844C4AE473797A604C6F0"><enum>5.</enum><header>Prohibition on issuance of licenses authorizing exports of certain defense services to Saudi Arabia</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the 2-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the President may not issue any license, and shall suspend any license or other approval that was issued before such date of enactment, authorizing the export to the Government of Saudi Arabia of defense services related to the maintenance or servicing of United States-provided aircraft belonging to military units determined to have undertaken offensive airstrikes inside Yemen in the preceding year that are not related directly to preventing or degrading the ability of Houthi (Ansar Allah) forces to launch missile and unmanned aircraft strikes on the territory of Saudi Arabia or the United Arab Emirates. </text></section><section id="HA222BC5F4F8A4E0B9500493AF46E8870"><enum>6.</enum><header>Quarterly updates on end-use monitoring of Saudi Arabia use of United States-origin weapons in Yemen</header><subsection id="H33A6B7F87ACA4ADB9E86204420F1047A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act and until such a date as the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia is assessed by the intelligence community to no longer be conducting airstrikes in Yemen, the Secretary of State, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence, shall submit quarterly reports to the relevant committees with the following information:</text><paragraph id="H0E82676772354324B44679CC164A7CAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of strikes by the Saudi Air Force in Yemen over the past three months that the United States Government considers “legitimate self defense”, “internal security”, and “preventing or hindering the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or the means of delivering such weapons”.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0350651E36FF4963B277B0063554E22B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of strikes by Saudi Arabia in Yemen, over the past three months that the intelligence community assesses do not constitute “legitimate self defense”, “internal security”, and “preventing or hindering the proliferation of weapons of mass destruction or the means of delivering such weapons,” consistent with the statement of policy described in section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E8030BE422544AB8D067B718B3191ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of the investigations that the United States Government carried out of the strikes described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD2A0DF13C19C44B485DA6CCE616C808D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of any violations of the terms of sale for United States Munitions List-listed aircraft to Saudi Arabia for purposes of compliance with 3(c)(2) of the Foreign Military Sales Act that the investigations described in paragraph (3) found.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E71DDCC70964588A17B5AF627E2F9DD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A certification from the Secretary of State that, consistent with United States law and policy—</text><subparagraph id="HD94B5426F8AD4CEFB44014EC862DAB90"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all Department of State personnel are implementing faithfully and consistently their obligations under United States law and policy to be alert to and report to the Secretary of State any indication that United States-origin defense articles are being used against anything other than legitimate military targets in Yemen; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC7DB6A1AE704B09A6088C075D330DF0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Department of State is investigating any indications that United States-origin defense articles are not being used against anything other than legitimate military targets in Yemen and taking necessary corrective actions to ensure compliance with United States law and policy. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC589928790CF469FAAF2D3144BF61105"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD0382D5D47084C649B5A5AC51F780364"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H651A26CDC6C74D5FA5DCB8EE87B71D30"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H43D8634AB2DA4B9694EF9F52CC3495CE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA8A2596EB914B86A449A7A5C37B1302"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C443EA628974394BFE9212082CCF1CA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Intelligence community</header><text>The term <quote>intelligence community</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 3 of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3003">50 U.S.C. 3003</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

