<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E5160EDF4D0403397DF9350A5EAFBE5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8627 IH: DOD Cyber Training Modernization Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8627</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Defense to include a module on digital literacy in the annual cyber awareness training provided to certain members of the Armed Forces.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE92B516C055E49DB8437ED0B681C2979" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HBA5FCDC1CDE845FD9F7600B708631FF0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>DOD Cyber Training Modernization Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HF9A1E3ED61A441A2AB8C0FCE3B6F2A3C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Training on digital citizenship and media literacy in annual cyber awareness training for certain members</header> <subsection id="HC476D74F99D34B7BB5D0CA37898284F4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The annual cyber awareness training provided to members of the covered Armed Forces shall include a digital literacy module regarding digital citizenship, media literacy, and protection against cyber threats (such as influenced or digitally altered information).</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE0A29E3DC1174FCC9C0214C0B748005A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC5D4658D95FE4D7E8B3864E6A89AB9A3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered Armed Force</quote> means the following:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCFC4727ABCE5495FAD8C41D6FD6EEB30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Army.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD09326B073243E6A5BEA2D129FB3891"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Navy.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HAC1FAB8FE8F4406C9FBA6BDC9666A02C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Marine Corps.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB187EED9CE0B47B0B75E09D1A0632022"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Air Force.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC7AFD03B422E4FD8AE994E1BE9CD05E6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Space Force.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H52C90E0D87224380A6A1FE5B1372B4BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>digital citizenship</quote> means the ability to safely, responsibly, and ethically use communication technologies and digital information technology tools and platforms; create and share media content using principles of social and civic responsibility and with awareness of the legal and ethical issues involved; and participate in the political, economic, social, and cultural aspects of life related to technology, communications, and the digital world by consuming and creating digital content, including media.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H34E1334816E843D681973AE01E2C9FFF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <quote>media literacy</quote> means the ability to access relevant and accurate information through media in a variety of forms; critically analyze media content and the influences of different forms of media; evaluate the comprehensiveness, relevance, credibility, authority, and accuracy of information; make educated decisions based on information obtained from media and digital sources; operate various forms of technology and digital tools; and reflect on how the use of media and technology may affect private and public life.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

