<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H4185027EE38746AB93454BFF54B96599" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 7321 RH: Global Aircraft Maintenance Safety Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 381</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7321</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–506]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220331">March 31, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000191">Mr. DeFazio</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001285">Ms. Brownley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000317">Ms. Malliotakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000295">Mr. Joyce of Ohio</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001119">Ms. Craig</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on March 31, 2022</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 49, United States Code, to require certain air carriers to provide reports with respect to maintenance, preventive maintenance, or alterations, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HPW00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HCDB3F00E761C41F58C58E13C92AC36DD"><section id="H4CEACDEDBD194213893BD557D6BE1BD2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Aircraft Maintenance Safety Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4F9E85F0912D45BEBBBF64191C7FDB7C"><enum>2.</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HB0E8A693E50F4408A09227BB86DCFA91"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the safety of the global aviation system requires the highest standards for aircraft maintenance, repair, and overhaul work;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7F5667EE824204AB0C399FD8C6CD53"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the safety of aircraft operated by United States air carriers should not be dependent on the location where maintenance, repair, and overhaul work is performed; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B470318D9904B9693225D7B6B5A31C8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal Aviation Administration must fully enforce, in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements, Federal Aviation Administration standards for maintenance, repair, and overhaul work at every facility, whether in the United States or abroad, where such work is performed on aircraft operated by United States air carriers.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H1E5F61EC7A544A468E73AD0F34C8D5A1"><enum>3.</enum><header>FAA oversight of repair stations located outside the United States</header><subsection id="H349499138E5B4867B79749730AA999DA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 44733 of title 49, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEC85D16476CB45668A892CA776DECDCA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the heading by striking <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Inspection</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="section" style="USC">Oversight</header-in-text></quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C1084D60D784EBA8B2D2C1322E15E58"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)—</text><subparagraph id="H99A78DF514024836A83399111455172B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, without prior notice to such repair stations,</quote> after <quote>annually</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC778D80E09874228AFCF2709F84156CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and the applicable laws of the country in which a repair station is located</quote> after <quote>international agreements</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6722BDC1654C41C78754FEECE71D9884"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking the last sentence and inserting <quote>The Administrator may carry out announced or unannounced inspections in addition to the annual unannounced inspection required under this subsection based on identified risks and in a manner consistent with United States obligations under international agreements and with the applicable laws of the country in which a repair station is located.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB68A8DAD3DF493E9FEBEE94D526B379"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (j); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9E7BA479EE4471C8A6FA7D31DB8238C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following:</text><quoted-block id="HB3923DA44950404A93200D85B9786046" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><subsection id="HB184A9230B11417780817EC5AA283058"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Data analysis</header><paragraph id="HDA5E8293FC374FAC817BBC0650931F61"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An air carrier conducting operations under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, shall provide to the appropriate office of the Administration, not later than every year, a report containing the information described in paragraph (2) with respect to heavy maintenance work on aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engines) performed in the preceding year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA85519E16DEC46948177D985E04C87E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information required</header><text>A report under paragraph (1) shall contain the following information:</text><subparagraph id="HF11B2A54786544CD99C892659871514F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The location where any heavy maintenance work on aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engines) was performed outside the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3F8B75D78BB4EBE9C75045555639B7D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A description of the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44E14AD031E04E12B50C85D76715297F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The date of completion of the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33682DB16AA6407884B68DBAD618D2D8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>A list of all failures, malfunctions, or defects affecting the safe operation of such aircraft identified by the air carrier within 30 days after the date on which an aircraft is returned to service, organized by reference to aircraft registration number, that—</text><clause id="HA0B46A2784ED43CD81F8C39AC739969C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires corrective action after the aircraft is approved to return to service; and</text></clause><clause id="H93EE4F95FB3F461B8457993875540ADA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>results from the work performed on such aircraft.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD91CA00B8AD54332AC641A2B4B3B73A6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The certificate number of the person approving such aircraft or aircraft engine, for return to service following completion of the work performed at each such location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2851F85BAD4E424692DF01F32DA3E763"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration shall—</text><subparagraph id="H70CFBD4099434FC8B1D23BFBE743F044"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">analyze information made available under paragraph (1) of this subsection and sections 121.703, 121.705, 121.707, and 145.221 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, or any successor provisions, to detect safety issues associated with heavy maintenance work on aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engines) performed outside the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF94E4218E233491799DDC02BC4FB5868"><enum>(B)</enum><text>require appropriate actions in response.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D642EAF67AD41B29CD709D0C1F1785E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Confidentiality</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information made available under paragraph (1) shall be subject to the same protections given to voluntarily-provided safety or security related information under section 40123.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H040DF55A52114F4FBA6DA9E5C6F0575B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Applications and requests for renewal</header><paragraph id="HA6043AE781904EA2AB08715E8F5109A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may not approve any new application under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, from a person located or headquartered in a country that the Administration, through the International Aviation Safety Assessment program, has classified as Category 2.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA1E31F9EC39447478D143E3D93AFECC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maintenance implementation procedures agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may elect not to enter into a new maintenance implementation procedures agreement with a country classified as Category 2, for as long as that country remains classified as Category 2, if the Administrator determines that doing so is necessary to comply with the requirements of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94511640D0FB4110908362FBBB3ECA78"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Continued heavy maintenance work</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No air carrier conducting operations under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, may enter into a new contract for heavy maintenance work with a person located or headquartered in a country that the Administration, through the International Aviation Safety Assessment program, has classified as Category 2, for as long as such country remains classified as Category 2.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB27013B3C4854A43B17BA87D2DAC14B1"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Minimum qualifications for mechanics and others working on U.S. registered aircraft</header><paragraph id="H3D9DFE87D45748258B3ABC7256706106"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall require that, at each covered repair station—</text><subparagraph id="H5BD3FE0B1963465E9F9549DE77BCD6CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>all supervisory personnel are appropriately certificated as a mechanic or repairman under part 65 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, or under an equivalent certification or licensing regime, as determined by the Administrator; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H529C1CCC74934BC4AD558F37F19A0A57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all personnel authorized to approve an article for return to service are appropriately certificated as a mechanic or repairman under part 65 of such title, or under an equivalent certification or licensing regime, as determined by the Administrator. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H01146795D5844EABBFCCA170AAC2BB21"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Available for consultation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this subsection, the Administrator shall require any individual who is responsible for authorization of return of an article to service or who is directly in charge of aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engine) maintenance performed on aircraft operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, be available for consultation while work is being performed.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H050A89BA4B7F4B59BD42B9B702E2A05F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition of covered repair station</header><paragraph id="H2CA49BD768764E48A1296E68B0ED95E2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 44733(j) of title 49, United States Code (as redesignated by this section), is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HC660432409D34B5FAD0582D7766F49E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (1) through (3) as paragraphs (2) through (4), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H36CF184E0D654E958D4732B7F976713A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting before paragraph (2), as so redesignated, the following:</text><quoted-block id="H0CEB01F85C72421B9789011ACE4516FF" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><paragraph id="H723611BDB52D4237AE1FF2B65BAFA0BE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Covered repair station</header><text>The term <quote>covered repair station</quote> means a facility that—</text><subparagraph id="HEE5F8D87B06E4C1EBD8DF8545B43786D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located outside the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47EF100CE81C46BF9D7AF62261CAC269"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is certificated under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC61FF14F9DD84D67AD8643C61FDB67F1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>performs heavy maintenance work on aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engines) operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFADE3C99FAC74592B9B823479D0264B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Technical amendment</header><text>Section 44733(a)(3) of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>covered part 145 repair stations</quote> and inserting <quote>part 145 repair stations</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE275037C51E04623A7C8934CA79474EF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>The analysis for <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/447">chapter 447</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 44733 and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2541EF2802664CDFB84DCF1CCAEB4876" style="USC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HPW00"><toc-entry level="section">44733. Oversight of repair stations located outside the United States.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H5451BAECCA6E418D96EF1AB4E6A69348"><enum>4.</enum><header>International standards for safety oversight of foreign repair stations</header><subsection id="HD7DFE89DB6C74F22BF5D39ACF1923B67"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Foreign repair station working group</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall convene a foreign repair station working group with other civil aviation authorities (hereinafter referred to as <quote>repair station working group</quote>) to conduct a review of the certification and oversight of foreign repair stations and to identify any future enhancements that might be appropriate to strengthen oversight of such repair stations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H8B85F2007BC1441AB53F8773455590E0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition of the repair station working group</header><text>The repair station working group shall consist of—</text><paragraph id="HFE24EA385E11448BB36C50C959D3DEE9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>technical representatives from the FAA; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B06B8E2E0C2436CA5CB2AAB7C024476"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such other civil aviation authorities or international intergovernmental aviation safety organizations as the Administrator shall invite that are willing to participate, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE5C6B7205BB846EE9BB87367CC641D78"><enum>(A)</enum><text>civil aviation authorities responsible for certificating foreign repair stations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41DE260AC45641879C34E5EB7DA6D6DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>civil aviation authorities of countries in which foreign repair stations are located.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7FB7361116924813BD61CEF6FEDDD604"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In conducting the review under this section, the repair station working group shall, as appropriate, consult with relevant experts and stakeholders.</text></subsection><subsection id="H42FE4B1EB75549F7BCE2EA98266FA72F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Recommendations</header><text>The repair station working group shall make recommendations with respect to any future enhancements that might be appropriate to—</text><paragraph id="H7FD4D6CF36554845AB5569BE1F3D3535"><enum>(1)</enum><text>strengthen oversight of foreign repair stations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39EA7F71915840E384F8FE9653C80D48"><enum>(2)</enum><text>better leverage the resources of other civil aviation authorities to conduct such oversight.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H649D5B34126641C5AFC3D6363586D8CB"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H0B642343151A40BF926BD64E05AF82A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Repair station working group report</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the first meeting of the repair station working group, the repair station working group shall submit to the Administrator a report containing the findings of the review and each recommendation made under subsection (d).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA21B7BC232914A16A159C65C2F9B007A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FAA reports</header><subparagraph id="HA1D545FD513541F88FF5E287EBAEBAED"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Transmission of repair station working group report</header><text>The Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate the report required under paragraph (1) as soon as is practicable after the receipt of such report.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFA040E3EC8E4B67BF795459F68B6805"><enum>(B)</enum><header>FAA report to congress</header><text>Not later than 45 days after receipt of the Report under paragraph (1), the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives, and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate a report containing—</text><clause id="H0189A90095674151836993093322B539"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a statement of whether the Administrator concurs or does not concur with each recommendation contained in the report required under paragraph (1);</text></clause><clause id="HECF7548DC2014F54BB000AFAE3D07EB5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for any recommendation with which the Administrator does not concur, a detailed explanation as to why the Administrator does not concur;</text></clause><clause id="H0BE6C9324AC5482492F6D49D8A0B05DC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan to implement each recommendation related to FAA oversight of foreign repair stations contained in such report with which the Administrator concurs; and</text></clause><clause id="HEF4CC64A38114A00A06B9F75F563567D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a plan to work with the international community to implement the recommendations applicable to both the FAA as well as other civil aviation authorities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3A350B0B3DDD4E949E7FA96BD5E13EAF"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>The repair station working group shall terminate on the earlier of the date of submission of the report under subsection (e)(1) or on the date that is 2 years after the repair station working group is commissioned under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H1620EF6A60A6484997DA4780F2966382"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definition of foreign repair station</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>foreign repair station</quote> means a repair station located outside of the territory of the country of the civil aviation authority which certificated the repair station, including repair stations certified under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations, which are located outside the United States and the territories of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="HBFC8AE69672044AD8F65C1DF8243D965"><enum>5.</enum><header>Alcohol and drug testing and background checks</header><subsection id="HF7F34188125E452086DFCF4B1B3146FA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator may not approve or authorize international travel for any employee of the Federal Aviation Administration until a final rule carrying out the requirements of subsection (b) of section 2112 of the FAA Extension, Safety, and Security Act of 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/190">Public Law 114–190</external-xref>) have been published in the Federal Register.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC867AA6D84EA4A459A44223DF6DD7BBC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rulemaking on assessment requirement</header><text>With respect to any employee not covered under the requirements of section 1554.101 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations, the Administrator shall initiate a rulemaking that requires a covered repair station to confirm that any such employee has successfully completed an assessment commensurate with a security threat assessment described in subpart C of part 1540 of such title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6F90070AA22344D487A97E9924D599AD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text>The prohibition in subsection (a) shall not apply to international travel that is determined by the Administrator on an individual by individual basis to be—</text><paragraph id="HBA4B88D780754722B01D4147B80B72CE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>exclusively for the purpose of conducting a safety inspection;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE7A962DB6414F9783C32182B85492B5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>directly related to aviation safety standards, certification, and oversight; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31E1A2D4AEA04462B832552E52042C1E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>vital to the national interests of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF418E44469E47C8AEB3D65A4C32317B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Non-delegation and reporting</header><text>For any determination to make an exception based on the criteria in paragraph (2) or (3) of subsection (c), the Administrator—</text><paragraph id="HF17E946610D94926B8FC06AB38DD5B55"><enum>(1)</enum><text>may not delegate the authority to make such a determination to any other individual; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17AB43340F534225B2761FFE88C9129F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall report to the Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate not later than 3 days after making each determination under subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HA20A183716234A3C9D5AC0BE21019A27"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the name of the individual approved or authorized to travel internationally;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4C09F3345004B92B7DAD26A930DAEE4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the location to which the individual is traveling;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H719659A4A4AF473A958CA968186C585B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a detailed explanation of why the Administrator has determined the travel is—</text><clause id="HE2C9C8E6793D4B6A8FBB37B730E2B896"><enum>(i)</enum><text>directly related to aviation safety standards, certification, and oversight; or</text></clause><clause id="H6EDE5C931BC6411FAB48F81363E6DEA2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>vital to the national interests of the United States; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DE2FD73DFD348EFB3A9F64648FDC249"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a detailed description of the status of the rulemakings described in subsection (a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HA0D8E420FD0E4930994DD20D4289BF87"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H0A63BB5F356F40C8B988BCDBFA16A874"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Faa</header><text>The term <quote>FAA</quote> means the Federal Aviation Administration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05AE9FEDEAAA4A37A633BE9A5994E1CD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <quote>Administrator</quote> means the Administrator of the FAA.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2BC9E806AB634DFE90E94E3A6C375848"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered repair station</header><text>The term <quote>covered repair station</quote> means a facility that—</text><subparagraph id="HF063F5D55C03478DA4830A968E65C5B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is located outside the United States;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE7E93F5B9AB49C381E5E20D14B46D3E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is certificated under part 145 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D5685F57E8B44C3A92877489BE5A8D7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>performs heavy maintenance work on aircraft (including on-wing aircraft engines), operated under part 121 of title 14, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

