<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H3BFE69E1F2BA4C759BF315D3A1E4CC25" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9273 IH: Central American Network for Democracy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-03</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9273</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221103">November 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of State to establish a fellowship program for regional democracy and rule of law activities in Central America.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H468807A43A234854B4E79EC66842E111" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5B81C39657494C9B9E4E1A5AD8933696" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Central American Network for Democracy Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H91AF8ED829B349D0BAF5F7B2E19B2113" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of State fellowships for regional democracy and rule of law activities in Central America</header> <subsection id="H06966237E23C41CCBB1E95EBD39B9F02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State shall establish a fellowship program, to be known as the <quote>Central American Network for Democracy</quote>, to support a regional corps of civil society activists, lawyers (including members of the judiciary and prosecutors’ offices), journalists, and investigators for regional democracy and rule of law activities in Central America.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H563B0B0FFB9A4882B9DF2F8C8C8CC810"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The fellowship program required by subsection (a) shall—</text> <paragraph id="H8385D999E9F048F98434DBE84F5A6408"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide a temporary respite for members of the regional corps in a safe environment;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H55C5ABA73F3C4D19BF4F443DE39AD245"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">allow members of the regional corps to continue to work through engagement with universities, think tanks, government actors, and international organizations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H73AFA4A5DC5947E49B5AD98292FFE15F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist members of the regional corps in leveraging lessons learned in order to contribute to regional democracy and rule of law activities in Central America, including electoral and transition support, institutional reform, anti-corruption investigations, and local engagement.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H82F0D0283FEE4268BED086D72B0EBFFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Regional and international support</header><text>The Secretary of State shall take such steps as may be necessary—</text> <paragraph id="H63B8C65DC5094EDCBF8EC484056059A5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to obtain support for the fellowship program required by subsection (a) from international foundations, regional and United States governmental and nongovernmental organizations, and regional and United States universities; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H955CA7B4902C4E3397517403C45FC50F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to ensure the fellowship program is well coordinated with and complementary of existing mechanisms, such as the Lifeline Embattled CSO Assistance Fund. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H3868AD3B5BB54228B0EB47E5438E9311"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Focus; safety</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities carried out under the fellowship program required by subsection (a)—</text> 
<paragraph id="H67A22421311445F6AA7C79C01E03B6E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">should focus on coordination and consultation with key agencies and international bodies to continue their democracy efforts, including the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Justice, the Department of the Treasury, the Organization of American States, the Inter-American Court for Human Rights, and the United Nations; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC7F83E046D73409AB41D2AD2349E3F21"><enum>(2)</enum><text>may include strengthened protection for the physical safety of individuals who must leave their home country to participate in the program, including assistance for temporary relocation, English language learning, and mental health support.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC5909C37A174465A85F67C62CD837880"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of Appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for fiscal year 2023.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

