<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H86C94AB3653E44B0B1DF613DC2233FC5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7181 IH: Human Trafficking Prevention Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7181</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220321">March 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="I000056">Mr. Issa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001270">Ms. Bass</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 to direct the Secretary of Transportation to seek to provide for the posting of contact information of the national human trafficking hotline in the restrooms of each aircraft, airport, over-the-road bus, bus station, passenger train, and passenger railroad station operating within the United States, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H17321D2D19CD46278BDD89163FD51C14" style="OLC"><section id="HB2F956D7F577419CBDA90083EFD68A8D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Human Trafficking Prevention Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE8EB07B5B8814416808DAD665376B3DD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Posting of national human trafficking phone number in certain restrooms</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 107(b)(1)(B)(ii) of the Trafficking Victims Protection Act of 2000 (enacted as division A of the Victims of Trafficking and Violence Protection Act of 2000 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/7105">22 U.S.C. 7105(b)(1)(B)(ii)</external-xref>)) is amended by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Secretary of Transportation, in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall seek to coordinate with the owners and operators of aircraft, airports, over-the-road buses, bus stations, passenger trains, and passenger railroad stations to place the contact information of the national human trafficking hotline (including options to reach out to the hotline such as through phone, text, or TTY) in the restrooms of each such aircraft, airport, over-the-road bus, bus station, passenger train, and passenger railroad station operating within the United States.</quote>. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

