<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="H9A938D6DA84245909C4AB66DAAB8CC65" public-private="public" key="S" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1" slc-id="S1-MIR22191-T5Y-LX-M99"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 408 RS: Department of Homeland Security Mentor-Protégé Program Act of 20212022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2021-04-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 584</calendar><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 408</legis-num><associated-doc role="report">[Report No. 117–225]</associated-doc><current-chamber display="yes">IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date date="20210422">April 22, 2021</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date>December 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor>, with amendments</action-desc><action-instruction>Omit the part struck through and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Homeland Security Act of 2002 to establish a mentor-protégé program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H985D5A95BB6E4D3E8B2D923FC0704EC0" style="OLC" display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause"><section id="H9155A43FBF2340249E7E7B8ABFE95C1F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Homeland Security Mentor-Protégé Program Act of <deleted-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="strikethrough">2021</deleted-phrase><added-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="italic">2022</added-phrase></short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HC2A68F5F26804BB0B11A634B88EAFBE7"><enum>2.</enum><header>Department of homeland security mentor-protégé program</header><subsection id="H87E2CEC950AD4313BAD849A0D24EE923"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subtitle H of title VIII of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/451">6 U.S.C. 451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="H120BDB06D6EB460387BE5A5215C49B27" style="OLC"><section id="H10454155969044308DA50BD329096F0B"><enum><deleted-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="strikethrough">890B</deleted-phrase><added-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="italic">890C</added-phrase>.</enum><header>Mentor-protégé program</header><subsection id="H627F72045FD540EABE95CF1EAB0B540B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Department a mentor-protégé program (in this section referred to as the <quote>Program</quote>) under which a mentor firm enters into an agreement with a protégé firm for the purpose of assisting the protégé firm to compete for prime contracts and subcontracts of the Department.</text></subsection><subsection id="H685BA4640A504E0092362E890336C732"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>The Secretary shall establish criteria for mentor firms and protégé firms to be eligible to participate in the Program, including a requirement that a firm is not included on any list maintained by the Federal Government of contractors that have been suspended or debarred.</text></subsection><subsection id="H710E671CB5FF46D0B31A8F74C876A6C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Program application and approval</header><paragraph id="H83A37FE583564172BE75095544B277D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization of the Department, shall establish a process for submission of an application jointly by a mentor firm and the protégé firm selected by the mentor firm. The application shall include each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HD4709DE3A42B44028A19A5C7D1176C11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A description of the assistance to be provided by the mentor firm, including, to the extent available, the number and a brief description of each anticipated subcontract to be awarded to the protégé firm.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB49B11E6285047379756C25C420C70A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A schedule with milestones for achieving the assistance to be provided over the period of participation in the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE1F0B3579EAC478C8A808D16B2B210B9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An estimate of the costs to be incurred by the mentor firm for providing assistance under the Program.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05443B731D5A44A7A656A6628C5642CD"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Attestations that Program participants will submit to the Secretary reports at times specified by the Secretary to assist the Secretary in evaluating the protégé firm’s developmental progress.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4B9AD16636284548A8FE1AB427146559"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Attestations that Program participants will inform the Secretary in the event of a change in eligibility or voluntary withdrawal from the Program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AC594BE396F46D7AE4B60DFFD3289F2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>Not later than 60 days after receipt of an application pursuant to paragraph (1), the head of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization shall notify applicants of approval or, in the case of disapproval, the process for resubmitting an application for reconsideration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H401BB2F501CA4D99A19DF543CFFBC080"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>The head of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization may rescind the approval of an application under this subsection if it determines that such action is in the best interest of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDB84A4B9D0464BB2BBA8C0B19981D2AA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Program duration</header><text>A mentor firm and protégé firm approved under subsection (c) shall enter into an agreement to participate in the Program for a period of not less than 36 months.</text></subsection><subsection id="H73194A39E46B4840B92BC27BEE6B77BC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Program benefits</header><text>A mentor firm and protégé firm that enter into an agreement under subsection (d) may receive the following Program benefits:</text><paragraph id="H13172260B8C946F0A74A85E81FD4EF70"><enum>(1)</enum><text>With respect to an award of a contract that requires a subcontracting plan, a mentor firm may receive evaluation credit for participating in the Program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5ED7BBA2C81B478FA7E455D45498D851"><enum>(2)</enum><text>With respect to an award of a contract that requires a subcontracting plan, a mentor firm may receive credit for a protégé firm performing as a first tier subcontractor or a subcontractor at any tier in an amount equal to the total dollar value of any subcontracts awarded to such protégé firm.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7E395E4A6164CC5980965F62DD625AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A protégé firm may receive technical, managerial, financial, or any other mutually agreed upon benefit from a mentor firm, including a subcontract award.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB452E629CEA544A0ABFE00C0111E65C9"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reporting</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the head of the Office of Small and Disadvantaged Business Utilization shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs and the Committee on Small Business and Entrepreneurship of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security and the Committee on Small Business of the House of Representatives a report that—</text><paragraph id="H21816D2F26DA4B2E89735DE3F1AA6112"><enum>(1)</enum><text>identifies each agreement between a mentor firm and a protégé firm entered into under this section, including the number of protégé firm participants that are—</text><subparagraph id="H8CE9F1E9A2FB41B5992B97AE5710EFBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>small business concerns;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CD56E2008BC4D588EE85D05D98F769C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>small business concerns owned and controlled by veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8197504DA184A24BCBE58234C53A463"><enum>(C)</enum><text>small business concerns owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABEAE86AE4604E85A39D16EE790C0B07"><enum>(D)</enum><text>qualified HUBZone small business concerns;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FE774BEE10E48D08FE4A128195E4FA2"><enum>(E)</enum><text>small business concerns owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB666ADB758B1480795A784A1CF1E3DB9"><enum>(F)</enum><text>small business concerns owned and controlled by women;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H444ECE009D2643288ADB21DBCB5274BA"><enum>(G)</enum><text>historically Black colleges and universities; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H200400CE67BB4792A29D651ECC394EEF"><enum>(H)</enum><text>minority institutions of higher education;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5E7AE0F0689B4FF2985880DFA017FFA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the type of assistance provided by mentor firms to protégé firms;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB8A142499D2645DC89FA3AC2E1142ABF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identifies contracts within the Department in which a mentor firm serving as the prime contractor provided subcontracts to a protégé firm under the Program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFD948D6D6B41AF8F4B4D8FB1250D4E"><enum>(4)</enum><text>assesses the degree to which there has been—</text><subparagraph id="H7A8B7F41BD994E998540D38C687FCAFA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an increase in the technical capabilities of protégé firms; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6040BD443E094482B5CADC5329ABB6D1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an increase in the quantity and estimated value of prime contract and subcontract awards to protégé firms for the period covered by the report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD5DDB39B44F94B8DB71AB079C6340630" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit, diminish, impair, or otherwise affect the authority of the Department to participate in any program carried out by or requiring approval of the Small Business Administration or adopt or follow any regulation or policy that the Administrator of the Small Business Administration may promulgate, except that, to the extent that any provision of this section (including subsection (h)) conflicts with any other provision of law, regulation, or policy, this section shall control.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDDA3C41B32744CB885D4B8803CE47D7B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H3B9AF567B81E45B987169C662FC98493"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Historically black college or university</header><text>The term <term>historically Black college or university</term> means any of the historically Black colleges and universities referred to in section 2323 of title 10, United States Code, as in effect on March 1, 2018.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC377987C075B45F2A520D8841944BBFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mentor firm</header><text>The term <term>mentor firm</term> means a for-profit business concern that is not a small business concern that—</text><subparagraph id="HA0AE32E59CE948C1B28712CCA8C4329A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has the ability to assist and commits to assisting a protégé to compete for Federal prime contracts and subcontracts; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE56BC432D37346E78D5288959FEF98C3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>satisfies any other requirements imposed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEA43798E638431AB99D89E0E8A99097"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Minority institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>minority institution of higher education</term> means an institution of higher education with a student body that reflects the composition specified in section 312(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1058">20 U.S.C. 1058(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD1681117CC84764A06D8E74A2BB96E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Protégé firm</header><text>The term <term>protégé firm</term> means a small business concern, a historically Black college or university, or a minority institution of higher education that—</text><subparagraph id="HC65F4166E67A43D1BC976D77207CEE83"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is eligible to enter into a prime contract or subcontract with the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35378BA945A74D40AB5F83A6ACD81C55"><enum>(B)</enum><text>satisfies any other requirements imposed by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B9964AEEEE24349A2F6C1DC06215644"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Small business act definitions</header><text>The terms <term>small business concern</term>, <term>small business concern owned and controlled by veterans</term>, <term>small business concern owned and controlled by service-disabled veterans</term>, <term>qualified HUBZone small business concern</term>, <term>and small business concern owned and controlled by women</term> have the meanings given such terms, respectively, under section 3 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/632">15 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>). The term <term>small business concern owned and controlled by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8(d)(3)(C) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/637">15 U.S.C. 637(d)(3)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H60EC0D7F58F740A29822F12772E9F31C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section <deleted-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="strikethrough">890A</deleted-phrase><added-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="italic">890B</added-phrase> the following new item:</text><quoted-block id="HA4FDE99478204934ABB0132C6F2396FE" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. <deleted-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="strikethrough">890B</deleted-phrase><added-phrase committee-id="SSGA00" reported-display-style="italic">890C</added-phrase>. Mentor-protégé program.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date>December 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with amendments</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

