<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H86D374AC54394608A4CCA78376ED3B85" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8242 IH: National Debt is National Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8242</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220628">June 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. C. Scott Franklin of Florida</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000563">Mr. Gibbs</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000246">Mr. Fallon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish limitations on the amount of debt issued by the United States which may be held by foreign governments, entities, and individuals.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H915CCCC25B8F4A6F804A733DC458014D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5695E4BBE61349058C93A55EDBE09219" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Debt is National Security Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H19DC294B1AEF4A51BE89D077E9FCBF10"><enum>2.</enum><header>Limit on public debt held by foreign governments, entities, and individuals</header> <subsection id="HA0E6A888A0164CD5AC16156E2AC90FB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3113">section 3113</external-xref> the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD9471954B19C484A96F6381893D0C17B"> 
<section id="HE2673980D8634FE69E15DAA9F052B100"><enum>3114.</enum><header>Limit on public debt held by foreign governments, entities, and individuals</header> 
<subsection id="HB4406B4BEB104463B109F8155B041116"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header> 
<paragraph id="HB51FD84073AB41559B0E8EB01FCEB6A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cumulative limit</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, the amount of the national debt which is cumulatively held by foreign governments, entities organized or incorporated under the laws of a foreign country, and citizens of foreign countries shall not exceed an amount equal to one-fourth of the national debt.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3522FF8076DA4B8FAC734F07E7DE5630"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Country-specific limit</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this chapter, with respect to any foreign country, the amount of the national debt which is cumulatively held by the government of such country, entities organized or incorporated under the laws of such country, and citizens of such country shall not exceed an amount equal to 5 percent of the national debt.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4A3FE06D624C40EAB00F32BE83F17E08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Determination</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of the Office of Management and Budget, shall issue guidance regarding implementation of this section, including calculation of the amount of the national debt held by foreign governments, entities organized or incorporated under the laws of a foreign country, and citizens of foreign countries.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE3A26504C1DE40E7B5E7553858341259"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Presidential waiver</header> <paragraph id="HD3C51BA93F614307804DC3D8B2ADE760"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may waive the application of paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a) if the President determines and, pursuant to paragraph (2), so reports that the important national interest of the United States requires the exercise of such waiver authority.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H804D356741494EACAACEA0D4A17DB173"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text>Not later than the date of the exercise of a waiver under paragraph (1), the President shall notify the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Finance of the Senate of the waiver or the intention to exercise the waiver, together with a detailed justification thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H48243E4902E94537BD611289FD09975F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>National debt</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>national debt</term> means the face amount of obligations issued under this chapter and the face amount of obligations whose principal and interest are guaranteed by the United States Government (except guaranteed obligations held by the Secretary of the Treasury).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59B8FD6EA0CE441A81D4BDE4BF59F53B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by inserting after the item relating to <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/31/3113">section 3113</external-xref> the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0395F128F6484A1187B71E23777BADB8"> <toc> <toc-entry level="section" bold="off">3114. Limit on public debt held by foreign governments, entities, and individuals.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

