<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4D5BDA2CBE1C4C33B070C970C762AC63" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6960 IH: Regaining Energy Freedom and Undeniable SEcurity and Preserving U.S. Trade Interests Now Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6960</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220307">March 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001180">Mr. McKinley</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Natural Resources</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAG00">Agriculture</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation of fossil fuels from the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H1F40FE4A6EAD4373851A20963CF78059" style="OLC"><section id="H729CC27E330740008AFA23757A366663" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Regaining Energy Freedom and Undeniable SEcurity and Preserving U.S. Trade Interests Now Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>REFUSE PUTIN Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2BDB6B1297A24B5197E1D7017F0380F6" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Finding; Sense of Congress</header><subsection id="HF3513DBF5A424D40BA196DFF9682FE35"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Finding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that exports of liquefied natural gas from the United States to Europe have a lifecycle emissions profile that is 41 percent lower than natural gas that is exported from the Russian Federation to Europe.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD9FF472FDFD142E095DEFD32383667AB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H03B9131B10E24343A08955F7B0E7C35E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any prohibition on the importation of fossil fuels, including crude oil, petroleum, petroleum products, liquefied natural gas, and coal, from the Russian Federation must be offset by an increase in the production of those fossil fuels in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74882F96265448EFB2D57A001D7B29E1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States allies in Europe should take similar steps to prohibit the importation of Russian fossil fuels so that the Russian Federation cannot benefit from production of those fossil fuels; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD624B8798A648059C2A029F5E1B6EB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>energy independence is critical to national security and should include the production, use, and export of all available energy sources, including coal, natural gas, oil, nuclear, and renewables, as well as strategic minerals critical to electric vehicles and other clean energy sources.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEAD7CE92AB6C4EC6A78A4A43D8C185EC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on the importation of fossil fuels, including crude oil, petroleum, petroleum products, liquefied natural gas, and coal, from the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="H7E67A0D9D22A45D29DA2F08C222AE5FF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, effective beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the President shall prohibit the importation of any fossil fuels, including crude oil, petroleum, petroleum products, liquefied natural gas, and coal, from the Russian Federation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7EC739442C324C3982C1C94B7D8CFB5C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition under subsection (a) shall not apply with respect to fossil fuels, including crude oil, petroleum, petroleum products, liquefied natural gas, and coal, that are loaded for transit or in transit to the United States on the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF92E926ADD644A23902CBF9C3DB5EDFD" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Requirements or other restrictions on the export of crude oil</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During any time in which the prohibition under subsection (a) is in effect, the President may not use the authority under section 101(d) of division O of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2016 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6212a">42 U.S.C. 6212a(d)</external-xref>) to impose a ban on the export of crude oil from the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8C83DFFAA95C412185150D11D051ECDE"><enum>4.</enum><header>Executive and agency action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">On the date of enactment of this Act, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H5ADF20F9B0724A3DB59887ED7A90655F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rescind the following executive and secretarial orders:</text><subparagraph id="H1D3B1F4EFBFF4ADDA615C66933F21D63"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 14008 (86 Fed. Reg. 7619; relating to tackling the climate crisis at home and abroad);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HACE9E58E9CB34092929DA4036D7E8C33"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Executive Order 13990 (86 Fed. Reg. 7037; relating to protecting public health and the environment and restoring science to tackle the climate crisis); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B49F4ED359D463F9304B4215747BA49" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Secretarial Order 3395 (relating to temporary suspension of delegated authority); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C211D3016D34A36A13544EE4AC8CDB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">direct each Federal agency (including the Council on Environmental Quality) to, not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act—</text><subparagraph id="HCBE7AB91A64440AAAF2522458A7508B5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify and repeal any regulation promulgated by the Federal agency that has the intent or effect of substantially reducing the energy independence of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5383E693CF84BF88DBFDF1020CCBCE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issue regulations and guidance to—</text><clause id="H908ED66671C141F999400B71DE4CC81F"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reduce the regulatory burden for energy producers in the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HE1D5A9D4EB6947A889E187461FFD75EC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increase the energy output by those producers.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H429A0FD5CC3F4DDBA1D3FD4C36F41482"><enum>5.</enum><header>Increasing United States production for allies</header><subsection id="H70310A99DEC04ECAB9D91CB17473E543"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Applications for the export of liquefied natural gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Natural Gas Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/717b">15 U.S.C. 717b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HFBEFBFE1C4FA47D3902DD88921B6017E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking subsections (a) through (c);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5EA58AA65BEA48498A7CF7DD860BC647"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (e) and (f) as subsections (a) and (b), respectively;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1DD0D88E705B44EF8EFBE94AD63CE9DF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (d) as subsection (c), and moving such subsection after subsection (b), as so redesignated;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E3D8DEFBFC146F881B3C44C3D0919A0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in subsection (a), as so redesignated, by amending paragraph (1) to read as follows: <quote>(1) The Commission shall have the exclusive authority to approve or deny an application for the siting, construction, expansion, or operation of a facility to export natural gas from the United States to a foreign country or import natural gas from a foreign country, including an LNG terminal. Except as specifically provided in this Act, nothing in this Act is intended to affect otherwise applicable law related to any Federal agency’s authorities or responsibilities related to facilities to import or export natural gas, including LNG terminals.</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57B79D2FCB0B49C19B911A523297314D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H61AF03898D504EC2B06685F6D3C1D62F" style="OLC"><subsection id="H7866926EBA74429A91924E8368738621"><enum>(d)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF8A566E8C707404EAFC8836C77973345"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Nothing in this Act limits the authority of the President under the Constitution, the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>), the National Emergencies Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1601">50 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), part B of title II of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6271">42 U.S.C. 6271 et seq.</external-xref>), the Trading With the Enemy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4301">50 U.S.C. 4301 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other provision of law that imposes sanctions on a foreign person or foreign government (including any provision of law that prohibits or restricts United States persons from engaging in a transaction with a sanctioned person or government), including a country that is designated as a state sponsor of terrorism, to prohibit imports or exports of natural gas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B902988D74F485EB8F2453B5ABF2DE3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In this subsection, the term <term>state sponsor of terrorism</term> means a country the government of which the Secretary of State determines has repeatedly provided support for acts of international terrorism pursuant to—</text><subparagraph id="HD7BEFC702D884712A848D231E2127874"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 1754(c)(1)(A) of the Export Control Reform Act of 2018 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/4318">50 U.S.C. 4318(c)(1)(A)</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1C04BCB74D14E6CB99F74019DC0C799"><enum>(B)</enum><text>section 620A of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2371">22 U.S.C. 2371</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3226682A267A45328C263090A6EDC0E5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 40 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2780">22 U.S.C. 2780</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H856C36EB87194B25A6F1043D2041ED06"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other provision of law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD643D4D0369246C282C99817FF664942"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategic petroleum reserve</header><text>Section 161 of the Energy Policy and Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6241">42 U.S.C. 6241</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H0BE88C5EFA764B76B782BA97F69D60BD" style="OLC"><subsection id="H56DDC13E86144211A5DE40E3A3010F29"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Plan</header><paragraph id="H306B80CA19A642888EC4598FCC62F3B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except in the case of a severe energy supply interruption described in subsection (d), the Secretary may not execute the first drawdown of petroleum products in the Reserve after the date of enactment of this subsection, whether through sale, exchange, or loan, until the Secretary has developed a plan to increase the percentage of Federal lands (including submerged lands of the Outer Continental Shelf) under the jurisdiction of the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of Energy, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Defense leased for oil and gas production by the same percentage as the percentage of petroleum in the Strategic Petroleum Reserve that is to be drawn down in that first and subsequent drawdowns, subject to the limitation under paragraph (2).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6EF2DD19778044488A96715F1346061E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>The plan required by paragraph (1) shall not provide for a total increase in the percentage of Federal lands described in paragraph (1) leased for oil and gas production in excess of 10 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38C6AA279F1E44E381213EDCF7BAE0F2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Secretary shall prepare the plan required by paragraph (1) in consultation with the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of the Interior, and the Secretary of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H790D4C8E33CC4BB3876AC537E84A34EA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Keystone xL pipeline</header><paragraph id="HC828B692BB494A4AA01E927942F06F4A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>TransCanada Keystone Pipeline, L.P. may construct, connect, operate, and maintain the pipeline facilities at the international border of the United States and Canada at Phillips County, Montana, for the import of oil from Canada to the United States as described in the Presidential Permit of March 29, 2019 (84 Fed. Reg. 13101 (April 3, 2019)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4441F3415A5A4CA799E688F5CCE1AA61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Presidential permits</header><text>No Presidential permit or any other Executive order shall be required for the construction, connection, operation, or maintenance of the pipeline facilities described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

