<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC0D1DDA2FED6483B89F2C28E1778067B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>95 HR 6451 IH: Chiricahua National Park Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6451</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000368">Mrs. Kirkpatrick</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the Chiricahua National Park in the State of Arizona as a unit of the National Park System, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD55A1BC7459E4964A3980B23661F8EBF" style="OLC"><section id="HD65A5B0FD1B74524A797E29F22FA6D41" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Chiricahua National Park Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC9699BE564794966842B1DB7781CB7EC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H2954CBF4A9C34249A7B384DE18D14B2D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Tribal commission established under section 4(c).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44D4A7DC14694DCF8C95B8A7DA3461AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian Tribe</header><text>The term <quote>Indian Tribe</quote> has the meaning given the term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA8017F3D429D48EC9FF60DC9C00D6640"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Monument</header><text>The term <quote>Monument</quote> means the Chiricahua National Monument established by Presidential Proclamation 1692 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/320301">54 U.S.C. 320301</external-xref> note; 43 Stat. 1946).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H437998A6CD5F4A288FC6D7C81843D666"><enum>(4)</enum><header>National park</header><text>The term <quote>National Park</quote> means the Chiricahua National Park established by section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BF16D20D42246188F448E3456DFEDBD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAC68107E2524C78B92E93C227ED559E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <quote>State</quote> means the State of Arizona.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H0F49EA26DFBA4503B71A3B67A24898DF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Designation of chiricahua national park</header><subsection id="HDA43351EBB904BCDB771CB3D1056A333"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To protect, preserve, and interpret the rhyolitic rock formations, biodiversity, and other natural and cultural resources of the area, the Chiricahua National Monument in the State shall be known and designated as the <quote>Chiricahua National Park</quote>.</text><paragraph id="HEAC6322D585F48A9AA43C28C1A75ADD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Incorporation</header><text>The land and any interest in land that constitute the Monument (as in existence on the day before the date of the enactment of this Act) are incorporated in, and shall be considered to be part of, the National Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C3D0CF5E5FC4EE88F5122FC20F8D78A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Any funds available for the Monument shall be available for the National Park.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DC4A692F54B4EEDAAEFF6C522442BAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Boundaries</header><paragraph id="H1EB945695A7F4CCFB384C5071118F227"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundaries of the National Park are as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Chiricahua National Park Proposed Boundary</quote>, numbered 145/156,356, and dated March 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B00264AD8EC410FBC7EDE930937122A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF963BC38FECF4751BF3ADC86E150C58D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><paragraph id="HC7B276C1942748778462D79D0DFF64D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the <quote>Chiricahua National Monument</quote> shall be deemed to be a reference to the <quote>Chiricahua National Park</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B3DCB9953694FD483C854BE8F4FEDE1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Wilderness</header><text>Any reference in a law, map, regulation, document, paper, or other record of the United States to the <quote>Chiricahua National Monument Wilderness</quote> designated by <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/94/567">Public Law 94–567</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1132">16 U.S.C. 1132</external-xref> note; 90 Stat. 2692) shall be considered to be a reference to the <quote>Chiricahua National Park Wilderness</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H584D8BD6504A4B9C9EC651EEDB932434"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Administration</header><text>The Secretary shall administer the Park in accordance with—</text><subparagraph id="H326585CCCF41493DA9E79BF8ABF5B457"><enum>(A)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H770B1CBB05184BDE9A32FD225427A628"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HEC7585D9EB1A4EA6BD5528A165720662"><enum>4.</enum><header>Management of Chiricahua National Park</header><subsection id="HA147152658C844169FE73894A7E578C3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Traditional cultural and religious sites</header><paragraph id="H684A50358E7F4D269277B8394B6BA066"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with Indian Tribes, shall ensure the protection of traditional cultural and religious sites in the National Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7CE0A697843489EA95414F839A51B9C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Access</header><text>The Secretary, in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996 et seq.</external-xref>) shall ensure access to the sites described in paragraph (1) by members of Indian Tribes for traditional, cultural, religious, and customary uses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H69A8F07634F5439F890FDB119B5F935D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Temporary closures</header><subparagraph id="H8FF1A3DC8F5C41D0BAD162071AC64158"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary, on request of an Indian Tribe, may temporarily close to the general public one or more specific portions of the National Park to protect traditional cultural and customary uses in the area by members of the Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H766EE4AF13384F098E554C47C7C80A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>Any closure under subparagraph (A) shall be—</text><clause id="H813A80FF9800452486500587E69DAEAC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>made in such a manner as to affect the smallest practicable area for the minimum time necessary for the activity to be carried out; and</text></clause><clause id="HE742718339504DDABD0A045AEB57EBF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>be consistent with the purpose and intent of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/95/341">Public Law 95–341</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>American Indian Religious Freedom Act</quote>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1996">42 U.S.C. 1996</external-xref>) and the Wilderness Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1131">16 U.S.C. 1131 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0A0F85EA2A124FAB81CD2CE4DD6ACD72"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Collection of plants and mineral resources by members of culturally affiliated indian tribes</header><paragraph id="H8809BA8AE3B04686B85682086A3CF48C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall allow an enrolled member of any Indian Tribe that is culturally affiliated with the land located within the boundaries of the National Park to collect plants, including parts or products of plants, and mineral resources within the National Park for noncommercial traditional, religious, customary, and cultural uses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AA365243128463DB1ED5FBD61F2D5CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="HB4F77B01E22841059EE086717FEDE740"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a collection activity under paragraph (1) shall be—</text><clause id="H73E59FB21A5E49CB97DDDB18FB842B9C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>consistent with applicable laws; and</text></clause><clause id="H677DBDBBE4A64364A32CD9907B702FE2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subject to such conditions as the Secretary determines to be necessary to protect the resources and values of the National Park.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2BBF6676FC3B4CBEA69DFCFC43526CE1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Quantity limitations</header><clause id="H4FF571F7601541718A789FB26D8C4796"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Existing regulations</header><text>No quantity limitation contained in a regulation of the National Park Service in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act shall apply to a collection activity under paragraph (1).</text></clause><clause id="HF75219804B864769AE945BFEC4336672"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitations imposed by secretary</header><text>The Secretary may limit the quantity of plants, including parts or products of plants, and mineral resources collected under paragraph (1) if the Secretary determines, through consultation with the Commission, that the limitation is necessary to protect the resources and values of the National Park.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDEC583EE3CA48399267A9D14867D784"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Tribal commission</header><paragraph id="HFB07D6D9331E4A539528D564CFA3433A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>To ensure that the management of the National Park reflects the expertise and traditional and historical knowledge of members of applicable Indian Tribes, the Secretary shall establish a Tribal commission for the National Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA45A7BD379BC4920992FAAD258C694EB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The commission shall provide guidance and recommendations on the development and implementation of the management plans for, and the policies of, the National Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D91E879A634405D950CC8959437EDB4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The commission shall consist of 1 representative designated by the governing body of each Indian Tribe with a historical association with the area within the boundaries of the National Park.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03504789A6B247798F81E24E2C22B925"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Incorporation of recommendations</header><text>In developing plans and policies for the National Park, the Secretary shall carefully and fully consider incorporating the traditional and historical knowledge and special expertise of members of the commission or a comparable entity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H504CB65043D04417AE5BAEDE5E548A6F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Written explanation</header><text>If the Secretary determines not to incorporate a specific recommendation submitted to the Secretary in writing by the commission, the Secretary shall provide to the commission a written explanation of the reason for the determination.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCE01DA6617184897A713316F03E0C4B9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Withdrawal from federal mining and mineral leasing laws</header><paragraph id="H1FEBE759F4354CF2948FF1594DEFB7A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Subject to valid existing rights in effect on the date of the enactment of this Act, the land located within the boundaries of the National Park is withdrawn from—</text><subparagraph id="H94D4EBFCFB094F6087BF5C9A15152EB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE2DC31E2B6843C1904B98F7F8505A94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>disposition under all laws pertaining to mineral and geothermal leasing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1492A51BC4A4BECBE7FA28AAF0D4FE5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Acquired land</header><text>Any land or interest in land that is acquired by the United States after the date of the enactment of this Act for inclusion in the National Park, shall, on acquisition, be immediately withdrawn in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H280115048133483DA9006DDFCF83FC56"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>Nothing in this subsection affects any recreational use, including hunting or fishing, that is authorized on the land within the boundaries of the National Park under applicable law as of the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

