<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA87D441DF0BD434597426BF6C045A5AB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7688 IH: Consumer Fuel Price Gouging Prevention Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7688</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220506">May 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To protect consumers from price-gouging of consumer fuels, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB1D8DC7CCBDE48A2994EB8783A8C463E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5964990BCAAA465993E886A301B306E2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Consumer Fuel Price Gouging Prevention Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC51FEF9F176F45098CD09AFA0E90B8FF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Unconscionable pricing of consumer fuels during emergencies</header> <subsection id="HE93D459AE9694A75B8C77E9CF601D7BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Unconscionable pricing</header> <paragraph id="HB402ACB7DDD544F0A7F4F13ACF974471"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be unlawful for any person to sell a consumer fuel, at wholesale or retail, in an area and during a period of an energy emergency covered by a proclamation issued under paragraph (2) at a price that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H126F8116B4FD42E69BBD4714E11D4FDE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is unconscionably excessive; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA7B9650767DF4903B5A232B3939EFAA1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicates the seller is exploiting the circumstances related to an energy emergency to increase prices unreasonably.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFF0B353153374338BA41ECC3497D09C6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy emergency proclamation</header> 
<subparagraph id="H32B40CD60BF3464D975CF4C6C40C7238"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The President may issue an energy emergency proclamation for any area within the jurisdiction of the United States, during which the prohibition in paragraph (1) shall apply, that includes the geographic area covered, the consumer fuel covered, and the time period that such proclamation shall be in effect.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBC43C2764BA34B4CB2BAEE9A966020E5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The proclamation—</text> 
<clause id="H28FAC7575C864E50B26BA3477C6AAF41"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not apply for a period of more than 30 consecutive days, but may be renewed for such consecutive periods, each not to exceed 30 days, as the President determines appropriate; and</text></clause> <clause id="H675D2C4F869E4E3D9F72952E0D983839" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include a period of time not to exceed 1 week before a reasonably foreseeable emergency. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13A8EDF12E6C419D8F20420CA010B039"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Factors considered</header> 
<subparagraph id="HBBCA5D4A79BC4FC49A37D94A87AF34C7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In determining whether a person has violated paragraph (1), there shall be taken into account, among other factors, the aggravating factors described in subparagraph (B) and the mitigating factor described in subparagraph (C).</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA8D8693B2E924BD4A4F86F1356023B51"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Aggravating factors</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The aggravating factors described in this subparagraph are the following:</text> 
<clause id="H07998ACDB3E34499BEC9004852EA3C4C"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the amount charged by such person grossly exceeds the average price at which the consumer fuel was offered for sale by such person during—</text> <subclause id="H83119F043F534271A65D94A447E3FEDB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the 30-day period before the date on which the proclamation was issued; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H139B4232271048A2AB1E1149154A4362"><enum>(II)</enum><text>another appropriate benchmark period, as determined by the Commission.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H9CA3EE9B5F0C409393783CB4E5C1BD2E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Whether the amount charged by such person grossly exceeds the price at which the same or a similar consumer fuel was readily obtainable in the same area from other sellers during the energy emergency period.</text></clause> </subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8B2383E84BA64BF2BDDF86B5C77C6E8A" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Mitigating factor</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The mitigating factor described in this subparagraph is whether the quantity of any consumer fuel such person produced, distributed, or sold in an area covered by the proclamation during the 30-day period following the date on which the proclamation was issued increased over the quantity such person produced, distributed, or sold during the 30-day period before the date on which the proclamation was issued, taking into account any usual seasonal demand variation.</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="H5B9BC02EB5FA4C3191BD44E4590B41EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Affirmative defense</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be an affirmative defense in any civil action or administrative action to enforce subsection (a), with respect to the sale, at wholesale or retail, of a consumer fuel by a person, that the increase in the price of such consumer fuel reasonably reflects additional costs that were paid, incurred, or reasonably anticipated by such person, or reasonably reflects additional risks taken by such person, to produce, distribute, obtain, or sell such consumer fuel under the circumstances.</text> </subsection> 
<subsection id="H2057641EE34C4B3EB3DC3CB58B68A1B3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This section may not be construed to cover a transaction on a futures market.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H627AA3CE1F704384A34904408F5FAD52"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enforcement</header> <paragraph id="H46D927587D0A46D78F324A7F861F6C33"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Federal Trade Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A violation of subsection (a) shall be treated as a violation of a rule defining an unfair or deceptive act or practice prescribed under section 18(a)(1)(B) of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/57a">15 U.S.C. 57a(a)(1)(B)</external-xref>). The Federal Trade Commission shall enforce this section in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act were incorporated into and made a part of this section. In enforcing subsection (a), the Commission shall give priority to enforcement actions concerning companies with total United States wholesale or retail sales of consumer fuels in excess of $500,000,000 per year.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H09D2D18DA3344882BFBC39B71DD6C9CF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Enforcement at retail level by State attorneys general</header> 
<subparagraph id="HFED77112A49E4A1FB119111383A3226A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the chief law enforcement officer of a State, or an official or agency designated by a State, has reason to believe that any person has violated or is violating subsection (a) involving a retail sale, the attorney general, official, or agency of the State, in addition to any authority it may have to bring an action in State court under its laws, may bring a civil action in any appropriate United States district court or in any other court of competent jurisdiction to—</text> <clause id="H1F81E68EA168438F9E69F3B1F7468FC1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>enjoin further such violation by such person;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9B2B0F1B2FD342D19D43465F8617A908"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>enforce compliance with such subsection;</text></clause> <clause id="H7AC3F50C613340719A161D9695A812EE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>obtain civil penalties; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4F09EEA0037E459EA92CD02A5D111278"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>obtain damages, restitution, or other compensation on behalf of residents of the State.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA3047E1C4C0D46ACB042B082EB92012B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notice</header><text>The State shall serve written notice to the Commission of any civil action under subparagraph (A) before initiating such civil action. The notice shall include a copy of the complaint to be filed to initiate such civil action, except that if it is not feasible for the State to provide such prior notice, the State shall provide such notice immediately upon instituting such civil action.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4EC2FA785FEE482F86E6D41892430A60"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Authority to intervene</header><text>Upon receipt of the notice required by subparagraph (B), the Commission may intervene in such civil action and upon intervening—</text> <clause id="H653E61C346124A3893EC3522E0988327"><enum>(i)</enum><text>be heard on all matters arising in such civil action; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H4ADC81E917E14EF991F829AE2D721F93"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>file petitions for appeal of a decision in such civil action.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H90047D79C82A4F3B815D2BB4A50339C5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Construction</header><text>For purposes of bringing any civil action under subparagraph (A), nothing in this paragraph shall prevent the attorney general of a State from exercising the powers conferred on the attorney general by the laws of such State to conduct investigations or to administer oaths or affirmations or to compel the attendance of witnesses or the production of documentary and other evidence.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2463295AB6C540DFA81CE7747E9A22EE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Limitation on State action while Federal action is pending</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Commission has instituted a civil action or an administrative action for violation of subsection (a), a State attorney general, or official or agency of a State, may not bring an action under this paragraph during the pendency of that action against any defendant named in the complaint of the Commission or another agency for any violation of this Act alleged in the complaint.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDA6A361444524FB8A49EAE72431F1276"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>This paragraph may not be construed to prohibit an authorized State official from proceeding in State court to enforce a civil or criminal statute of such State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H68F91AD46AFE456680C5A82BA6FE002D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Low income energy assistance</header> 
<paragraph id="HB351D9702F4B41F98BA1C03581CF0B4D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Deposit of funds</header><text>Amounts collected in any penalty under subsection (d)(1) shall be deposited in a separate fund in the Treasury to be known as the Consumer Relief Trust Fund.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAAF443D65A68455F9151518229E56C2C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent provided for in advance in appropriations Acts, the amounts deposited into the fund shall be used to provide assistance under the Low Income Home Energy Assistance Program described in section 2602 of the Low-Income Home Energy Assistance Act of 1981 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8621">42 U.S.C. 8621</external-xref>) administered by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Weatherization Assistance Program established under part A of title IV of the Energy Conservation and Production Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6861">42 U.S.C. 6861 et seq.</external-xref>) administered by the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H6D02C5325DF84E128A00DEE3D0D9090F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Effect on other laws</header> 
<paragraph id="H1CEA8F9274AE447C8FB542DC8EA02C2E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Other authority of Commission</header><text>Nothing in this section may be construed to limit the authority of the Commission under the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>) or any other provision of law.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H47E05CD4BC0149588998D0E986C8C338"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State law</header><text>Nothing in this section preempts any State law.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H7C088FA22DD2485FB661DCB8DEA703A9"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H64F9E7535582478490D3EAEB7CC878D0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Trade Commission. </text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8BE28ED3688B41D19513CFD13DF35C66"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consumer fuel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>consumer fuel</quote> includes gasoline, distillate fuel oil, jet fuel, liquid propane, aviation gasoline, compressed natural gas, and biofuel (including ethanol, biomass-based diesel, and renewable blending components) used for transportation fuels, and home heating oil and liquid propane used for residential heating or residential energy generation.</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H4C807774505446C89CF5C026B6FBB87E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Retail</header><text>The term <quote>retail</quote>, with respect to the sale of a consumer fuel, includes all sales to end users such as motorists as well as all direct sales to other end users such as agriculture, industry, residential, and commercial consumers.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD9A68A96BA5643BA9CCBF961B47A58B8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Wholesale</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>wholesale</quote>, with respect to the sale of a consumer fuel, means sale to any person for resale.</text></paragraph> </subsection> </section> </legis-body></bill>

