<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1270595655744CDFBD6C1DDFBDE62F8E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8138 IH: Lake Champlain Basin Program Reauthorization Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-16</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8138</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220616">June 16, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to reauthorize and modify the Lake Champlain Basin Program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5B6AF0E434A249F981D9C5BFD01E061E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H4AF3E7C91E214DA4B0AFD39516E0C0C4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lake Champlain Basin Program Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HD3339C6AD5044BD294DC27A809C0A503"><enum>2.</enum><header>Lake Champlain Basin Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 120 of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1270">33 U.S.C. 1270</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block id="H7F8ABDB8BAF14979984BA39895698E95" style="OLC" act-name=""> 
<section id="H1D13D8F21379426C8EAF0BFA989BCE82" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>120.</enum><header>Lake Champlain Basin Program</header> 
<subsection id="HD275EF0B1AF240BEB9008001BFF4FB6C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="H4B39F152C30648A3BC64631EC6CBA36D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership</header><text>The term <term>Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership</term> means the Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership established by section 284(a) of the Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/54/320101">54 U.S.C. 320101</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/338">Public Law 109–338</external-xref>). </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF612CEB0BBB94F3FBDE258C707FBC3F1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Education and Outreach Committee</header> 
<subparagraph id="HA99E6F8D8ABA452BB7CFBB35DBEC20FC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Education and Outreach Committee</term> means a committee established by the Steering Committee to provide objective information and funding recommendations to the Steering Committee upon request to be used in the decisionmaking process of the Steering Committee, including—</text> <clause id="HDEF3CD9C580D44B4BEFD8FC3B828371D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>funding recommendations relating to educational and outreach opportunities and issues; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H58B3D776882944C9977281B7CC1C7D73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>programmatic actions needed to address those educational or outreach opportunities or issues.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H50A33804B9B746CDA412FB0C2464D119" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>Education and Outreach Advisory Committee</term> includes a committee described in subparagraph (A) established before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Lake Champlain Basin Program Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H000C7888244643B99E1B6D24462DC83F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fiscal agent</header><text>The term <term>fiscal agent</term> means an organization that is responsible for fiscal and administrative management of the Program under the direction of the Steering Committee and the Administrator.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EA8B3A7D8A64329AA24C8AC6D0A17C0"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>The term <term>Foundation</term> means the Lake Champlain Basin Program Foundation that may be established pursuant to subsection (d)(1).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HCCA6E32088DC4324830F552E9C52A4FB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Lake Champlain Basin</header><text>The term <term>Lake Champlain Basin</term> means Lake Champlain and the natural watershed of Lake Champlain, including all land, streams, rivers, lakes, and other bodies of water in the United States and Canada that naturally drain into Lake Champlain, including all or a portion of—</text> <subparagraph id="H21E7606C27BD4410915F31016BFD4235"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the counties of Clinton, Franklin, Warren, Essex, and Washington in the State of New York; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H180EAFA483034D8F96BFB34AEEA1EEFC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the counties of Franklin, Grand Isle, Chittenden, Addison, Rutland, Bennington, Lamoille, Orange, Washington, Orleans, and Caledonia in the State of Vermont.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5A3B5A6713DA4B438349945B279075DF"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Lake Champlain Citizens Advisory Committee</header> <subparagraph id="HA208B8E5252E4225B80E4C8E1F61F35F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Lake Champlain Citizens Advisory Committee</term> means a committee in the State of Vermont, the State of New York, and, if the Province of Quebec elects to participate, the Province of Quebec, established by the Governor or executive officer of the State or province, as applicable, to advise on the protection and restoration of Lake Champlain.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H57DD494E5CAD485398D0127785B5ECF5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>Lake Champlain Citizens Advisory Committee</term> includes a committee described in subparagraph (A) established before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Lake Champlain Basin Program Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H604CA10384E140B79267618BE4103928"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>The term <term>Plan</term> means the comprehensive pollution prevention, ecosystem protection and restoration, and climate change response plan adopted and published under subsection (e)(1), including any revisions to that plan.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H094C79AE195C4DA1BE5821D9DC066E41"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Program</header><text>The term <term>Program</term> means the Lake Champlain Basin Program established by subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0E47FB081F354081B709193A50D46862"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Steering committee</header><text>The term <term>Steering Committee</term> means the Steering Committee established and maintained under the most recent Memorandum of Understanding on Environmental Cooperation on the Management of Lake Champlain entered into between the State of New York, the State of Vermont, and, if the Province of Quebec elects to participate, the Province of Quebec, as modified pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H943D479716594DEB937D13DFE77B4793"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Technical Advisory Committee</header> 
<subparagraph id="H8452AC72A7DB4836B754322629EC7E9F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>Technical Advisory Committee</term> means a committee established by the Steering Committee to provide objective information and funding recommendations to the Steering Committee upon request to be used in the decisionmaking process of the Steering Committee, including—</text> <clause id="H12C3D673A20C4D72BC5842EAA8C1AA3C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>funding recommendations relating to technical and scientific management issues; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HEC7A73B3850F433F83B93D448B80D6F4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>research or actions needed to address those technical or scientific management issues.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8635FBA5B8C747F0B4EDD2AC8D7DCB13" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion</header><text>The term <term>Technical Advisory Committee</term> includes a committee described in subparagraph (A) established before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Lake Champlain Basin Program Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8FF12F14E0F7499880CC491E3BE8F406"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="HC4B547C6AF6649C78CC2EA10BB58A462"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established a program within the Environmental Protection Agency, to be known as the <quote>Lake Champlain Basin Program</quote>, that shall coordinate efforts among the Federal Government, applicable State governments, applicable local governments, the Province of Quebec (if the Province of Quebec elects to participate), and other partners to develop, adopt, and implement the Plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DA1479EF2DA48F3BD0CE60084581C03"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>In implementing the Program, the Administrator—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H615992BF35914C75B6ADB9466A847A28"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may, with no competitive process, provide support to the State of Vermont, the State of New York, and the Foundation; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H59761C640F284DC38D417333680836F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall coordinate actions of the Environmental Protection Agency under subparagraph (A) with the actions of other appropriate Federal agencies.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H45906F61F2DB4AE3A06184735E9BFFD7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Steering committee</header> 
<paragraph id="H1CF7B6718D094338B4FCCFF4E2EA7E0D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maintenance</header><text>The Steering Committee shall assist in carrying out and overseeing the Program and the Plan.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0A113EA3C4BE4CBA8988D4C97AC176EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header> <subparagraph id="H5C25171F1B1141B696C356BEE28C1E47"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Each of the following shall be a member of the Steering Committee:</text> 
<clause id="H3928A30305E24EAF9BE403AFF381B4D6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The highest level official (or a designee) of each of the following:</text> <subclause id="HFA2A9C0ADCBE4A53A0E3139E3FC7435F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The State environmental agency of the State of New York.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H59F3ACC9A2FE43E4B991CDDE1F46FDB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text>The State environmental agency of the State of Vermont.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4D4B6D9E59584B9DA2B7C4B19A5FF59A"><enum>(III)</enum><text>The Ministry for the Environment of the Province of Quebec, if that ministry elects to participate. </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H31F6D1CF960C45B5B3FF789C402AA88C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A representative of—</text> <subclause id="H39467A5D0B6C4F2DA1533B59FD95EEF1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the State agriculture agency from each of the States of New York and Vermont; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HBFC92AC24065461291F4756BB6C78C63"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Quebec Agricultural Ministry, if that ministry elects to participate.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HF6C79FBC30F44D2298E2434CA309CDDC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The State Historic Preservation Officer from each of the States of New York and Vermont, or a designee of that officer.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9F41FCB81AC544D0851D6C6974258AB7"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>6 representatives of units of local government entirely within the Lake Champlain Basin, of which—</text> <subclause id="H91098D2D53AF49B5A56F76FEC5FDBF8E"><enum>(I)</enum><text>2 shall be representatives of units of local government in the State of New York;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H4B1F859444324C6787C50A985E7247BC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>2 shall be representatives of units of local government in the State of Vermont; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H9A4034293FE941EFBC9108CF70BB93FD" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>2 shall be representatives of units of local government in the Province of Quebec, if the Province of Quebec elects to send representatives.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="H42887ABCB3404D429B75D7AF15263887"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The chairperson of—</text> <subclause id="H276AEA592085403F8E072CEC8F3E4E7C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Lake Champlain Citizens Advisory Committee of the State of New York;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H88C3A26A16D14352B8608706CD20B06D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Lake Champlain Citizens Advisory Committee of the State of Vermont; and</text></subclause> <subclause id="H5A47823125A8457F9D930C68FA609A65"><enum>(III)</enum><text>if the Province of Quebec elects to participate, the Lake Champlain Citizens Advisory Committee of the Province of Quebec.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HDBA597B09C0E49DBAE0A3A906D21EDBA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>The chairperson of the Technical Advisory Committee.</text></clause> <clause id="HCAD19F8146974517A5F026678F41DAB2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>The chairperson of the Education and Outreach Committee.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H8D455BC6AC9A49ED8F02D287E12DC52D"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>The chairperson of the advisory committee for the Champlain Valley National Heritage Partnership.</text></clause> <clause id="H32E4F75D129343418A3395384B30F1ED"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>A representative from each of—</text> 
<subclause id="HE17BEB20E1954FE8B11AC63897DE3DBC"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the Region 1 office of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subclause> <subclause id="H3979AC91857D435BBE8FA043126819EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the Region 2 office of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8A1681C6A5354D5BA779D9A9FB5468A1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Region 5 of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HF5FB5914F4D64E8087EB98790A5518C4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the Natural Resources Conservation Service New York State office;</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H3D535EA32BDE4D5EBED2F4C80E770A49"><enum>(V)</enum><text>the Natural Resources Conservation Service Vermont State office;</text></subclause> <subclause id="HFF5978B8D55D42FDA6AE489FF3C13C18"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>the National Park Service; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HCEC71682F4B244AFA5098CF786C57CEA"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>the New York District of the Corps of Engineers.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HA7E1FA7E49184F1F9D35053ECC4C40B0"><enum>(x)</enum><text>The Director of the Lake Champlain Sea Grant Institute.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H19597C1025E340C6ABD55D48877FC169"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>A representative of the Great Lakes Fishery Commission.</text></clause> <clause id="H19A604B3F31A46EB96EAF84584CDACC5"><enum>(xii)</enum><text>Such additional members as may be confirmed by the Steering Committee. </text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0BC14DBCE37E497C8268472E1339FDB8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The position of chairperson of the Steering Committee shall regularly rotate among the members of the Steering Committee described in subparagraph (A)(i). </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA2FD308CD6B4D3D9F70CC8AA19CC8B7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Ratification</header><text>Any actions of the Steering Committee taken before the date of enactment of the <short-title>Lake Champlain Basin Program Reauthorization Act of 2022</short-title> are ratified and confirmed.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HD78E051D4A5A4B72B6AFD297D8C502CD"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Lake Champlain Basin Program Foundation</header> 
<paragraph id="H3D90E7625AB144F1968284E511F5FC77"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Administrator and the Steering Committee may, in the discretion of the Administrator and by a vote of the Steering Committee, jointly establish a foundation, to be known as the <quote>Lake Champlain Basin Foundation</quote>, as a charitable and nonprofit corporation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1FD75953967840BC93B654722C813868"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Not an agency</header><text>If established under paragraph (1), the Foundation shall not be an agency or establishment of the United States.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0709E01E6E644969B496E61E15BBD419"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text>The purposes of the Foundation, if established under paragraph (1), are—</text> <subparagraph id="H84CFE452CB574FDBBF1835BC0DDD4383"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to undertake and conduct activities that support—</text> 
<clause id="H13808EF624C74A448D80AE3F548F4E5C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the work of the Program; and</text></clause> <clause id="H745033590910430FAD88C1DEF06CD2E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the purposes of this section;</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFEFB8979AC4F423EA3A8F02B2DF390EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to accept and manage funds of the Foundation for the implementation of the Plan, including—</text> <clause id="HF881C841B3AB4082BE03B98DA8B95461"><enum>(i)</enum><text>amounts made available to the Foundation by the Administrator; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H3390CBF51BF64260858C29F3F40A31EF"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>amounts made available to Federal agencies under subsection (i)(2) for transfer to the Foundation;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9936868C9A294D8BBEB98C32826D8FBD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to make subgrants, enter into contracts, and administer funds of the Foundation to carry out activities described in subparagraph (A); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H82DE96136F834D2C90DA2ABDF5211403"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to participate with, and otherwise assist, Canada and the Province of Quebec in undertaking and conducting activities that further the work of the Program in fulfilling the purposes of this section and implementing the Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE3E1914ADD9E477F92AFBC280788F736"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Board of Directors</header> <subparagraph id="HDC6993672C9348738B8D7497613717DD"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If the Foundation is established under paragraph (1), the Foundation shall be governed by a board of directors (referred to in this subsection as the <quote>Board</quote>).</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H67159A6C100A45B190A4ED47AB1EA69A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>Members of the Board shall include—</text> <clause id="H8053CBD27AA4490997E81B97B9D1E3F3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each member of the Steering Committee, unless the member declines to serve on the Board; and </text></clause> 
<clause id="H3899A68CBCB045548A9F7F7DB431A8A0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>such additional members as may be appointed by the Steering Committee.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF506E4547F8F454E9AB79AE61E1FC422"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Recusal</header><text>Members of the Steering Committee may recuse themselves from votes on the Board.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H079322C6B73E4087A3209EA0E688A082"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Withdrawal</header><text>Members of the Board, including members of the Steering Committee that serve as members of the Board, may withdraw from membership on the Board.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H00104F3024DE46DBA4C1CB47CB0EFF9C"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>Members appointed to the Board under subparagraph (B)(ii) may be removed by the Steering Committee.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H38862D7B3F2B462F867D89A44B595B29"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Powers of the Foundation</header><text>Subject to any conditions imposed on the Foundation by the Steering Committee and subject to approval by the Board, the Foundation may—</text> <subparagraph id="HF78C4E173C6D41698350C4A0100BBE98"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive funds, including funds made available to Federal agencies under subsection (i)(2) for transfer to the Foundation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HED2DA22077E446C996720A34577087C6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>retain staff;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB44E32BB8F194C0BA9B80239496464E1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>issue subgrants;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC58A9EFEA320497784E564F1D837A288"><enum>(D)</enum><text>enter into contracts;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B9858278EB44DA6A6B0222FA9D301D1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>own property; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HD8D38E883BED4204B6F43500256E16DD"><enum>(F)</enum><text>serve as fiscal agent for the Program, if selected to serve as the fiscal agent by the Administrator.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H350295A2513146E9836BD37EFED885F3"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Dissolution</header> <subparagraph id="H2F0A6FA835FF41CAA651AC7089968DAE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator and the Steering Committee may jointly dissolve the Foundation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H49897A8827164B51BF6C7640C97F2E01"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Return of funds</header><text>If the Administrator and the Steering Committee jointly dissolve the Foundation under subparagraph (A), during the dissolution process, the Foundation shall return all unobligated funds to each Federal agency that provided funds to the Foundation in a manner that is proportional to the amount of funds received from that Federal agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H342D6AA43645479394DE138390F2F24A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Pollution prevention, ecosystem protection and restoration, and climate change response plan</header> <paragraph id="HF46DA140B4E549D095F8842726B9C691"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Adoption</header> <subparagraph id="H08D9E18DFEEA4AFFA3E74928C681D658"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Steering Committee shall adopt and publish a comprehensive pollution prevention, ecosystem protection and restoration, and climate change response plan for Lake Champlain that protects and benefits the water quality, fisheries, wetlands, wildlife, and cultural resources of Lake Champlain and within the Lake Champlain basin.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H73B5C4BA5EA249D3892BC0A6783F2FD5"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The Plan shall include strategies to advance clean water, healthy ecosystems, thriving communities, and an informed and involved public in the Lake Champlain Basin with respect to Lake Champlain.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3B49D5A982E44ECAABAE52ABE0B4F899"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Revision</header> <clause id="HC69F5D8B4E3046DF99070880FE38832E"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Steering Committee shall update and readopt the Plan not less frequently than once every 10 years, but may update and readopt the Plan more frequently as necessary to implement the Program.</text></clause> 
<clause id="H461AD3D84A5E4FFAA3A7A48A02A5A23B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Goal</header><text>The Steering Committee shall have the goal of updating and readopting the Plan every 5 years.</text></clause> <clause id="H954CA81BD4B7410B819F102F952DAFD3"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effect</header><text>A Plan adopted by the Steering Committee shall remain in effect until readopted by the Steering Committee pursuant to clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H486F34DB580A49BE9B1F2720974E77DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Use of plan</header><text>The Plan shall guide the work of the Program.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H886BE3B618B949578AB2E43343C38744"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Grant assistance</header> <paragraph id="H69A876B85E4542EB9355508AB9A3612D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Implementation grants</header> <subparagraph id="H7BD5F4BEFD974641AB9A67FDE35218A5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may, in consultation with the Steering Committee, make grants to State, interstate, and regional water pollution control agencies and public or nonprofit agencies, institutions, and organizations for the purpose of implementing the Plan.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5D83781AB61A4E469B6D51BC3D7AA8C6"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Federal share</header> 
<clause id="H61E95A44FAF744F094F70257C106356A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to clause (ii), the amount of a grant under subparagraph (A) shall not exceed 75 percent of the cost of the research, survey, study, or other work to be carried out using grant funds.</text></clause> <clause id="H6194656E036C42E6BB789F3003855D78"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header> <subclause id="H0B009B82BC664833B57713065BDC4B5C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may, on a case-by-case basis and in consultation with the Steering Committee, increase the Federal share under clause (i) to 85 percent of the costs described in that clause.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H100661B7437B40FD96EEB5346B992B3C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>In carrying out subclause (I), the Administrator shall be guided by policy adopted by the Steering Committee.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1ACE79834C3A4A1F94B2BFA15FADF42C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Administrator may establish such requirements for the administration of grants under subparagraph (A) as the Administrator determines to be appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H02D4DDBCA292428082D4551CB755D3E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Fiscal agent grants</header> 
<subparagraph id="HF947C1660A2A41C28C81A3880F8C9B13"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator may award grants to a qualified entity to serve as a fiscal agent for purposes of oversight of the Program.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H02CFAFA25625422AB3DB47819E27452D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>The Administrator and the Steering Committee shall—</text> 
<clause id="HF2A8AAC0539D4BB7B2ED8AD8680A8113"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as necessary but not less frequently than once every 10 years, assess the effectiveness of the fiscal agent for the purposes described in subparagraph (A); and</text></clause> <clause id="HF4879E15A0F847ACAC8981F53ACCBAB7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if appropriate, select a new qualified entity through a competitive process to serve as a fiscal agent for the purposes described in that subparagraph.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HABEE4B868FEC49518C4A29EB7765E50A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>No competitive process</header> 
<clause id="H500F6FA6F8B6432DAE2FC94EE5E41C52"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>If the Foundation is established pursuant to subsection (d)(1) and is selected to serve as fiscal agent by the Administrator, the Administrator may award the grants under subparagraph (A) to the Foundation with no competitive process.</text></clause> <clause id="H0A36864D900D4E329C5FE0435CF65793"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Other entities</header><text>If a qualified entity is selected to serve as a fiscal agent through a competitive process pursuant to subparagraph (B)(ii), the Administrator may award grants under subparagraph (A) to the qualified entity with no competitive process.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE447683B98564516B6D1D71E0A731A7E" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Great Lakes Fishery Commission</header> 
<paragraph id="HB929E5AF326648C9918E9C4780189BF0" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Great Lakes Fishery Commission may undertake, fund, and support work on Lake Champlain, in the Lake Champlain Basin, and other areas within the Saint Lawrence River basin in Vermont, including through—</text> <subparagraph id="HFAAB5D1CC2F0419CBED04B139E6A7A1F" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>fisheries and aquatic ecosystem research, monitoring, restoration, and management;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H594F2C2B97204878A9AE6004350B0A9A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sea lamprey control;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H98A0DDEDE7314A8CBBA8023F9C034EEF" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>aquatic invasive species prevention and mitigation;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H1ED8691CE6264A288EF710B38F8B8776"><enum>(D)</enum><text>public engagement and education; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H5C6C6C57CA8548D58023E6219D66F546"><enum>(E)</enum><text>other work to implement the Plan.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3A3C3193021841C9812831E9178E6771" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Great Lakes Fishery Commission may work with the Program, the Foundation, Federal and State agencies, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, units of local government, and Canadian federal and Quebec provincial authorities. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2817833477D1470A834826A2927E3E39"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Savings provisions</header> <paragraph id="H8E2D5D59E4FE4060AF639030A38F51D8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No effect on certain authority</header><text>Nothing in this section—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H9D95EB52538A4462BA9AD58E91188069" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>affects the jurisdiction or powers of—</text> <clause id="HD2401C46E0A849C2B13E7531E3A96B27" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any department or agency of the Federal Government or any State government; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H9920B400C157429DAA7CD9C6D75E41E9" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>except as provided in subsection (g), any international organization or entity related to Lake Champlain created by treaty or memorandum to which the United States is a signatory;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H745BD50CF25340B3A804AE9587E3CB86" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>provides new regulatory authority for the Environmental Protection Agency; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8D7A05F8D5314F94988B68978E6983A6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>affects section 304 of the Great Lakes Critical Programs Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/1270">33 U.S.C. 1270</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/101/596">Public Law 101–596</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2C790AFFEE44F21A7247E50FBF7F67F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No effect on obligations</header><text>Nothing in this section affects the obligations of Canada, the Province of Quebec, or any agencies or representatives of Canada or the Province of Quebec referenced in this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA93B7D42BCD84AB9BDF9B52870803D12"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header> 
<paragraph id="HC6EDBABFD1B4431D8BACFA883BCA2193"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Environmental Protection Agency to carry out the Program $50,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2033.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0695D045754F4B42BECC938DD045CA9D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Foundation</header><text>If the Foundation is established pursuant to subsection (d)(1), there is authorized to be appropriated for each fiscal year beginning with the fiscal year during which the Foundation is established through fiscal year 2033 for transfer to the Foundation—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H873B707FE244404D94269A21F6702D5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$15,000,000 to the United States Fish and Wildlife Service;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B980317EF5548C38824108840CDA5FA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to the Natural Resources Conservation Service; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8C5DC9168F1B47CFADB9D692A1D47579"><enum>(C)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

