<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4A8ECDB0FC424AE7B4DAEFB86A84C051" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7537 IH: Help for Healing Communities Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7537</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220418">April 18, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="N000191">Mr. Neguse</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To amend title V of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use, to establish a program under which the Secretary will award grants to eligible entities to provide community-based mental health services in communities in which an active shooter event or incident of targeted violence occurred, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H24B2F35C40714F8AB1EFA8D86CA8F226" style="OLC">
<section id="H3428C88B18404B0AA874118DBDAA9D84" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Help for Healing Communities Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section> <section id="HB2FE1FA1ED224DD7ADB75A00DB8005FA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Community-based mental health services for gun violence survivors</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart 3 of part B of title V of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-31">42 U.S.C. 290bb–31 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 520A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/290bb-32">42 U.S.C. 290bb–32</external-xref>) the following: </text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H26A7223E825945779F6FF2DFEDBE1B1C" display-inline="no-display-inline">
<section id="HF5FCD3EE2A3646289C1583EA35924A3C"><enum>520A–1.</enum><header>Community-based mental health services for gun violence survivors</header>
<subsection id="HA1552D37C6124B239B14035D81D23737"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, acting through the Assistant Secretary (referred to in this section as the <quote>Secretary</quote>), shall establish a program under which the Secretary may award grants to eligible entities, to provide a means for communities in which an active shooter event or incident of targeted violence occurs—</text> <paragraph id="H2DA462D0BCF2418BA0BBED4E87180ADA"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to prioritize mental and behavioral health of survivors of active shooter events and incidents of targeted violence through establishing evidence-based, violence prevention, and community engagement programs to support survivors of such an event or incident; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H841F9325834C417094D97613A8C5F63F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to ensure equitable access to high-quality trauma-informed behavioral health services through the use of evidence-based materials, practices, programs and resources. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H177430D5D37147B88C9F9E154FA08AAE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An entity is eligible to receive a grant under this section if such entity is—</text>
<paragraph id="H5D50A2BD761D4E0FA7F661A11DFCC323"><enum>(1)</enum>
<subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HDFEED29D93E743D08C7AA9E52A0AF214"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a State, political subdivision of a State, an Indian Tribe, or Tribal organization (as such terms are defined in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act);</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9B81B55EE7D04CB091676A830F244986" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a health facility, or a program operated by, or in accordance with, a contract or grant with the Indian Health Service; or</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB88287DCC195414080C750979406914C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">another public or private nonprofit entity; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3004A9D4AD8848C0893DD0D2A0F59845"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">located in or serves a community in which an active shooter event or incident of targeted violence has occurred in the preceding fiscal year.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF31E204B02B8430688A12C0A7220AEB5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may use funds received under such grant to—</text> <paragraph id="HC488EFEF60204B0D8E2E2BACC6604D23"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide racially, culturally, linguistically, and gender-appropriate, evidence-based, and trauma-informed and trauma-competent psychological supports to individuals who have survived an active shooter event or incident of targeted violence;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7DCBF24669E4B8BAB4E843E50829BCB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">implement evidence-based violence prevention and community engagement programs; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEC499800410F4683AB707D8DE4565597"><enum>(3)</enum><text>implement programs to connect such survivors to the supports described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H0951E8CC751243D882A59F3822D8CB83"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Pre-Implementation report on selection process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days before the date on which the Secretary establishes the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall submit to Congress a report detailing the selection process the Secretary shall use in making grants under such program. </text></subsection> <subsection id="HC6F78A35A9FE4BE78ADD2A246FA41291"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text>
<paragraph id="HDC46E774FF2E413C9B4567F056BC8570"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assessment of the need for mental and behavioral health services for survivors of an active shooter event or incident of targeted violence in the community involved; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA4A8F20CD66410CA984FC46BE9BB18D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a plan to implement the activities described in subsection (c) during the period of the grant; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3EC77925C97C498BADA983813F6270E7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a cost assessment with respect to implementing such plan. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5558216550E648A7B87AAD8E3BA65AED"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Consultation and Assistance</header><text>In establishing the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H02EF980C132B4524B60B7875431FFF56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>consult with nationally recognized organizations that identify, support, and advocate for evidence-based, trauma-informed behavioral health services; </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF4375C64A61347A38E5BEDB63B2DCA5C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>consult with nationally recognized organizations—</text>
<subparagraph id="H5F8691D307FF4F21BFDCCF7373AA12A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with expertise in trauma-informed behavioral health services, mental and behavioral health, or violence interruption; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD91778CEC2F846E6974D91F3266C5D48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that identify, support, and advocate for evidence-based prevention of, and intervention for, trauma; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEE7BFE4716EC491E94C4BBB56D4140B1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to grant recipients with respect to the implementation and execution of activities supported by a grant under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H6FC1196D60454E81BB42F3EAA981D357"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Evaluation and report</header> <paragraph id="H2F5B92EAA6AD42A2B6C2B9D4B2CE50C6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the first grant is awarded and each year thereafter, the Secretary shall coordinate with the entities described in subsection (f)(2) to provide an evaluation of the success of the grant program. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE853E98B6FB040829D96316F135C8383"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the completion of each evaluation under paragraph (1), the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and make publicly available on the website of the Department of Health and Human Services, a report on such evaluation, including a recommendation on whether to continue or expand the program. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H934536ACDF6841A1BAD08E3F9D89CE05"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H73EAD9F48DAE49E48DE31051B5708BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <term>active shooter event</term> means an event in which an individual is actively engaged in the unauthorized killing or attempting to kill a person or persons in a confined and populated area using a firearm.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3CA04C678D5D4162BB4DB549961DCED6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <term>incident of targeted violence</term> means an incident of violence in which an assailant identified a particular target prior to such incident of violence, which may be one or more individuals, a class or category of individuals, or an institution, without regard to whether the chosen target was harmed during such incident.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H24EE877CDB1242DEBBA2C32CB2137C94"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The term <term>State</term> has the meaning given such term in section 534.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1BA8DDA1989143E4AEB437139F17BCF6"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $20,000,000, for the each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


