<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H72C671D8914642C78ADA1B7E7AE75C95" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9054 IH: End Lockdowns and Vaccine Mandates Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9054</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220929">September 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001211">Mrs. Miller of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000133">Mr. Van Drew</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Committee on Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To end COVID–19 lockdowns and COVID–19 vaccine mandates.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HE48C360724644F02B69EB060E520D7E4" style="OLC"><section id="H1C15F7CE94EA4FC9BD7ED99AC42DAB4B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Lockdowns and Vaccine Mandates Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF812A37A3A634DCB9F9C9AC5E9DBA4DE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H0D0CC4D33B4B4854BB6485937F96218B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">States and localities have violated the rights of American citizens to assemble by refusing them entry into churches, places of business, and entertainment venues.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H768C9F5943BC4A7D92A7EA1C735BD412"><enum>(2)</enum><text>States and localities have restricted the rights of American citizens by denying men and women the ability to earn a living and provide for a family through forced inoculation of the COVID–19 vaccine. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H1B3BCA5B8DC7407A98539E1F8B424095"><enum>3.</enum><header>Ending lockdowns; allowing the unvaccinated to participate in normal life</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State, a political subdivision thereof, and the Federal Government, may not forbid people in the hopes of containing a communicable disease from—</text><paragraph id="H5BEF4B5F5D9E4475A195EF4D0E34F4F7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>entering or remaining in a place of business, including but not limited to restaurants, movie theaters, stadiums, or concert venues; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0766FAFBA8664822AB9073CA1DB85E32"><enum>(2)</enum><text>opening their places of business or selling goods or services at a physical location.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H8EFB77B942B042418D4D57AC7D6F7A2F"><enum>4.</enum><header>Ending vaccine mandates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A State, a political subdivision thereof, or the Federal Government may not—</text><paragraph id="H467C86C9BDEB4EDAACEF26A96B7084D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make a condition of employment whether someone has been inoculated with a vaccine; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9FF4A62B2774DA6BC08DD2C5A528388"><enum>(2)</enum><text>discriminate in employment, including but not limited to reducing wages, refusing to increase wages, or refusing a promotion, based on whether an individual has been inoculated or will be inoculated with a vaccine.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HF202609687534C549280D43618151711"><enum>5.</enum><header>Private right of action</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">A citizen of the United States who has experienced violations under this Act may assert that violation as a claim or defense in a judicial proceeding and obtain appropriate relief against the Federal Government, a State, or a locality.</text></section><section id="HCB14F3E0B49D473EB37349A78583AE75"><enum>6.</enum><header>Prohibition on use of Federal funds</header><subsection id="H11A84E274D6149DCBF99E756AA39320E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No Federal funds are authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to a State or political subdivision under any program for which appropriations are provided on a discretionary basis if the head of the Federal department or agency administering such program determines that such State or political subdivision has violated any provision of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H171C59C050B9428D95E32E07F378E8D4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this Act may be construed to alter, affect, or otherwise limit any Federal payment to which an individual is entitled under a provision of law.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3CD0F40BAE5544039A6A7BDF79FDFBB3"><enum>7.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The provisions of this legislation shall be deemed severable and the invalidity or unenforceability of any provision shall not affect the validity or enforceability of the other provisions hereof.</text></section><section id="HD235BB0799B0483E87F0472E1CE184C5"><enum>8.</enum><header>Definition of a communicable disease</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>communicable disease</quote> is a disease that can spread from one person to another through direct or indirect contact.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

