<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4DAE7F60280B47B79003031FB9903B69" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8182 IH: James Weldon Johnson Commemorative Coin Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8182</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000586">Mr. Lawson of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of the Treasury to mint a commemorative coin in recognition of James Weldon Johnson.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H7082DEE6A3834E75AABB98C571732415" style="OLC">
<section id="H2BF3679E028D498892DD1364BC9767BE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>James Weldon Johnson Commemorative Coin Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF81117851B8D41D1850CD77BA71E8054"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H2DB7F5A883EF4D048A4F2241CFAC1CD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson was born on June 17, 1871, in Jacksonville, Florida, to a Bahamian mother, Helen Louise Dillet, and African-American father, James Johnson. He had a younger brother, John Rosamund Johnson. His mother had a large influence on his interest in literature and music.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0FAB36221C047A192783D569E09C134"><enum>(2)</enum><text>At the age of 16, James Weldon Johnson enrolled at Atlanta University, now Clark Atlanta University, a historically Black college, and graduated in 1894.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8EA51B51DCC443448FD8EDA69AAD89B0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson returned to Jacksonville following his graduation, where he served as principal of the Stanton School. He expanded the school to include Florida’s first high school for African Americans, which opened in 1898.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2A5B921BEB0848458BF456132073A2CB"><enum>(4)</enum><text>In 1895, James Weldon Johnson started the Daily American, Florida’s first African-American newspaper.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H95CF37DE8C1442CA821060944E29307B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>During this period, James Weldon Johnson was admitted to the Florida Bar in 1897. He became the first African American to pass the Florida Bar since the Reconstruction Era ended.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1709E2C788584073A6746BBAA840587F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In 1899, James Weldon Johnson wrote the poem <quote>Lift Every Voice and Sing</quote> to honor Abraham Lincoln’s birthday. His brother, John Rosamund Johnson, composed the music to turn it into a song. In 1919, the National Advancement of Colored People (NAACP) designated the song as the <quote>Negro National Anthem</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD043A83E9A334FE4AA3FBD99D5E1216C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>As part of the Great Migration, James Weldon Johnson and John Rosamund Johnson moved to Harlem, New York. They became composers for Broadway shows and later became integral figures of the Harlem Renaissance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD21540AC9EB74402BFA0C613E6D2E189"><enum>(8)</enum><text>After winning the election, in 1906, President Theodore Roosevelt appointed James Weldon Johnson as U.S. Consul in Venezuela. In 1909, he was appointed as U.S. Consul in Nicaragua by President William Taft.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H083905C7036C4581A11BE76CDC9A6336"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Following his diplomatic service, James Weldon Johnson became a field secretary for the NAACP in 1916. In 1920, he became the first African-American Executive Secretary for the NAACP, where he helped increase membership, create new chapters, and organize Civil Rights movements across the country.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H76988B0912964230AD28E6B1251670C8"><enum>(10)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson represented the NAACP as the chief Congressional lobbyist to encourage passage of the Representative Leonidas Dyer anti-lynching bill. This bill went on to pass the U.S. House of Representatives in 1922 but failed in the U.S. Senate due to the filibuster.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HEBEEA192878B4A77870F1403A18F5F2F"><enum>(11)</enum><text>In 1930, after serving 10 years in the NAACP, James Weldon Johnson accepted an offer to become the Spence Chair of Creative Literature and Writing at Fisk University, a historically black college in Nashville, Tennessee.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H003E0DBF7B90460E9974BE3C868D997E"><enum>(12)</enum><text>In 1934, James Weldon Johnson was hired as the first Black professor at New York University, where he taught Creative Literature and Education.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDDFC514499AE4B1496784358DE6DCEBD"><enum>(13)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson was an accomplished novelist and poet. He released several poetry collections and novels, among his most popular pieces of literature were God’s Trombones: Seven Negro Sermons in Verse and The Autobiography of an Ex-Colored Man.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE5940CEF08E74C26AD9B7C643C504A3C"><enum>(14)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson passed away suddenly in 1938. His funeral was held in Harlem, New York, where over 2,000 people attended.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H279DE8F4CE854D6C919E7B562E139E44"><enum>(15)</enum><text>James Weldon Johnson’s excellence revolutionized literature, music, education, politics, and law. His fearlessness to fight for equality created pathways for African Americans to proudly pursue their aspirations.</text></paragraph></section> <section id="H4361603BC742497687252FD41A488ED3"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coin specifications</header> <subsection id="H9CAD33AC2BD7447984934A7ABB35644E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Denominations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In recognition and celebration of James Weldon Johnson, the Secretary of the Treasury (hereafter in this Act referred to as the <quote>Secretary</quote>) shall mint and issue not more than 400,000 $1 coins, which shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H282FD1D8A98A4358A5AF7227C9969F40"><enum>(1)</enum><text>weigh 26.73 grams;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2008B957D023408799B8A4314F1DBA43"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have a diameter of 1.500 inches; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAFCFD9AE62FE44EFBCB1637E96A6F440"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">contain not less than 90-percent silver.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HACEE0A347CFC484A9886015BBC2A1A19"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Legal tender</header><text>The coin minted under this Act shall be legal tender, as provided in section 5103 of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H490879BC511C40D084A1ACC958519653"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Numismatic items</header><text>For purposes of sections 5134 and 5136 of title 31, United States Code, all coins minted under this Act shall be considered to be numismatic items.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HB66A075A25B148D0BAD9BDE2CE6A839D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Design of the coin</header> <subsection id="H65173C96D8AC4813B170C5407085F365"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The designs for the coin minted under this Act shall be emblematic of James Weldon Johnson and shall bear the name and image of James Weldon Johnson.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H593E747879AB451B974551A5CFF18DEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Designations and inscriptions</header><text>On the coin minted under this Act there shall be—</text> <paragraph id="HE21D853AC1134A1BAD9598C6B239AD31"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a designation of the denomination of the coin;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H7A3EB52BAF9E4610AFFFDD8E3F5F0CA0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an inscription of the year <quote>2025</quote>;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB78F7BAAEE454BC4BF15B044DFAF768F"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the name and likeness of James Weldon Johnson; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H08B4E989EAD24965A254F5FD5D2573EA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>inscriptions of the words <quote>Liberty</quote>, <quote>In God We Trust</quote>, <quote>United States of America</quote>, and <quote>E Pluribus Unum</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HFCAF877488644953899F9915C9AF2EC7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The designs for the coin minted under this Act shall be—</text>
<paragraph id="H94A1211FD7124CCDBB91C47F97F19BA6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>selected by the Secretary, after consultation with the James Weldon Johnson Foundation, Historic Stanton, Inc., the family of James Weldon Johnson, and Commission of the Fine Arts; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H051176A526064FC1BFD2050D11303663"><enum>(2)</enum><text>reviewed by the Citizens Coinage Advisory Committee.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="HBEADD3E547534ABFBCBD846EDF065EDA"><enum>5.</enum><header>Issuance of the coin</header>
<subsection id="H2308C2DD7D264020A45AED10911BEE81"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Quality of the coin</header><text>The coin minted under this Act shall be issued in uncirculated and proof qualities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H67E5B66120A242FCBDBD2B16F486671C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Period for issuance</header><text>The Secretary may issue the coin minted under this Act only during the 1-year period beginning on January 1, 2025.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HB4CEB78098C44757835729D884FB59BA"><enum>6.</enum><header>Sale of the coin</header>
<subsection id="HFCFAA9F4F1EE4E2FB04A4DCCB7C6DE9C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sale price</header><text>The coin issued under this Act shall be sold by the Secretary at a price based upon the sum of—</text> <paragraph id="HC85C9051056B41C187FC8264323F9049"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the face value of the coin;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H08E28F6131014991B9390DE7606A5D64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the surcharge provided in section 7(a) with respect to such coin; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC29DCDCF68104709AD89730A1BB684C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the cost of designing and issuing the coin (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA02A123AC4104E68A452EF24644EE23E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Bulk sales</header><text>The Secretary shall make bulk sales of the coin issued under this Act at a reasonable discount.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H77AEFB838E944409939BB8A3FC658CFB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prepaid orders</header> <paragraph id="H1729370767E4497793E96C114F5CF262"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall accept prepaid orders for the coin minted under this Act before the issuance of such coin.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H304C24EA0AAF425CB2B417D0FCF9E8DD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Discount</header><text>Sale prices with respect to prepaid orders under paragraph (1) shall be at a reasonable discount.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H755201C4277F44BD9C568BB982FDF322"><enum>7.</enum><header>Surcharges</header> <subsection id="HBB3AA60C12FB453BB098BF317AEB9D07"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All sales of the coin minted under this Act shall include a surcharge of $10 per coin for the $1 coin.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H371F7DD164CB4CA38A79C7E344E3BE8D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Distribution</header><text>Subject to section 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code, all surcharges received by the Secretary from the sale of coin issued under this Act shall be promptly paid equally by the Secretary to the Historic Stanton, Inc., and the James Weldon Johnson Foundation, for the purpose of strengthening educational outcomes for students, with a focus on students of color.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H3209492E0EC24182BD31F00528064126"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The Historic Stanton, Inc., and James Weldon Johnson Foundation shall be subject to the audit requirements of section 5134(f)(2) of title 31, United States Code, with respect to amounts received under subsection (b).</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2DFA4539AD9B4BF88A6F319EA1B0EF61"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (a), no surcharge may be included with respect to the issuance under this Act of any coin during a calendar year if, as of the time of such issuance, the issuance of such coin would result in the number of commemorative coin programs issued during such year to exceed the annual 2 commemorative coin program issuance limitation under section 5112(m)(1) of title 31, United States Code. The Secretary may issue guidance to carry out this subsection.</text></subsection></section> <section id="H27B8C8253B3941F2A7C3AEE6FC967A2C"><enum>8.</enum><header>Financial assurances</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that—</text>
<paragraph id="H4A185D6E556C4A7B8D4B3B12C3A6ABC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>minting and issuing the coin under this Act will not result in any net cost to the United States Government; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC89B25D1851947A99DF855B26DE96512"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no funds, including applicable surcharges, are disbursed to the recipient designated in section 7 until the total cost of designing and issuing all of the coins authorized by this Act (including labor, materials, dies, use of machinery, overhead expenses, marketing, and shipping) is recovered by the United States Treasury, consistent with sections 5112(m) and 5134(f) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


