<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF84BE1DB25404AE6AD913B55F98CA94F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8022 IH: International Medical Graduates Assistance Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8022</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220609">June 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000486">Ms. Roybal-Allard</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To address barriers immigrants and refugees face to entering the health care workforce, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H286A6DA1360C4261811066E985A1F0F7" style="OLC"><section id="HF6230B759FD447698C4802EB6FC4A850" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>International Medical Graduates Assistance Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><title id="H52DA67FA9D714F4692D54558E2AF6E2F"><enum>I</enum><header>Incentivizing States to allow transitional practice by international medical graduates</header><section id="H1F45AB97C1D0472798B1271E9E028C41"><enum>101.</enum><header>Grants</header><subsection id="H0A606AC8B8D441B598CB062D85B65FF0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may award grants to States to develop and implement programs to allow eligible international medical graduates, for a period of up to 4 years while completing steps 1 and 2 of the United States Medical Licensing Examination, to practice medicine in the respective State under the supervision of a fully licensed physician.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC007BCF8D8D84A2D91E176F33FE961F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H75B02EE13D614AF49F892BF9198F15F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>eligible international medical graduate</quote> means an individual who—</text><subparagraph id="HDE657C4C65974B559B3F62A557831815"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">graduated from a school of medicine outside of the United States or Canada; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H461CA7707A3A44F9AB05D197959119FC" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is—</text><clause id="H0D00F0D1E53A467B8D01E8AC3B4A2417" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>lawfully admitted for permanent residence;</text></clause><clause id="HB7F7454A19DD492D81A89C7684A638A8" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>admitted as a refugee under section 207 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1157">8 U.S.C. 1157</external-xref>);</text></clause><clause id="H2CA754028BDE4BF394D4770A7B76B129" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>granted asylum under section 208 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1158">8 U.S.C. 1158</external-xref>); or</text></clause><clause id="H0807DE37663B49388354BFFCCC15D703" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an immigrant otherwise authorized to be employed in the United States.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HADF071A81D7E4678948BB0DC8C5990B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>State</quote> includes the District of Columbia and any territory of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF46D676A6E13475DBC8E55D754307655"><enum>102.</enum><header>Exemption of certain eligible international medical graduates from application of FTE cap</header><subsection id="H0358C48614384752B67FEFE171071DAE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1886(h)(4)(H) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(h)(4)(H)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE0E9B95DFA0040D099F39D0C7B7C9827" display-inline="no-display-inline"><clause id="H41AB5EAA5FFD4C2EA89FEC916B41CCC8"><enum>(vii)</enum><header>Exemption of certain foreign medical graduates from counting towards cap</header><subclause id="HD5AA5A783A2A40EE81E766A298ECDE90"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying the limit described in subparagraph (F), a specified resident (as defined in subclause (II)) shall not be taken into account in determining the total number of full-time equivalent residents before application of weighting factors (as determined under this paragraph) with respect to a hospital’s approved medical residency training program.</text></subclause><subclause id="HBF6D7803A2E44D179C766A2CB428E1FD"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Specified resident defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subclause (I), the term <quote>specified resident</quote> means an eligible international medical graduate (as defined in section 101(b) of the Pathways to Health Care Act of 2022) who is a resident in a hospital’s approved medical residency training program, but only if such hospital—</text><item id="HA940F767EBED4FA7A5FEA07D90285A7F"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>has in effect an agreement with a Federally qualified health center under which residents training in such program spend time training at such center;</text></item><item id="HD83CF2B5113C4BA887C6D87045763228"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located in a State that allows such eligible international medical graduates to practice medicine as described in section 101(a) of such Act; and</text></item><item id="H7EEF6350595441A79D93F1CC18738DE0"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">predominantly serves medically underserved populations (as defined in section 330(b)(3)(A) of the Public Health Service Act), as determined by the Secretary.</text></item></subclause></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H036233CFEEFB45D5A719B440BE44708B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study on removal of resident cap</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to Congress a report on the possibility of removing the resident cap under section 1886(h)(4)(F) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395ww">42 U.S.C. 1395ww(h)(4)(F)</external-xref>). </text></subsection></section></title><title id="HE3E51AD46F424126AA77703D83CE5CD3"><enum>II</enum><header>Assisting international medical graduates during pursuit of licensure</header><section id="HF2901E2400714F83AADFC393EB65920F"><enum>201.</enum><header>Grants</header><subsection id="H9F410C0F5BE346D1B83031BB760501A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Health and Human Services may award grants to States to provide assistance to eligible international medical graduates while such graduates are completing steps 1 and 2 of the United States Medical Licensing Examination.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4298BEDC360C49A09F44F7BF1C04AB33"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered assistance</header><text>Assistance provided to an eligible international medical graduate pursuant to this section may include paying the costs of the United States Medical Licensing Examination, career counseling, case management, classes in English as a second language, assistance in diploma verification, and test preparation courses.</text></subsection><subsection id="H211725F6F1A24331A7D644060BC03540"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Definition</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the terms <quote>eligible international medical graduate</quote> and <quote>State</quote> have the meanings given to those terms in section 101.</text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

