<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4B09B96A7AD2466CA3BE16ED9F70565B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7458 IH: Public Health and Border Security Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7458</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000592">Mr. Golden</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000594">Mr. Tony Gonzales of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000614">Mr. Pappas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001211">Mr. Stanton</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a procedure for terminating the suspension of entries and imports from designated places related to the COVID–19 pandemic.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9A2F117F13E946B881FC98EAF85C0199" style="OLC"><section id="H411E77AF84E842CCB77136416D87786A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Public Health and Border Security Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HA32BEF9D9C5444E8BD45F6F354438DD8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Termination of suspension of entries and imports from designated places related to the COVID–19 pandemic</header><subsection id="H78634D355BC247DDA62B27007116F902"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An order of suspension described in subsection (b) shall not be lifted before the date that is 60 days after the date on which the Secretary of Health and Human Services provides written notification to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of Congress that the public health emergency declaration described in subsection (b) has been terminated.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE99B45462356445ABC06967F0CD1E038"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Order of suspension described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An order of suspension described in this subsection is an order of suspension issued under section 362 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/265">42 U.S.C. 265</external-xref>) as a result of the public health emergency declaration relating to the Coronavirus Disease 2019 (COVID–19) pandemic under section 319 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/247d">42 U.S.C. 247d</external-xref>) made on January 31, 2020, including any renewal of such declaration.</text></subsection><subsection id="H45DA7ECAB69D4636AF2A3F2872EEF1FB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures during 60-Day termination window</header><paragraph id="HD15DCA9493964E12BF5048C08B72D9F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date on which a written notification is provided under subsection (a) with respect to an order of suspension described in subsection (b), the Secretary of Health and Human Services, in consultation with the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the head of any Federal agency, State, local, or Tribal government, and nongovernmental organization that has a role in managing outcomes associated with the suspension, as determined by the Secretary of Health and Human Services, shall develop and submit to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of Congress a plan to address any possible influx of entries or imports related to the termination of such order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8FDE48D41D64DCF88345359E11158BF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to submit</header><text>If a plan under paragraph (1) is not submitted to the appropriate authorizing and appropriating committees of Congress within the 30-day period described in such paragraph, not later than 7 days after the expiration of such 30-day period, the Secretary of Health and Human Services—</text><subparagraph id="H91359418A8C2409A846BCFDD9387EB79"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall notify such committees of Congress, in writing, of the status of preparing such a plan and the timing for submission as required under paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H878E3A148B84450B9DBC3ED55A2C6A4D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>delay the termination of an order of suspension described in subsection (b) until the date that is 30 days after the date on which such plan is submitted to such committees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

