<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-Senate" dms-id="HB15090C5265E4029B5F58E44B67524B7" public-private="public" key="S" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1" slc-id="S1-HEN22701-R8L-WL-9XX"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5615 RS: Homeland Security Capabilities Preservation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">II</distribution-code><calendar>Calendar No. 521</calendar><congress>117th CONGRESS</congress><session>2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5615</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE SENATE OF THE UNITED STATES</current-chamber><action><action-date>March 8 (legislative day, March 7), 2022</action-date><action-desc>Received; read twice and referred to the <committee-name committee-id="SSGA00" added-display-style="italic" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><action stage="Reported-in-Senate"><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported by <sponsor name-id="S380">Mr. Peters</sponsor>, with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Homeland Security to submit a plan to make Federal assistance available to certain urban areas that previously received Urban Area Security Initiative funding to preserve homeland security capabilities, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD885B1FF91CA488191194A9DD693886B" style="OLC"><section id="H370087B135CD417D8F71DE78B0F2EEE9" section-type="section-one" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Security Capabilities Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9CBECC268684488FB2973C5111751E16" changed="deleted" reported-display-style="strikethrough" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preservation of homeland security capabilities</header><subsection id="H57DDF5B68F2D480D91DA4F8842EBE0E6" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Plan</header><paragraph id="H2B3CC8E977B94C3B8EA2F3864D524BAD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a plan, informed by the survey information collected pursuant to subsection (b), to make Federal assistance available for at least three consecutive fiscal years to certain urban areas that in the current fiscal year did not receive grant funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/604">6 U.S.C. 604</external-xref>) and require continued Federal assistance for the purpose of preserving a homeland security capability related to preventing, preparing for, protecting against, and responding to acts of terrorism that had been developed or otherwise supported through prior grant funding under such Initiative and allow for such urban areas to transition to such urban areas costs of preserving such homeland security capabilities.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E73506ADEA47E9861E3F880CDA2043"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan required under paragraph (1) shall also contain a prohibition on an urban area that in a fiscal year is eligible to receive Federal assistance described in such paragraph from also receiving grant funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002. In such a case, such plan shall require such an urban area to promptly notify the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency regarding the preference of such urban area to retain either—</text><subparagraph id="H89F910A88B194E95A5475424AE248D11"><enum>(A)</enum><text>such eligibility for such Federal assistance; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C9548C7669141EAA07DB9520260CEE5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such receipt of such grant funding.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H660DE0918D144AFFA6203F58B4645CB7" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Survey</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the plan required under subsection (a), the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency, shall, to ascertain the scope of Federal assistance required, survey urban areas that—</text><paragraph id="H946490FF2AD448D5BB9791DC8A33698E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>did not receive grant funding under the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 in the current fiscal year concerning homeland security capabilities related to preventing, preparing for, protecting against, and responding to acts of terrorism that had been developed or otherwise supported through funding under such Initiative that are at risk of being reduced or eliminated without such Federal assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEE47A60EF764B20B0CDEA790C691C44"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received such funding in the current fiscal year, but did not receive such funding in at least one fiscal year in the six fiscal years immediately preceding the current fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD342EAFF939A41148E38241FB85ED11D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other urban areas the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H69B5DE4FFDA540FDBD8B0F5EFB5A5246"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may exempt the Federal Emergency Management Agency from the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), for purposes of carrying out subsection (b) if the Secretary determines that complying with such requirements would delay the development of the plan required under subsection (a).</text></subsection><subsection id="H346AB39BE1DC43E78981FF2476EFECE8" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The plan required under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H69732F51678A4A43BD195CA7005DC048" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish eligibility criteria for urban areas to receive Federal assistance pursuant to such plan to provide assistance for the purpose described in such subsection;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA7D244101041C78E590537D36AFFA6" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">identify annual funding levels for such Federal assistance in accordance with the survey required under subsection (b); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA214E7738DB2469BB3B6726005940141" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider a range of approaches to make such Federal assistance available to such urban areas, including—</text><subparagraph id="H0B02667AE7C24E8091FB30625AA36A04" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">modifications to the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 in a manner that would not affect the availability of funding to urban areas under such Initiative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFD3EFE3111F4398A80D89AFE926F80C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of a competitive grant program;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2CBCAC94E9384795AF351EF4F0DFEE46" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the establishment of a formula grant program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED21EF74F8164E7DAAFB9C0A081E4ECF" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a timeline for the implementation of any such approach and, if necessary, a legislative proposal to authorize any such approach.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><legis-body display-enacting-clause="no-display-enacting-clause"><section id="S1" section-type="section-one" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Homeland Security Capabilities Preservation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="id80df0ab949eb497297ae8c52d54ecb09" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="SSGA00"><enum>2.</enum><header>Preservation of homeland security capabilities</header><subsection id="id9DEAF2D302334AD9A0FFB12643275DB0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="idD5CF97943F9F43469205BAE96225EDC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="id9F50BFCF788B490A814D7AD59B9CFCF1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id87F432E0550C4623B29C2460316F97AC"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered homeland security capability</header><text>The term <term>covered homeland security capability</term> means a homeland security capability related to preventing, preparing for, protecting against, or responding to acts of terrorism that— </text><subparagraph id="id3546EE2DE7A34DD891FED5FF8B53FF56"><enum>(A)</enum><text>was developed or otherwise supported through grant funding under the UASI before the current fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id95AB84DBC9374C46B134AB3C6522EEE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is at risk of being reduced or eliminated without additional Federal financial assistance.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id8AD50C2F9A2942F88CD44F2F1CDFF8E2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered urban area</header><text>The term <term>covered urban area</term> means an urban area that— </text><subparagraph id="idBD396029642640919EEDEB120B449563"><enum>(A)</enum><text>during the current fiscal year did not receive grant funding under the UASI; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id688AD0ECBDFD494F97E037E965A94E52"><enum>(B)</enum><text>requires continued Federal assistance for the purpose of preserving a covered homeland security capability.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="idFFA0F9581FA045E7A9DCE431E9A1C4AB"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id4164BA22E93746C89C285F2649EE4500"><enum>(6)</enum><header>UASI</header><text>The term <term>UASI</term> means the Urban Area Security Initiative under section 2003 of the Homeland Security Act of 2002 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/6/604">6 U.S.C. 604</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id83d6f6ac807a47c0b37f5a8dbf783655"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report and proposal</header><paragraph id="id80024ee14bba40708774f259744ff66a"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, acting through the Administrator, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report regarding covered homeland security capabilities, including a proposal relating to providing Federal assistance to covered urban areas to preserve such capabilities that is informed by the survey information collected pursuant to subsection (c)— </text><subparagraph id="idF66E9828AE1348AAAB5166F5CE6F1B87"><enum>(A)</enum><text>under which the Administrator would make Federal financial assistance available for at least 3 consecutive fiscal years to covered urban areas; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idCCEB54DA24DE4999802B27A7B9B0D3E5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that would allow covered urban areas to transition funding for the covered homeland security capabilities that were previously funded through the UASI to other sources.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="iddbe8c9ebb88745a9b53c26d89230b096"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements relating to UASI funds</header><text>The proposal required under paragraph (1) shall contain— </text><subparagraph id="id5049E50C20AF4FD68FA8F4DC72914A44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a prohibition on a covered urban area that receives Federal financial assistance described in paragraph (1)(A) during a fiscal year from also receiving funds under the UASI during that fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="id13ED110EBA0F4EA9A557F39D9ACCD889"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a requirement for a covered urban area to submit to the Administrator notice of whether the covered urban area would elect to receive—</text><clause id="idd8d959dd689348a18126cfae06c239d3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Federal financial assistance under paragraph (1)(A); or</text></clause><clause id="idb249ddfc81c44a7da84168af27441dda"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>funding under the UASI.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id38FC4A6F3BA042A7B6A6BA540D4EB9F1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Analysis</header><text>The report required under paragraph (1) shall include— </text><subparagraph id="id8464de6f29b94866b7135741fc26f475"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis of whether providing additional Federal financial assistance, as described in paragraph (1)(A), would allow covered urban areas to preserve covered homeland security capabilities on a long-term basis; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idF1C185E3EB2344C6A0B3869E506A478D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an analysis of whether legislative changes to the UASI are necessary to ensure urban areas receiving funds under the UASI are able to preserve covered homeland security capabilities on a long-term basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="id0eff4c0f67ae45d189601d56601f58f4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Other contents of proposal</header><text>The proposal required under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="id3a7c2f00e1b44f0dac936b7c275b805e"><enum>(A)</enum><text>set forth eligibility criteria for covered urban areas to receive Federal assistance described in paragraph (1)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idd1bf1896b1424b5caae6210a39d5d5d7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identify annual funding levels that would be required to provide Federal assistance described in paragraph (1)(A), in accordance with the survey required under subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="idf6336ff90a1640a0a6af968b074de94e"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consider a range of approaches to make Federal assistance described in paragraph (1)(A) available to covered urban areas, including—</text><clause id="id4ef51f2206e44c84830677950ec77dec"><enum>(i)</enum><text>modifications to the UASI in a manner that would not affect the availability of funding to urban areas under the UASI;</text></clause><clause id="idf0894d407ba0481cb28e84f7d829a152"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the establishment of a competitive grant program;</text></clause><clause id="id56e9b51c159d45a285897e4b21c628a5"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the establishment of a formula grant program; and</text></clause><clause id="id6c894cd0946444c7907dcd1e3c656b0e" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a timeline for the implementation of any such approach and, if necessary, a legislative proposal to authorize any such approach. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id2301962f54b14868abfeba6f1d9d4a36"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Survey</header><text>In developing the proposal required under subsection (b), the Administrator shall, to ascertain the scope of Federal financial assistance required, survey—</text><paragraph id="id3694555ecc2c4479816b7a15f71cc36e"><enum>(1)</enum><text>urban areas that did not receive grant funding under the UASI during the current fiscal year concerning covered homeland security capabilities that are at risk of being reduced or eliminated without additional Federal financial assistance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id7ba1872ac8b646eaa7c157a69b9f4025"><enum>(2)</enum><text>urban areas that received grant funding under the UASI during the current fiscal year, but did not receive such funding during at least 1 fiscal year of the 7 fiscal years immediately preceding the current fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="id2a8a393d5c434634a6e129675be81410"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any other urban areas the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="id4c85c45276de40518b915d2d05e7e1c8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>The Secretary may exempt the Administrator from the requirements of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/44/35">chapter 35</external-xref> of title 44, United States Code (commonly referred to as the <quote>Paperwork Reduction Act</quote>), for purposes of carrying out subsection (c) if the Secretary determines that complying with such requirements would delay the development of the proposal required under subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="id9DE72EFD581448879DA68218CE7B4E9D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to be directing or authorizing the Administrator to implement the proposal required under subsection (b).</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement><action-date date="20220928">September 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

