<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA0C8F8C859F64E749FA9928D703C5C30" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7030 IH: Open App Markets Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-09</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7030</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220309">March 9, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001297">Mr. Buck</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001104">Mr. Cawthorn</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To promote competition and reduce gatekeeper power in the app economy, increase choice, improve quality, and reduce costs for consumers.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFA80CD526A444AAC86ACCECAD1F3A6E8" style="OLC"><section id="H59F602FA18824080ADAFF147CFCCF0A2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Open App Markets Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H57630B605E4C46259E8D407D2C817015"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HF958D293C97E4723AFBB442C75E0F406"><enum>(1)</enum><header>App</header><text>The term <term>app</term> means a software application or electronic service that may be run or directed by a user on a computer, a mobile device, or any other general purpose computing device.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F785F91BC1243DE8D9CC736A11F0904"><enum>(2)</enum><header>App store</header><text>The term <term>app store</term> means a publicly available website, software application, or other electronic service that distributes apps from third-party developers to users of a computer, a mobile device, or any other general purpose computing device.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H044115B27A9E42AA964830E9499813B4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered company</header><text>The term <term>covered company</term> means any person that owns or controls an app store for which users in the United States exceed 50,000,000.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA04B817ED31148F7B13B54A56F768CB1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Developer</header><text>The term <term>developer</term> means a person that owns or controls an app or an app store.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6A1B4A233A241459776EFD2870BF28B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>In-app payment system</header><text>The term <term>in-app payment system</term> means an application, service, or user interface to manage billing or process the payments from users of an app.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1FE3F450F6841F68F73554C1D3A724F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Nonpublic business information</header><text>The term <term>nonpublic business information</term> means nonpublic data that is—</text><subparagraph id="H3886C7622A794E70BF650857B3F6CC9D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>derived from a developer or an app or app store owned or controlled by a developer, including interactions between users and the app or app store of the developer; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9029525876A54EC28C33EA4B6ADFF381"><enum>(B)</enum><text>collected by a covered company in the course of operating an app store or providing an operating system.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC04EEC7E1CD14804ABC11CF06973B4B7"><enum>3.</enum><header>Protecting a competitive app market</header><subsection id="H07B2DA4D8983454A98BA1E69492A5A37"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exclusivity and tying</header><text>A covered company shall not—</text><paragraph id="HA9C277A976D849E6A983283970D960F2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>require developers to use or enable an in-app payment system owned or controlled by the covered company or any of its business partners as a condition of the distribution of an app on an app store or accessible on an operating system;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70EAF39FB166449D84A2C0FAEA6C44E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>require as a term of distribution on an app store that pricing terms or conditions of sale be equal to or more favorable on its app store than the terms or conditions under another app store; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7BEB87DD836C4A488AC3DD4D2D498FDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>take punitive action or otherwise impose less favorable terms and conditions against a developer for using or offering different pricing terms or conditions of sale through another in-app payment system or on another app store.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H41F086B74F9C438DA9C424FD115E5A24"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Interference with legitimate business communications</header><text>A covered company shall not impose restrictions on communications of developers with the users of an app of the developer through the app or direct outreach to a user concerning legitimate business offers, such as pricing terms and product or service offerings. Nothing in this subsection shall prohibit a covered company from providing a user the option to offer consent prior to the collection and sharing of the data of the user by an app.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF104978663D94B7A82B2DB646836043A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nonpublic business information</header><text>A covered company shall not use nonpublic business information derived from a third-party app for the purpose of competing with that app.</text></subsection><subsection id="H00A2860846B94E53B4979CCF398DDF8D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Interoperability</header><text>A covered company that controls the operating system or operating system configuration on which its app store operates shall allow and provide readily accessible means for users of that operating system to—</text><paragraph id="H19D88494399644368E530178B0F2A4B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>choose third-party apps or app stores as defaults for categories appropriate to the app or app store;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6CEFC3E238A4474BBA79350FE24F7B0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>install third-party apps or app stores through means other than its app store; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB85196B937F46E6A2A21DF16487DEAD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>hide or delete apps or app stores provided or preinstalled by the app store owner or any of its business partners.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC22B9AE4E36F42DA8ECC864BF1ABA86C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Self-Preferencing in search</header><paragraph id="H378770FB3CC64184AF2E6029DFE366E6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A covered company shall not provide unequal treatment of apps in an app store through unreasonably preferencing or ranking the apps of the covered company or any of its business partners over those of other apps in organic search results.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3D1931F0FF94F1C84326C51829FC623"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>Unreasonably preferencing—</text><subparagraph id="HB0D6AD716B974F7B98CB8D51715E9E67"><enum>(A)</enum><text>includes applying ranking schemes or algorithms that prioritize apps based on a criterion of ownership interest by the covered company or its business partners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6ECA59DCA190480ABD7BB43E60893481"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include clearly disclosed advertising.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D3665E42A4F4C99804746E87D6A6F23"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Open app development</header><text>A covered company shall provide access to operating system interfaces, development information, and hardware and software features to developers on a timely basis and on terms that are equivalent or functionally equivalent to the terms for access by similar apps or functions provided by the covered company or to its business partners.</text></subsection></section><section id="HB947A5CD458C4F1597EBC6862E26B2BD"><enum>4.</enum><header>Protecting the security and privacy of users</header><subsection id="H941535CCB78A4A5BA17009B8DDC27DB3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H2098C0B022C3479185B22B23AE157D2C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>No violation</header><text>Subject to section (b), a covered company shall not be in violation of section 3 for an action that is—</text><subparagraph id="H8F70E0341AF3409D8D24B989CC1293D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>necessary to achieve user privacy, security, or digital safety;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7015C0480D0C42E185D074DEF59DE44D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>taken to prevent spam or fraud;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCCADA3BB68442AB92524E4E32264BB8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>necessary to prevent unlawful infringement of preexisting intellectual property; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D6A34B9A7C945B691714BEF49627507"><enum>(D)</enum><text>taken to prevent a violation of, or comply with, Federal or State law.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H86ACA93A12404E3FB2A8E41525DED429"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Privacy and security protections</header><text>In paragraph (1), the term <term>necessary to achieve user privacy, security, or digital safety</term> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H0FF5F3A202C14C419365EF7139D06B7D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>allowing an end user to opt in, and providing information regarding the reasonable risks, prior to enabling installation of the third-party apps or app stores;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91A83CC824644A30876EC66B136BD646"><enum>(B)</enum><text>removing malicious or fraudulent apps or app stores from an end user device;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05F5C5E1C7E940CAB98939B0FFF53952"><enum>(C)</enum><text>providing an end user with the technical means to verify the authenticity and origin of third-party apps or app stores; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5C2F4D62BDF84457AF3A1D361A20E0A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing an end user with option to limit the collection sharing of the data of the user with third-party apps or app stores.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H10BE10C6B2E041FDB58E1C18D3138753"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Subsection (a) shall only apply if the covered company establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that the action described in that subsection is—</text><paragraph id="H5F9E2BCD3E214596A99CED159074E849"><enum>(1)</enum><text>applied on a demonstrably consistent basis to—</text><subparagraph id="HBE8B918FB171423DB0AD8B159F4A1F64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>apps of the covered company or its business partners; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57A009D232FA423F954175CEECC9099A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>other apps;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9C28A69D64D944DC95A11DDE613532DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>not used as a pretext to exclude, or impose unnecessary or discriminatory terms on, third-party apps, in-app payment systems, or app stores; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A01E72A377C48D79F75001E234ACC4B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>narrowly tailored and could not be achieved through a less discriminatory and technically possible means.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF113C7C344CA4C02AC83BE0AC0942F5B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Enforcement</header><subsection id="HC7A3B947B18D4BA7B4B19B1E80512C53"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H2E1FE66266B14E4AA81CC0C815D2A63C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal Trade Commission, the Attorney General, and any attorney general of a State subject to the requirements in paragraph (3) shall enforce this Act in the same manner, by the same means, and with the same jurisdiction, powers, and duties as though all applicable terms and provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>), the Sherman Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1">15 U.S.C. 1 et seq.</external-xref>), the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12 et seq.</external-xref>), and Antitrust Civil Process Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1311">15 U.S.C. 1311 et seq.</external-xref>), as appropriate, were incorporated into and made a part of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AFED2EA1C32431B832DC89C62FE1D1D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Federal trade commission independent litigation authority</header><text>If the Federal Trade Commission has reason to believe that a covered company violated this Act, the Federal Trade Commission may commence a civil action, in its own name by any of its attorneys designated by it for such purpose, to recover a civil penalty and seek other appropriate relief in a district court of the United States against the covered company.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H33C47DF637374FD79EC8A5AD3BD43616"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Parens patriae</header><text>Any attorney general of a State may bring a civil action in the name of such State for a violation of this Act as parens patriae on behalf of natural persons residing in such State, in any district court of the United States having jurisdiction of the defendant, and may secure any form of relief provided for in this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H05281A100C454141A35872E87ABE05F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Suits by developers injured</header><paragraph id="H0858373C1FA14259804BD4297EB40CD7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), any developer injured by reason of anything forbidden in this Act may sue therefor in any district court of the United States in the district in which the defendant resides or is found or has an agent, without respect to the amount in controversy, and shall recover threefold the damages by the developer sustained and the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee. The court may award under this paragraph, pursuant to a motion by such developer promptly made, simple interest on actual damages for the period beginning on the date of service of the pleading of the developer setting forth a claim under this Act and ending on the date of judgment, or for any shorter period therein, if the court finds that the award of such interest for such period is just in the circumstances. In determining whether an award of interest under this paragraph for any period is just in the circumstances, the court shall consider only—</text><subparagraph id="HE113B1F2753444BCA938364BA0A50D84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whether the developer or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, made motions or asserted claims or defenses so lacking in merit as to show that such party or representative acted intentionally for delay or otherwise acted in bad faith;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC938E689C054041ADCDEE1D1AE4D960"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether, in the course of the action involved, the developer or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, violated any applicable rule, statute, or court order providing for sanctions for dilatory behavior or otherwise providing for expeditious proceedings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H713A63B30AB44FF28DFC6B364ECDE50F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>whether the developer or the opposing party, or either party’s representative, engaged in conduct primarily for the purpose of delaying the litigation or increasing the cost thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD70ABC6B09C641D99AE5B502FBCD5FB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Injunctive relief</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), any developer shall be entitled to sue for and have injunctive relief, in any court of the United States having jurisdiction over the parties, against threatened loss or damage by a violation of this Act, when and under the same conditions and principles as injunctive relief against threatened conduct that will cause loss or damage is granted by courts of equity, under the rules governing such proceedings, and upon the execution of proper bond against damages for an injunction improvidently granted and a showing that the danger of irreparable loss or damage is immediate, a preliminary injunction may issue. In any action under this paragraph in which the plaintiff substantially prevails, the court shall award the cost of suit, including a reasonable attorney’s fee, to such plaintiff.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5D925DB95DE42B09B31CC9F18C34AD8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Foreign state-owned enterprises</header><text>A developer of an app that is owned by, or under the control of, a foreign state may not bring an action under this subsection. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H10C4C5C4451B43E6BECC82A82BAFD8C7"><enum>6.</enum><header>Reporting</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Federal Trade Commission, the Comptroller General of the United States, and the Antitrust Division of the Department of Justice shall each separately review and provide an in-depth analysis of the impact of this Act on competition, innovation, barriers to entry, and concentrations of market power or market share after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></section><section id="HCB207B27E1704E45B055D4B3D5BD66E0"><enum>7.</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act may be construed—</text><paragraph id="HAAE97F30D7B44BB8904F2F9B47C74CBA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to limit—</text><subparagraph id="HF7C0963F0103489E9BA236A2654AF741"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any authority of the Attorney General or the Federal Trade Commission under the antitrust laws (as defined in the first section of the Clayton Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/12">15 U.S.C. 12</external-xref>), the Federal Trade Commission Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/41">15 U.S.C. 41 et seq.</external-xref>), or any other provision of law; or </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H213AB9CC433042A9B6B552939E6929A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the application of any law;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54FBC2C489A3420C8DC048BB07229C64"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to require—</text><subparagraph id="H675516C5AD3D4B738286941DEA3D728B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered company to provide service under a hardware or software warranty for damage caused by third-party apps or app stores installed through means other than the app store of the covered company; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C7D1D0E6CA24602B399FE644D096E94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>customer service for the installation or operation of third-party apps or app stores described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCE7A69F47F46416BB97BE792EF774F87"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to prevent an action taken by a covered company that is reasonably tailored to protect the rights of third parties under section 106, 1101, 1201, or 1401 of title 17, United States Code, or rights actionable under sections 32 or 43 of the Act entitled <quote>An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trademarks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes</quote>, approved July 5, 1946 (commonly known as the <quote>Lanham Act</quote> or the <quote>Trademark Act of 1946</quote>) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1114">15 U.S.C. 1114</external-xref>, 1125), or corollary State law;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4424467FA29742C184818BAB8AE56AEE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to require a covered company to license any intellectual property, including any trade secrets, owned by or licensed to the covered company;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72572CC41F294DB997D83953E48F1328"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to prevent a covered company from asserting preexisting rights of the covered company under intellectual property law to prevent the unlawful use of any intellectual property owned by or duly licensed to the covered company; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF0FA2DC40A043DAA74A1679E549F79E"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to require a covered company to interoperate or share data with persons or business users that—</text><subparagraph id="HC0B33A12FA43427BAF8212A7A7718E7F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are on any list maintained by the Federal Government by which entities are identified as limited or prohibited from engaging in economic transactions as part of United States sanctions or export control regimes; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B77DC7AD13C45E08EFDBB345C54F826"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have been identified by the Federal Government as national security, intelligence, or law enforcement risks. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H14A3C0318A474DD486A7D364AA77EAB4"><enum>8.</enum><header>Severability</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any provision of this Act, or the application of such a provision to any person or circumstance, is held to be unconstitutional, the remaining provisions of this Act, and the application of such provisions to any person or circumstance shall not be affected thereby.</text></section><section id="H3E23A2C983844440BE9C614F1E462637"><enum>9.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act shall take effect on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

