<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2E918954FA8943F29FC4368C20C8E1F5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8551 IH: Technology Assessment for Air Quality Management Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8551</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barrag&#225;n</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve air quality management and the safety of communities using the best available monitoring technology and data.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC546DC263815418680EDAA26228749F2" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H851925D27FC74721A01618425BF4A35F" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Technology Assessment for Air Quality Management Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HC9E75BEBD427400D9E3658DD27BF88FA" commented="no"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text> 
<paragraph id="H429264B91D0E4BB6AB98093FDBF22968" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Environmental Protection Agency can further strengthen air quality planning and management by consistently gathering information on local air quality monitoring systems across the United States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5EB73E6408C4868B41D30D34CEA5508" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">newer air sensor technologies create the possibility for enhanced, community-scale air pollution data;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4BDBBB9CB61947169CB403ADFE9DB565" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>despite national progress in reducing air pollution, more than 40 percent of people in the United States live in places with unhealthy levels of ozone or particle pollution;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6FA5F377396542318F79A5DE07BCDB3E" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>people of color, Indigenous people, and low-income communities bear disproportionately higher exposures and health burdens due to air pollution;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA2DF6C845E2E42B69EEA4E80A23A2D35" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>air quality can vary up to 800 percent from block to block within a single neighborhood; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBAAD85891FCE42E1B4DE8B898A59C445" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">existing methods that are prescribed for basin-wide air quality monitoring are cost-prohibitive for monitoring community-scale air quality.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="H46F9FCA5811245A4ADDFD03FAE25F7C8" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0B3DA9A161314C64ACCF553100776B96" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text>The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H986354F0071047E0AC5B7E807E3025F5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Air pollutant</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>air pollutant</term> has the meaning given such term in section 302(g) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7602">42 U.S.C. 7602(g)</external-xref>).</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H19C724F53B964640805A1C7DFA14F9B9" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Area source</header><text>The term <term>area source</term> has the meaning given the term in section 112(a) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7412">42 U.S.C. 7412(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3742917B724B4730B5C8EB3DBD348437" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Environmental justice</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice</term> means the fair treatment and meaningful involvement of all people, regardless of race, color, culture, national origin, or income, in the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws (including regulations) and policies to ensure that each person enjoys—</text> <subparagraph id="H437ED2DBC6FE405E8C65BC11DCD100B5" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the same degree of protection from environmental and health hazards; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE20E16994D4B4BB3914944424FFD7428" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>equal access to any Federal agency action relating to the development, implementation, and enforcement of environmental laws (including regulations) and policies for the purpose of having a healthy environment in which to live, learn, work, and recreate. </text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H08FE055EB9B540AC8BC5ACFB6C760260" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Environmental justice community</header><text>The term <term>environmental justice community</term> means a community with significant representation of communities of color, low-income communities, or Tribal and Indigenous communities, that experiences, or is at risk of experiencing, higher or more adverse human health or environmental effects, as compared to other communities.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H58E49861FC4046B9AD87CE6AF1F225EB" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Hybrid method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>hybrid method</term> means a method for monitoring air pollutants that combines information from multiple sources, including monitors at ground level, modeling, and satellites, to aid in calculating the expected number of exceedances per year and the design values for air pollutants for purposes of determining compliance or non-compliance with the national ambient air quality standards for those pollutants. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H846F8ED599D74F60AC49D8D47954F13C" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Hyperlocal air quality monitoring system</header><text>The term <term>hyperlocal air quality monitoring system</term> means a system of monitoring air pollutants that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCD9F0DF872E743398D25B7C598FF7AB7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>yields frequently repeated, ongoing measurements of air pollutants at a geographic scale that is—</text> <clause id="HA6EFEAAED63847CD8F820A4D480253AB" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>as small as practicable to identify communities; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="HF9E3DAFD687040A68C1899D62A65DD37" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not larger than that of a census tract; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2E4E88B941E749928BEA24CA1D97928D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies hotspots of persistent elevated levels of air pollutants localized to, and caused by the characteristics of, a specific geographic location.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEBF1B5E93C8641F6AED66562DB176582" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Hyperlocal data</header> 
<subparagraph id="H29743AFC85B3415A817CA75E5D24F3B8" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>hyperlocal data</term> means the data returned by a hyperlocal air quality monitoring system.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDEAC30601771437FADE04E66090F189C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>The term <term>hyperlocal data</term> may include data on—</text> 
<clause id="H0FB6377C8CDC40CA95F8B6140123DBFD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the health impacts of air pollution; and</text></clause> <clause id="H46DB167350FB46DEBC2A690ABC98A164" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>sources of air pollutants.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H57475E32C0C44D82A62E06D0180D0D93" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Indirect source</header><text>The term <term>indirect source</term> has the meaning given the term in section 110(a)(5)(C) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7410">42 U.S.C. 7410(a)(5)(C)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F623CB35BE148CD81E355A866CA6B48" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Major source</header><text>The term <term>major source</term> has the meaning given the term in section 501 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7661">42 U.S.C. 7661</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H86A3719CD827474580BB65CB6DABB616"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Reference method</header><text>The term <term>reference method</term> has the meaning given such term in section 50.1 of title 40, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB500407A11104358B5DE0ADEB08BA35D" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Relevant committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>relevant committees of Congress</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H1FB2F30B3B724CEAB66F1B3082D2CD64" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7E796AC35475440AA702C7CE5984F952" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H15CDE4B48AF2412FB2A7152C934EF605" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>Compendium of air quality monitoring technologies and uses of air quality insights</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Administrator shall update the Air Sensor Toolbox of the Environmental Protection Agency or an equivalent online, publicly available compendium—</text> <paragraph id="H37AFBB8E2C5B4A158695B0C7E4CCEA52" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to describe all types of common air quality monitor technologies, which may include—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H8CA06BF52FD44D39B40D2D7B9394ECCA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Federal Reference Method or Federal Equivalent Method monitors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H97420D0DED114549B9F2DF8804ABB600" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>mobile monitoring platforms;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HECC85D3EAFD74F61909C27D56A0E606B" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>low-cost stationary monitors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFA832892190249CAAAB73D63D395A85E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>satellite sensors and surface monitors; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H965952B9F3254CACB2215EC6D71CCCE3" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>fenceline monitoring instruments;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B50184A103F48D78C2A8260F645C305" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>high-resolution cameras; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCB4DD682E94047EA8F631CA0040EF8D9" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>other technologies, as determined to be appropriate by the Administrator;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H41CCFDF07C614DD086468A7052D83EBD" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to describe the uses of the data associated with the types of common air quality monitor technologies described under paragraph (1);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H733610E7651740F6BD02C7018E366A99" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to update and describe the advantages of monitoring technologies with respect to different air quality management applications, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H47DCA4CBF10841BDB4AB17ECF94A09EB" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the costs and ease of purchase, installation, operation, and maintenance of monitors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFF563FE1F83F49569869D8CE86EAE7E2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>air pollutant or air pollutants monitored;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2155D19F34C549E4B3F3B9FA08E4DC86" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>spatial resolution;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HBCA2DE39822440049B1CB041F0FD9877" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>temporal resolution;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3F0EDE30C9A7412B92B0D625EDF716E5" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>frequency of data collection by monitors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8E3CCD52948C409A9056EA9C75CA3987" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>data quality and data processing needs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H497A33211C0345F4910F905F7168B43A" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>compatibility, accessibility, and ease of use of a type of monitor with online databases;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9F7968ECF3164666BDA4DEE7003701D3" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to describe—</text> <subparagraph id="H7D0102A71E85491CB1E9168C9269EE0E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">potential incongruities between air quality monitor measurements from reference methods and hybrid methods; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H00942153C4254D8586726BF07129D67E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">relevant insights from data returned from hybrid methods, despite the potential incongruities described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A822493E7D04E218EEAA77C75981F2A" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>to describe the availability of, and how to access, data on—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0DCFB09AB4C94489A47B6D06852B753C" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the location and nature of likely sources of air pollution, including major sources, area sources, and indirect sources; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H14F703394AEF4BBBB10C6338DC75149C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>potential health impacts that may result from air pollution exposure;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAE58BFDCFEA44F8784ACAEA1FF2CE6C6" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to connect and integrate the Air Sensor Toolbox or equivalent compendium with the EJSCREEN mapping tool of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Environmental Information Exchange Network, and other relevant Federal, State, and local environmental justice mapping and screening tools—</text> <subparagraph id="H90257D03295341EF811041F00ECD3275" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to inform communities and local air agencies of local air pollution concerns; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HC629EFB8CDB44A4EACA444B88CD6C65E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to help communities understand and describe— </text> <clause id="H929C39C79EE14CEFB72908892876F45C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the multiple and cumulative exposures identified in environmental human health analyses under section 3–301(b) of Executive Order 12898 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4321">42 U.S.C. 4321</external-xref> note; relating to Federal actions to address environmental justice in minority populations and low-income populations); and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H112C0C1C81C24426B72F62F0030D5555" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any exclusion from participation in, denial of and the benefits of, or discrimination under programs and activities receiving Federal financial assistance on the ground of race, color, or national origin, as prohibited under section 601 of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000d">42 U.S.C. 2000d</external-xref>); and</text></clause></subparagraph> </paragraph> <paragraph id="H07E4655CD8F94F199A7E17BBE2D33838" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text>to describe how to integrate air quality monitoring technologies and data across spatial and temporal scales to improve quantitative use of low-cost sensors, satellite sensors, and other technologies.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H9B56D01969D249839E3EC0764D47CC62" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Air Quality Technology Working Group</header> 
<subsection id="HDA6687587C084AF2BA2513F495CCDD21" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header> 
<paragraph id="HBF8C9BF13E534FA7B5D3F690014C0232" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall establish an Air Quality Technology Working Group (referred to in this section as the <quote>Working Group</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D11B41D6A8947498A7B2B5A23D3A55E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Working Group shall consist of 30 members, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H828EEC634A85460F95C22462F0C5F17B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 representative from each Regional Office of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB3467354546140A99C6B6E389A2CEE31" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative with a demonstrated record of experience with device installation, operation, maintenance, and calibration of different air quality monitoring approaches;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H9B6667F2B50D43AAA99D0A92666A44FB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>not less than 3 representatives with demonstrated records of experience in data science as it pertains to using measurements from monitoring technologies to develop air quality insights for environmental justice and associated air quality monitoring applications;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4CC447A5591B431096BCE42D2A469E39" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not less than 3 representatives of environmental justice community-based organizations, coalitions, networks, or alliances with experience in using new technologies to assess and address air pollution in the communities of those environmental justice community-based organizations, coalitions, networks, or alliances;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB74C956DA28B4A0BAD3D90A0439920E0" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative with a demonstrated record of experience in outreach and engagement with environmental justice communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H956DCA91E547438EB756C72185436A70" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from the national headquarters of the Environmental Protection Agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDD40A4FA65A2434DBFAED7B70BAD5900" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from a State air agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC6CE07C3E9B94864986626C8FE03AD35" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from a local air agency;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE41DC28651D14759ADC3286F2C2B4E15" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from a Tribal air agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H17C2416B095747CD9E28FB23AEEEC748" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>not less than 2 representatives who—</text> 
<clause id="HD9C70A5472F8467F86CC8F864B065954" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are—</text> <subclause id="H2412AE4931D8451196F6A3359AE3AF29" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>from public health departments; or</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H7671CD6B9EB642FF88E7869AEAAA925A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>public health scientists; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HB606F1A07CA941D9A598AEE8CAA2A295" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>have a demonstrated record of experience with translating information collected from monitoring technologies into health insights for environmental justice applications and air quality management; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H2FB71909847748FF8B6169037DFF37C7" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text>not less than 1 representative from the air quality technology industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H55BC60FB11624F6FB599A4D47BCF3DA3" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Monitoring system template</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date on which the Working Group is established under subsection (a)(1), the Working Group shall develop and submit to the relevant committees of Congress a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H4B27C195060B4F6FA92EA5A21EAA5BCE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>templates for integrated air quality monitoring systems ranging in cost estimates, population sizes of communities served, atmospheric dispersion dynamics of air pollutants, and other relevant parameters, as determined to be appropriate by the Working Group, that provide a holistic understanding of local air pollutant measurements across time, which may incorporate—</text> <subparagraph id="H61CADE8077734D47BBE35B75493EFE1D" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>1 or more in-situ monitors;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H3E300DC61B1C4EDE9B98086219697356" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>1 or more satellite sensors;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8290FBF899A048A1867F821933DDCF77" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>computer modeling;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H45B4D2FE8552423D96C945E12F831997" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>multipollutant monitoring options;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5C008084C22D4380B9E835C277EAD440" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>single pollutant monitoring options; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7F4BFC2F7D0544C6B17EAB5F23608EC0" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>data collection, interpretation, and reporting to relevant Federal, State, local, and Tribal air agencies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F83420ADC594593BF779F03A74FFCFB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the costs and capacity needs associated with the integrated air quality monitoring systems described under paragraph (1), including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H5CC54AD4E5CA40ADB26335327A5D4768" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>costs of purchase, operation, maintenance, and calibration of monitor technologies;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H79D969A3A3704D57B2261495007F9191" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>workforce needs;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H312FEE47BBB04510A6A9424C04A5BA22" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>data infrastructure needs; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H26FBDF7FFF284CF88B61EF6DF6B38C70" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other needs, as determined to be appropriate by the Administrator; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF7741335434F42F09CA015A7B8FC7FDB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>technology modernization targets for upgrades to integrated air quality monitoring stations.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HCCB79BD36B4A451B957F2F2BF67DB51F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Hyperlocal monitoring support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 360 days after the date on which the Working Group is established under subsection (a)(1), the Working Group shall develop and submit to Congress a report that includes—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2BF86B006E14470CA3FE29B3B371DC91" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for how the Administrator can consider data returned from hybrid methods in designations pursuant to section 107 of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7407">42 U.S.C. 7407</external-xref>); and </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HAA5C087A6CAA4CFBBC8F2613D3392431" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations for dedicated staffing at the Environmental Protection Agency to robustly support communities interested in hyperlocal data, for example, assistance with grant applications, co-location of low-cost monitors with Federal reference monitors, and data analysis.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB29F564A9A664EC09234C3985A89E2F7" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>National infrastructure inventory</header> 
<subsection id="H4E80DEA52EA9485387516B5E70C8B779" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Comptroller General of the United States, in coordination with the Environmental Protection Agency, shall carry out a study to inventory national air quality monitoring infrastructure by documenting—</text> <paragraph id="HB4B5375D8C0C4A88A62AE378420FFA4A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>locations, operation statuses, frequencies of data return, and dates of installation of Federal air quality monitors;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HD017F5ABE80740D69E3F7E5629CB4409" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the number of people living within <fraction>1/2</fraction> mile of Federal air quality monitors that continuously return data;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB2DD81E140DF4C748C0DA3927020D875" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in coordination with Regional Offices of the Environmental Protection Agency, and State, local, and Tribal air agencies, the locations, operation statuses, and dates of installation of additional air quality monitors that are managed by State, local, and Tribal air agencies;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H342F4290DCD94DEB9EDC96C7E1C107AB" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>data infrastructure and online platforms that are associated with datasets collected by Federal, State, local, and Tribal air quality monitors that are documented under paragraphs (1) and (3); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD3F323EA4BBD4F1881170594255E4BBA" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">existing workforce capacity and needs for air quality monitoring, analysis and State and local engagement across Federal, State, local, and Tribal levels.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H3AC7757C407448C88173DFC76DD0A05D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the relevant committees of Congress a report that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H6819216FC9564453AF3FB89944490DC4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the study carried out under subsection (a);</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9CC91440F4484BF485A6D93B13428253" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of the results of that study;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H95EFDA7DFD804F919BA85F76992D7C3D" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a map of high-priority areas for air quality monitor deployment, based on factors such as proximity to or effects on environmental justice communities, discrepancies between monitor readings and satellite or low-cost sensor readings, proliferation of air pollution sources, and the lack of existing Federal Reference Method or Federal Equivalent Method monitors; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H74FDBD65FB7B4CD58842A45FF77CADF7" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>recommendations for legislative and regulatory action that would facilitate more effective and targeted air quality management across scales, which may include—</text> <subparagraph id="H947F8D02225448A69A32EF538522CE59" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>monitor placement;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDF86A2088118402C8C233B5FB5DA1BBA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>monitor accuracy;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB6C1AE2902D6456885B55B8ADAC510C7" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>integration of monitor, modeling, and satellite technologies;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HA5FF8439E1D14BB8A3994D2EF6E17B76" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Federal Equivalent Methods for hyperlocal monitoring;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6D84775D9FCF428BA3DBACB5F85C6BD6" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>information gathering and sharing; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H452FE478E01445D8B7198E7A1417241E" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>maintenance and regular upgrades to monitors and data infrastructure. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H6625535F98C247DE83588ADDF2868913" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Administrator $11,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 for the purposes of—</text> 
<paragraph id="HD2484FA1D88A45BAAFFC391FAEF3C8E6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>carrying out this Act; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA28029997C6F4EE39F2523C1A6BE5F88" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>funding 8 new full-time equivalent positions to assist the Administrator in carrying out this Act.</text> </paragraph></section> 
<section id="HE5DDB46D7433485F80DBE6EE5983AFF5" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed as altering, limiting, revising, or weakening existing Federal law to protect public health or welfare from air pollution. </text></section> </legis-body></bill>

