<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H198FB9EE33D24055B7E6EC5C00AA928A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8980 IH: Preserving the Gulf Test Range to Ensure Military Readiness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8980</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220922">September 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000600">Mr. Diaz-Balart</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000032">Mr. Donalds</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000628">Mr. Dunn</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000593">Mr. Gimenez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000168">Ms. Salazar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000609">Mr. Rutherford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001039">Mrs. Cammack</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000472">Mr. C. Scott Franklin of Florida</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000806">Mr. Webster of Florida</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a moratorium on energy development in certain areas of the Gulf of Mexico, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF5900AD4055F45C6ACFD56B795949C06" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H14C0E67DC1424A24A82CFC2F8958A2C6" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Preserving the Gulf Test Range to Ensure Military Readiness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB3F91A84F89947689AAC4E45D956BC68"><enum>2.</enum><header>Moratorium on energy development in certain areas of Gulf of Mexico</header> <subsection id="H6DBF0AA98BFD464285C6D8AB4F04FA89"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H12869EEB25D041B5B0875529AA3AAB3C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Military Mission Line</header><text>The term <term>Military Mission Line</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Gulf of Mexico Energy Security Act of 2006 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1331">43 U.S.C. 1331</external-xref> note; <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/109/432">Public Law 109–432</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7B80FFD6F6404D1A9A8291DC0248E020"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H25796ECB14694F3A9166A360485C4033"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Moratorium</header><text>Effective during the period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act and ending on June 30, 2032, the Secretary shall not offer for leasing, preleasing, or any related activity for energy development of any kind—</text> <paragraph id="HCEBB90D523184B75A2C5614684F4359A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any area east of the Military Mission Line in the Gulf of Mexico; or</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H192D9843F98D4755A62753D9ACC3792A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any area of the outer Continental Shelf described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C) of paragraph (2) of subsection (d), if oil, gas, wind, or any other form of energy exploration, leasing, or development in that area has been identified in a report under that subsection as having any adverse effect on the national security of the United States or the military readiness or testing capabilities of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H63A3D1EC6F1747BDAB7BF4AC069FCD0C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Environmental exceptions</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b), the Secretary may issue leases in areas described in that subsection for environmental conservation purposes, including the purposes of shore protection, beach nourishment and restoration, wetlands restoration, and habitat protection.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H3DCF1F5C80EE4E8FA849AE09B15E8DF8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports</header>
<paragraph id="H373BAB9BF48B43E19324B2201EBE4A42"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, and not later than June 30, 2031, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Appropriations and Armed Services of the Senate and the Committees on Appropriations and Armed Services of the House of Representatives a report that describes the impact of oil, gas, wind, and any other form of energy exploration, leasing, or development in areas of the outer Continental Shelf described in paragraph (2) on the national security of the United States and the military readiness and testing capabilities of the Department of Defense.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8EF9B6CA4C1241089E577C062C6CBF42"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Areas described</header><text>The areas of the outer Continental Shelf referred to in paragraph (1) are the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H167E929EC9A1415CA52F854A6CC9D6B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Any area west of the Military Mission Line in the Gulf of Mexico.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C0B823E43AB4CEFB7FB8F8B173C1594"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The South Atlantic Planning Area.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H805D108F25CE4D86BBB4A818F2877D8E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Straits of Florida Planning Area. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

