<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Enrolled-Bill" dms-id="H83626F6C836A4EB58C5C78C227CE6A55" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title> HR 1192 ENR: Puerto Rico Recovery Accuracy in Disclosures Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">One Hundred Seventeenth Congress of the United States of America</congress><session display="yes">At the Second Session</session><enrolled-dateline>Begun and held at the City of Washington on Monday, the third day of January, two thousand and twenty-two</enrolled-dateline> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 1192</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no"></current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To impose requirements on the payment of compensation to professional persons employed in voluntary cases commenced under title III of the Puerto Rico Oversight Management and Economic Stability Act (commonly known as <quote>PROMESA</quote>).</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HDB74B2DE56E7450E8655B967A498A8D0" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H3DA201A77FC2417BB51C0C26B0F3D439" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Puerto Rico Recovery Accuracy in Disclosures Act of 2021</short-title></quote> or <quote><short-title>PRRADA</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HAB2CAF7BB5024D8395868DBB229C4517"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disclosure by professional persons seeking approval of compensation under section 316 or 317 of PROMESA</header> <subsection id="H353F202A7F6742E4B8C551B89E4C8C4E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text>
<paragraph id="H6B12AC949BE742378FFEE3E1295A3C73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List of Material Interested Parties</header><text>The term <term>List of Material Interested Parties</term> means the List of Material Interested Parties established under subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC874EBF79BC94D85BCF4B5CE11DD869D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Oversight Board</header><text>The term <term>Oversight Board</term> has the meaning given the term in section 5 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2104">48 U.S.C. 2104</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H511B69DE43B549E4A0B08E9C84A88E45"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Required disclosure</header>
<paragraph id="HB8F2EDEC23FA413DB0DBF605504C925B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In a case commenced under section 304 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2164">48 U.S.C. 2164</external-xref>), no attorney, accountant, appraiser, auctioneer, agent, or other professional person may be compensated under section 316 or 317 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2176">48 U.S.C. 2176</external-xref>, 2177) unless prior to making a request for compensation, the professional person has filed with the court a verified statement conforming to the disclosure requirements of rule 2014(a) of the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure setting forth the connection of the professional person with any entity or person on the List of Material Interested Parties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3EEF8EF8517743D384C01D0339FC4648"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplement</header><text>A professional person that submits a statement under paragraph (1) shall promptly supplement the statement with any additional relevant information that becomes known to the person.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H1179A8BC7927439781DD58FD5018063E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Disclosure</header><text>Subject to any other applicable law, rule, or regulation, a professional person that fails to file or update a statement required under paragraph (1) or files a statement that the court determines does not represent a good faith effort to comply with this section shall disclose such failure in any filing required to conform to the disclosure requirements under rule 2014(a) of the Federal Rules of Bankruptcy Procedure.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9AE69AE05B4C4B53AA0203145C0D1538"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List of material interested parties</header> <paragraph id="HF2F390513CBC49C583DFCA606A3056D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Preparation</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Oversight Board shall establish a List of Material Interested Parties subject to—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCCF6FE4EADFA4EB597DAEA71E02CA1F9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the approval of the court; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC5154CB4370549A9AE197BAAF57BD487"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the right of the United States trustee or any party in interest to be heard on the approval.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H27CF393B40B74E68ABAB48B94A84D03A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (3), the List of Material Interested Parties shall include—</text> <subparagraph id="HB959ABC0A87B4D13B4D54E37CAD67D3B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the debtor;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H05728151FFF94633926CCA22B62FE571"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any creditor;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7BF524E375754C0493ED6DF3784ABE81"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any other party in interest;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3CDA65D92F634829A29A544FF924BCD9"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any attorney or accountant of—</text> <clause id="HE2A477A5672B43348B1CEB39FC875641"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the debtor;</text></clause>
<clause id="HDCB091579CBC43FAA9D2BA80203911BA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any creditor; or</text></clause> <clause id="H9152197F826D42FAB7AFFFCA63DB6B9B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other party in interest;</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD3418C66B7947E3B8B755230863AAE6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the United States trustee and any person employed in the office of the United States trustee; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2C55670E1C514BBDA4CCC5D6036FC1DE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Oversight Board, including the members, the Executive Director, and the employees of the Oversight Board.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB629F0FDEE17413A9776D4734B81E91A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The List of Material Interested Parties may not include any person with a claim, the amount of which is below a threshold dollar amount established by the court that is consistent with the purpose of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE50CD2A6014E4F6D8DF36267B2E069C9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Review</header> <paragraph id="H174447D858DF48899289DC06D66F2093"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The United States trustee shall review each verified statement submitted pursuant to subsection (b) and may file with the court comments on such verified statements before the professionals filing such statements seek compensation under section 316 or 317 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2176">48 U.S.C. 2176</external-xref>, 2177).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H75E4EF19BED141B6973494D512FBF33B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Objection</header><text>The United States trustee may object to applications filed under section 316 or 317 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2176">48 U.S.C. 2176</external-xref>, 2177) that fail to satisfy the requirements of subsection (b).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H857B681755D645FC99DE34CDD8569D35"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Limitation on compensation</header><text>In a case commenced under section 304 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2164">48 U.S.C. 2164</external-xref>), in connection with the review and approval of professional compensation under section 316 or 317 of PROMESA (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2176">48 U.S.C. 2176</external-xref>, 2177) filed after the date of enactment of this Act, the court may deny allowance of compensation or reimbursement of expenses if—</text>
<paragraph id="H91B3C10AF7EB48F38D37ED6FCC90DB0D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the professional person has failed to file the verified disclosure statements required under subsection (b)(1) or has filed inadequate disclosure statements under that subsection; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBABE93DD2996494F8551A23EEF8E111E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>during the professional person’s employment in connection with the case, the professional person—</text>
<subparagraph id="HF6CC1D5B905A4C8B9C17F1686C93940B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is not a disinterested person (as defined in section 101 of title 11, United States Code) relative to any entity or person on the List of Material Interested Parties; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HACCAB5BD6F374839A62EA3BAAA4BD0A7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>represents or holds an adverse interest in connection with the case.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section>
</legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><role>Speaker of the House of Representatives.</role></attestation-group><attestation-group><role>Vice President of the United States and President of the Senate.</role></attestation-group></attestation>
</bill> 


