<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1E2C1E5FEC75487A928CC5CD27545173" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7119 IH: Water Design-Build Improvement Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7119</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220317">March 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 to authorize the selection of eligible projects to be carried out using collaborative project delivery methods, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8AAC59C4D09E47AA84307CB1D463F5EA" style="OLC"><section id="HA10C4AB7D1614055AF0F9FA29F2C0FE8" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Water Design-Build Improvement Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDFF69656C4C649E6837BD6BD84C3D8EB"><enum>2.</enum><header>Collaborative project delivery methods</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 5028 of the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3907">33 U.S.C. 3907</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H82F1BDB6233548669F59AC3A16554729"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (c) as subsection (d); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB01EF6D8223A4D159703C7C11CBAB2C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF368536C5E634370BA8B9D847B57A329" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEF5B527A9D364B8A8861BD1F8BBFC3ED"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Collaborative project delivery methods</header><paragraph id="H68EFD94E0C184A2889B2EE62165CE576"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorization</header><text>The Secretary or the Administrator, as applicable, may select, in accordance with this section, a project to be carried out using a collaborative project delivery method (consistent with any applicable State or local law), including a construction management at-risk method and a design-build method.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6BDF69FDDFD24585840A303E092FE87F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H14559B910C78425EA8EB6306465C2B70"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Collaborative project delivery method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>collaborative project delivery method</term> means a method for carrying out a capital project that involves close collaboration among the eligible entity, the owner of the project (if different from the eligible entity), the designer of the project, and the contractor for the project, from design through completion of construction.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1FEDD25BC3E4ADC88AA73AC44ACFFEE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Construction management at-risk method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>construction management at-risk method</term> means a collaborative project delivery method in which an engineering firm and a construction management at-risk firm are retained under 2 separate contracts for design and construction, respectively.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8023C3B84D90454CA1B868AA6C4E3230"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Design-build method</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>design-build method</term> means a collaborative project delivery method under which a single lead contract is entered into with a design-builder for design and construction.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HA6F8809BE7CB49E3A37836AA9BA989EE" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Study on the use of collaborative project delivery methods</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, in coordination with the Regional Administrators, and the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall carry out, and make public the results of, a study that—</text><paragraph id="HE32652CD31954CC0833CF3F006D357E4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">evaluates the use of collaborative project delivery methods in projects carried out using assistance received under the Water Infrastructure Finance and Innovation Act of 2014 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/33/3901">33 U.S.C. 3901 et seq.</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04EDB78DE7094934A7223B5724AA4B12" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>determines barriers to increased use of collaborative project delivery methods in such projects;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA816D2BAD2EB464B86B7C805DFB3F06F" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>assesses the potential benefits of using collaborative project delivery methods in such projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37405DE6793643108B303CBAD321084C" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identifies areas of need to educate agency staff in collaborative project delivery method implementation and best practices.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

