<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA87EAA594B584431AF294D786AB1F189" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9247 IH: Abortion Care Awareness Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9247</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221028">October 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct a public health education, awareness, and outreach campaign to enhance access to abortion and related health services.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HEEDEDECED38D458CBB869BC8FA3EFBE6" style="OLC"><section id="H4823CBC27EC64109910F6E05AD37F1F2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Abortion Care Awareness Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H54DE59A0350A48F08BAD078E1976CE60"><enum>2.</enum><header>Public education and awareness campaign on access to abortion and related health services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part P of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/280g">42 U.S.C. 280g et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H98A3483F3D1D4991AAD6789159067AB2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H3F31C75424D449B08850057507F4CEBB"><enum>399V–7.</enum><header>Public education and awareness campaign on access to abortion and related health services</header><subsection id="HC2BD12E2935F41B3A453C8008C96E320"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall carry out a coordinated, focused, national public health education, awareness, and outreach campaign to enhance access to abortion and related health services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H575D08DC1B514C8D8ABFC2BDE16B7A47"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Campaign requirements</header><text>The campaign under subsection (a) shall—</text><paragraph id="H59222C0354B94793AAFAD0CB7218AC96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>include education, awareness, and outreach regarding—</text><subparagraph id="H15D0EF99A5FA4A20AE51D451806453AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">where and how to access abortion and related health services, including where and how to access medication abortion that is consistent with the labeling most recently approved by the Food and Drug Administration;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4372580A8FB043CA899F842A4831939C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>medically accurate information about medication abortion;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB18EE8BEA8684A32A7C8CC87FF049892"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the right of patients to legally travel across State lines to obtain abortion and related health services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A48F40520C7462FA14F7254D262DD94"><enum>(D)</enum><text>how to differentiate facilities commonly known as crisis pregnancy centers from facilities that actually provide abortion and related health services, including how to identify—</text><clause id="H9B063CED3A4F4F929396E5B333EF2342"><enum>(i)</enum><text>misleading claims by such centers about reproductive health care; and</text></clause><clause id="H763DC14E31EF42CB9983209B7B1C2DAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>inaccurate, misleading, or stigmatizing information disseminated by such centers about the risks of abortion and contraception; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4FD464DE823648B98D2DA03F59DAA962"><enum>(E)</enum><text>how to identify misinformation regarding abortion and related health services intended to deceive, or to discourage individuals from accessing such services; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F4CA6CD86004C17AD3B28E705979F89"><enum>(2)</enum><text>be designed to ensure cultural competency, efficacy, and accessibility for and within underserved communities, including communities of color, immigrants, people with disabilities, people with limited English proficiency, people with low income, young people, LGBTQI+ people, and people living in rural or other medically underserved areas.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC0D8B155B4C440B4A7F51D6FB8B6BA61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Campaign limitations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the campaign under subsection (a), the Secretary shall not—</text><paragraph id="HA7308B9645974720BD2B33DAC9992AFD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>promote misinformation regarding the safety of abortion and related health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC02EF9DD831242EAB90D549FF80949E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>promote abstinence-only-until-marriage programs, also referred to as sexual risk avoidance education programs, or other programs that are not comprehensive or medically accurate; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA0BBB4ADBA549E0B542AE299F30A0F7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>collect, retain, use, or disclose personal information about visitors to any website, app, or other educational or campaign resource.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5BBDB26BD66B41008442855018EE7384"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In carrying out the campaign under subsection (a), the Secretary shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H2F27D54637204C8DBB8CC7AB9277C60E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">licensed health care professionals who are experts in reproductive health as well as abortion and related health services, including medication abortion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD911E7452224FD0B0663277A2458CEA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">nonprofit organizations whose missions are focused on expanding reproductive rights and reproductive justice, including abortion funds;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99CE0980648F4944996B2A9942FCA2E3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>State and local public health departments; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAED6B76CAC4B45CFB2EC1582CB5FD162"><enum>(4)</enum><text>nonprofit institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD60F547001084401B39CDC428EED1E7E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there are authorized to be appropriated such sums as may be necessary.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

