<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71B4E0F627EC46DDBAC291A9403BDADA" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8955 IH: Ukrainian Territorial Integrity Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8955</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220922">September 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="C000266">Mr. Chabot</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To counter Russian influence and aggression in Ukraine.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H96CCE473FC4B4D14A3B7F4EDECEC3AC0" style="OLC"><section id="H72F9EEABAE794823AD2CC02574B66231" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Ukrainian Territorial Integrity Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1DC1F2A6915D48A6816B5DA6A105C655"><enum>2.</enum><header>Countering Russian influence and aggression in Ukraine</header><subsection id="HE51C51DCCCA24E8CAEC7AB940608CABF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States not to recognize the Russian Federation’s claim of sovereignty over, or independence, of any part of Ukraine occupied by Russian forces, including Crimea and the Donetsk and Luhansk regions. </text></subsection><subsection id="HFE5DF550B6864E29A23D4CF1E60F9EAD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><paragraph id="H923786679B5F406E924054FD361CD891"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds authorized to be appropriated or otherwise made available to any Federal department or agency may be used to provide assistance for the central government of a country that the Secretary of State determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees—</text><subparagraph id="H20196906378E4A9CBB4D5547DD0D4F58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has recognized the independence of, or has established diplomatic relations with, any region located in the territory of Ukraine that is occupied by the Russian Federation or under the control of Russian-backed separatists, including Crimea and the Donetsk and Luhansk regions; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD9D5589C7997468FBCDE2E93D3309304"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has taken affirmative steps intended to support or be supportive of the Russian Federation annexation of Crimea or other territory in Ukraine.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD369D0B96EC44338A4E384AAC4139FFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication of list of central governments</header><text>The Secretary of State shall publish on the Department of State website a list of such central governments in a timely manner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AA134C1DDC24A968642FB3AC26A5A8D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of State may waive the prohibition on assistance required by paragraph (1) with respect to any such central government if the Secretary determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that to do so is in the national interest of the United States, and includes a justification for such interest. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDD6AEE3A4F24B819944FAF2E0C52A1F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements and limitations of this section shall cease to be in effect if the Secretary of State determines and reports to the appropriate congressional committees that the Government of Ukraine has reestablished sovereignty over each region located in the territory of Ukraine that is occupied by the Russian Federation or under the control of Russian-backed separatists, including Crimea and the Donetsk and Luhansk regions.</text></subsection><subsection id="H36BF89840B964C08A28C7109FC5DB1EE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees defined</header><text>In this section, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

