<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HC0FA45C0152D42F4A46F61DDFCD23D03" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6360 IH: COVID–19 Supply Chain Relief Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6360</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220106">January 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000583">Mr. Gottheimer</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220110">January 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Commerce, and in addition to the Committee on Oversight and Reform, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a Supply Chain Czar, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCB1EEEB5775443CC9DC1DA1B492DF358" style="OLC"><section id="HB1A136807D2641A5A359BA7BE29468DF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>COVID–19 Supply Chain Relief Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1526398649F040B5BF2457A39AF2E863"><enum>2.</enum><header>Supply Chain Czar</header><subsection id="H23626B55F48E4BBAA1124CF35D180F65"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established in the Executive Office of the President an Office of Supply Chain Policy, which shall do the following:</text><paragraph id="HC2E273A9393E41D087E55A529B76679B"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Coordinate a national response to supply chain disruptions, shortages, and increased prices.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6493C52A9B124FDF999EBCC5ED960AC0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Serve as a resource for States as States deploy unused COVID–19 relief funds to address supply chain bottlenecks in their States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22ADBD767F564AD0A1563D0D2C99D0C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Appoint, oversee, and coordinate among regional supply chain leaders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2268FC4A23A84F2EBD22C431B1E52610"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Appointment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There shall be at the head of the Office a Supply Chain Czar, appointed by the President, who shall serve at the pleasure of the President.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD9AD1298E00A4137AB6B1F84F45E21D9"><enum>3.</enum><header>State use of COVID–19 relief funds for supply chain disruptions</header><subsection id="HCB338D7808E243EA93A2CE0A28DE00E4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unobligated balances of amounts appropriated or otherwise made available under title VI of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/801">42 U.S.C. 801 et seq.</external-xref>) to any State, territory, or Tribal government by the amendments made by subtitle M of title IX of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 may also be made available to such State, territory, or Tribal government to help address supply chain disruptions and labor shortages by undertaking one or more of the following:</text><paragraph id="H98697193B8194BEEBE707E2545BD8112"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Promoting employment in the trucking and logistics industries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD1039ECCD45435385B4A0AE78D3F8C8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Implementing apprenticeship programs to recruit more women and military veterans to become licensed commercial motor vehicle drivers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1F4526ACABD4DC0962853210C509477"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Undertaking port and shipping infrastructure projects.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21FBC89B43C94C8E9B7296EBF9956D16"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Providing relief from other detrimental economic impacts of supply chain disruptions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBE116E4FED647D38B3FC86AA667A148"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authority To issue guidance</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall issue such guidance as may be necessary to implement this section including, as needed, to define the scope of the allowable activities listed in subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H2526129D871C412EAC9F04B642EF3C94"><enum>4.</enum><header>Departments of Commerce and Transportation report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall publish and submit to Congress a report on the following, related to supply chains in the United States:</text><paragraph id="H48A71F257EA54056B91CFA0D36BE7888"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Points of congestion or blockages.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H474E78CA6C454DCDAE30DFD0E0E592FF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Underlying causes of supply chain disruptions, shortages, and delays.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FA1EC837062429FAD6779E6389313B5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Other supply chain shortcomings which, with public or private investment, could be remedied to result in more efficient movement of goods into and within the United States.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

