<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A8D0FCF41D345B49F7F4166E57F8F48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8478 IH: Credit Reporting Accuracy After a Legal Name Change Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8478</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to require nationwide consumer reporting agencies, upon request, to use a consumer’s current legal name on consumer reports, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0B5646BB173A4263B5676E99E9824BD3" style="OLC"><section id="H22F8CEA386A34D5693731CB25E3B3182" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Credit Reporting Accuracy After a Legal Name Change Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H1A0925A672394D139809E4A6D9B6A0B6"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HA059943AE5A24F7E9BB3AC3D3C7D14CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Consumer reports are significant to the ability for American consumers to access credit, housing, and employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H692A748AA45C4AE3A473082894BDF2E5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fragmented files created by the credit reporting industry lead to inaccuracies on the consumer reports of transgender and gender nonconforming consumers after a legal name change. Inaccurate consumer reports create additional burdens and barriers for these consumers and impair their ability to access credit, housing, and employment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CCB2ADF487C4CBBB7D411B0D37B6C6F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>As of 2017, there were approximately 1.4 million adults who identify as transgender, according to the Williams Institute report, <quote>Age of Individuals Who Identify as Transgender in the United States</quote>, and as of 2021, approximately 1.2 million adults identify as nonbinary, according to the Williams Institute report, <quote>Nonbinary LGBTQ Adults in the United States</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4AF5EE5286EA4325841FF374659BBFA1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As evidence that transgender and gender nonconforming adults are vulnerable to discrimination, harassment, and abuse based on their gender identity and expression, in its 2016 report <quote>Injustice at Every Turn</quote>, the National Center for Transgender Equality found that transgender adults experienced unemployment at twice the rate of the general population, and 90 percent reported experiencing harassment, discrimination, or mistreatment in the workplace. The report further found that one in five transgender adults reported having been refused a home or apartment because of their gender identity.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD0FFF1544E6741F1839CCB448BF3D9DC"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Transgender and gender nonconforming consumers face a myriad of problems in terms of consumer reporting problems after they change their names, including that their credit report fragments into two or more unconnected files upon their name change and that their name change and any credit actions that follow are never reflected in their report at all. Many consumers report that credit reporting problems have a negative impact on their financial and personal lives, including credit score decreases of 100 points or more, which can be a barrier to accessing banking services, mortgages, auto financing, employment, and rental housing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H437CBFCA2210492C9211143974C0F162"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Transgender consumers face severe adverse effects from having their former name reflected on their credit report. The disclosure of a transgender person’s prior name in a consumer report to a creditor, employer, or lessor can expose those consumers to unlawful discrimination on the basis of that consumer’s gender identity.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB304BE58E27343F1AE8A2853FCEFD64A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Requirement to use a consumer’s current legal name on consumer reports</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 605(a) of the Fair Credit Reporting Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/1681c">15 U.S.C. 1681c(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD84AB77C1F6A40B28B4344AF0A17EE69" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6307CE8D81A9425286D53491098DA76D"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to a consumer reporting agency described in section 603(p), any prior name of the consumer about whom the report relates, other than the consumer’s current legal name, after receiving a request from the consumer to use only the consumer’s current legal name on all consumer reports.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

