<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7A6310EC43274A5A80353644BC25861B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>115 HR 6470 IH: Defending Ukraine Sovereignty Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6470</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220121">January 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001137">Mr. Meeks</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="A000376">Mr. Allred</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001287">Mr. Bera</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001084">Mr. Cicilline</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001078">Mr. Connolly</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001066">Mr. Horsford</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence (Permanent Select)</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To counter the aggression of the Russian Federation against Ukraine and Eastern European allies, to expedite security assistance to Ukraine to bolster Ukraine’s defense capabilities, and to impose sanctions relating to the actions of the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFF9A2D7A6AD0457CBAFE978C8ABD6AC9" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H3E33BD232539476687FD27E7ED2C252D"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="HAE7FBCEA6E604133AB8A6069A29BA269"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Defending Ukraine Sovereignty Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA5D3D4D063CD458EA9934E86620BE085"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H3E33BD232539476687FD27E7ED2C252D">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H9F00EF3E48FA4D67A5B65B74AB7D54D2">Sec. 2. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H83CB5E29A9B04FF2BD7BB49777F8E414">Sec. 3. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H7DD171253C764FD5BE0160A948EB9006">Sec. 4. Statement of policy.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="HE352C3CECB4E47509C6D9E8B93316293">TITLE I—Expediting security assistance to Ukraine and bolstering Ukraine’s defense capabilities </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HBAFF4E1BAB404551A75C8FBBF3531E35">Sec. 101. Prioritizing delivery of excess defense articles to Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H17266D1E98F441B0A29262ADCFD6A2FE">Sec. 102. Use of Department of Defense lease authority and Special Defense Acquisition Fund to support Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H33FE36A49FF847579C475A3171DE1A48">Sec. 103. Strategy for bolstering defensive capacities of Ukraine and enhancing delivery of security assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H2F7774969A074DECB221FF1BC57D3572">Sec. 104. Presidential drawdown authority.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H93619B3F437C40CB981A196330DB2251">Sec. 105. Foreign Military Financing.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H58132BA0E64A494395140712A4A68D28">Sec. 106. International Military Education and Training cooperation with Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC018B66B900F424B827AFCD7935EC6F2">Sec. 107. Strategy on International Military Education and Training programming in Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD3CDF183FD4A431E9A9F72C0C44EAC9A">Sec. 108. Sense of Congress on loan program.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H76A5E694386E44F3BD154903DE276DF6">Sec. 109. Report on security assistance and provision of defense articles to armed forces of Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H3C825CEF6AEB4D029A8ADA2A3F32FA5B">TITLE II—Countering Kremlin aggression against Ukraine and Eastern European allies</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H4CCF67988FD04EE3948C31C67BC03D47">Sec. 201. Authorizing programs to counter and combat disinformation activities of the Russian Federation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H592D4DD6B0CA40218D8218B7D5BF9EAD">Sec. 202. Expanded support and authorization for Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty to reach audiences on the periphery of the Russian Federation.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H09648727C685442789315191E4FB0D78">Sec. 203. Multilateral efforts to bolster Ukraine’s cyber defense capabilities.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H1D643CF6E42A4BB19E3B4AA475123B72">Sec. 204. Report on role of intelligence and security services of the Russian Federation in efforts to undermine the independence and integrity of Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H8A4A15F45E7846878BCF76BE08073F13">Sec. 205. Strategy for forum on European security.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HCE8FE03761244531A172418D8A2182C9">Sec. 206. Deepening security and economic ties with Baltic allies.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6807C0017DAB430C9DBCBCC98BC5BCCB">Sec. 207. Public disclosure of assets of Vladimir Putin and his inner circle.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HF895565BAC8B4D27B76DDBB27BF8A3EC">Sec. 208. Briefing to fulfill United States-Ukraine strategic dialogue objectives.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="HD66487232AD54C608C0C08ACE045D208">TITLE III—Deterrence measures against further military escalation and aggression by the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA4FD650E0D1E4E328F56AB15AC4DB7F1">Sec. 301. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H062032924F504A2EB5A0A7CFD270DC74">Sec. 302. Determination with respect to operations of the Russian Federation in Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE8E2E6EE10CA4E4DBC677A2ED6479958">Sec. 303. Imposition of sanctions with respect to officials of the Government of the Russian Federation relating to operations in Ukraine.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HCFF0884F5311451CBC66C4D41F8CA118">Sec. 304. Imposition of sanctions with respect to Russian financial institutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H4F0968878A8F4FD6A490CB033EB7BC76">Sec. 305. Imposition of sanctions with respect to provision of specialized financial messaging services to sanctioned Russian financial institutions.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HE203838FCF534E32BE033D9752A6B1D2">Sec. 306. Prohibition on and imposition of sanctions with respect to transactions involving Russian sovereign debt.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H16DAEC4A27F1415AB4A6474661EA73BF">Sec. 307. Department of State review of sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HDB0BED18F5F34143B0DA7292F0FBCF9F">Sec. 308. Imposition of sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H334039392536485A93D342452FB1E9CA">Sec. 309. Imposition of sanctions with respect to Russian extractive industries.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H14521787A5AF4281BF760B961002CC99">Sec. 310. Sanctions described.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD830D10BA22148F9B0C6D02DDC8AE22D">Sec. 311. Implementation; regulations; penalties.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H90F6BC06F0D24287874384FFB7D7AF20">Sec. 312. Exceptions; waiver.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H6081EA1C7F464A119FC4B6B10C4B40F8">Sec. 313. Termination.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="title" idref="H59AE3041BFB04E95ACD9DD06A53424FF">TITLE IV—General provisions</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H614B849B6CD44D14804327F4B669D899">Sec. 401. Sunset.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HA6A417CDCD174598BE72FBF936A4DA73">Sec. 402. Exception relating to importation of goods.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="H9F00EF3E48FA4D67A5B65B74AB7D54D2" changed="not-changed"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H0A02B9958D2547D98FE51BE1B33F3D87"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4090FAEC46D2406894296D265719043F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Defense article; defense service</header><text>The terms <quote>defense article</quote> and <quote>defense service</quote> have the meanings given those terms in section 47 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2794">22 U.S.C. 2794</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H83CB5E29A9B04FF2BD7BB49777F8E414"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HA4879A2FF8C741D6A70D59A48065DEBC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>it is in the national security interests of the United States to continue and deepen the security partnership between the United States and Ukraine, and support Ukraine’s sovereignty and territorial integrity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4DD1785294AD43808B9653A0E9E6CD0E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>aggression and malign influence by the Government of the Russian Federation and its proxies in Ukraine is a threat to the democratic sovereignty of Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H395F3319A22D489B923A06261B20450B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in coordination with the European Union, the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), and members of the international community, the United States should support the territorial integrity of Ukraine and oppose any effort by the Government of the Russian Federation to further encroach on Ukraine’s territory and independence; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H417769C2B786481086577C3C15EFEB9B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States should work in close concert with allies and partners of the United States—</text><subparagraph id="H63F1B5411BA843EE8484D38DE9B79AB5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to support and expedite the provision of lethal and non-lethal assistance to Ukraine; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF48EBDBC90F445C0933E37C354F27213"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to support and bolster the defense of Ukraine against potential renewed aggression and military escalation by the Government of the Russian Federation or through any of its proxies;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H088DF9EEF3C447C39789A42E3C59C31B"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States and NATO should not cede to the demands of the Government of the Russian Federation regarding NATO membership or expansion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F18A18FC418404F8A972E82C1CAB735"><enum>(6)</enum><text>economic and financial sanctions, when used as part of a coordinated and comprehensive strategy, are a powerful tool to advance United States foreign policy and national security interests; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H22B5C06F13324C11AA3820A9FC57F756"><enum>(7)</enum><text>the United States, in coordination with allies and partners of the United States, should impose substantial new sanctions in the event that the Government of the Russian Federation or its proxies engages in escalatory military operations or other destabilizing aggression against Ukraine.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H7DD171253C764FD5BE0160A948EB9006"><enum>4.</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States that—</text><paragraph id="H939A6CEBD7C84D028171C0F54A35C269"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States will support the territorial integrity of Ukraine and other Eastern European countries against aggression by the Government of the Russian Federation or its proxies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74BB63F6439348E597510AB706F15E03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States will work to ensure the swift and ongoing provision of lethal and non-lethal security assistance to Ukraine, particularly so long as the Government of the Russian Federation or its proxies has armed forces within the territorial borders of Ukraine or stationed near Ukraine’s border; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCAB2A3D39F274A089B72D338BFB10330"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States will continue to build the resiliency of Ukraine’s military and cyber defenses and bolster Ukraine’s ability to defend against aggression by the Government of the Russian Federation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0385E8C4CA8B459489335E01D40DDFA3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States will continue to improve Ukraine’s interoperability with NATO forces and seek to further enhance security cooperation and engagement with and among partners in the Black Sea and Baltic region; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97877F0B0B5E4386AA561535A1A8F8A9"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the United States will work closely with regional partners, including those in the Black Sea region and the Baltic states, to strengthen Ukrainian and regional security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F46D99292B948BF84782DA9FD06E34D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>the United States is committed to a strong and unified NATO and will not cede to the demands of the Government of the Russian Federation regarding NATO membership.</text></paragraph></section><title id="HE352C3CECB4E47509C6D9E8B93316293" style="OLC"><enum>I</enum><header>Expediting security assistance to Ukraine and bolstering Ukraine’s defense capabilities </header><section id="HBAFF4E1BAB404551A75C8FBBF3531E35"><enum>101.</enum><header>Prioritizing delivery of excess defense articles to Ukraine</header><subsection id="H59B4FC48AFC44C299B302912C4B282F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>During fiscal year 2022, the United States should give priority to the delivery of excess defense articles to Ukraine over the transfer of such articles to other countries and regions under section 516(c)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2321j">22 U.S.C. 2321j(c)(2)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H97A3F317558F437FBA16AF1D41981F55"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The President may waive subsection (a) if the President certifies to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, that such a waiver is in the national security interest of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H17266D1E98F441B0A29262ADCFD6A2FE"><enum>102.</enum><header>Use of Department of Defense lease authority and Special Defense Acquisition Fund to support Ukraine</header><subsection id="H82A9028BDE3E4D3997E8059AE4783BA1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Use of special defense acquisition fund</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may utilize, to the maximum extent possible, the Special Defense Acquisition Fund established under section 51 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2795">22 U.S.C. 2795</external-xref>) to expedite the procurement and delivery of defense articles and defense services for the purpose of assisting and supporting the armed forces of Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3AA1E691BC9B476C966AFC49935F4E11"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Use of lease authority</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in consultation with the Secretary of State, may utilize, to the maximum extent possible, its lease authority, including with respect to no-cost leases, to provide defense articles to Ukraine for the purpose of assisting and supporting the armed forces of Ukraine.</text></subsection></section><section id="H33FE36A49FF847579C475A3171DE1A48"><enum>103.</enum><header>Strategy for bolstering defensive capacities of Ukraine and enhancing delivery of security assistance</header><subsection id="HCD8C3D19879B4E59AB67D9B2A16926F2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, a strategy for bolstering the defensive capabilities of the armed forces of Ukraine and enhancing the delivery of security assistance to Ukraine, which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H2DFC2F369F0047EEA3DBF81BE3E8B335"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A plan to meet the most critical capability gaps and capacity shortfalls of the armed forces of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F27FCD538CC4CAB8FC4D82371C0062A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan for United States cooperation with allies and partners to provide immediate assistance to the armed forces of Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA54D75C935B424F83F10CACFCE4C259"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A plan to prioritize the delivery of excess defense articles to Ukraine in accordance with section 101.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66995809F526497A978C5C9AED658FD3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan to transfer to Ukraine defense articles previously allocated for operations in Afghanistan that are available for transfer, as appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H67A0BFA6889145BBA6DB457BA1DBF420"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary. </text></subsection></section><section id="H2F7774969A074DECB221FF1BC57D3572"><enum>104.</enum><header>Presidential drawdown authority</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The authority under section 506(a) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2318">22 U.S.C. 2318(a)</external-xref>) may be exercised during fiscal year 2022 for Ukraine to the maximum extent available for that fiscal year.</text></section><section id="H93619B3F437C40CB981A196330DB2251"><enum>105.</enum><header>Foreign Military Financing</header><subsection id="H54EBAABD5ECB405A8A83C223F04681C7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H829DE04BC43349F6A63361BE567C37A0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the provision of security assistance to Ukraine is one of the most efficient and effective mechanisms for supporting Ukraine and ensuring that it can defend against aggression by the Russian Federation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H799765EABD6944B288AA3CE632B83F2A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in light of the military build-up by the Government of the Russian Federation, the United States, working with allies and partners, should work to expedite the provision of defense articles and other security assistance to Ukraine and prioritize and facilitate assistance to respond to the most urgent defense needs of the armed forces of Ukraine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEE7BEF4BC7E4586B3A9A9ED34C0B2CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should ensure adequate planning for maintenance for any equipment provided to Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H723840C1C69E4F798511DFC077EA4994"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of emergency supplemental appropriations</header><text>Upon an affirmative determination under section 302, there is authorized to be appropriated for the Department of State for fiscal year 2022 $500,000,000, as an authorization of emergency supplemental appropriations, for Foreign Military Financing assistance to Ukraine to assist the country in meeting its defense needs.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9797A1A688F047568CEB247064D8E3C7"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header><text>Not later than 15 days before providing assistance or support pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a notification containing the following:</text><paragraph id="HBFDB1B974143402598F69D63341B2EA8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the assistance or support to be provided, including—</text><subparagraph id="HB2C44FC01EBB491A8A68F2AFDC69A3D4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the objectives of such assistance or support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB80D424EC41B4E61802E5E489185FFC3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the budget for such assistance or support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE78F3E545EEE4EA587B7E66876BC71EA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the expected or estimated timeline for delivery of such assistance or support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA4CD18875CE4B63A6715FF2E2FE52BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H308D8795B8C94205992D09B143374526"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authority To provide lethal assistance</header><text>The Secretary of State is authorized to provide lethal assistance under this section, including anti-armor weapon systems, mortars, crew-served weapons and ammunition, grenade launchers and ammunition, anti-tank weapons systems, anti-ship weapons systems, anti-aircraft weapons systems, and small arms and ammunition. </text></subsection></section><section id="H58132BA0E64A494395140712A4A68D28"><enum>106.</enum><header>International Military Education and Training cooperation with Ukraine</header><subsection id="H728C51D86A1E4AC0A01F583DFB28DC29"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H72E2EA171FD0481F8CC22AC399352022"><enum>(1)</enum><text>International Military Education and Training (IMET) is a critical component of United States security assistance that facilitates training of international forces and strengthens cooperation and ties between the United States and foreign countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D0A34068FA74DDBA243184BD3E6F2EE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>it is in the national interest of the United States to further strengthen the armed forces of Ukraine, particularly to enhance their defensive capability and improve interoperability for joint operations; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1EF8A628E1B498692353B30F3BA72C3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Government of Ukraine should fully utilize the United States IMET program, encourage eligible officers and civilian leaders to participate in the training, and promote successful graduates to positions of prominence in the armed forces of Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H14F6CE8CE4B34BA6BF0CAFDD88EDCBCE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of State for fiscal year 2022 $3,000,000 for International Military Education and Training assistance for Ukraine. The assistance shall be made available for the following purposes: </text><paragraph id="H19BDD4B2A3824C77B49750FD2BEC5C87"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training of future leaders.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0826BBEBCB44411965C222721FC8B7F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Establishing a rapport between the United States Armed Forces and the armed forces of Ukraine to build partnerships for the future.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD01EFCCEC8704E63B91F1B3ABC586E5C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Enhancement of interoperability and capabilities for joint operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2948756610744623950832B6F2F7B2A1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Focusing on professional military education, civilian control of the military, and human rights.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H27C7251DC3A64A2BA2247FE663C86F39"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Fostering a better understanding of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0E616D845512456AAF53AEDCECF713E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notice to Congress</header><text>Not later than 15 days before providing assistance or support pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a notification containing the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H5C9D76930E134768871B7FA99971DE11"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A detailed description of the assistance or support to be provided, including—</text><subparagraph id="H1B0B4740469D441EA63E707EB5D0AEB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the objectives of such assistance or support;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F6AE16CDF7945F0AD84488208B6A7DC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the budget for such assistance or support; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H30895A2422A84EEFA5D2A21D41B74B48"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the expected or estimated timeline for delivery of such assistance or support.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8495D40406D54F258EA90FB38684ED63"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of such other matters as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC018B66B900F424B827AFCD7935EC6F2"><enum>107.</enum><header>Strategy on International Military Education and Training programming in Ukraine</header><subsection id="HDC1C365C9AE64C50A130CD801638BE02"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for the implementation of the International Military Education and Training program in Ukraine authorized under section 106.</text></subsection><subsection id="H979C2FC2C74944698450211FDF416F35"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text><paragraph id="H1F4A8FF3B53242B7A7CB09EA8B166F2B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A clear plan, developed in close consultation with the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense and the armed forces of Ukraine, for how the IMET program will be used by the United States Government and the Government of Ukraine to propel program graduates to positions of prominence in support of the reform efforts of the armed forces of Ukraine in line with NATO standards.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D3A5BD2E1F444DBA1860C2EF8F4070F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the education and training requirements of the armed forces of Ukraine and clear recommendations for how IMET graduates should be assigned by the Ukrainian Ministry of Defense upon completion of education or training.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H54DB6A6CC95D432A816DC5496FEB581C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An accounting of the current combat requirements of the armed forces of Ukraine and an assessment of the viability of alternative mobile training teams, distributed learning, and other flexible solutions to reach such students.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9900668695F24E6D9597EAB5F9CD2558"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An identification of opportunities to influence the next generation of leaders through attendance at United States staff and war colleges, junior leader development programs, and technical schools.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H212E9AD4E8E74F139AC555D9E3FD4A61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may contain a classified annex.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD3CDF183FD4A431E9A9F72C0C44EAC9A"><enum>108.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on loan program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H1008FB193A1D471AB2BD43A4F28C3AEC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as appropriate, the United States Government should provide direct loans to Ukraine for the procurement of defense articles, defense services, and design and construction services pursuant to the authority of section 23 of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2763">22 U.S.C. 2763</external-xref>) to support the further development of Ukraine’s military forces; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H100D367A6015412B9FC14B192551E82B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>such loans should be considered an additive security assistance tool, and not a substitute for Foreign Military Financing for grant assistance or Ukraine Security Assistance Initiative programming. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H76A5E694386E44F3BD154903DE276DF6"><enum>109.</enum><header>Report on security assistance and provision of defense articles to armed forces of Ukraine</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="H9A6D4D75194A43438D956D2B4C655287"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the steps the United States has taken to provide and expedite security assistance, defense articles, and any other forms of support to Ukraine and the armed forces of Ukraine, including increasing air defense capabilities, since September 1, 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9274C96D63834924BF1B7A1DA7D89B27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a description of any increased assistance and support provided by allies and partners of the United States or Ukraine to Ukraine or the armed forces of Ukraine, including increasing air defense capabilities, since September 1, 2021; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC756CFF652CE47B1B6A7376E4553F945"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a description of any plans by the United States to provide additional assistance and support to Ukraine or the armed forces of Ukraine.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H3C825CEF6AEB4D029A8ADA2A3F32FA5B" style="OLC"><enum>II</enum><header>Countering Kremlin aggression against Ukraine and Eastern European allies</header><section id="H4CCF67988FD04EE3948C31C67BC03D47"><enum>201.</enum><header>Authorizing programs to counter and combat disinformation activities of the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="H5CB17E68DCF147D782220FA887B5C98D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Countering Russian influence fund</header><text>The Secretary of State should use funds available for obligation in the Countering Russian Influence Fund described in section 7070(d) of the Department of State, Foreign Operations, and Related Programs Appropriations Act, 2017 (division J of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/115/31">Public Law 115–31</external-xref>; 131 Stat. 706)—</text><paragraph id="H73AC8BA88AF74FD6AB1538F9BE9BFE20"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to prioritize assisting Ukraine to detect and combat disinformation from the Russian Federation and its proxies; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9839CC292F8452C826E49CB2BCA32B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to assist the Government of Ukraine in developing new defense strategies and technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H884CB89ED95B4990810F41937992D29F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy required</header><paragraph id="H70F9A99D657C4386AE06B314CA622DB6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 60 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a plan for countering and combating disinformation by the Russian Federation and supporting free and independent media in Ukraine that includes—</text><subparagraph id="H92962ECBCA874035BC8FF9290763D525"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a plan to assist the Government of Ukraine in combating and responding to malign influence operations of the Russian Federation aimed at inflaming tensions and dividing Ukrainian society;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF5CB7AF5D23407399608BDB41ED27D2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an assessment of effective efforts and programs to improve media literacy in Ukraine and recommendations for how the United States can assist in supporting and expanding those programs;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37E03286B2CC41C7874267EB65AD3A62"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a plan to assist the Government of Ukraine improve efforts to detect and remove content originating from Russian troll farms, bots, and other sources aimed at sowing division and disseminating disinformation in Ukraine or targeting Ukrainian audiences; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H777B903DCAB94EED808CE7A6529FABE1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>recommendations to increase support for independent media outlets, including Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BC9956A7057445B83A66B7458E48103"><enum>(E)</enum><text>recommendations to increase support for independent media outlets catering to Russian-speaking populations residing in Russian-occupied Crimea, the Donbas region of Ukraine, and throughout Ukraine. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D393D740E5A4A788F7B2C61919FAD9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Form</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy required by paragraph (1) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H592D4DD6B0CA40218D8218B7D5BF9EAD"><enum>202.</enum><header>Expanded support and authorization for Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty to reach audiences on the periphery of the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="H12FF9565894C4B92A65637967A719B79"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="HE7F0EDFAEEB64B97B041C61938D9FDF7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty continues to fulfill its mission of providing reliable, uncensored, and accessible news and reporting in Ukraine and other countries where media freedom is restricted;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02EBF62051E14826AA0C6415CD3BF02E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty is one of the most critical sources of unrestricted, independent news and reporting for audiences on the periphery of the Russian Federation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H344757E98B8E4057AFEBFCD9720708ED"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Government of the Russian Federation has engaged in systematic targeting of Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty reporters inside the Russian Federation, which has negatively impacted the organization’s ability to provide timely, reliable, and accurate news from inside the country; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1B0A1A7923D49E7AC20B61D1B804392"><enum>(4)</enum><text>despite pressure from the Government of the Russian Federation, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty’s audience continues to grow inside the Russian Federation and surrounding countries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C265340CDC0432E808FC4231CD3C078"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $155,500,000 for Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty for fiscal year 2022.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE1A3846DC53846D6825E78FABD36064D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of new bureaus</header><text>Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty may explore opening new bureaus to help expand its ability to reach audiences on the periphery of the Russian Federation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC39AF0227DE14EA6BF2CA34046A09989"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Initiatives To bolster Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty bureaus around Russian Federation’s periphery</header><text>To help expand its reach to Russian-speaking audiences and increase its reach to audiences through digital media, Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty should—</text><paragraph id="H40D6DFF3027747368A6E8CF81EB2F752"><enum>(1)</enum><text>evaluate where Russian disinformation is most deeply pervasive in the Eurasia region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5C4DD7187B0048398B2E6DC1D67BB5CB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>develop strategies to better communicate with predominately Russian-speaking regions; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7247FB4E49524E32BBD3B044FAB34AB7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>build on efforts to increase capacity and programming to counter disinformation in real time;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H560BAA18DBE14E85B9337F91B3DEA1CE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>expand Russian language investigative journalism;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B82B25F007D4233A4670F5F88D96AF7"><enum>(5)</enum><text>improve the technical capacity of the Ukraine bureau; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H411B466C07894E23862EFFE98EB625AA"><enum>(6)</enum><text>continue efforts to increase digital news services.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6B0AB855EF03491F8B6ECAE3260353DA"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the United States Agency for Global Media shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives a report that includes—</text><paragraph id="HC8B71E9E6915472D9EADF0CA82EC5C90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>recommendations of locations to open new bureaus to help reach new audiences in the broader Eurasia region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H15B8C18569A94A81B9645AFFED93F978"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of current staffing and anticipated staffing needs in order to effectively reach audiences in the broader Eurasia region; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5F7C56254914E9A955D82DFA7CCFCAC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an assessment of the impact of the Government of the Russian Federation closing down Radio Free Europe/Radio Liberty within the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H09648727C685442789315191E4FB0D78"><enum>203.</enum><header>Multilateral efforts to bolster Ukraine’s cyber defense capabilities</header><subsection id="H62F6DB25C0474B1188AA1184DB800322"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>It is the policy of the United States—</text><paragraph id="H580BAC489625419883C1679C0012646F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to support multilateral, intergovernmental, and nongovernmental efforts to improve Ukraine’s cybersecurity capacity, including addressing legislative and regulatory gaps in Ukraine’s cybersecurity policies, improving cybersecurity sector governance, and expanding collaboration among relevant stakeholders in both the public and private sectors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H46EAF34200C645EB8701520EFD451BFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to work with the Government of Ukraine to strengthen cybersecurity technical capacity within critical infrastructure sectors and improve the overall cybersecurity workforce by strengthening cybersecurity-related academic and training programs and exchanges; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8EDDDC1D6DF4737A0C91620B6FD9414"><enum>(3)</enum><text>to work closely with the NATO Cooperative Cyber Defence Centre of Excellence, the European Union Agency for Cybersecurity, and the National Cyber Security Centre of the United Kingdom to bolster Ukraine’s cyber defense capabilities; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59688D096B2E402E96A81ACC1AF5F4F3"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to strengthen the ability of the Government of Ukraine to detect, investigate, disrupt, and deter cyberattacks and to develop cybersecurity incident response teams.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H490642E352DF4F4BBD35E4F1726565C7"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on efforts to implement the policy described in subsection (a). </text></subsection><subsection id="H9A2AF274428F4EF7A6C7EB3A9C0D83FE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Evaluation of imposition of sanctions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the event the Government of the Russian Federation or any of its proxies engages in a cyberattack or cyber incident that materially disrupts or degrades any critical infrastructure in Ukraine, the President shall evaluate whether imposing any of the sanctions described in section 310 is in the national security interests of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="H1D643CF6E42A4BB19E3B4AA475123B72"><enum>204.</enum><header>Report on role of intelligence and security services of the Russian Federation in efforts to undermine the independence and integrity of Ukraine</header><subsection id="HDE892D81C1214D5D8CB0F14CC415DE91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Director of National Intelligence, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees, the Select Committee on Intelligence of the Senate, and the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence of the House of Representatives, a report on the role of the intelligence and security services of the Russian Federation in efforts to undermine and interfere with the independence of Ukraine.</text></subsection><subsection id="H461529D46CCB4A14BD8CC9C0139C41C9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H410D0CF8A9154187876C566B99116A0A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of the priorities and objectives of the intelligence and security services of the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE372FD8DBD5244B5B233AB9EC9D4B67B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a detailed description of the steps taken by any intelligence or security services of the Russian Federation to undermine the stability of Ukraine or the Government of Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB2B64A1BB0374BA5B7246D2574721EB6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a complete list of the branches of the intelligence or security services of the Russian Federation that have engaged in any influence efforts or campaigns to undermine the stability of Ukraine or the Government of Ukraine;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B866004E6924E1FAD1F6EBA19690ACF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>an assessment of—</text><subparagraph id="H8F4624816A3A4C3599CA2F88A601F9E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the tactics and techniques used by any intelligence and security services of the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0A82A6D9880447A59712D37CC57A9F2A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the success of those tactics and techniques; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC341938B5DC245F1877657AE3C1D6BEC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>any plans by the United States to provide additional support to the Government of Ukraine to prevent internal destabilization efforts, including through intelligence sharing and support for reforms and anti-corruption efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8A4A15F45E7846878BCF76BE08073F13"><enum>205.</enum><header>Strategy for forum on European security</header><subsection id="HBD4C522703434D4D8A78220554EC8FA2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H70216292BBE34C75971256048B844844"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States should work closely with NATO allies, particularly those that share a border with the Russian Federation, on any matters related to European security; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2451B201409444AA95F4C810824EDCBD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Mission to the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe (commonly referred to as the <quote>OSCE</quote>) should—</text><subparagraph id="H4070D22398BA4016BF09C84154D7725D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>support an inclusive European security dialogue that calls on OSCE participating states to comply with principles set forth in the Helsinki Final Act, the Charter of Paris for a New Europe, and the Charter of the United Nations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8E4EECA47610404592DCE57B8C095231"><enum>(B)</enum><text>continue to publicly call for the Government of the Russian Federation to adhere to its commitments as an OSCE participating state.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCA0DD09A7960481BAE19D2F88329D4DA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategy on European security</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a strategy for continued engagement with the Government of the Russian Federation following January 2022 security dialogues, including the Strategic Stability Dialogue in Geneva, the NATO-Russia Council Meeting in Brussels, and the Organization for Security and Co-operation in Europe Permanent Council Meeting in Vienna, which shall include—</text><paragraph id="H34D7D5D3228D4EA887A9951C2BED41BD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an assessment of whether the Government of the Russian Federation has sufficiently de-escalated regional tensions, including through a significant withdrawal of troops from the border of Ukraine, to merit further discussion;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E302C70B934E8BB1B4EFE09A091C52"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an assessment of the objectives of the Government of the Russian Federation related to European security;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H282519FBCE204B46BF30EA3467BB40B8"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a plan to reduce tensions between the Russian Federation and Eastern European allies, taking into account the perspectives of a wide cross section of European allies of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H343CF8F20FA74ABB89A64030892D7822"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a plan for including Eastern European NATO allies, specifically those that share a border with the Russian Federation, in any conversations on European security.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H28E949A3A3434C0A904D2DB483E14A0F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The strategy required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex if necessary.</text></subsection></section><section id="HCE8FE03761244531A172418D8A2182C9"><enum>206.</enum><header>Deepening security and economic ties with Baltic allies</header><subsection id="HA17EA4622A664D948C07C840A8002B94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H0EE34F5F91FF489FA988607D4B9FEDBD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supporting and bolstering the security of the Baltic states of Estonia, Latvia, and Lithuania is in the national security interests of the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9D0609416AA4AA5BECFCE60EEF1BC42"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Baltic states are critical in countering aggression by the Government of the Russian Federation and maintaining the collective security of the NATO alliance;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA5F2494DABB84518A61E16FF3324878D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should continue to support and foster a security partnership with the Baltic states that aims to meet their security needs and provides additional capabilities and tools to help defend against aggression by the Government of the Russian Federation in the region;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H57BCBA21EC494CB7AA102C737EA091B9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States should encourage the initiative undertaken by the Baltic states to advance the Three Seas Initiative to strengthen transport, energy, and digital infrastructures among eastern Europe countries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF036C784221744A0A49AE510ABDAF9AA"><enum>(5)</enum><text>there are mutually beneficial opportunities for increased investment and economic expansion between the United States and the Baltic states; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D16108869F440F89F6551F76834C031"><enum>(6)</enum><text>improved economic ties between the United States and the Baltic states will lead to a strengthened strategic partnership.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A4F3B1860DF4CDDAB3BF525D88A7F6E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Baltic security and economic enhancement initiative</header><paragraph id="H15B25AB9E59745A2829C467AC3CDF894"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of State shall establish an initiative to deepen and foster security and economic ties with the Baltic states.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C69874B5EA948B28FE24C1893AB07A6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Purpose and objectives</header><text>The initiative established under paragraph (1) shall have the following goals and objectives:</text><subparagraph id="H27689F3014C3482D9ACC3FFA046EE0F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Ensuring the efficient and effective delivery of security assistance to the Baltic states, prioritizing assistance that will bolster defenses against hybrid warfare and improve interoperability with NATO forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H894C423EA8C64A15A8004B6AF56BBE24"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Bolstering United States support for the Baltic region’s physical and energy security needs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5BD7736BAB7A4A3BBBF60D51F628064A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Mitigating the impact of economic coercion by the Russian Federation and the People's Republic of China on Baltic states and identifying new opportunities for foreign direct investment and United States business ties.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC62C7F605E374193B79A5F48DB70A347"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Improving high-level engagement between the United States and the Baltic states, with a focus on improving high-level security and economic cooperation.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF63D2604D2C64DCE9CAF97EFE823268B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>The initiative established under paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H43CAC6042AA64FEC88CEDCA9E5C37979"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a comprehensive security assistance strategy to strengthen the defensive capabilities of the Baltic states, in coordination with other security assistance authorities, that takes into account the unique challenges of the proximity of the Baltic states to the Russian Federation and the threat of aggression against the Baltic states from the Government of the Russian Federation;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA58A0C127F1D45FFA5787E5A4D7D6AC7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage the United States International Development Finance Corporation to identify new opportunities for investment in the Baltic states;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF16626B999143EF9A7C11E90CB55E3F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>send high-level representatives of the Department of State to—</text><clause id="H8B6DFC43328745B78460A16C48FD5537"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Baltic states not less frequently than twice a year; and </text></clause><clause id="H75FB61A3E96B4217AFF264FA75E1B541"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>major regional fora on physical and energy security, including the Three Seas Initiative Summit and Business Forum and the Baltic Sea Security Conference;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE951D485889F4FE8B518E5EB4A601F22"><enum>(D)</enum><text>convene an annual trade forum, in coordination with the governments of Baltic states, to foster investment opportunities in the Baltic region for United States businesses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5BC3BBFA34A4E32BC217A3365C55598"><enum>(E)</enum><text>foster dialogue between experts from the United States and from the Baltic states on hybrid warfare, cyber defenses, economic expansion, and foreign direct investment. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6807C0017DAB430C9DBCBCC98BC5BCCB"><enum>207.</enum><header>Public disclosure of assets of Vladimir Putin and his inner circle</header><subsection id="H6DD01C4816494AE5836358613940FFCA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of the Treasury, in coordination with the Director of National Intelligence and the Secretary of State, shall submit to the committees specified in subsection (d) a detailed report on the personal net worth and assets of the President of the Russian Federation, Vladimir Putin, and his inner circle.</text></subsection><subsection id="H79FED5D2DD5D40C5A3DAD05B3DD8410F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H455113820992493CA102077BD353993F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an identification of significant senior foreign political figures and oligarchs in the Russian Federation, as determined by their closeness to Vladimir Putin;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21F3E69A141740FD953526579A60FEA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the estimated net worth and known sources of income of the individuals identified under paragraph (1), Vladimir Putin, and the family members of such individuals and Vladimir Putin (including spouses, children, parents, and siblings), including assets, investments, bank accounts, business interests, held in and outside of the Russian Federation, and relevant beneficial ownership information;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9729EBD7CFD4CDDBE70CEA2D0F869E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an estimate of the total annual income and personal expenditures of Vladimir Putin and his family members for calendar years 2017 through 2021; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51D9D139B1BF497A8B56E4533ECCE1C1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>all known details about the financial practices and transparency, or lack thereof, of Vladimir Putin and the individuals identified under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77284906E3964841A5FAA157A578D561"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Form</header><paragraph id="H1C6EE8970F28454BA38BF2E9DF02DBCD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required by subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE8727B03F1846459F5EAF7CBE8D6B10"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The unclassified portion of the report required by subsection (a) shall be made available on a publicly accessible internet website.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AF651DE38174E3BB1341D96A0592BC2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Committees specified</header><text>The committees specified in this subsection are—</text><paragraph id="HEFBFACDAAC144210A6290881A0FDA7DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the appropriate congressional committees; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDECB644E35AD435D91C944BDA07A4A68"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA35EFCE0A1F44D89B1CD6616F378D104"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF895565BAC8B4D27B76DDBB27BF8A3EC"><enum>208.</enum><header>Briefing to fulfill United States-Ukraine strategic dialogue objectives</header><subsection id="HADFFD574A3D34510B0FFE002E7A95C2D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall provide to the appropriate congressional committees a briefing on efforts to deepen ties with Ukraine and fully implement the objectives outlined in the United States-Ukraine Charter on Strategic Partnership, signed by Secretary of State Antony Blinken and Ukrainian Foreign Minister Dmytro Kuleba on November 10, 2021. </text></subsection><subsection id="H86D377FDB89844D9ABB91897B9EA1EA9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The briefing required by subsection (a) shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="HD25D47CFFE4948889988932C917A11E9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A plan to bolster support for Ukraine’s sovereignty, independence, territorial integrity, and inviolability of borders, including plans for high-level representation and robust participation in Ukraine’s Crimea Platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCFEB2C907114080ADD79B0263C1735D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A plan to highlight human rights abuses by the Government of the Russian Federation in Ukrainian territory, which shall include mechanisms to draw attention to persecuted minorities and political prisoners in Crimea and the Donbas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H589F9CE84457442DB80BEBC517674A72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>An assessment of humanitarian assistance needs for those affected or displaced by the war in Donbas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE73CF346033D4F209AB90322EEDA3910"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A plan to support democracy and the rule of law in Ukraine, which shall include efforts to build on progress made on the establishment of anti-corruption institutions, land reform, local governance, and digitalization.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></title><title id="HD66487232AD54C608C0C08ACE045D208" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Deterrence measures against further military escalation and aggression by the Russian Federation with respect to Ukraine</header><section id="HA4FD650E0D1E4E328F56AB15AC4DB7F1" commented="no"><enum>301.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this title:</text><paragraph id="HD690F745E2E04A8A8BFA577ED66E9BEC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Admission; admitted; alien</header><text>The terms <term>admission</term>, <term>admitted</term>, and <term>alien</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5546912B16FB427CAE23ABA176BC5208" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text>The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HEE6B264DC66D4A50B679DE22B3C55F59" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C92EA168AA94991A347B1E88CC4F3B9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs and the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B9EA250FAFB401F85B1C1C8CF3B9831"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Financial institution</header><text>The term <term>financial institution</term> means a financial institution specified in subparagraph (A), (B), (C), (D), (E), (F), (G), (H), (I), (J), (M), or (Y) of section 5312(a)(2) of title 31, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74E9991EF286446CA879EF8D8FC2E224"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Foreign financial institution</header><text>The term <term>foreign financial institution</term> has the meaning given that term in regulations prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98DA977FE96F440D97FB4FEDD16804A1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Foreign person</header><text>The term <term>foreign person</term> means an individual or entity that is not a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25F3E38F3B504B81B5BC29713E00C875"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Knowingly</header><text>The term <term>knowingly</term> with respect to conduct, a circumstance, or a result, means that a person had actual knowledge, or should have known, of the conduct, the circumstance, or the result.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A7BF26D2537440F86019A838D26CD73"><enum>(7)</enum><header>United states person</header><text>The term <term>United States person</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="HB52504B87C5F437A9EB86E9B57823E64"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence to the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C9E08C5A1954FC7B63FBAAF33715023"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity organized under the laws of the United States or any jurisdiction within the United States, including a foreign branch of such an entity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H062032924F504A2EB5A0A7CFD270DC74"><enum>302.</enum><header>Determination with respect to operations of the Russian Federation in Ukraine</header><subsection id="H4C59148F78AF4EB7AB0FEFBF2C9A239A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall determine, at such times as are required under subsection (b), whether—</text><paragraph id="H948C2E7831674C26A38E740D41709BB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Government of the Russian Federation, including through any of its proxies, is engaged in or knowingly supporting a significant escalation in hostilities or hostile action in or against Ukraine, compared to the level of hostilities or hostile action in or against Ukraine prior to December 1, 2021; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5697739BE44A8BB12F6540C3AFD438"><enum>(2)</enum><text>if so, whether such escalation has the aim or effect of undermining, overthrowing, or dismantling the Government of Ukraine, occupying the territory of Ukraine, or interfering with the sovereignty or territorial integrity of Ukraine.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB024F93518F74CB6B9170AAB686C649F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing of determinations</header><text>The President shall make the determination described in subsection (a)—</text><paragraph id="H82CC9E3E87BE44C79EA3D18A1538A780"><enum>(1)</enum><text>not later than 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85E4525933DE4BC6A4E8CCE81B3B60C9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>after the first determination under paragraph (1), every 90 days (or more frequently as warranted) during the one-year period beginning on such date of enactment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB87D6D419E34F51A8B73CEA7A37EFC1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>after the end of that one-year period, every 120 days.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6C5B414690E842B7A5E172E6279474D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report required</header><text>Upon making a determination under this section, the President shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress, the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate, and the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives, a report on the determination. </text></subsection></section><section id="HE8E2E6EE10CA4E4DBC677A2ED6479958"><enum>303.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to officials of the Government of the Russian Federation relating to operations in Ukraine</header><subsection id="H52F2098142094482900101635B537FCB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon making an affirmative determination under section 302 and not later than 60 days following such a determination, the President shall impose the sanctions described in section 310 with respect to each of the officials specified in subsection (b).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A5F6119F6BF41F1B17FDC9581B65E63"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Officials specified</header><text>The officials specified in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="HDBC0A892D09549BEBE2EEB294F638FFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The President of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H215D75B8C6C14D098311F8943028159D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Prime Minister of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H839AAD4EFA3F46EF9559C94C2D11439F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Foreign Minister of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17CE28DA8F53443A8A7E76AE3B5522D1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Minister of Defense of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB987C1FD8A354D19A95779CE267AAB1C"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Chief of the General Staff of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0AC6E4348744718B62147B441AA23C6"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Commander-in-Chief of the Land Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BF34DA19943408C81E98E489A959908"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The Commander-in-Chief of the Aerospace Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4C0B456D59DE4877ABF280C37E76C2E1"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The Commander of the Airborne Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB11AAB45B3B74E228AD069818413650A"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Commander-in-Chief of the Navy of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFF6DED931C54ECC8B6248AAA7AD56E7"><enum>(10)</enum><text>The Commander of the Strategic Rocket Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFF7A36FAF5046F0B17C0C84D8739787"><enum>(11)</enum><text>The Commander of the Special Operations Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4383F223BF4944F5841902ED4EB542F3"><enum>(12)</enum><text>The Commander of Logistical Support of the Armed Forces of the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00242496958A462BB5258C96D11B7D64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional officials</header><paragraph id="H02191EFC7838447691C0C8205B773AEB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302 and every 90 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a list of foreign persons that the President determines—</text><subparagraph id="H0656B6EA312647C2812A00559C0AEBDC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are—</text><clause id="HE7EF464647A942D292401752D5B56DE2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>senior officials of any branch of the armed forces of the Russian Federation leading any of the operations described in section 302; or</text></clause><clause id="H6ADDD3118C1B4F969641E3F963C2449D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>senior officials of the Government of the Russian Federation, including any intelligence agencies or security services of the Russian Federation, with significant roles in planning or implementing such operations; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3F4685B67E74727948D8D699C5CE21F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to which sanctions should be imposed in the interest of the national security of the United States. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4B4849CC5294570BE67832260321BFB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Upon the submission of each list required by paragraph (1), the President shall impose the sanctions described in section 310 with respect to each foreign person on the list.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCFF0884F5311451CBC66C4D41F8CA118"><enum>304.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Russian financial institutions</header><subsection id="HD8A6CA6C59B24476B625BB79F89E19D0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="H73ADE41D33564D54A6DE655DA0416539"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Upon making an affirmative determination under section 302 and not later than 30 days following such a determination, the President shall impose the sanctions described in section 310(a)(1) with respect to 3 or more of the following financial institutions:</text><subparagraph id="H1C014B2D01BF4F6A82703A7B1A20FDC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Sberbank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC684B068A2840978A1E09A0F312F2E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>VTB.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4DC1A565E617470E86E280A836CE0E5A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Gazprombank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H44A2C70611FA4ECB9AF6E6422E0FFD9C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>VEB.RF.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H111D2B6629ED4A2DB7AB417103FEE6CA"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The Russian Direct Investment Fund. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H431178004DD44DD1A86BDF60DCE5B691"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Credit Bank of Moscow. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H634701FBF35E43458A468A8AB3721407"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Alfa Bank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A47841E221A4AFDA143DFE293468A38"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Rosselkhozbank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB1BE79754E9E4851ACCE73A3146721B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>FC Bank Otkritie.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2F6B65930BE42B6A2210B13C62C2DD9"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Promsvyazbank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H822B6FE1FBEC44D79EB9908BCF040CBF"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Sovcombank.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8565390C69B84086BEE4524EB208F224"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Transkapitalbank.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H897861831DA741B9BC256862F780EB85"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Subsidiaries and successor entities</header><text>The President may impose the sanctions described in section 310(a)(1) with respect to any subsidiary of, or successor entity to, a financial institution specified in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7C95A493CD4E4785902BC605CD24494B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional Russian financial institutions</header><paragraph id="H23FA324B139E48F6A336D4B067B9E785"><enum>(1)</enum><header>List required</header><text>Not later than 30 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302, and every 90 days thereafter, the President shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a list of foreign persons that the President determines—</text><subparagraph id="H1F3406E9ED174381A1E6C516D856C39D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>are significant financial institutions owned or operated by the Government of the Russian Federation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BD35AD8DDC8465FB8E955558A8BBC61"><enum>(B)</enum><text>should be sanctioned in the interest of United States national security.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02A2A665A1774A5AA8E38132006A4764"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><text>Upon the submission of each list required by paragraph (1), the President shall impose the sanctions described in section 310(a)(1) with respect to each foreign person identified on the list.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4F0968878A8F4FD6A490CB033EB7BC76"><enum>305.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to provision of specialized financial messaging services to sanctioned Russian financial institutions</header><subsection id="HC3D5274481EC4806B567447E579FDF3E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>List of providers of specialized financial messaging services to russian financial institutions</header><text>Not later than 60 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302, and not later than 30 days after the submission of any list of Russian financial institutions under section 304(b)(1), the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a list of all known persons that provide specialized financial messaging services to, or that enable or facilitate access to such services for, any financial institution specified in subsection (a) of section 304 or on the list required by subsection (b) of that section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H944AFCE623D74BFBAC3158D8DAD5D746"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report on efforts To terminate the provision of specialized financial messaging services for sanctioned russian financial institutions</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the imposition of any sanctions under section 304, and every 30 days thereafter as necessary, the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of the Treasury, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report that—</text><paragraph id="H3D4401D9A59842959085B1E93387E74C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>describes the status of efforts to ensure that the termination of the provision of specialized financial messaging services to, and the enabling and facilitation of access to such services for, any financial institution with respect to which sanctions are imposed under section 304; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A65B06E4C234C71AEE3AFE01F2FC239"><enum>(2)</enum><text>identifies any other provider of specialized financial messaging services that continues to provide messaging services to, or enables or facilitates access to such services for, any such financial institution.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD182D1239A8E4297B8DFC39DD0AE5010"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization for the imposition of sanctions</header><text>If, on or after the date that is 90 days after the imposition of any sanctions under section 304, a provider of financial specialized financial messaging services continues to knowingly provide specialized financial messaging services to, or knowingly enable or facilitate direct or indirect access to such messaging services for, any financial institution with respect to which sanctions are imposed under section 304, the President may impose sanctions pursuant to that section or the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) with respect to that provider.</text></subsection><subsection id="H37216250F3A9407ABDD082389B1E2010"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Enabling or facilitation of access to specialized financial messaging services through intermediary financial institutions</header><text>For purposes of this section, enabling or facilitating direct or indirect access to specialized financial messaging services includes doing so by serving as an intermediary financial institution with access to such messaging services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H387CDB06DD0341298630AF0C786F3680"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Form of lists and reports</header><text>Each list required by subsection (a) and each report required by subsection (b) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex. </text></subsection></section><section id="HE203838FCF534E32BE033D9752A6B1D2"><enum>306.</enum><header>Prohibition on and imposition of sanctions with respect to transactions involving Russian sovereign debt</header><subsection id="HE79407DC4EC04394B6A711D570498480"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition on transactions</header><text>Upon making an affirmative determination under section 302 and not later than 30 days following such a determination, the President shall prohibit all transactions by United States persons involving the sovereign debt of the Government of the Russian Federation issued on or after the date of the enactment of this Act, including governmental bonds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1E7CB8086350492D9DF47AC08C07B485"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to state-Owned enterprises</header><paragraph id="H46F26DFD56AB43C280A9FAE2648FE054"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 60 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302, the President shall identify and impose the sanctions described in section 310 with respect to foreign persons that the President determines engage in transactions involving the debt—</text><subparagraph id="HF66DC60FFE8E45DE872C54A5C989415F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>of not less than 10 entities owned or controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0106530B6F14936A9CE92E0AC35F86D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that is not subject to any other sanctions imposed by the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H931C1074D2A6471AA4B3DE1A8CDA4947"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Sanctions imposed under paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to debt of an entity described in subparagraph (A) of that paragraph that is issued after the date that is 90 days after the President makes an affirmative determination under section 302.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1FAB8A88BE284DDB98E8A9D982E4EF37"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List; imposition of sanctions</header><text>Not later than 30 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302, and every 90 days thereafter, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H4E877BA8AA1B4EEBAF47652B9CA9AD1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a list of foreign persons that the President determines are engaged in transactions described in subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7E6FF37B13F4B1498225C97104AC03F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in section 310 with respect to each such person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H16DAEC4A27F1415AB4A6474661EA73BF"><enum>307.</enum><header>Department of State review of sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2</header><subsection id="H4B72354FBD4D4A908B4F4055B9CD31C6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H84697ADF3DF741F68DC3073FD3674313"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Nord Stream 2 pipeline is a tool of malign influence of the Russian Federation and if it becomes operational, it will embolden the Russian Federation to further pressure and destabilize Ukraine; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEACB122C52B24466A9D7DA7DA29BBA6B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States should consider all available and appropriate measures to prevent the Nord Stream 2 pipeline from becoming operational, including through sanctions with respect to entities and individuals responsible for planning, constructing, or operating the pipeline, and through diplomatic efforts.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06363B4D75DE4F4FB62A21A132BF5962"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Department of State review of sanctions on Nord Stream 2</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State shall review whether the May 19, 2021, waiver regarding sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2 AG and the chief executive officer of Nord Stream 2 AG remains in the best interest of United States national security, especially in light of the Russian Federation’s military build-up along the border of Ukraine. </text></subsection></section><section id="HDB0BED18F5F34143B0DA7292F0FBCF9F"><enum>308.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Nord Stream 2</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Upon making an affirmative determination under section 302 and not later than 30 days following such a determination, the President shall impose the sanctions described in section 310 with respect to a foreign person that is—</text><paragraph id="HED5631E7E71D4FAE85434F4CF78268E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any entity established for or responsible for the planning, construction, or operation of the Nord Stream 2 pipeline or a successor entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H386B73EC903B40AD9F4CE192AC5BDF90"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any corporate officer of an entity described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H334039392536485A93D342452FB1E9CA"><enum>309.</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions with respect to Russian extractive industries</header><subsection id="H08DFB70ABE6A4F63A66DAAF10EF3A054"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Not later than 60 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302, the President shall identify foreign persons in any of the sectors or industries described in subsection (b) that the President determines should be sanctioned in the interest of United States national security.</text></subsection><subsection id="H83A0D9B45FE547B2849DA8418603FB88"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sectors and industries described</header><text>The sectors and industries described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph id="H23B415677CA048DCB304F7178B126006"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Oil and gas extraction and production.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H035870C3B0DC42F98252B033A68E605B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Coal extraction, mining, and production.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B415D22A41A4BDF9504A227EC37480B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Minerals extraction and processing. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA5FC650FAA64C06A5C114BC26C75694"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any other sector or industry with respect to which the President determines the imposition of sanctions is in the United States national security interest.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF45FDC0ECD674010A6F6F3EA0D9CC32C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>List; imposition of sanctions</header><text>Not later than 90 days after making an affirmative determination under section 302, the President shall—</text><paragraph id="H342D50292B9944969B05F5AE48087B6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a list of the persons identified under subsection (a); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6391C307636A475680CDD5D679F08331"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose the sanctions described in section 310 with respect to each such person.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H14521787A5AF4281BF760B961002CC99"><enum>310.</enum><header>Sanctions described</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The sanctions to be imposed with respect to a foreign person under this title are the following:</text><paragraph id="H98E54D9C0F794061BE2CA5ACB069938C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Property blocking</header><text>The President shall exercise all of the powers granted by the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1701">50 U.S.C. 1701 et seq.</external-xref>) to the extent necessary to block and prohibit all transactions in all property and interests in property of the foreign person if such property and interests in property are in the United States, come within the United States, or are or come within the possession or control of a United States person.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCF90DCD8FA614BFEA6CBE8511372C0E9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Aliens inadmissible for visas, admission, or parole</header><subparagraph id="H2D7DACFF66F141D89FE581C7A15209A6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Visas, admission, or parole</header><text>In the case of an alien, the alien is—</text><clause id="H1BBA8781426F40789E588DD90AFF6346"><enum>(i)</enum><text>inadmissible to the United States;</text></clause><clause id="HBA75CD81825F4067861FCC44880A4B20"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ineligible to receive a visa or other documentation to enter the United States; and</text></clause><clause id="HE3C0D660D83045EB9E58B227C68C0425"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>otherwise ineligible to be admitted or paroled into the United States or to receive any other benefit under the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0982CAA2CEA34DAC998635FA210A8C6A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Current visas revoked</header><clause id="H816B6A51D4DA4146B5354D9BCEAAB56C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The visa or other entry documentation of an alien described in subparagraph (A) shall be revoked, regardless of when such visa or other entry documentation is or was issued.</text></clause><clause id="HAC145CCCFC454DC5B897C514281EFBE5"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Immediate effect</header><text>A revocation under clause (i) shall—</text><subclause id="H3D9C945AB8B34D2585551A4AFDDBF79F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>take effect immediately; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H61119E6C178F4FC092CF39526C984F2B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>automatically cancel any other valid visa or entry documentation that is in the alien’s possession.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HD830D10BA22148F9B0C6D02DDC8AE22D"><enum>311.</enum><header>Implementation; regulations; penalties</header><subsection id="HBD3C8AFF9D6344E1B00312199426C53C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The President may exercise all authorities provided to the President under sections 203 and 205 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (50 U.S.C. 1702 and 1704) to carry out this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2E86001DA17D479BB291673A42C6A71F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The President shall issue such regulations, licenses, and orders as are necessary to carry out this title.</text></subsection><subsection id="H7333A7DD01C14EB0BBD81CF2D7BF62E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Penalties</header><text>A person that violates, attempts to violate, conspires to violate, or causes a violation of this Act or any regulation, license, or order issued to carry out this title shall be subject to the penalties set forth in subsections (b) and (c) of section 206 of the International Emergency Economic Powers Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1705">50 U.S.C. 1705</external-xref>) to the same extent as a person that commits an unlawful act described in subsection (a) of that section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H90F6BC06F0D24287874384FFB7D7AF20"><enum>312.</enum><header>Exceptions; waiver</header><subsection id="H3B76710103504F82903358806FF92C0E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><paragraph id="H3790127696074BBDA00C56EA6BB479E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exception for intelligence activities</header><text>This title shall not apply with respect to activities subject to the reporting requirements under title V of the National Security Act of 1947 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3091">50 U.S.C. 3091 et seq.</external-xref>) or any authorized intelligence activities of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2867D1B6D394D9FAEB73D209D822DE2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for compliance with international obligations and law enforcement activities</header><text>Sanctions under this title shall not apply with respect to an alien if admitting or paroling the alien into the United States is necessary—</text><subparagraph id="H069BB0F5816E407C83B284582E4ED2B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to permit the United States to comply with the Agreement regarding the Headquarters of the United Nations, signed at Lake Success on June 26, 1947, and entered into force November 21, 1947, between the United Nations and the United States, or other applicable international obligations of the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7653FD86A94A423085643003A179D881"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to carry out or assist law enforcement activity in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D7319AAC0364B1AA1A4B32D8D568F37"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National security waiver</header><text>The President may waive the imposition of sanctions under this title with respect to a person if the President—</text><paragraph id="HA17934F07FAC4ECAA714107086ABC425"><enum>(1)</enum><text>determines that such a waiver is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC172EC1C3C184913B5943705CED17551"><enum>(2)</enum><text>submits to the appropriate committees of Congress a notification of the waiver and the reasons for the waiver.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6081EA1C7F464A119FC4B6B10C4B40F8"><enum>313.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The President may terminate the sanctions imposed under this title after determining and certifying to the appropriate committees of Congress that the Government of the Russian Federation has—</text><paragraph id="H8E1EEB7A1C714D2E8160AE106283DF83"><enum>(1)</enum><text>verifiably withdrawn all of its forces from Ukrainian territory that was not occupied or subject to control by forces or proxies of the Government of the Russian Federation prior to December 1, 2021;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA2CB3FDCEE74603A39568FB64F1B8AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>ceased supporting proxies in Ukrainian territory described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H77BA3C02A56E4957BE521F2877C3F6CE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>entered into an agreed settlement with a legitimate democratic government of Ukraine. </text></paragraph></section></title><title id="H59AE3041BFB04E95ACD9DD06A53424FF" style="OLC"><enum>IV</enum><header>General provisions</header><section id="H614B849B6CD44D14804327F4B669D899"><enum>401.</enum><header>Sunset</header><subsection id="HCE0B05EC34934BE69612669F434F7BB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Titles I and II</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of titles I and II shall terminate on the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection><subsection id="H31ADF4BF6C4748EF949CD2A80A4B8EB3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Title III</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The provisions of title III shall terminate on the date that is 3 years after the date of the enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="HA6A417CDCD174598BE72FBF936A4DA73"><enum>402.</enum><header>Exception relating to importation of goods</header><subsection id="H1B2055C863494D848B2441908AC322CF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions under this Act shall not include the authority or a requirement to impose sanctions on the importation of goods.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC396F4BEA74F4962A4E248BB4FE7309B" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Good defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>good</term> means any article, natural or manmade substance, material, supply, or manufactured product, including inspection and test equipment, and excluding technical data. </text></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

