<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5CD6FC4A5C3B4EC89E2953C46569CEFF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9554 IH: To prohibit the use of Federal funds to negotiate or contribute to international agreements that provide for “loss and damage” funds as a result of climate change.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9554</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000825">Mrs. Boebert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001177">Mr. McClintock</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000603">Mr. Rouzer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001053">Mrs. Hartzler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001199">Mr. Mast</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000522">Mr. Smith of New Jersey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000814">Mr. Weber of Texas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001195">Mr. Mooney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the use of Federal funds to negotiate or contribute to international agreements that provide for <quote>loss and damage</quote> funds as a result of climate change.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA890A303BC7F4ABBAFD915FF73783DBF" style="OLC"><section id="HD96F2A5119E344A2BCCFC396BEFABABE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H11C3628DC48B4A34B7F42B2FEBD78A3F"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On November 26th, 2022, the Biden Administration agreed to establish a <quote>climate justice</quote> fund which compels United States taxpayers and other wealthy nations to pay developing countries for <quote>loss and damage</quote> caused by natural disasters.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A26E315DEB648F5AE19CF997FEA9778"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The world’s top polluter, China, generated more CO<subscript>2</subscript> in 2019 than the United States and the next four largest countries combined, and many individual corporations in China have more sway over warming temperatures than most developed countries as a whole. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB4C743C505B44CD7A8015172C60EC4AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Despite being the world’s second-largest economy, China is still categorized as a <quote>developing</quote> country by the United Nations and enjoys the same differential treatment afforded to nations like Guinea-Bissau and Yemen.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC76527EF495C4FA292636C58E1C4CDCB"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Other countries the United Nations has identified as <quote>developing</quote>, and are therefore still eligible for the $1,000,000,000 in United States taxpayer dollars committed by President Biden to the <quote>Loss and Damage</quote> fund include the Islamic Republic of Afghanistan, the Russian Federation, the Kingdom of Saudi Arabia, the Islamic Republic of Iran, the Islamic Republic of Pakistan, the United Arab Emirates, the Republic of Cuba, and the Bolivarian Republic of Venezuela.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E9B588999EC408E98EF16A68883FE41"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to a study by Accenture, 93 percent of all large companies with net zero emission commitments have failed to back those pledges, and are larger polluters than most developed nations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H24AC84002E184D3F8125426B0D55E189"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In December 2009, at the United Nations Climate Change Conference, Todd Stern, President Obama’s special envoy for climate change, outright rejected arguments by diplomats from developing nations that the United States owes them hundreds of billions of dollars in reparations for decades of American emissions, stating, <quote>I actually completely reject the notion of a debt or reparations or anything of the like</quote>, he said.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H79BC9992217A4E9995AA6486A468E07B"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">President Biden’s own climate envoy, John Kerry, was quoted at the COP27 summit on November 12th, 2022, stating, <quote>It's a well-known fact that the United States and many other countries will not establish . . . some sort of legal structure that is tied to compensation or liability</quote>, yet, a week later, the Biden Administration had caved to activist demands, and Kerry released a statement saying he <quote>welcomes</quote> the fund’s creation.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HFBFB7BF4BB32419BA998597EF8FB50AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on funds to negotiate or contribute to international agreements that provide for <quote>loss and damage</quote> funds as a result of climate change</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">None of the funds available to any Federal department or agency may be used to negotiate or contribute to international agreements that provide for <quote>loss and damage</quote> funds as a result of climate change. </text></section></legis-body></bill> 

