<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H97A4E0C7C9474F2C8E492819BB26807A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7427 IH: To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require CMI testing of incentive payments for behavioral health providers and certain other providers for adoption and use of certified electronic health record technology, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7427</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220406">April 6, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001190">Mr. Mullin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000629">Ms. Davids of Kansas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000298">Mr. Estes</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XI of the Social Security Act to require CMI testing of incentive payments for behavioral health providers and certain other providers for adoption and use of certified electronic health record technology, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9530AF977E1B48EE99E7C6DECE68BAB6" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HC4D362EBEB224BF9904C08E101F4D2D4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Requiring CMI testing of incentive payments for behavioral health providers and certain other providers for adoption and use of certified electronic health record technology</header> 
<subsection id="H564C01BB51004119B346AD0C6D02F960"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1115A(b)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H2B1A7B8C78754FD0A69BEC93A2C6B855"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>, except that the models selected under this subparagraph shall include the models described in subparagraph (B)(xxv) (with policy decisions regarding the scale of funding, number of behavioral health provider participants, and the length of the demonstration program to be determined by the Secretary)</quote> after <quote>subparagraph (B)</quote>; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC3D3520DEAB34077B24B0883EBFA270D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)(xxv), by striking <quote>to improve quality and coordination</quote> and inserting <quote>and implementing interoperability projects provisions to improve the integration, quality, and coordination pursuant to Section 4003 of the 21st Century Cures Act</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB24D2D9A30C84AF9944FB43AE7E00926"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following flush left matter: </text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE5EDC89A86E2420E94490D9A3D3E838B" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<quoted-block-continuation-text quoted-block-continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Behavioral health providers participating in models authorized under clause (xxv) shall not be eligible for health information technology incentive payments unless these providers demonstrate (through a process specified by the Secretary (such as the use of attestation)) that they have acquired health information systems that meet the 2015 Office of the National Coordinator certification standards and that such systems are fully compliant with regulations specified in the Interoperability and Patient Access Rule (42 C.F.R. 485; 45 C.F.R. 156).</quoted-block-continuation-text><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HB46AB64A6BCF484EB282FEDD25082A9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Behavioral IT standards development</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing models described in section 1115A(b)(2)(B)(xxv) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(b)(2)(B)(xxv)</external-xref>), the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall, acting through the Assistant Secretary for Mental Health and Substance Use and the Director of the Office of the National Coordinator for Health Information and in consultation with appropriate stakeholders, develop voluntary standards for behavioral health information technology that address issues such as privacy, minimum clinical data standards, and sharing relevant patient health data across the behavioral health care, primary health care, and specialty health care systems.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9045864EEA9547C8A495857C5F96B4E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1115A(f)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1315a">42 U.S.C. 1315a(f)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="HB8188DE6E716494B8398A050ADB64814"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HCFA479EC8A4E4B1890E0C9D48C4404AA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HC2AB1FE502394579BEA29FE55C92CB2F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H7ED3DE1589A34CD9B7C483BCE72B72C4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subparagraph id="H21F72B76ED344E04904A220B8BF926B1"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in addition to any amounts made available under subparagraph (B), $250,000,000 for the period of fiscal years 2023 through 2025 for purposes of carrying out the model described in subsection (b)(2)(B)(xxv). </text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

