<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H79F4B51C31084027BC13CF4B8F0B9992" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8474 IH: Second Chance at Public Service Loan Forgiveness Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8474</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="N000188">Mr. Norcross</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve the public service loan forgiveness program under section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965, to improve loan forgiveness eligibility provisions under such Act for teachers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H46882328D07E487AAFC25FDF3A87A90E" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFB3C92E70C2548A4958AAE14A905AB00" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Second Chance at Public Service Loan Forgiveness Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HB76255CF9B1F46758F279AEC8BD3A26F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text> 
<paragraph id="H77D2880C34B9420BA46FED105B858155"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The public service loan forgiveness program under section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) was created in 2007 to attract individuals to public service by forgiving an individual’s Federal loans under part D of title IV of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1071">20 U.S.C. 1071 et seq.</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087a">20 U.S.C. 1087a et seq.</external-xref>) after 10 years of employment in areas of national need.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF6B346367B6E438EA60DF6372C894421"><enum>(2)</enum><text>These public service careers, which include employment in military, emergency management, government, public safety, law enforcement, public health, education, child care, social work, services for individuals with disabilities, services for the elderly, public interest legal services, and library sciences, pay substantially less than similar careers in the private sector.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5403775D8A164B99B108553A0AEA7DD1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The public sector also repeatedly experiences workforce shortages, especially following the COVID–19 pandemic.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1D285F7D37A043588171E2A7514CB25B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>An undergraduate degree, certification, or advanced degree is a prerequisite to enter or advance in these public service careers. Yet, research suggests that the prospect of several decades of student loan payments often deters individuals from pursuing careers in public service.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF9C36C24A63145179C04E6BE70196B0F"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The public service loan forgiveness program has substantially failed. In 2018, 99 percent of the borrowers who applied for relief under the program were denied due to improper type of loans, employment, or repayment plan, or the number of payments that they had made.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A6FD29A2D754B70B2C7C375715F3185"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Advocates and enforcement agencies, including 38 State Attorneys General and the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection, have repeatedly found that all of the major Federal student loan servicers provided inaccurate information to borrowers who were interested in or relying upon the public service loan forgiveness program. They also found that servicers repeatedly steered borrowers away from public service loan forgiveness into higher monthly payments and into deferment and forbearances.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2BDB4FDF4FAF4C9484F9A3F7B30A505C"><enum>(7)</enum><text>This has caused millions of public servants irreparable economic harm, including preventing them from buying a home, opening a small business, starting a family, or retiring, because of their student debt.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06CC6A0A3C984403BA663A731CDD2A1A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Despite the recent actions of President Biden's administration to improve the public service loan forgiveness program, these actions are limited and will not fully atone for the repeated, pervasive, and systemic actions by Federal student loan servicers to prevent public servants from fully benefitting from this program.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H68F292A0AF284042A2A94FC5F428BA8E" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Making forgiveness attainable for public sector workers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455(m) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H708F2EF375664E458AA30E2B4A824EE8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21E6D15739BB4A798A846CAD55A0D167"> 
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE6DE7AAE93064EDD840DD6B59C2AF5C4"><enum>(1)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall cancel the balance of interest and principal due, in accordance with paragraph (2), on any eligible Federal Direct Loan not in default for a borrower who—</text> <subparagraph id="H0C328CF02B3A4FA4A23EE860547878D1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>obtained an eligible Federal Direct Loan on or after January 1, 1994;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HFF53D1F55A19453E8E6EB13CE34CBF5F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has been employed full-time in public service for a total period of 10 years or more after the date on which the first eligible Federal Direct Loan was obtained; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HEB61E44106324FCE8739E3E2B69D3341"><enum>(C)</enum><text>while employed full-time in public service during the period described in subparagraph (B), completes 120 monthly payments on the eligible loans of the borrower, pursuant to any one or a combination of the following: </text> 
<clause id="HEBB362678BA84CB7B1F8EAC6A7706241"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Payments under an income-based repayment plan under section 493C.</text></clause> <clause id="H2801077C33C941C5BF060EE500E1C7CA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Payments under a standard repayment plan under subsection (d)(1)(A), based on a 10-year repayment period.</text></clause> 
<clause id="HFB527A3F0A0D49D69B9CAE5C05898592"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Monthly payments under a repayment plan under subsection (d)(1) or (g) of not less than the monthly amount calculated under subsection (d)(1)(A), based on a 10-year repayment period.</text></clause> <clause id="HBB0DA94D7BED4F6C8BB282E8B43CB1E5"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Payments under an income contingent repayment plan under subsection (d)(1)(D). </text></clause> 
<clause id="H47159CC3AF334364848456C6C9FB0BF6" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Any monthly payment that would have otherwise been made by the borrower on 1 or more eligible loans during a period of forbearance, including—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H315101A6B8CC4DB6ADC7A77F6B69A375"><enum>(I)</enum><text>discretionary or mandatory administrative forbearance; </text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H8A03A717120E4B058FA0E32B59DC0DE9"><enum>(II)</enum><text>forbearance described in section 428(c)(3)(A)(i), including forbearance because— </text> <item commented="no" id="H3C83D2A9FF6746169786DAAA400BAB33"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the borrower is serving in a medical or dental internship or residency program described in section 428(c)(3)(A)(i)(I); </text></item> 
<item commented="no" id="H224899056CCF4A8F9107BA57B423C106"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the borrower is serving in a national service position for which the borrower receives a national service educational award under the National and Community Service Trust Act of 1993 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12501">42 U.S.C. 12501 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></item> <item commented="no" id="H818334EE72C2419E9439D79252E69227"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the borrower is eligible for interest payments to be made on such loan for service in the Armed Forces under section 2174 of title 10, United States Code, and, pursuant to that eligibility, the interest is being paid on such loan under subsection (o); </text></item></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H0E920EDEC0184C429904097D74763654"><enum>(III)</enum><text>forbearance provided because the borrower is serving in an educator residency program; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HCB06A6CE3677429CB7D08769F71A3812"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>forbearance provided to a borrower due to the borrower's qualifying National Guard service.</text></subclause></clause> 
<clause commented="no" id="H8510A727203049B2B604AB0E246B775B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Any monthly payment that would have otherwise been made by the borrower on 1 or more eligible loans during a period of deferment, including— </text> <subclause commented="no" id="HF6AC48A9EC844CEBBBB6039364981B1C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>deferment relating to cancer treatment under subsection (f)(3) or section 427(a)(2)(C)(v);</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="HC711D4427EDF479ABE131462EFBA4E8E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>deferment relating to active duty during a war or other military operation or national emergency, or performing qualifying National Guard duty during a war or other military operation or national emergency, under subsection (f)(2)(C) or section 428(b)(1)(M)(iii); </text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="H6F17030EA0D24839ACA9591B2A12AC89"><enum>(III)</enum><text>deferment relating to a period of unemployment under subsection (f)(2)(B) or section 428(b)(1)(M)(ii), or of economic hardship under subsection (f)(2)(D) or section 428(b)(1)(M)(iv);</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H6D4C6A686F164C1E898CA5C28AD9BBC4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>deferment provided in connection with services in the Peace Corps; and</text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HE4B126C1365A40F193CB628B3B933D6F"><enum>(V)</enum><text>deferment provided—</text> 
<item commented="no" id="HC03A505333EC48F39BD42407746F0FB6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>while the borrower is carrying at least one-half the normal full-time work load under subsection (f)(2)(A) or section 427(a)(2)(C) and employed full-time in public service; or</text></item> <item commented="no" id="H61F07079340F46A79FCB62CDFF7E6677"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in connection with a graduate student fellowship or while employed by a qualifying employer and pursuing a graduate, professional, or certificate program or in connection with a rehabilitation training program under subsection (f)(2)(A) or section 427(a)(2)(C). </text></item></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HAF1C04D909F54C5583DACCAF8F4C3AF0" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Any monthly payment that otherwise would have been made by the borrower during a grace period lasting in excess of 6 consecutive months.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HCB2CEF4359E84AA994424D72049EC82E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (3) and (4) as paragraphs (6) and (7), respectively; </text></paragraph> 
<paragraph commented="no" id="H770DCD9B8F644F428FBC38239BBC2220"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (2) the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDFE02C9CF6EF4CAC9B5752B97427AEF0"> <paragraph commented="no" id="H5183EDA10D9A4ED2A79177D707842329"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Special rules relating to employment</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H829D8660ABDC436ABE6F42502127CF3F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Grace period public service employment</header><text>The Secretary shall include any payments made by a borrower on an eligible Federal Direct Loan during a 6-month grace period, as described in section 428(b)(7)(A), while the borrower was employed full-time in public service, upon notification by the borrower of such employment and payments made. </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H03691E148B9549428B8B7753C9110F30"><enum>(B)</enum><header>AmeriCorps and Peace Corps service</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, volunteer service as an AmeriCorps or Peace Corps volunteer, as described in subclause (III) or (IV) of paragraph (6)(C)(i), shall be deemed to be employment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9DFE5902C5B7488FB7C2F3FEA7D29469"> <paragraph commented="no" id="HFDB651FC5DA740488BEE0965848A2ACE"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special rule for certain loans and borrowers</header> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H53E0655FC394485486B9D8A54108C730"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Parent Plus loans</header><text>In the case of a borrower of an eligible Federal Direct Loan that is on behalf of a student, any public service employment required under this subsection may be completed by the borrower or by the student on whose behalf the loan was made.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HE32BF4C230AA4D399DFE87EC0198164B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rules for Federal Direct Consolidation loans</header> 
<clause commented="no" id="HD46C4FFBEA754A19825668396B661E70"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A borrower who has obtained an eligible Federal Direct Loan that is a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan that includes a loan made, insured, or guaranteed under part B or part E shall receive credit—</text> <subclause commented="no" id="H6031349274A745DB959A342ABE02D364"><enum>(I)</enum><text>under paragraph (1) for any years of full-time employment in public service that occurred while the borrower had a component loan of the Federal Direct Consolidation Loan; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H6E8FD0A86F354B8CA56B1EBB86E4F30C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>under paragraph (1)(C) for any monthly payment described in such paragraph that was made by, or credited to, the borrower on a component loan of the Federal Direct Consolidation Loan.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H642377870C554750BFA36E43B34141A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Special rules for joint borrowers</header><text>The Secretary shall allow the borrowers of a Joint Consolidation Loan or a Joint Direct Consolidation Loan who are employed in a public service job to consolidate such loan into a Federal Direct Consolidation Loan in order to receive loan cancellation pursuant to this subsection.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1D34B2145701489D8DDEE5C65DAD8035" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (6), as redesignated by paragraph (2), and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC70F8B25FC946CCA92E1BE80EA7172D"> <paragraph id="H82C2D9F403FA4DB1A19DDD9AD1181CC9" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0FB10BBF8F7A4191B525C5ECBEBD304A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Eligible Federal direct loan</header><text>The term <term>eligible Federal Direct Loan</term> means a Federal Direct Stafford Loan, Federal Direct Unsubsidized Loan, Federal Direct PLUS Loan (including such loan made on behalf of a student), or Federal Direct Consolidation Loan. </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36A57BA338A74DA0AE27B00ADB652EA0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Full-time</header><text>The term <term>full-time</term>, when used with respect to employment in public service, means working in public service employment in one or more jobs for a total of—</text> 
<clause id="HF388FC8713314C8B9662F7DA99AF2EA2" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not less than 30 hours a week;</text></clause> <clause id="H3161F62EB56846E88CAF597C50AED20E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of any form of educational public service employment that is under a contract for not less than 8 months, not less than 30 hours per week during the contract period; or</text></clause> 
<clause id="H7CD211F4C42B486A994B6103FB04E657" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of employment as an adjunct, contingent, or part-time faculty member, teacher, or lecturer who is paid solely for the credit hours taught at an institution of higher education, the equivalent of 30 hours per week determined by multiplying each credit or contract hour taught per week by 3.35.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H81D054EB70FB43A5B69383CDCB420DAB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Public service</header> <clause id="HA4E232435E3442B7BD928EEAB3F713C0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>public service</term> means—</text> 
<subclause commented="no" id="H2A87DF78C17F4D9094FB7F850F9CB9A7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>employment with a qualifying employer described in clause (i) or (ii) of subparagraph (D); </text></subclause> <subclause commented="no" id="HDAA851BC89C2444F92F296D9EDCBFF62"><enum>(II)</enum><text>employment with a qualifying employer described in subparagraph (D)(iii) that—</text> 
<item commented="no" id="HA511B13AB5DD4002B714E585FAE5D1C6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>provides direct services to the public through its employees; and</text></item> <item commented="no" id="HA9007CE4D2A04DF7BF217F37A2062E0F"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>has devoted a majority of its full-time equivalent employees to working in not less than 1 of the following areas: </text> 
<subitem commented="no" id="H17990E3AD0894B38B2211C7DA6C35538"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>Early childhood education programs. </text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="HDB2E38E24B984552AB62F6B45A288C6C"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>Emergency management.</text></subitem> 
<subitem commented="no" id="HE6A5DF6115A04672A3B03427F29FD5B3"><enum>(CC)</enum><text>Law enforcement. </text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="H569742CFA1BD452EB2E542DD5742D187"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>Military service.</text></subitem> 
<subitem commented="no" id="H15AA105BF8EC4B8FB86336D7F3219811"><enum>(EE)</enum><text>Other school-based services. </text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="HDB05A59C097B4087934B402A36D1675E"><enum>(FF)</enum><text>Public education (including higher education).</text></subitem> 
<subitem commented="no" id="H258918B40995485EBB759EF082163C76"><enum>(GG)</enum><text>Public health.</text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="H317BAD943CA6450AAF2C7673DE33CCC2"><enum>(HH)</enum><text>Public interest law services. </text></subitem> 
<subitem commented="no" id="H9AD5423EDDB344EDB9187C8CF9E5F787"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Public library services.</text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="HE784CCBD13B748E0915D2085002E030D"><enum>(JJ)</enum><text>Public safety.</text></subitem> 
<subitem commented="no" id="H4061BEC651434633872E1B56B14B0BF9"><enum>(KK)</enum><text>Public services for individuals with disabilities or public services for the elderly. </text></subitem> <subitem commented="no" id="HA8600989BD79459DB0B975B5373F73BD"><enum>(LL)</enum><text>School library services; </text></subitem></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H28A07EAB8A05494EBFB245500382B7AD"><enum>(III)</enum><text>satisfactory service as a Peace Corps volunteer in accordance with section 5 of the Peace Corps Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2504">22 U.S.C. 2504</external-xref>); or </text></subclause> <subclause id="H1C26B9D622C84EC9BE5E3B5F5718A93E"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>successful service as a participant in a position described in section 123 of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12573">42 U.S.C. 12573</external-xref>). </text></subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HF0CDBF656E954DC583BA4829FCE8107B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Additional definitions</header><text>For purposes of clause (i): </text> <subclause id="H0D3B9FE5991F41E6AE5CB2BFD0EDD845" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Emergency management services</header><text>The term <term>emergency management services</term> means services that help remediate, lessen, or eliminate the effects or potential effects of emergencies that threaten human life or health or real property.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H8B29DD6391F943DB8651F5BD9A261AF2" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Law enforcement</header><text>The term <term>law enforcement</term> means services performed by an employee of a public service organization that is publicly funded and whose principal activities pertain to crime prevention, control or reduction of crime, or the enforcement of criminal law.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H8F6C3C7C32874C2F9006A6BFA45293A3" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Military service</header><text>The term <term>military service</term> means providing service to or on behalf of members, veterans, or the families or survivors of members or veterans of the Armed Forces, including the National Guard, that is provided to a person because of the person’s status in the Armed Forces or National Guard.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="HB4C12257F2C846A58ED6A285B339319F" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Other school-based services</header><text>The term <term>other school-based services</term> means an employee of a State, or of any political division of a State, or an employee of a nonprofit organization, who works in any grade from prekindergarten through grade 12 in any of the following occupational specialties:</text> <item id="HE516F73A66C7425E96259E1BCACF1088" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>Paraprofessional services, including paraeducator services.</text></item> 
<item id="H417ECE65084447F7BB89A0406DF713D6" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>Clerical and administrative services.</text></item> <item id="H83554CCE3DA8457DBA2A6AFF629B761A" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>Transportation services.</text></item> 
<item id="H3EC145106B79469AAA99625234345F77" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>Food and nutrition services.</text></item> <item id="H1C21F0332E7549B08988E65B97355B1C" commented="no"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>Custodial and maintenance services.</text></item> 
<item id="HA89DD2AC421D4417B06D920456832E9D" commented="no"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>Security services.</text></item> <item id="H30E1C222FD4F46A0A9F94195D86CAE54" commented="no"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>Health and student services.</text></item> 
<item id="H0533AB03A497480BAFDE3F15977CB1F2" commented="no"><enum>(hh)</enum><text>Technical services.</text></item> <item id="HD2EC2252ED1E4E43827470E41F351096" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Skilled trades. </text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H5854428A73664DAAAC1B610C94A55387" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Public education</header><text>The term <term>public education</term> means—</text> <item commented="no" id="H2CE389FB56844D7BACFBB411F20859F8"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the provision of educational enrichment or support to students in a school or a school-like setting, including teaching; and</text></item> 
<item commented="no" id="HC77FCCBC6C5C443294D974498E8F7F87"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>teaching as a full-time faculty member at a Tribal College or University, as defined in section 316(b), and other faculty teaching in high-needs subject areas or areas of shortage (including nurse faculty, foreign language faculty, and part-time faculty at community colleges), as determined by the Secretary.</text></item></subclause> <subclause id="HF90F1553BF3243E88D1A1FC2A1B84474" commented="no"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>The term <term>public health</term> means—</text> 
<item commented="no" id="H6C1FD12ECB8A4617A193CCEC91DCB4DD"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>services provided by physicians, nurses (including nurses in a clinical setting), and nurse practitioners; and </text></item> <item commented="no" id="H2F102BA38DAA4F1F884E37262BDC1359"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>services provided by health care practitioner occupations, health care support occupations, and counselors, social workers, and other community and social service specialist occupations, as those terms are defined by the Bureau of Labor Statistics.</text></item></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1DACB37D54FB4A929805B1FC5ECF057A" commented="no"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>The term <term>public interest law</term> means legal services or legal advocacy provided by a nonprofit organization, but excludes services provided by individuals who are registered lobbyists at the Federal, State, or local level.</text></subclause> <subclause id="HB63FE76D8C1944C4A29E63EDF3B07A8B" commented="no"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>The term <term>public library services</term> means the operation of public libraries or services that support their operation.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H807878330FFF4133ADE05E9DCECA0E4A" commented="no"><enum>(IX)</enum><text>The term <term>public safety services</term> means services that seek to prevent the need for emergency management services.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H4A3FCC2454034A66B250572666C97F66" commented="no"><enum>(X)</enum><text>The term <term>public services for individuals with disabilities</term> means services performed for, or to assist, individuals with disabilities (as defined in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>)) that is provided to an individual because of the individual's status as an individual with a disability.</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H518C169E2B6A4C1682F3BCC31AE8621E" commented="no"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>The term <term>public service for the elderly</term> means services that are provided to individuals who are aged 59.5 years or older and that are provided to an individual because of the individual's status as an individual of that age, including services related to retirement plans, pensions, social security, retiree health plans, or Medicaid.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H647BB2FF99884D3CA10DEEAD2575EA9C" commented="no"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>The term <term>school library services</term> means the operations of school libraries or services that support their operation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H4A596591C897493593B45E2496363A27" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Qualifying employer</header><text>The term <term>qualifying employer</term> means—</text> <clause id="HF202337CFAB44FB7BCFDE7E6D9AE8405" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Federal, State, Tribal, local, intergovernmental, or regional governmental organization, agency, or entity based or headquartered in the United States, including the Armed Forces, National Guard, Merchant Marines, or Coast Guard; </text></clause> 
<clause id="HCE9D73E804F74B59A06D086E3F581F4B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that is qualified under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; or</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H4C9BBF377A8B40A7BABF9346E48B7614"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that is qualified under section 501(a) of such Code, with respect to an employee in public service employment.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HA55A493E7C5248299BE3CE8C443EF171"><enum>4.</enum><header>Loan forgiveness for teachers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="H72D34CE700C741EBAD4C40BD562BA7E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 428J(g)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1078-10">20 U.S.C. 1078–10(g)(2)</external-xref>)—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA737248D09A3454E91AEBD34F94583E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB8B06C1DAD4441CDA425A3A44B38CA53"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB3131B470E8142FE8752C6D204AF1365"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B);</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBFA008F2EB7B4F5CAB508D03E8B48893"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (7) of section 455(m) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e(m)</external-xref>), as amended by section 3(2), by striking <quote>both this subsection and section 428J, 428K, 428L, or 460</quote> and inserting <quote>both this subsection and section 428K or 428L</quote>; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6B94AFD49F8E4FFAAC6CDD46A402BF80"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in section 460(g)(2) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087j">20 U.S.C. 1087j(g)(2)</external-xref>)—</text> <subparagraph id="H4380BA86A1F34936B8F8CF680BB94A2C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or</quote> after the semicolon at the end;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H782FEE762B5B4B9AB6C7C8B412BDC57C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B); and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B49CACE4101492593C861BCCED5DC21" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraph (C) as subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

