<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFA98F3A6F9F14505995264F03C19F8A0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6443 IH: Arm Taiwan Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6443</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To accelerate deployment by Taiwan of the asymmetric defense capabilities required to deter or, if necessary, defeat an invasion of Taiwan by the People’s Republic of China, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8EDF9C615856442791D9B36F9A4B7BEC" style="OLC"><section id="H2761B1A242364D928FCB810311C3D882" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Arm Taiwan Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HCC88D813BAE54F1FB1EEBE9690682305"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings; sense of Congress</header><subsection id="HEA32DF0E5FC44DF5902FC9927E9E679E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H377F59B537624938AB4FEA2B193B1309"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Department of Defense has warned that the Government of the People’s Republic of China may conclude that it can successfully invade and seize control of Taiwan in the latter half of the 2020s.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H97FD15D8483A4F598C7BFFDB9943AB71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>In October 2021, the Minister of National Defense of Taiwan, Chiu Kuo-cheng, echoed these warnings when he stated that the People’s Republic of China—</text><subparagraph id="H923EFDA09498443D94ABE20CB5B7D933"><enum>(A)</enum><text><quote>is capable now</quote> of invading Taiwan; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFAF1A451808E48A584225908EA7E3651"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will have <quote>lowered the costs and losses</quote> associated with invading Taiwan <quote>to a minimum</quote> after 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC4049692863447BA90CE33FA92256AA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>If the People’s Republic of China were to invade and seize control of Taiwan, it would deal a severe blow to United States interests by—</text><subparagraph id="H15C24B8E93A544B09A45373A3C0E36CD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>destroying one of the world’s leading democracies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4766810EA2B4003B4CD04183A16A113"><enum>(B)</enum><text>casting doubt on the ability and resolve of the United States to uphold its security commitments;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3F6D5E494784F39A91E3A0B4BF0C11E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>incentivizing other countries in the Indo-Pacific region to bandwagon with the People’s Republic of China; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H93468729F5ED4738B0676CE2F8AFC5A6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>facilitating the formation of a regional order dominated by the People's Republic of China in which the Government of the People's Republic of China may—</text><clause id="HC289B3C6BEBF46BCA5AAAEE66C3A8516"><enum>(i)</enum><text>regulate or otherwise limit the ability of individuals in the United States to trade in the Indo-Pacific region, which would have dire effects on the livelihoods and freedoms of such individuals; and </text></clause><clause id="H8E9028B095874D639CFC556A914EA033"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>use the Indo-Pacific region as a secure base from which to project military power into other regions, including the Western Hemisphere.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A7811AB2F574F21AD4D7B1FA6CFC03D"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Taiwan's proximity to the People’s Republic of China, coupled with investments by the People’s Republic of China in capabilities designed to delay intervention by the United States Armed Forces in support of Taiwan, means that Taiwan may be forced to delay, degrade, and deny an invasion by the People’s Republic of China with limited support from the United States Armed Forces for the initial days, weeks, or months of such an invasion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BE4C94AEBC0416CA8952C4D87391874"><enum>(5)</enum><text>If Taiwan is unable to delay, degrade, and deny an invasion by the People’s Republic of China with limited support from the United States Armed Forces, especially in the initial period of war, then the People’s Republic of China may conclude that it is, or may actually be, capable of—</text><subparagraph id="HE83B0DF511534C949DF2D286AC5BCCC7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>invading and seizing control of Taiwan before the United States or any other partner country of Taiwan is able to respond effectively, thereby achieving a fait accompli; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H173D0E289A1A4091BF24C55D47F1A76A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>potentially rendering any attempt by the United States or any other partner country of Taiwan to reverse territorial gains by the People’s Republic of China prohibitively difficult, costly, or both. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3247DC2A215946B98359D94889541C04"><enum>(6)</enum><text>To defend itself effectively, especially in the initial period of war, it is imperative that Taiwan accelerate deployment of cost-effective and resilient asymmetric defense capabilities, including mobile coastal and air defenses, naval mines, missile boats, man-portable anti-armor weapons, civil defense forces, and their enablers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96B13911172F47469B93A2FCB55C6E53"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The deployment of such asymmetric defense capabilities by Taiwan would not only improve the ability of Taiwan to defend itself, but also reduce operational risk to members of the United States Armed Forces under a Taiwan contingency. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD937E7FFB87D410A8A9C7288B7941891"><enum>(8)</enum><text>The President of Taiwan, Tsai Ing-Wen, has—</text><subparagraph id="HD0E15B7331F94B74AA258B9F7F1F1360"><enum>(A)</enum><text>vowed to bolster the national defense of Taiwan and demonstrate Taiwan's determination to defend itself so as to ensure that Taiwan will not be forced to take the path that the People's Republic of China has laid out for Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H690C08E035B34EA7AD9BC83DDC1AA68A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>advocated the deployment of asymmetric defense capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AFBB45BD1F54622B89A358A54AB78F4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>The Government of Taiwan has begun taking steps to improve Taiwan's defenses, including by increasing Taiwan's defense budget and through Taiwan's new proposed special defense budget, but far more is needed, and quickly, to ensure that Taiwan is able to maintain a sufficient self-defense capability.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H09198BEAD25F436D946839D44929D971"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H66C5793F2EB4409DB1C5145C22BD95A9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the threat of an invasion of Taiwan by the People’s Republic of China is increasing rapidly and expected to reach especially dangerous levels by the latter half of the 2020s;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF769DE7801704E58AA88660208FEC011"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States has a strong interest in preventing the People’s Republic of China from invading and seizing control of Taiwan, especially by ensuring that Taiwan is able to maintain a sufficient self-defense capability;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H172A6B80A2BD4A69B204E5302BB41196"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the United States should establish a security assistance initiative so as to accelerate, to the greatest extent possible, Taiwan’s deployment of cost-effective and resilient asymmetric defense capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H277578ADCF614027A8A5245CF7755C11"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the United States should provide such assistance on the condition that Taiwan—</text><subparagraph id="H5252272EC5BE480DBB38F8771168E4A9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>matches investments by the United States in its asymmetric defense capabilities;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FC31FCAADC046A090783F97813951D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>increases its defense spending to a level commensurate with the threat it faces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1DD722CD1DC4B5798D4FF271B7FE917"><enum>(C)</enum><text>prioritizes acquiring cost-effective and resilient asymmetric defense capabilities as rapidly as possible, including from foreign suppliers, if necessary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7BF6133B946044738D058CF2FDD95FBB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>demonstrates progress on defense reforms required to maximize the effectiveness of its asymmetric defenses, with special regard to Taiwan’s reserve forces; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9BCA042EAA84138B73B0E14BBDCE2BE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in the course of executing such a security assistance initiative, the United States should—</text><subparagraph id="H8D6D40D0558448E3969E59872E317E34"><enum>(A)</enum><text>seek to co-produce or co-develop cost-effective and resilient asymmetric defense capabilities with suppliers in Taiwan, including by providing incentives to that effect, so long as those suppliers can produce such capabilities at a reasonable cost, in the quantities required, as rapidly, and to the same quality and technical standards as suppliers in the United States or other countries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6883581DEA904CE4BD9CF7F25FDF9857"><enum>(B)</enum><text>encourage other countries, particularly United States allies and partners, to sell, lease, or otherwise provide appropriate asymmetric defense capabilities to Taiwan so as to facilitate Taiwan’s rapid deployment of the asymmetric defense capabilities required to deter or, if necessary, defeat an invasion by the People’s Republic of China.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3D95C1A28E7745A48BD6C049C58DA6DE"><enum>3.</enum><header>Taiwan Security Assistance Initiative</header><subsection id="H37C8FF557382477BB0047F8C9E34204B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall establish an initiative, to be known as the <quote>Taiwan Security Assistance Initiative</quote> (referred to in this Act as the <quote>Initiative</quote>), to accelerate Taiwan's deployment of asymmetric defense capabilities required to deter or, if necessary, defeat an invasion by the People’s Republic of China. </text></subsection><subsection id="H31F5342D7CB4426F8BDB4AF8142C757A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $3,000,000,000 for the Department of Defense for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 to provide assistance to the Government of Taiwan under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD1614662A6D94B93BCD20465CA971990"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authority To provide assistance</header><paragraph id="H4F9B21934FF94B41A060D89D89FED9D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall use the funds authorized to be appropriated under subsection (b) to provide assistance to the Government of Taiwan for the purpose described in subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H008B80216271482F8DC9E441717CD2BA"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The purpose of the Initiative is to provide assistance, including equipment, training, and other support, to the Government of Taiwan so as to accelerate Taiwan’s deployment of asymmetric defense capabilities required to achieve, with limited support from the United States Armed Forces for the initial days, weeks, or months after the initiation of an invasion by the People’s Republic of China of Taiwan, the following objectives:</text><paragraph id="H4D4B5D6AABD64AD0B1A821F91C539673"><enum>(1)</enum><text>To delay, degrade, and deny attempts by People’s Liberation Army forces to enter or transit the Taiwan Strait and adjoining seas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC889032B43204CBB8DFF4959873AD9F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>To delay, degrade, and deny attempts by People’s Liberation Army forces to secure a lodgment on Taiwan and expand or otherwise use that lodgment to seize control of a population center or other key territory in Taiwan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H836AF9322A8149448D18C1FC41601C26" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(3)</enum><text>To prevent the People’s Republic of China from decapitating, seizing control of, or otherwise neutralizing or rendering ineffective the Government of Taiwan. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A8FF558F4AE470F8DD62A48B2FE3ED6"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Asymmetric defense capabilities</header><text>In this section, the term <term>asymmetric defense capabilities</term> includes, in such quantities as the Secretary of Defense determines to be necessary to achieve the purpose specified in subsection (d), the following: </text><paragraph id="H7CE139D809AE481988EABFCA02A20D6A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Mobile, ground-based coastal defense cruise missiles and launchers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A4915A5FBAE4617910495E3BD083281"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mobile, ground-based short-range and medium-range air defense systems.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19923A73E64C4D7091268637D95B05DD"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Smart, self-propelled naval mines and coastal minelaying platforms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H65536AAE0A0A457DBF23805538EC8612"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Missile boats and fast-attack craft equipped with anti-ship and anti-landing craft missiles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB8214F1C87149C8B5B901428ED51DBE"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Unmanned aerial and other mobile, resilient surveillance systems to support coastal and air defense operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF90D2C9FB0904E32BDCA5D4DD9C3C80A"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Equipment to support target location, tracking, identification, and targeting, especially at the local level, in communications degraded or denied environments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7427775B12E048AB8DEBC70C0E7BF881"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Man-portable anti-armor weapons, mortars, and small arms for ground combat operations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H920579E08DDC4B168F62A3E8705848EC"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Equipment and technical assistance for the purpose of developing civil defense forces, composed of civilian volunteers and militia.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7C0DCAA82C6438C8A4920E19F816354"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Training and equipment, including appropriate war reserves, required for Taiwan forces to independently maintain, sustain, and employ capabilities described in paragraphs (1) through (8).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC6E967E8CD94012A9D89C4BCE947BDA" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Concept development for coastal defense, air defense, decentralized command and control, civil defense, logistics, planning, and other critical military functions, with an emphasis on operations in a communications degraded or denied environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4B71EC895B904273ADB15041A63AC362" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Any other capability the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate for the purpose described in subsection (d). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H506D3B46593A4B78AB2F7BC1FD299B89"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><paragraph id="H81EF5DCB0C8544E2A791D87E91FD5266"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Plan</header><text>Not later than December 1, 2022, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a plan for using funds authorized to be appropriated under subsection (b) for the purpose specified in subsection (d). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5DFB0FFE18A414DBBEA003149606210"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Initial certification</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (b) for fiscal year 2023 may not be obligated or expended until the date on which the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, certifies that the Government of Taiwan has committed—</text><subparagraph id="HDE6A98DF4A374865B3C1E2B2075191A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to spending an equivalent amount on asymmetric defense capabilities in fiscal year 2023; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDB7B2661B1B4F01ACB27F1330388E2B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to spending not less than two and a half percent of Taiwan’s national gross domestic product on defense on an annual basis by the end of fiscal year 2025, and not less than three percent of Taiwan’s national gross domestic product on defense on an annual basis by the end of fiscal year 2027, including expenditures under the normal defense budget and any supplemental or special defense budgets of Taiwan; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEBFEE6CC6E048DDB093201A8F733E7C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to acquiring asymmetric defense capabilities as rapidly as possible, including from suppliers in the United States or other countries, if the Secretary of Defense determines that such suppliers will be able to provide such capabilities at a reasonable cost, in sufficient quantities, of sufficient quality and technical standards, and more rapidly than suppliers in Taiwan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H49736EC9A6184CAE9AD29A8DA13ADAFA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to undertaking the defense reforms required to maximize the effectiveness of an asymmetric defense against an invasion by the People’s Republic of China, including by improving organization, mobilization, and training of the reserve forces and other military personnel of Taiwan. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA84A122CC1CE4E2E80C8606F1BB9BAAE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent certifications</header><text>Amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (b) for each of fiscal years 2024, 2025, 2026, and 2027 may not be obligated or expended until the date on which the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, certifies that the Government of Taiwan has committed—</text><subparagraph id="HBB35EED9B4894D1297E6609440EAB6CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to spending an equivalent amount on asymmetric defense capabilities in the applicable fiscal year and upheld its commitment to spend an equivalent amount as the United States in the preceding fiscal year on asymmetric defense capabilities to be deployed by Taiwan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H41C4CA9D413548EA9ACA2B349215C68E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to spending not less than two and a half percent of Taiwan’s national gross domestic product on defense on an annual basis by the end of fiscal year 2025, and not less than three percent of Taiwan’s national gross domestic product on defense on an annual basis by the end of fiscal year 2027, including expenditures under the normal defense budget and any supplemental or special defense budgets of Taiwan, and demonstrated progress toward these spending targets in the preceding fiscal year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF2CA96EFFC04CDCAF5B50DB857CDF40"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to acquiring asymmetric defense capabilities as rapidly as possible, including from suppliers in the United States or other countries, if the Secretary of Defense determines that such suppliers will be able to provide such capabilities at reasonable cost, in sufficient quantities, of sufficient quality and technical standards, and more rapidly than suppliers in Taiwan, and upheld its commitment to acquire asymmetric defense capabilities as rapidly as possible in the preceding fiscal year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C3844B4483E42BC8F3CC1A0B183DD7E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to undertaking the defense reforms required to maximize the effectiveness of an asymmetric defense against an invasion by the People’s Republic of China, including by improving the organization, mobilization, and training of the reserve forces and other military personnel of Taiwan, and demonstrated progress on such reforms in the preceding fiscal year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CFB6C2A10A64C45B4824CF19639AF92"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Notification to Congress</header><text>Not later than 30 days after making a certification under paragraph (2) or (3), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a notice and explanation of such certification.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE29C6E664274BB9BD872F960AF5B7B1"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Remaining funds</header><subparagraph id="H2E3AB0548D344D22B59D682D28B79F06"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), amounts appropriated for a fiscal year pursuant to the authorization of appropriations under subsection (b) that are not obligated and expended during that fiscal year shall be added to the amount that may be used for the Initiative in the subsequent fiscal year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F34CCDF5E54498295E4245A8617CC4E" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Rescission</header><text>Amounts appropriated pursuant to the authorization of appropriation under subsection (b) that remain unobligated by the end of fiscal year 2027 shall be rescinded and deposited into the general fund of the Treasury. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC86F1E3C613944B19C869DF5B3D405EB"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Defense articles and services from United States inventory and other sources</header><paragraph id="H3744700AA8C246079D146C3C8BA7845E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In addition to assistance provided pursuant to subsection (c), the Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of State, may make available to the Government of Taiwan, in such quantities as the Secretary of Defense considers appropriate for the purpose described in subsection (d), the following:</text><subparagraph id="H488B93B8326D4F4B80A31358CE05EDAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Weapons and other defense articles from the United States inventory and other sources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC60B4A8A6D3E41AFB56F4B4E6BDA4E62"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Excess defense articles from the United States inventory.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DCEB57C4F0D460DA7D911578CB69A53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Defense services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7EB6B50F86004E20BDE7BE306731F814" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Replacement</header><text>Amounts for the replacement of any item provided to the Government of Taiwan under paragraph (1)(A) may be made available from the amount authorized to be appropriated under subsection (b). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H951270D997E94E6B9798C246BFC4C311"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Termination of authority</header><text>Assistance may not be provided under this section after September 30, 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2BE132B744DA4DB697498CEBC12480D8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on conventional arms sales</header><subsection id="HF0EA991BE68E483DAF86E9398F1D4ADD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text>It is the sense of Congress that—</text><paragraph id="H502BF44E487D4EDE8E2BA888CF66BA3A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>historically, the Government of Taiwan has prioritized the acquisition of conventional weapons that would be of limited utility in deterring or defeating an invasion by the People’s Republic of China at the expense of the timely acquisition of cost-effective and resilient asymmetric defense capabilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39883EE5569C45ABADE28970BE414E6F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the United States Government has often shared responsibility for the misguided prioritization of defense acquisitions described in paragraph (1) by approving sales of conventional weapons to Taiwan, despite knowledge that such sales would do little to enhance, and may even undermine, the ability of Taiwan to deter or defeat an invasion by the People’s Republic of China;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC6961F98BF043C9B3FAF92E6A2988E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the misguided prioritization of defense acquisitions described in paragraph (1) has not only undermined the ability of Taiwan to deter or defeat an invasion by the People’s Republic of China, but has also placed at greater risk of death or injury members of the United States Armed Forces who may come under attack or be asked to come to the aid of Taiwan to repel such an invasion; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H04BBC351484C4AFA99AB7322B94529C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any future sales, leases, or other provision of conventional weaponry to Taiwan by the United States should be conditioned on meaningful progress by the Government of Taiwan on the acquisition of appropriate asymmetric defense capabilities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9C6C22540F29411688E8A89B77F836FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Statement of policy</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, the United States Government shall not sell, lease, or otherwise provide military capabilities to Taiwan other than asymmetric defense capabilities described in subsection (e) of section 3 until the earlier of—</text><paragraph id="HA98E4326924E432FB2832E11E5DA14B5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary of Defense has submitted a notification under subsection (f)(4) of that section for the fiscal year in which the Government of Taiwan has requested the sale, lease, or other provision of military capabilities other than such asymmetric defense capabilities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H053EBFDDBCBE47BB860B6CE7AD714C7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the date on which the Secretary of Defense certifies to the appropriate committees of Congress that the sale, lease, or other provision to Taiwan of military capabilities other than such asymmetric defense capabilities—</text><subparagraph id="HEFF62B15B3204939B74E322F90318224"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is necessary to enhance the ability of Taiwan to deter or, if necessary, defeat an invasion by the People’s Republic of China; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H328A5790CA6D4C22BDA2BB5FBC21B3EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>will not slow, delay, limit, or otherwise detract from or undermine the ability of Taiwan to deploy such asymmetric defense capabilities.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6C3534088D434587BD461F7D70F480F7"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definition of appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means—</text><paragraph id="HCFD02F64948348E68D816EB4A040F689"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFFDE9B0BFF04CECBE62DF3DECE7F4BB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

