<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H534B657604214867B8C6DBCD600EB148" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6378 IH: Local Control Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6378</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001274">Mr. Brooks</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Homeland Security to notify the Governor of a State prior to the date on which any alien without lawful status under the immigration laws is transported to, housed in, or resettled in such State, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9066D5E85B014B2C81BE7EF7529D772E" style="OLC"><section id="HB3949413856B4030B4F58036647BF357" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Local Control Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC81A53966129403BB740E5DDD3F7B650"><enum>2.</enum><header>Disapproval of settlement of certain aliens</header><subsection id="H05E4E503AF904A6D957AF6A517FA4D6A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conditions on settlement of certain aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security in consultation with the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Attorney General, shall notify the Governor of a State and the chief executive of a political subdivision prior to the date on which any alien without lawful status under the immigration laws is transported to, housed in, or resettled in such State or political subdivision.</text></subsection><subsection id="H371F69B584AE4A3C87D56592307AECE1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disapproval of settlement of certain aliens</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of law, beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the following conditions on transportation, housing, and resettlement of aliens without lawful status under the immigration laws shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H56521BE16A554B7C93D104478EED2627"><enum>(1)</enum><text>No Federal funds may be used to transport, house, or resettle any alien without lawful status under the immigration laws within a State without the approval of the Governor of the State.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEE5AB6F956764797A90A7ED7181E408B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Notwithstanding any approval granted under paragraph (1), no Federal funds may be used to transport, house, or resettle any alien without lawful status under the immigration laws in any political subdivision within a State if the political subdivision has in effect a law, a policy with the effect of law, or resolution prohibiting or disapproving of the transportation, housing, or resettling of aliens in that political subdivision.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB9C9CE9CDE43419A947F28FC130673E2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1) or (2), nothing in this subsection shall be construed to prohibit the use of Federal funds for the transportation or detention of an alien without a lawful immigration status for civil or criminal law enforcement purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF3B37440F73E45FCAA75FC8903151088"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed to restrict or limit the transportation or detention of an alien without a lawful immigration status for civil or criminal law enforcement purposes.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA55DC6AE8EE746CA9F673A7FD7740B63"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Alien defined</header><text>In this Act, the term <quote>alien</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

