<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4CF4DA46FFC746238A549421E682CBC2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9491 IH: Billy’s Law</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9491</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221212">December 12, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To increase accessibility to the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System, to facilitate data sharing between such system and the National Crime Information Center database of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="HA82AEC05F0F44F37B6DDA46917266A27" style="OLC">
<section section-type="section-one" id="H803BC2F01FE94CB9A0D08725BCF65EE2"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as <quote><short-title>Billy’s Law</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>Help Find the Missing Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEBD6AE8FAFD147EDB101A289F6326279"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authorization of the national missing and unidentified persons system</header> <subsection id="H591E10FB9EE7480BB05B87A302C7E80E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Attorney General shall maintain the <quote>National Missing and Unidentified Persons System</quote> or <quote>NamUs</quote>, consistent with the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HA5A687A55E0D4981AD376585EC8AF340"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The NamUs shall be a national information clearinghouse and resource center for missing, unidentified, and unclaimed person cases across the United States administered by the National Institute of Justice and managed through an agreement with an eligible entity.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD943CC3687EC4057818014E25D8CFC16"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The NamUs shall coordinate or provide—</text>
<subparagraph id="HE141EC5AF2414746AE4C3307539C2684"><enum>(A)</enum><text>online database technology which serves as a national information clearinghouse to help expedite case associations and resolutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9F58815907DC4321914D6276C93AD316"><enum>(B)</enum><text>various free-of-charge forensic services to aid in the identification of missing persons and unidentified remains;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1DDA78F0DDCE4BB087E0AA20F92CFA2F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>investigative support for criminal justice efforts to help missing and unidentified person case resolutions;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE9FBA7528B03492EA9EE3F0F9C8907FC"><enum>(D)</enum><text>technical assistance for family members of missing persons;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H05B4BBBE750D4622A72ED60FB53D66D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text>assistance and training by coordinating State and local service providers in order to support individuals and families impacted by the loss or disappearance of a loved one; and </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6B20B0A4B1C64981BC68A9E2FB1D4751"><enum>(F)</enum><text>training and outreach from NamUs subject matter experts, including assistance with planning and facilitating Missing Person Day events across the country.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF560DEB9F48C4ACC9FFC144A505658F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Permissible use of funds</header>
<paragraph id="H46C6CC9DF0F64254852B889B0FD40492"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The permissible use of funds awarded under this section for the implementation and maintenance of the agreement created in subparagraph (a)(1) include the use of funds—</text> <subparagraph id="H8CB57CEF00164F6781751236FE0A388D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to hire additional personnel to provide case support and perform other core NamUs functions;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCDDBC377ECA4445995998EE2A196D424"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to develop new technologies to facilitate timely data entry into the relevant data bases;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEB989B4146D743A794308D9B8A0ABBA2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>to conduct contracting activities relevant to core NamUs services;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2F8673AA77D04BDEB708DEDA2EBDB114"><enum>(D)</enum><text>to provide forensic analyses to support the identification of missing and unidentified persons, to include, but not limited to DNA typing, forensic odontology, fingerprint examination, and forensic anthropology;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H703F16C10058407A8E36056B04A2D775"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to train State, local, and Tribal law enforcement personnel and forensic medicine service providers to use NamUs resources and best practices for the investigation of missing and unidentified person cases;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H593B393F0AE64B73AAC7F56B320C3DB1"><enum>(F)</enum><text>to assist States in providing information to the NCIC database, the NamUs database, or any future database system for missing, unidentified, and unclaimed person cases; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA952FC9271634CAE87834DB2C83A0FCD"><enum>(G)</enum><text>to report to law enforcement authorities in the jurisdiction in which the remains were found information on every deceased, unidentified person, regardless of age;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H17808CBC51624B6BBEA165722EC201A9"><enum>(H)</enum><text>to participate in Missing Person Days and other events to directly support family members of the missing with NamUs case entries and DNA collections;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC05FD464D7FC4D6BADD72069D9043F40"><enum>(I)</enum><text>to provide assistance and training by coordinating State and local service providers in order to support individuals and families;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H43ADC71987CA4606BEEF1A531F1930BF"><enum>(J)</enum><text>to conduct data analytics and research projects for the purpose of enhancing knowledge, best practices, and training related to missing and unidentified person cases, as well as developing NamUs system enhancements;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H21F0B393684D41E39B033EE1D3EEA6EC"><enum>(K)</enum><text>to create and maintain a secure, online, nationwide critical incident response tool for professionals that will connect law enforcement, medicolegal and emergency management professionals, as well as victims and families during a critical incident; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H480E392E203A4721B88316B630DDB0F9"><enum>(L)</enum><text>for other purposes consistent with the goals of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1913D72C22E54947B23E6EDADEFDB3D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Amendments to the Crime Control Act of 1990 To require reports of missing children to NamUs</header> <paragraph id="H5F367D92BC8F4356A5E2873EB5839AF1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reporting requirement</header><text>Section 3701(a) of the Crime Control Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/41307">34 U.S.C. 41307(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the period and inserting the following: <quote>and, consistent with section 3 (including rules promulgated pursuant to section 3(c)) of the Help Find the Missing Act, shall also report such case, either directly or through authorization described in such section to transmit, enter, or share information on such case, to the NamUs databases.</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HD411316F1410470B8C4D1022DFA57D6B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>State requirements</header><text>Section 3702 of the Crime Control Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/41308">34 U.S.C. 41308</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <subparagraph id="HCA152675CA0841859033D4CD467A1CEF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or the National Crime Information Center computer database</quote> and inserting <quote>, the National Crime Information Center computer database, or the NamUs databases</quote>;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3BD41307DA51430D86C0D83A0CE017F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the matter following paragraph (3), by striking <quote>and the National Crime Information Center computer networks</quote> and inserting <quote>, the National Crime Information Center computer networks, and the NamUs databases</quote>; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2FA038C4BEC04E6F84D53D1F715B7EB6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text>
<clause id="H7B2C4FA1B153427D8A8A3FA73A2AB517"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by inserting <quote>or the NamUs databases</quote> after <quote>National Crime Information Center</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause id="H3E66AEFB82D44B1DA5E9923823102F49"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and National Crime Information Center computer networks</quote> and inserting <quote>, National Crime Information Center computer networks, and the NamUs databases</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H279BFEF51E394785ABE8C9BDA6978413"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this subsection shall apply with respect to reports made before, on, or after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H75A77298CF9D46D99D08D7021B566532"><enum>3.</enum><header>Information sharing</header> <subsection id="HF5DCBBCFE88C4456A246BAE4D362A2D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Access to NCIC</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, in accordance with this section, provide access to the NCIC Missing Person and Unidentified Person Files to the National Institute of Justice or its designee administering the NamUs program as a grantee or contractor, for the purpose of reviewing missing and unidentified person records in NCIC for case validation and NamUs data reconciliation.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF65E71E647E043C19205BAA7A8422E9B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Electronic data sharing</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall, in accordance with this section, have completed an assessment of the NCIC and NamUs system architectures and governing statutes, policies, and procedures and provide a proposed plan for the secure and automatic data transmission of missing and unidentified person records that are reported to and entered into the NCIC database, with the following criteria, to be electronically transmitted to the NamUs system:</text> <paragraph id="H3C455D8801F34ACC9356ABC771C306B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Missing Person cases with an MNP (Missing Person) code of CA (Child Abduction) or AA (Amber Alert) within 72 hours of entry into NCIC.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBEA9F8BFD7ED4615A6C8E0C15C6C32BC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Missing Person cases with an MNP code EME (Endangered) or EMI (Involuntary) within 30 days of entry into NCIC.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9D9EF18512C8460DA961D29541601358"><enum>(3)</enum><text>All other Missing Person cases that have been active (non-cancelled) in NCIC for 180 days.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00FA9A76613045CDBE94F8357249B9CD"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Unidentified person cases that have been active (non-cancelled) in NCIC for 60 days.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38E038672B0B4D6EA1D758E1D66ABB55"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Once case data are transmitted to NamUs, cases are marked as such within NCIC, and any updates to such cases will be transmitted to NamUs within 24 hours.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7A4EB6D1D763475C95FA068DCB66CA02"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rules on confidentiality</header>
<paragraph id="H15E223E8E5B3419397981C53A1B32C71"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General, in consultation with the Director of the FBI, shall promulgate rules pursuant to notice and comment that specify the information the Attorney General may allow NamUs to access from the NCIC Missing Person and Unidentified Person files or be transmitted from the NCIC database to the NamUs databases for purposes of this Act. Such rules shall—</text> <subparagraph id="H5CECACA799F94A77BA432052D6BC9DD5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>provide for the protection of confidential, private, and law enforcement sensitive information contained in the NCIC Missing Person and Unidentified Person files; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3B7FFB81BA044B7AB4BC1D83DFF34863"><enum>(B)</enum><text>specify the circumstances in which access to portions of information in the Missing Person and Unidentified Person files may be withheld from the NamUs databases.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HF1C7E5AE373A46F3857B2387A1272D11"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on best practices</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Attorney General shall issue a report to offices of forensic medicine service providers, and Federal, State, local, and Tribal law enforcement agencies describing the best practices for the collection, reporting, and analysis of data and information on missing persons and unidentified human remains. Such best practices shall—</text>
<paragraph id="H267F3339736C485DAD6D4858E44567CC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide an overview of the NCIC database and NamUs databases;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81EC75F223DF4F0FB92C3E492ED958FD"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describe how local law enforcement agencies, and offices of forensic medicine service providers should access and use the NCIC database and NamUs databases;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H705C3DCA44E14DFD8300DC7D41A645E6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>describe the appropriate and inappropriate uses of the NCIC database and NamUs databases; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA9DBA88C767B448FBCFBC2764E038531"><enum>(4)</enum><text>describe the standards and protocols for the collection, reporting, and analysis of data and information on missing persons and unidentified human remains.</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H7B4320A45E9C4284AE718217F261DC37"><enum>5.</enum><header>Report to congress</header>
<subsection id="H6F3DAE6CA0D84584BA4371C484D41BEF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act and biennially thereafter, the Attorney General shall submit to the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives and the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate a report describing the status of the NCIC database and NamUs databases.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H45C40DF594E14219B5FF948521AC925C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The report required by subsection (a) shall describe, to the extent available, information on the process of information sharing between the NCIC database and NamUs databases.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H110A79C31CA54626AFA17809CED69AE4"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H5C123B34C5654FA3BE47EB1F6A697E0B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authorized agency</header><text>The term <term>authorized agency</term> means a Government agency with an originating agency identification (ORI) number and that is a criminal justice agency, as defined in section 20.3 of title 28, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H75B507351F17427784DAE0CF8EE501C2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>FBI</header><text>The term <term>FBI</term> means the Federal Bureau of Investigation.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7FB2EDAE7D844B07A923757617FDD172"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Forensic medicine service provider</header><text>The term <term>forensic medicine service provider</term> means a State or unit of local government forensic medicine service provider having not fewer than 1 part-time or full-time employed forensic pathologist, or forensic pathologist under contract, who conducts medicolegal death investigations, including examinations of human remains, and who provides reports or opinion testimony with respect to such activity in courts of law within the United States. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HC3789CA8EEBA4E67A2FA1152C3359854"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Forensic science service provider</header><text>The term <term>forensic science service provider</term> means a State or unit of local government agency having not fewer than 1 full-time analyst who examines physical evidence in criminal or investigative matters and provides reports or opinion testimony with respect to such evidence in courts in the United States. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1CF5C7789F0740E9A09FBD4800846460"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Nam<enum-in-header>U</enum-in-header>s databases</header><text>The term <term>NamUs databases</term> means the National Missing and Unidentified Persons System Missing Persons database and National Missing and Unidentified Persons System Unidentified Decedents database maintained by the National Institute of Justice of the Department of Justice, which serves as a clearinghouse and resource center for missing, unidentified, and unclaimed person cases.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H56D226310EBB4C3DA28FC6B2CC4FC05F"><enum>(6)</enum><header>NCIC database</header><text>The term <term>NCIC database</term> means the National Crime Information Center Missing Person File and National Crime Information Center Unidentified Person File of the National Crime Information Center database of the FBI, established pursuant to section 534 of title 28, United States Code.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0DD6504F52B64BFC8A251B582F67AEF8"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualifying law enforcement agency defined</header><text>The term <term>qualifying law enforcement agency</term> means a State, local, or Tribal law enforcement agency. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H81171054F14C4DC4AD424531D5FE4C92"><enum>(8)</enum><header>State</header><text>The term <term>State</term> means any State of the United States, the District of Columbia, the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, Guam, and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></paragraph></section> </legis-body> </bill> 

