<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5DC573BC8C4F40878D5E7139509F504E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7508 IH: Improving Specialty Care for Women Veterans Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7508</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220414">April 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001111">Mr. Crist</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Secretary of Veterans Affairs to carry out a program for the recruitment, retention, and training of providers of specialty care for women veterans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3CC188CF48934F4DA56A9C9DCE3D8691" style="OLC"><section id="HD248BA76FDC54A23BF8058D9FE9D5428" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Improving Specialty Care for Women Veterans Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HF6C691AB9AE44512A0DCA6DA3CECDC15"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority for Department of Veterans Affairs program on recruitment, retention, and training of specialty care providers for women veterans</header><subsection id="H784415E04374425A967FAB70EA98F18D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Veterans Affairs may carry out a program, including a pilot program, for the recruitment, retention, and training of providers of specialty care for former members of the Armed Forces who are women.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5A68EC7E96294EB7BDC255B420D93ACC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Participants</header><text>Participation in a program under subsection (a) shall be available to the following:</text><paragraph id="HC66054B07C7E43858A3657267CD0A5C0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Individuals serving in a medical internship or residency program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A38C62D1DB74359BE8A7C04A91F90F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nurses and physicians who are covered providers.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0CEC54D221F04160B40260B0559544D6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Specialty care areas; incentives for recruitment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out a program under subsection (a), the Secretary may—</text><paragraph id="H842E97F5E0A047A58A890862041B1DE8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>target for recruitment individuals with expertise in such specialty care areas as the Secretary may determine appropriate for purposes of the program; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD1DAD5C12BA244C1BCC886B73BDC571C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">offer to individuals targeted for recruitment under the program such incentives as the Secretary determines appropriate to facilitate the recruitment and retention of such individuals, including monetary incentives and incentives relating to the reduction of education debt under the Education Debt Reduction program authorized under section 7681 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6DEB6695D17541589F4E493589BCBDE9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Training and support for providers</header><paragraph id="HD4A0CEC28D2049978665DE8116D3905E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Training and support</header><text>In carrying out a program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall furnish to each individual recruited under the program such training and support as the Secretary determines necessary with respect to the unique needs of women veterans, including with respect to mental and behavioral health conditions relating to the service of women veterans in the Armed Forces.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H349CF8B8342C469F952256C1F9558AD3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contracts with non-Department entities</header><text>The Secretary may only enter into a contract with a non-Department entity for such entity to provide training or support under paragraph (1) if, not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary enters into the contract, the Secretary submits to the Committees on Veterans Affairs of the House of Representatives and the Senate a notification regarding the contract.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7AB91A2FF5994B8AB1349014C37728D9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Relationship to appointment scheduling</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H7AFB961FA82743A28C26B3610BDC9CB1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make available to veterans enrolled in the patient enrollment system of the Department under section 1705 of title 38, United States Code, information indicating whether a covered provider has participated in a program under subsection (a); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H42DEA7E1683E48D593AF9A25EE13B401"><enum>(2)</enum><text>take such steps as may be necessary to improve the timeliness of appointments scheduled by such veterans with covered providers who have so participated, including by waiving requirements of the Department relating to wait times for such appointments.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3B5164A03FC5455AA18E593439E51F9F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HEBC18F771A504F4D8DDADE71D7B2E3FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>covered provider</quote> means a health care provider—</text><subparagraph id="H516AE06181EB498B9FEE28AB7E396D89"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is an employee of the Department of Veterans Affairs; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A02106D04464D39918EA00C2D00AE9B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who provides medical care or services to veterans under the Veterans Community Care program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF399337BA3B74A03A170820E2147D407"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>Veterans Community Care program</quote> means the program of the Department of Veterans Affairs under section 1703 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

