<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1023D8C0CCD745DEAAA735465546B888" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8737 IH: End Subsidies for Fossil Fuel Advertising Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8737</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220819">August 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to deny deductions for marketing related to the extraction, distribution, or consumption of fossil fuels.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB6D456506A924B1C9BD4656C6B208418" style="OLC"><section id="H4965CDD53342488EAF871DAFF0E83B4D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>End Subsidies for Fossil Fuel Advertising Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H1D1DEBB2C6E74EDC99F473AD9E2827E0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Denial of deduction for marketing related to extraction, distribution, or consumption of fossil fuels</header><subsection id="HD1BD980C464A49948FAA5E13D3FA3AC9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part IX of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBCF20FB849C54F23A78EE047352620F2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H63E3229C4E0446E6B4DB83230A621587"><enum>280I.</enum><header>Marketing related to extraction, distribution, or consumption of fossil fuels</header><subsection id="H129C1678705E4B64BD670DC0390C6F91"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of any covered person, no deduction shall be allowed under this chapter with respect to any amount paid or incurred for any of the following if such amount is so paid or incurred for purposes of promoting extraction, exploration, or consumption of fossil fuels or for the purposes of promoting the covered person or a trade or business of the covered person (or any activity described in subsection (b) with respect to any fossil fuel):</text><paragraph id="HA55196B526F742248D80BA159AB2EA18"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Marketing expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E44C475C6984F47BBFCC8853F3AA936"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Travel expenses (including meals and lodging).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6B913CFC90A4542B926C774040B3BD9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Goods or services of a type generally considered to constitute entertainment, amusement, or recreation, or the use of a facility in connection with providing such goods and services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFBBBAF7AAB754AF591D49C832EC0A85C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Gifts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63BB47F8EEFC4CDDB1B807529546C9BF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Other promotion expenses.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA31E60F8B97A4E81B4E9A786D620437B"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any other development, production or placement (including any form of transmission, broadcast, publication, display, or distribution) of any communication to the general public (or portions thereof) which is intended to promote the covered person or a trade or business of the covered person (or any service, facility, or product provided pursuant to such trade or business). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H568D337808E841D7AE45D99ED9E7ECD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered person</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>covered person</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H577402D1C1474275B8C6569FA3692B93"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any person involved in the manufacturing, production, extraction, refining, transportation, distribution, or marketing of any fossil fuel, including any person involved in—</text><subparagraph id="H32352CE2B9A24E0995C37884BB2C5DF6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>providing support activities for the production or extraction of fossil fuels, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBC9CCA2D10747828E811AC9A1EB5E1F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the sale (whether wholesale or retail) of fossil fuels, and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4707448A985546CF8F5BA86EDFE9408A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any person involved in electric power generation, transmission, or distribution (with respect to electricity generated from any fossil fuel).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B6808EC7BBB426CA559962C09B3EA6F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Marketing</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <quote>marketing</quote> means any advertising or marketing technique, including—</text><paragraph id="H59D061BE0907403FA00B0AA8B011E574"><enum>(1)</enum><text>any sponsorship, endorsement, or product placement,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA07A53ED69B0440CA6EB3B6CF0F4E653"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any promotional items or loyalty programs,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3FF9EDDD466C4844B94937CF6010963E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any licensing, cobranding, or cross-promotions,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51C6FA8F140245C586117B022AE66190"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in-school advertising including corporate-branded materials, corporate incentive programs, fundraisers, signs, scoreboards, posters, in-school TV and radio, corporate sponsorships, curriculum development, sponsored educational materials, and market research activities, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD943A1139CFA44BA87F9C9FE9770F796"><enum>(5)</enum><text>sponsorship of events, competitions, conferences, and contests.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6240CE53C074B179A44A822667F658D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fossil fuel</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <quote>fossil fuel</quote> means coal, petroleum, natural gas, natural gas liquids, or any derivative or byproduct of coal, petroleum, natural gas, or natural gas liquids that can be used for energy or energy applications.</text></subsection><subsection id="H68A196CE23924B47A1021ACFA421829D"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Derivative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term ‘derivative’ means gasoline, diesel fuel, jet fuel, home heating oil, natural gas, blue hydrogen, or any other product derived from the refining or production of fossil fuels for the purposes of energy production or support for energy production or energy generation.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2F3F55367FD0436BA753EDC47E80EB2B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this section, the Secretary, after consultation with the Chair of the Federal Trade Commission, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, the Secretary of Energy, and the Secretary of the Interior, shall issue such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section. </text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7B4ECD46061245E4B1F87DE0D987ADCB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections for part IX of subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H19C0F8ADBAAE47ADBBDF4FA1610C25FB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="HBCF20FB849C54F23A78EE047352620F2" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H63E3229C4E0446E6B4DB83230A621587" level="section">Sec. 280I. Marketing related to extraction, distribution, or consumption of fossil fuels.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC2906294E82244DABDED8BF5C25B3726"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to taxable years beginning after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

