<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HB47A1FCFBA7D49B199134132005DE650" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7865 IH: Flood Insurance for Farmers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-24</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7865</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220524">May 24, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000559">Mr. Garamendi</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="L000578">Mr. LaMalfa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase the availability of flood insurance for agricultural structures, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H3F24C4D463564E63ADB15BE033B2E2EF" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H769FA1BCE32F491CAF46A77829F173A4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Flood Insurance for Farmers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text> </section> <section id="H133CB82175554AF6BC27D7CF8BDCC65F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Agricultural structures in special flood hazard zones</header> <subsection id="HDC47B4A8A1C640EBA5C861B9E3DA195A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements for State and local land use controls</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 1315 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4022">42 U.S.C. 4022(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1675E74F1D714D77B5E2076846F52A3C" style="OLC"> 
<paragraph id="H5F81E3DE67A1428CB8311DCF853486F7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Allowable local variances for certain agricultural structures</header> 
<subparagraph id="HC42A8C8BFA5249B392AD6EF5E88A6D46"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act—</text> <clause id="HD0428FCE270D43DEBDE359C12D2BDFA4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the land use and control measures adopted pursuant to paragraph (1) may not, for purposes of such paragraph, be considered to be inadequate or inconsistent with the comprehensive criteria for land management and use under section 1361 because such measures provide that, in the case of any agricultural structure that is located in an area having special flood hazards, a variance from compliance with the requirements to elevate or floodproof such a structure and meeting the requirements of subparagraph (B) may be granted; and</text> </clause> 
<clause id="H1A477070A1FA4D25820F761B3AA5EC41"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Administrator may not suspend a community from participation in the national flood insurance program, or place such a community on probation under such program, because such land use and control measures provide for such a variance.</text> </clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">This subparagraph shall not limit the ability of the Administrator to take enforcement action against a community that does not adopt adequate variance criteria or establish proper enforcement mechanisms.</continuation-text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC18D3BCB90E643EAA567A28F9C3E286F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Variance; considerations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirements of this subparagraph with respect to a variance are as follows:</text> 
<clause id="H98F31218059940DDAD9AB5AFB74B8FB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The variance is granted by an official from a duly constituted State or local zoning authority, or other authorized public body responsible for regulating land development or occupancy in flood-prone areas.</text> </clause> <clause id="H2D601CB7FD2B428DA738F79D544AD7C7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of new construction, such official has determined—</text> 
<subclause id="H66E4683804A747E5BC0D2D8AD3DBE081"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that neither floodproofing nor elevation of the new structure to the base flood elevation is practicable; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="HE5D2318D632141CA8993D06820895038"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that the structure is not located in—</text> 
<item id="H8DDCD4FDAC6D40D1A8C76B761075F4AB"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>a designated regulatory floodway;</text> </item> <item id="H1C8BF455075F436DB3162161F1574F59"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>an area riverward of a levee or other flood control structure; or</text> </item> 
<item id="H961B26A71687434A9B1E49EFB66F6475"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>an area subject to high velocity wave action or seaward of flood control structures.</text> </item></subclause></clause> <clause id="H779D26189C244129ACC44519A4197652"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of existing structures—</text> 
<subclause id="HD53B49FCD8DC4FA29A0F72991ACF86F4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if such structure is substantially damaged or in need of substantial repairs or improvements, such official has determined that neither floodproofing nor elevation to the base flood elevation is practicable; and</text> </subclause> <subclause id="H04A885C9F96E4C0EAF0A930B6675B4A4"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such structure is located within a designated regulatory flood­way, such official has determined that the repair or improvement does not result in any increase in base flood levels during the base flood discharge.</text> </subclause></clause> 
<clause id="HD8191E68DA5D41B68ADC83BCF1A7DFCA"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such official has determined that the variance will not result in increased flood heights, additional threats to public safety, extraordinary public expense, create nuisances, cause fraud on or victimization of the public, or conflict with existing local laws or ordinances.</text> </clause> <clause id="H7799034E20A14D6B8757B644AAD3CECA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Not more than one claim payment exceeding $1,000 has been made for the structure under flood insurance coverage under this title within any period of 10 consecutive years at any time prior to the granting of the variance.</text> </clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HE34E88001F824061809D0F8F27B29199"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the following definitions shall apply:</text> <clause id="H2F2742D7E9E64273A75FF01A23C3E117"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Agricultural structure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>agricultural structure</term> has the meaning given such term in paragraph (2)(D), except that such term includes not more than one single-family dwelling that, as of the date of enactment of this paragraph, is located on the same property as the agricultural operation, but only if such dwelling is occupied by the owner or operator of the operation.</text> </clause> 
<clause id="HE201BBFF81A1464EB5957D4C5A46EC47"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Floodproofing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>floodproofing</term> means, with respect to a structure, any combination of structural and non-structural additions, changes, or adjustments to the structure, including attendant utilities and equipment, that reduce or eliminate potential flood damage to real estate or improved real property, water and sanitary facilities, structures, or their contents.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection> <subsection id="HCAECAE4D499B401D83C571F6F7D568C4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Premium rates</header><text>Section 1308 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4015">42 U.S.C. 4015</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text> 
<quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB27A314D675545A3BB8820E552B58EDE" style="OLC"> 
<subsection id="HDBCCD78AD08346E887ECE58210A90B59"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Premium rates for certain agricultural structures with variances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, the chargeable premium rate for coverage under this title for any structure provided a variance pursuant to section 1315(a)(3) shall be the same as the rate that otherwise would apply to such structure if the structure had been dry floodproofed or a comparable actuarial rate based upon the risk associated with structures within the applicable AL-E zone established under section 1360(l).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block> </subsection></section> <section id="H88BB53CD213949EDBAD571E6B7DDA66F" display-inline="no-display-inline" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Optional coverage for umbrella policies</header> <subsection id="HFF01294F864C4AD3B3EE67EFAA41C401"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subsection (b) of section 1306 of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/4013">42 U.S.C. 4013(b)</external-xref>), is amended—</text> 
<paragraph id="H8C4865E020AF4E3EB19CE18DBEA4AECA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text> </paragraph> <paragraph id="HC97473AC933B47F3A5593E1DB22C1749"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text> </paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE77773A9B7244E4DA88B9692B947D1C5"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text> <quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2638E02FA71343068176361CEEF345D5" style="OLC"> <paragraph id="HE232784F29D246AE8BAEB1F26B1DF6D4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Administrator may provide that, in the case of any commercial property or other residential property, including multifamily rental property and agricultural property, one umbrella policy be made available to every insured upon renewal and every applicant with multiple structures on the same property, except that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H7AEC67DDC0B54B58B20F37DE32C79992"><enum>(A)</enum><text>purchase of such coverage shall be at the option of the insured; and</text> </subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H610C4FBD172A411A9713BFE9E4955DD0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any such coverage shall be made available only at chargeable rates that are not less than the estimated premium rates for such coverage determined in accordance with section 1307(a)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H765881DAB0AE4B7FBB88258ED935934F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the expiration of the 5-year period beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act, the Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall submit to the Congress a report evaluating the implementation of section 1306(b)(6) of the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968, as added by the amendments made by subsection (a) of this section. </text> </subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

