<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9FA8F529FF33495D8F7F4FD54B84622B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7882 IH: DOD Clean Energy Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-27</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7882</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220527">May 27, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001196">Mr. Moulton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000299">Ms. Escobar</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to codify certain clean energy targets of the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC8BD5544D8654F74932509EF031F1420" style="OLC"><section id="H90CE656987754E76840F408F7955DD7A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Depend on Domestic Clean Energy Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote>DOD Clean Energy Act</quote>.</text></section><section id="H6FA00E5F677440F88E67F5289A9EF0AA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HF3C2F267118746C6880F15ABF697AF87"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of Defense, the agency charged with protecting the national security of the United States, observed as early as 1990 that climate change threatens our military readiness.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5BAB709EC4D14A5189E6DFB5B0BF4172"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As of 2019, the Department of Defense is the single largest consumer of energy in the United States, and the single largest institutional consumer of petroleum in the world. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFE1E80149E3A4E7C81860561F9BB6E94"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since 2001, the Department of Defense has consistently consumed between 77 and 80 percent of all energy consumption of the United States Government. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE74C4324792472790E1191CDF7C29DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>As climate change brings more extreme weather, water and soil stress, sea-level rise, ocean acidification, glacial melt, and pollution, greater global tensions over food and water insecurity, resource scarcity, living patterns, and climate-related migration will emerge.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5D007760D55C4F5B8610753B0D608AF2"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that any unobligated amounts for the Energy Resilience and Conservation Investment Program of the Department of Defense at the end of fiscal year 2022 should remain available for obligation by the Department after such fiscal year for deserving projects so that the Department is able to appropriately vet those projects while increasing staffing.</text></section><section id="H7EE1A5E414DD42C7B5FA3F41C08FE966"><enum>4.</enum><header>Codification of certain Department of Defense clean energy targets</header><subsection id="HC96F07F8E5384556BA2C59834B7B133C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Codification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 2911(g) of title 10, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA578A65F84FB4FCF901C7E76A093C270"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraph (3) as paragraph (4); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FBBB5689FD34006BFD55B4E868311B4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraphs (1) and (2) and inserting the following new paragraphs (1) through (3):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HB315A1DB7E8E4FF29D1FB96F0A701739" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6C1E3E77465E498C9A8D188AB31636E5" indent="up1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It shall be the target of the Department of Defense, with respect to the activities, personnel, resources, and facilities of the Department located within the United States—</text><subparagraph id="HED84931A1C7F4FD9B1702758E6377BF5"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to achieve at least 40 percent carbon pollution-free electricity on a net annual basis by 2024 within all such facilities of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5F91B0405ED04108BB37DD1C63FC7444"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to achieve 100 percent carbon pollution-free electricity on a net annual basis by 2030 within all such facilities of the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7B5C4E6F660491FA3B690752205192C"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce emissions from installation procurement by at least 20 percent by 2024 and to achieve net-zero emissions from installation procurement by 2050;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9AD185A1C6DB427B81332DE59B7B860C"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to reduce emissions from buildings on Department installations by 50 percent by 2032 and to achieve net-zero emissions from buildings on installations by 2045;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABC4D162DA6C44E1A5E0D2324D522485"><enum>(E)</enum><text>to reduce emissions from Department operations by 65 percent by 2030 and support the achievement of net-zero emissions from Department operations by 2050; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BB3A2277D8B4D7F8008B5FCD611CF9E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to achieve 100 percent zero-emission vehicle acquisitions for nontactical vehicles by 2035, including 100 percent zero-emission light-duty vehicle acquisitions by 2027, and to work towards 100 percent zero-emission tactical vehicle acquisitions by 2045. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H65F943D35A1044A7A30FF4387140D7A3" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may issue an exemption to the targets under paragraph (1) with respect to an activity of an agency, and any related personnel, resources, and facilities if the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H9FC6B04386864C6BAC2EC429798309F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>determines that the exemption is in the national security interests of the United States; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E90939D0CAE4450AF4B4E58AE0B9E00"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submits to the congressional defense committees notice in writing of the exemption within 30 days of issuing the exemption.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H99DEE0693ABC4B19A43413968DC0DDB7" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H21AE67EDDF7C432788B00CE48B0C42F8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees an annual report on the progress the Department of Defense has made towards achieving the targets under paragraph (1). Each such report shall cover activities to achieve such targets conducted during the year preceding the date of the submittal of the report and shall include—</text><clause id="H53F3818FC9444C0DBF8525F11DA6FC06" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an identification of outstanding funding and staffing resources need to implement such activities;</text></clause><clause id="H744DEDC029784651BC45BCD95A3AC028" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a description of any planned activities the Secretary intends to carry out in order to meet such targets, including how the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the military departments, and Defense agencies plan to collaborate to implement such activities; and</text></clause><clause id="H837C46C2D386415C8FC52817F5B38BC0" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan to increase production of renewable energy on Department of Defense installations and pursue any energy reduction or conservation efforts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D7B88D2E9C54ABC8E4E5B3E7A006670" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Each report under subparagraph (A) shall be made publicly available on an appropriate website of the Department of Defense.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H77CC1DC6A38848F7A764BF9C4D427CF2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H593FBA1394734A5EBFC27B6DB832AAD2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H6ED19F878DB2453DABAD1A7EFCFCD356" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense shall delegate the responsibility for carrying out this subsection to the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H390498A3675F4CF7A1EE7FF016A38CD0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Non-Domestic application of targets</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may apply, in whole or in part, the targets set forth in section 2911(g)(1) of title 10, United States Code, as amended by subsection (a), with respect to the activities, personnel, resources, and facilities of the Department of Defense located outside of the United States if the Secretary determines such application to be in the interest of the United States.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC28EB0AC53FB418A89AF72D4C1DF0658" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Direct hire authority for positions supporting Department of Defense energy independence and climate resilience efforts</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/81">Chapter 81</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HE7C94AC141BE41BAAB7AD59A852EF0D1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H4FBE40439CD24E088B78EC8080525B88" commented="no"><enum>1599j.</enum><header>Direct hire authority for positions supporting Department of Defense energy independence and climate resilience efforts</header><subsection id="H99F9DD259D8A4A2FAEF8EF955198947C" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text>The Secretary of Defense may appoint in the Department of Defense, without regard to the provisions of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/33">chapter 33</external-xref> of title 5, other than sections 3303 and 3328 of such title, qualified candidates to positions described in subsection (b) who possess skills and experience the Secretary determines are necessary to support the sustainability efforts of the Department of Defense.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD795F51351F64417BE811529F2E40032" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Positions</header><text>The positions described in this subsection are all positions involved in supporting the energy independence and climate resilience efforts of the Department, including the following:</text><paragraph id="HDFB683FC65CB47C689C1711BCAAD9D03" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any position under the Assistant Secretary of Defense for Energy, Installations, and Environment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5A1F46FCE4D549E0AFD853D750DDB04E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Any position that supports the remediation or response efforts of the Department with respect to perfluoralkyl substances and polyfluoroalkyl substances.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H887CF612A49A4B1197271394713BB438" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Any position that supports the environmental stewardship programs of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2CA55A21CC884605B2D29308C1B659F6" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Any position that supports the efforts of the Department to meet the energy resilience and security goals outlined in—</text><subparagraph id="HAD045DAB3F2F4E729F9253FA50631435" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 203 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15852">42 U.S.C. 15852</external-xref>);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08648FFA23534E64B9D16F6697EEE42D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17001">42 U.S.C. 17001 et seq.</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C6ABF9D9D84698B0C2A0062C9B9DBB" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>section 2911(g) of this title.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2A8F12C79464A9A9CEBF30A4DDD8F88" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Any position that supports the Chief Sustainability Officer of the Department.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF4DEAFEC872F4D13902008885C1E8C79" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Any other position the Secretary determines is essential to advancing the energy independence and climate resilience efforts of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HB22EC830B3F84B9E8841DBF13908F923"><enum>6.</enum><header>Investment in and development of energy efficient technology by Department of Defense</header><subsection id="H6E2DB3AA8C1A4C8DB325B38B0AF7E41E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authorities of Department relating to climate and energy resilience</header><paragraph id="HED7F702616F544978CB471A68A716DE9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Charging and refueling stations for alternative fuel vehicles</header><subparagraph id="H4EB55994132D4F199B1A14B1B174D64D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may carry out the development of charging or refueling stations for alternative fuel vehicles on installations of the Department of Defense under the authorities, and using the funding methods, specified in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA32D5754E2D84A2EAC7CFB551B5DA51F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorities specified</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authorities and funding methods specified in this paragraph are the following:</text><clause id="HD7809CEF5FD64B3D8EA82FFF942311D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Sections 2805 and 2912 of title 10, United States Code.</text></clause><clause id="HB55C5F32CF214D01AF2F2627078F1D8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The authority under section 2913(d) of such title, to enter into agreements with utilities for the purpose of providing or operating such charging or refueling stations.</text></clause><clause id="H7E8FBD901915433480EAF4329187D93B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The authority under section 2914 of such title (known as the Energy Resilience and Conservation Investment Program).</text></clause><clause id="H1832C0249826483F97559C52C29654B6"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Energy savings performance contracts.</text></clause><clause id="H2A3C89441A5A4F05A5EDEDF45BEF7B18"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Utility energy services contracts.</text></clause><clause id="HDB41787F61C740EF99ABBAC74D88D4F3"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Other funding mechanisms financed by non-Department entities for the deployment of alternative fuel vehicles and related charging or refueling infrastructure.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3A195E27E5C8422C865FE6A1737FF8FA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renewable energy utilities for power management at installations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in carrying out the Energy Resilience and Conservation Investment Program, may enter into public-private partnerships with nongovernmental entities determined appropriate by the Secretary under such Program for the purpose of developing renewable energy utilities for power management at installations of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2A11A9D005AA41C9B412082C849B81B4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Review of investment by Department in alternatively fueled vehicles</header><paragraph id="HAF44EC6CC29543D09DC1C132522365F2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Defense, acting through the Director of Cost Assessment and Program Evaluation, shall conduct a strategic review of the investment by the Department of Defense in alternative fuel vehicles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FFC435F6C6470CB2CC6E6E09E8414F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The review under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="HBF36321E42F94B008D78AE1F6E60B196"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An assessment of funding levels for investment by the Department in alternative fuel vehicles and associated trends for such investment across programs and Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8653CA7919746F08320C7E22AD931F5"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An assessment of any duplication of efforts relating to such investment across programs and Armed Forces.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H924FC8487AF34CECA8436325E059BD9D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An assessment of the long-term availability to the Department of internal combustion engines and spare parts for such engines.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD198BDF9DE304AB0A4A8F3161026258E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An assessment of the relative tactical benefits and limitations of each type of vehicle propulsion (such as speed, acceleration, noise production, time to refuel or recharge, range, and operational duration), across the various types of military missions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H071884E7A427470FA272D3D46FCC068B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>An assessment of the relative tactical benefits and limitations of each type of vehicle propulsion with respect to the provision of support to other tactical systems requiring electricity.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC4589DCEF598433EB131F7F46BB5042A"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of how the propulsion systems of electrical and other alternative fuel vehicles may be fueled on the battlefield and of what investments may be necessary to maintain such a fueling system.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H80ACA0711B1B486AA323CDB8ABE6AAC5"><enum>(G)</enum><text>A comparison of the relative risk to Department personnel and to the supply chain between different fuel types, to determine the tradeoffs associated with the adoption of any given fuel type.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFF4460C082D84694ACB86B09D2F45312"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A projected timeline of when a potential conversion to the use of alternative fuel vehicles as tactical vehicles could reasonably occur without causing a significant effect on the readiness of the Armed Forces, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D038040DA2A4500BE2997C43DED3A34"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The projected costs of converting (or replacing) and sustaining alternative fuel vehicles as tactical vehicles, to include training, in total and for the two-year period following the date of the review.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H45F7966350A4495C96816F8F417E372C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>An assessment of any national security implications relating to the use and effects on the supply chain of alternative fuel vehicles and the source materials of such vehicles.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5651C0C014D644358B744CA364610327"><enum>(K)</enum><text>Recommendations for further coordination of efforts of the Department and any legislative or organizational changes that may improve the coordination or alignment of investment by the Department in the operationalization of alternative energy sources.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECE87CE8DC644D308460EB39A5D8879D"><enum>(L)</enum><text>Such other elements as the Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6540903EC7C6410280E7DA67B8414E27"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the review under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29390A9FD77342BAAA738F68A71C2770" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorizations of appropriations</header><paragraph id="HE11484498C6D4241B49964C9543ADFCA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Defense Innovation Unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $8,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, for the purpose of carrying out activities under the energy division of the Defense Innovation Unit to leverage advancements in energy and materials technology, enhance capabilities, and strengthen energy resilience across military installation and distributed operations, including with respect to alternative fuel vehicles and the fuel efficiency of vehicles.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA932444DE09467383B92670CD81D8EA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sustainable Technology Evaluation and Demonstration program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $5,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, for the purpose of carrying out activities under the Sustainable Technology Evaluation and Demonstration program of the Department for the evaluation and demonstration of, and the transition to, sustainable technologies that reduce military installation and operational energy consumption.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60B7C975DD4E4A56BCA766EB67BC0793" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Strategic Environmental Research and Development Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Department of Defense $18,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, for the purpose of carrying out activities under the Installation Energy and Water program, or any successor program, of the Strategic Environmental Research and Development program of the Department. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA83B2F2B877C47369B353DC98FD579FC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA95A5EA47BCB4A0ABD96E5E3F908C84F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>alternative fuel vehicle</quote> includes a vehicle that uses—</text><subparagraph id="H465748C4B0F54C54A067368ACB38D052"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a fuel or power source described in the first sentence of section 241(2) of the Clean Air Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/7581">42 U.S.C. 7581(2)</external-xref>); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H601A02CAC24641AFAF28D84ACEC64A66"><enum>(B)</enum><text>propane.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5E9AA2C405344C9847B889B0BE0E8BE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>energy savings performance contract</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 804(3) of the National Energy Conservation Policy Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/8287c">42 U.S.C. 8287c(3)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H849EF43F39B045C8BD34B048C5D183B5"><enum>7.</enum><header>Independent study on scope 3 emissions resulting from certain Department of Defense activities</header><subsection id="H498D27531D484D4B871B6CA807FE5C48"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Independent study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall seek to enter into a contract with a federally funded research and development center to conduct a study on the scope 3 emissions resulting from certain activities of the Department of Defense, including such activities carried out under contracts or other agreements, in accordance with the guidance of the Environmental Protection Agency titled <quote>Scope 3 Inventory Guidance</quote> (relating to scope 3 emissions), or any successor guidance.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDFC4CC3C8FDD429EAF40B0B4B3113DE4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The study referred to in subsection (a) shall include a comprehensive review and assessment of the following:</text><paragraph id="H5823A8DC00E6489381F2DDEFE8683112"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any contracts or other agreements relating to manufacturing that the Secretary of Defense has entered into. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01B2022051714A05804EFA68E90A85CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The extent to which, in performing work under such contracts or other agreements, contractors and other partners track greenhouse gas emissions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18673882212F4687B2E062BC21E66F32"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The known greenhouse gas emissions that occur within the supply chain of the Department.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C3581417D81460981254AA5A5180546"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><paragraph id="HBC24690677674738A655D955BE844DC4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission to Secretary</header><text>The terms of the contract under subsection (a) shall include a requirement that the federally funded research and development center that conducts the study under the contract to submit to the Secretary of Defense a report on the results of the study, which shall include an identification of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H21A870D986144C3BA13124C1F8E0EB2E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Considerations and recommendations for the reduction of greenhouse gas emissions of contractors and other partners performing work under contracts or other agreements with the Department. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E8C79127047403CAED2F666266BBCC1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any existing alternatives that produce lower greenhouse gas emissions while still aligning with the national security interests of the United States and the priorities set forth in the national defense strategy.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4D5867EBCA534F8CA6FBEAEA7F2FDD12"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Any legislative recommendations to—</text><clause id="H0547B03DED844FDCAFDA30DF62E71D65"><enum>(i)</enum><text>support and facilitate implementation of the national defense strategy with respect to climate- and environmental-related goals; or</text></clause><clause id="H20C263B8D19D46898A050A0CC8FC5D78"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>reduce greenhouse gas emissions through modernization of the supply chain of the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D0734A2ED8F4AB68CEC702D6C980320"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Upon receiving the report on the results of the study under paragraph (1), the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the congressional defense committees an unedited copy of such report, together with the written perspectives of the Secretary of Defense and the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff with respect to the results.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8AF07947CA4C4DFAB0C60F7238228A8C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form</header><text>The report submitted under paragraph (2) shall be submitted in unclassified form, but may include a classified annex.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8B9876DBCC8F4AA08C7227964478EA7E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="HAE4D62D8A2764C2A80DDE095DEE39755"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>national defense strategy</quote> means the review of the defense programs and policies of the United States that is carried out every four years under section 113(g) of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3CF5BA66D5474686994385D8470E2031" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>scope 3 emissions</quote> means emissions that result from activities of a Federal department or agency but are generated from sources that are neither owned nor controlled by the Federal department or agency.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

