<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H3926DF7A268849778EE3D14A8F18DB2D" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2773 EH: Recovering America’s Wildlife Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress>117th CONGRESS</congress> <session>2d Session</session> 
<legis-num>H. R. 2773</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act to make supplemental funds available for management of fish and wildlife species of greatest conservation need as determined by State fish and wildlife agencies, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HE12DC55242E94A4A977724B033E0F578" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H8EC9314CC9624046A1E50F26E5567F96"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Recovering America’s Wildlife Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HEC0251B5700B44A686815D900C85A5F1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Statement of purpose</header> <subsection id="HCB38F37CE6344805908C1438093189B8"><enum></enum><text>The purpose of this Act is to extend financial and technical assistance to States, territories, the District of Columbia, and Indian Tribes, including under the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669">16 U.S.C. 669 et seq.</external-xref>), for the purpose of avoiding the need to list species, or recovering species currently listed as a threatened species or an endangered species, under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) or under State law.</text></subsection></section>
<title id="H4691751EF3624F569FAA5452191AC47F"><enum>I</enum><header>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration</header>
<section id="H964F5FCCBC1440A084A1BCEEDF2ACFAA"><enum>101.</enum><header>Wildlife conservation and restoration subaccount</header>
<subsection id="H52F67C61741044B88E54DF95BE61ED32"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 3 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669b">16 U.S.C. 669b</external-xref>) is amended in subsection (c)—</text> <paragraph id="H2A838F8F71B84AF891211379683B67D3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (9) and (10); and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H891ED82FAC4044F2995A638BA7585F79"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE3FFF7E5B71F47D79108D13FCAAEC02F"> <paragraph id="H323A210EB7CA4C0A94757F40E6E18770"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment of subaccount</header> <subparagraph id="H08869476A834402AB4EC216545A50B5A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the fund a subaccount to be known as the <quote>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Subaccount</quote> (referred to in this section as the <quote>Subaccount</quote>).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HCD89B3540FF9457A8E8A09AD0ED5F9DC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts in the Subaccount shall be available without further appropriation, for each fiscal year, for apportionment in accordance with this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF79208A48CB4B568B530E18A0730875"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Deposits into Subaccount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the general fund of the Treasury to the Subaccount—</text>
<clause id="H2B54D06C7E3E407AAFE03DF8600D4AF8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2023, $850,000,000;</text></clause> <clause id="H10F1AD0AC828476ABE6868D26744999E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2024, $1,100,000,000;</text></clause>
<clause id="H04393CA3EB594BA98119377417804D76"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2025, $1,200,000,000; and</text></clause> <clause id="H2F6F01992B174AC4ACD7C1CA96D2E4B4"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>for fiscal year 2026 and each fiscal year thereafter, $1,300,000,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8FBD2FBF74094064A08CB4ADB88A1796"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Supplement not supplant</header><text>Amounts transferred to the Subaccount shall supplement, but not replace, existing funds available to the States from—</text> <subparagraph id="H36A054265D394806B6DA1E5BC8D6B303"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the funds distributed pursuant to the Dingell-Johnson Sport Fish Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/777">16 U.S.C. 777 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE938C8933961471E91B0C12856495027"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the fund.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6A33331A549A43CBA4F62A7586B0F4C4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Innovation grants</header> <subparagraph id="HC6516B1B12A446E0B25DE9F37C2B8A92"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall distribute 10 percent of funds apportioned from the Subaccount through a competitive grant program to State fish and wildlife departments, the District of Columbia fish and wildlife department, fish and wildlife departments of territories, nonprofit organizations, or to regional associations of fish and wildlife departments (or any group composed of more than 1 such entity).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8F646CFD459F4433A4772656F9598B6A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>Such grants shall be provided for the purpose of catalyzing innovation of techniques, tools, strategies, or collaborative partnerships that accelerate, expand, or replicate effective and measurable recovery efforts for species of greatest conservation need and species listed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) and the habitats of such species.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B50D981352A401483FA5F5CFECBDAA1"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Review committee</header><text>The Secretary shall appoint a review committee comprised of—</text>
<clause id="H3B8B1E00AC014161BB1F55171FD1DE14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a State Director from each regional association of State fish and wildlife departments;</text></clause> <clause id="H80508161C07B44B1B53FA2E4725A803D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the head of a department responsible for fish and wildlife management in a territory;</text></clause>
<clause id="H3935C76AB46C481895E2F10D585FF003"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one delegate from the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, for the purpose of providing technical assistance; and</text></clause> <clause id="H28249CC7D1A148F997A3D95FC320D275"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>beginning in fiscal year 2023, four individuals representing four different nonprofit organizations each of which is actively participating in carrying out wildlife conservation restoration activities using funds apportioned from the Subaccount.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HDDC133BBE0F74796A8E7FE70F8E4FE69"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Support from united states fish and wildlife service</header><text>Using not more than 3 percent of the amounts apportioned under subparagraph (A) to carry out a competitive grant program, the United States Fish and Wildlife Service shall provide any personnel or administrative support services necessary for such committee to carry out its responsibilities under this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0B0A874C9BF143B28DEE0624A85F678E"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>Such committee shall evaluate each proposal submitted under this paragraph and recommend projects for funding, giving preference to solutions that accelerate the recovery of species identified as priorities through regional scientific assessments of species of greatest conservation need.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H73D534FEF4344B01B0B6A97D1BF9E389"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Funds apportioned from the Subaccount shall be used for purposes consistent with section 2 of the <short-title>Recovering America’s Wildlife Act of 2022</short-title> and—</text> <subparagraph id="HE4D3DA546BC34B9A99BC4A59D02DCDF9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>shall be used to implement the Wildlife Conservation Strategy of a State, territory, or the District of Columbia, as required under section 4(e), by carrying out, revising, or enhancing existing wildlife and habitat conservation and restoration programs and developing and implementing new wildlife conservation and restoration programs to recover and manage species of greatest conservation need and the key habitats and plant community types essential to the conservation of those species, as determined by the appropriate State fish and wildlife department;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0917166A522C4B909BA83DD5902FB8E3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall be used to develop, revise, and enhance the Wildlife Conservation Strategy of a State, territory, or the District of Columbia, as may be required by this Act;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7C8BBE7F49DC40ADBDA5F845D1B82FAD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>shall be used to assist in the recovery of species found in the State, territory, or the District of Columbia that are listed as endangered species, threatened species, candidate species or species proposed for listing, or species petitioned for listing under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) or under State law;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5A5F28569F4D4979B5C033B8A5B31B19"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used for wildlife conservation education and wildlife-associated recreation projects, especially in historically underserved communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4279CBC47FD943329FB9F6D70142307D"><enum>(E)</enum><text>may be used to manage a species of greatest conservation need whose range is shared with another State, territory, Indian Tribe, or foreign government and for the conservation of the habitat of such species;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H58266D9B2E114BCAA797906856C7F3B0"><enum>(F)</enum><text>may be used to manage, control, and prevent invasive species, disease, and other risks to species of greatest conservation need; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC4670167A3944AB6BBA76C6AD29B1CB8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>may be used for law enforcement activities that are directly related to the protection and conservation of a species of greatest conservation need and the habitat of such species; </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H35F886A786DD4B5F92A88FDA4970EA30"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used to expand the use of innovative technologies, tools, strategies, or collaborative partnerships that accelerate, expand, or replicate effective and measurable recovery efforts for species of greatest conservation need and species listed as threatened or endangered under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 and the habitats of such species; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H80FC0478A96545DFBE410DC339837DC9"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used for conservation infrastructure projects related to the protection and conservation of a species of greatest conservation need and the habitat of such species; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC4DB54C3B9A44194878A6E4E2DA605DC"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be used to conserve and restore a native pollinator species which is a species of greatest conservation need.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6CE2C0C66D5E468D8F70E2F0171C5B8E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Minimum required spending for endangered species recovery</header><text>Not less than an average of 15 percent over a 5-year period of amounts apportioned to a State, territory, or the District of Columbia from the Subaccount shall be used for purposes described in paragraph (4)(C). The Secretary may reduce the minimum requirement of a State, territory, or the District of Columbia on an annual basis if the Secretary determines that the State, territory, or the District of Columbia is meeting the conservation and recovery needs of all species described in paragraph (4)(C).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4062ED69D1C241A18105495BA5218970"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public access to private lands not required</header><text>Funds apportioned from the Subaccount shall not be conditioned upon the provision of public access to private lands, waters, or holdings.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8DED557151A441E8A650F6A382B6040D"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Requirements for matching funds</header> <subparagraph id="H58E0CB17E63244509F948CC30204F273"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For the purposes of the non-Federal fund matching requirement for a wildlife conservation or restoration program or project funded by the Subaccount, a State, territory, or the District of Columbia may use as matching non-Federal funds—</text>
<clause id="H648A3ECB58FE418EB225A97101A0446D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>funds from Federal agencies other than the Department of the Interior and the Department of Agriculture;</text></clause> <clause id="HC32E4D2D57AD45EFB42A1654D88EB186"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>donated private lands and waters, including privately owned easements;</text></clause>
<clause id="H6EBAD8D8BDB2428EBD4F427C972E7E6F"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in circumstances described in subparagraph (B), revenue generated through the sale of State hunting and fishing licenses; and</text></clause> <clause id="H78E06AD1D56941C6893BA9E98B21EF99"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>other sources consistent with part 80 of title 50, Code of Federal Regulations, in effect on the date of enactment of the <short-title>Recovering America’s Wildlife Act of 2022</short-title>.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HC664EDE671194FE9BC6F7EA0B6DAE4BC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Revenue described in subparagraph (A)(iii) may only be used to fulfill the requirements of such non-Federal fund matching requirement if—</text> <clause id="H6789C12C7D6D49C0A619DD4FC2AD3E2C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>no Federal funds apportioned to the State fish and wildlife department of such State from the Wildlife Restoration Program or the Sport Fish Restoration Program have been reverted because of a failure to fulfill such non-Federal fund matching requirement by such State during the previous 2 years; and</text></clause>
<clause id="HC693E185B0A74A8C9D63B7FBBAC90D7A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the project or program being funded benefits the habitat of a hunted or fished species and a species of greatest conservation need.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD1126855AE9D4A3FB8A9D60895019C37"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection, the following definitions apply:</text>
<subparagraph id="H77BAF9B8B1B648F79DAB9E1094524203"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Partnerships</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>partnerships</term> may include collaborative efforts with Federal agencies, State agencies, local agencies, Indian Tribes, nonprofit organizations, academic institutions, industry groups, and private individuals to implement a State’s Wildlife Conservation Strategy.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC27C91A68C64407EAD2CB9F832E9D6EE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Species of greatest conservation need</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>species of greatest conservation need</term> may be fauna or flora, and may include terrestrial, aquatic, marine, and invertebrate species that are of low population, declining, rare, or facing threats and in need of conservation attention, as determined by each State fish and wildlife department, with respect to funds apportioned to such State.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H7D80D84EEC114798A725EAEDEB6D0344"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Territory and territories</header><text>The terms <term>territory</term> and <term>territories</term> mean the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands, and the United States Virgin Islands.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H007600DCB2204A89994F0A3D1965A5C6"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Wildlife</header><text>The term <term>wildlife</term> means any species of wild, freeranging fauna, including fish, and also fauna in captive breeding programs the object of which is to reintroduce individuals of a depleted indigenous species into previously occupied range.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H27C1875F31A343A88F65568DAC760224"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 3 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669b">16 U.S.C. 669b</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HFC300D808A25454A8186320D6B3877E4" display-inline="no-display-inline"> <subsection id="H7E3F3BBDE1ED4B7881C7DA06215AE687"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations to Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of the Interior <fraction>1/2 </fraction>of 1 percent of the amounts made available under subsection (c) for the purposes of providing oversight and accountability with respect to expenditure of funds authorized under such subsection, to remain available until September 30, 2029.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection>
<subsection id="H033F11B62B544F6C8F85D47E1A5ECD79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Allocation and Apportionment of available amounts</header><text>Section 4 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669c">16 U.S.C. 669c</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph id="HE0E29E12EF89425B927AF625AC57B82F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text>
<subparagraph id="HCE3578D5FCDC477398BEDAF3A645FFD4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text> <clause id="HE075E4772F7A4B21B10987DB8A11F0A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>to the District of Columbia and to the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, each</quote> and inserting <quote>To the District of Columbia</quote>;</text></clause>
<clause id="H8BEDFC5B857A48E49B38C3442D72DB35"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text> <subclause id="H950A249C59BB4DDA8F42F1F9C8BACD64"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>to Guam</quote> and inserting <quote>To Guam</quote>; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H0E5DB71AB51645B4A902D7AAF2134DE2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>not more than one-fourth of one percent</quote> and inserting <quote>not less than one-third of one percent</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H34F495466356466CB0B180B9C70250BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0926610046014B7CB524AD01322B6316">
<subparagraph id="H6E8DD24F57784BCB9B28C63387227764"><enum>(C)</enum><text>To the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, a sum equal to not less than 1 percent thereof.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4D93441550E74C1BA41992954328567F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A)—</text>
<clause id="H415E83D0BD94435DB3A8B409739F80CE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by amending clause (i) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8B96978C98F4A48BED79E457C856592"> <clause id="H087A905747B441AABAD021993E44AD81" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">one-half of which is based on the ratio to which the land and water area of such State bears to the total land and water area of all such States;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause>
<clause id="H3E5248F6EC924A19A08DD03A4EC67F73"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text> <subclause id="HA14582EBCC294F6F92867D8E291FEE17"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>two-thirds</quote> and inserting <quote>one-quarter</quote>; and</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H6FC26CB9D7794578BCE080A0AF9D516A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H6E8CF1061F39456A995430D3988E4CAE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA28D94307DE44901987D26613919EA60">
<clause id="H29FCED4DBDFA4C5C9C53D860463A416A" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>one-quarter of which is based upon the ratio to which the number of species listed as endangered or threatened under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) in such State bears to the total number of such species listed in all such States.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7565201CBABB43A0AB78099AB0C40CCC"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by amending paragraph (2)(B) to read as follows:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2897967641AF42618461907E857A6420">
<subparagraph id="H0E166394EC9E425EBBD85931DCBD6A7E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amounts apportioned under this paragraph shall be adjusted equitably so that no such State, unless otherwise designated, shall be apportioned a sum which is less than 1 percent or more than 5 percent of the amount available for apportionment under—</text> <clause id="H170CD371B882438796A009B392EACAD6"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subparagraph (A)(i);</text></clause>
<clause id="H872338D2E0904FAA842260FBCAC8CCE8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>subparagraph (A)(ii); and</text></clause> <clause id="H7E7B7824D731403EBFC59E673E47E84A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the overall amount available for subparagraph (A).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HFE17880E684D45BDB384BDB8812A42DB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (3), by striking <quote>3 percent</quote> and inserting <quote>1.85 percent</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H519D84960A3240FAB86A34516B8BB562"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(4)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H94FB8E4781CA4084B438A6AA78FA7FDE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by amending subparagraph (B) to read as follows:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="H43ECE6251C18457EA4EF533ED2E267AB"> <subparagraph id="H29AE1A28924645389FE74721B913E736" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not more than an average of 15 percent over a 5-year period of amounts apportioned to each State, territory, or the District of Columbia under this section for a wildlife conservation and restoration program may be used for wildlife conservation education and wildlife-associated recreation.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H0F5D042E3DFE4C7096CB07F3B1615192"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subparagraph (B), as so amended, the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD396153C8404489DB06C6FD02907E868"> <subparagraph id="HE11B0BDD7C9F4558B7249D92365E836C" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">5 percent of amounts apportioned to each State, each territory, or the District of Columbia under this section for a wildlife conservation and restoration program shall be reserved for States and territories that include plants among their species of greatest conservation need and in the conservation planning and habitat prioritization efforts of their Wildlife Conservation Strategy. Each eligible State, territory, or the District of Columbia shall receive an additional 5 percent of their apportioned amount. Any unallocated resources shall be allocated proportionally among all States and territories under the formulas of this section.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCF5ED6CD1FCD428A932532E1E976BAE9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC45B892F097A4D7893FD3B0C3C76DAB9"> <subsection id="H4A25784B3D9F416CA9A34DB7D4B00FAE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Minimization of planning and reporting</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be interpreted to require a State to create a comprehensive strategy related to conservation education or outdoor recreation.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA1DF127927B94A49B253E5EB81D5DD66"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Accountability</header>
<paragraph id="H11047C51427E430B9FE8063C67316087"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not more than one year after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Recovering America’s Wildlife Act of 2022</short-title> and every 3 years thereafter, each State fish and wildlife department shall submit a 3-year work plan and budget for implementing its Wildlife Conservation Strategy and a report describing the results derived from activities accomplished under subsection (e) during the previous 3 years to the United States Fish and Wildlife Service for review, which shall summarize such findings and submit a report to—</text> <subparagraph id="HBA47E077A6AA4A54BD0E3F0871C2DA3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H5FDBF580342947AC855ABF96EC4DA27C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA0BA232EB89B41FB9BF78B19AF9FEC97"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The format of the 3-year work plans, budgets, and reports required under paragraph (1) shall be established by the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, in consultation with the Association of Fish and Wildlife Agencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF7DB99E9949948F1A45A47B391176891"><enum>(3)</enum><header>GAO study</header><text>Not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Recovering America’s Wildlife Act of 2022</short-title>, the Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study to examine the progress of States, territories, the District of Columbia, and Indian Tribes towards achieving the purpose described in section 2 of that Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HE7B4D53E73054498893BF3BC1CA6FBCC"><enum>102.</enum><header>Technical amendments</header> <subsection id="H5C308B7B4E134B3A9D14F5D76726DB62"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 2 of the Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669a">16 U.S.C. 669a</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HD2276A0EE03B419999B6AD42C3176AA0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (7), by striking <quote>including fish,</quote>; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2F904DD64D8B42518901009DE6EC281C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by inserting <quote>Indian Tribes, academic institutions,</quote> before <quote>wildlife conservation organizations</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H831EBD0934334190A3AB2972E2D045C8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><text>The Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669">16 U.S.C. 669 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text> <paragraph commented="no" id="H3BD5E4FDFDB94A54BDC0D9B5E2E1DBD1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in section 3—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H4340CA681DF84842A85266F32B3C3C40"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text> <clause commented="no" id="HE32130006D8748F38E9B62B9A7544B83"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(1) An amount equal to</quote> and inserting <quote>An amount equal to</quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H00E8E1CEA4574853BE41C88FAC14D811"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2);</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H381421CE38CB42E296E2981896DD308D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text>
<clause commented="no" id="HB1E0DCC7F33B498C8E14D850C1B0E4E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), as redesignated by section 101(a)(1), by striking <quote>or an Indian tribe</quote>; and</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H81F5D2E9AC4C4C24910715481CD80A96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (10), as redesignated by section 101(a)(1), by striking <quote>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="H44FD84AE2326443596AF32AFC9F3AE39"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="HE8436B8A639C47C8B0ED8FDC5EC7133F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 4 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669c">16 U.S.C. 669c</external-xref>)—</text>
<subparagraph commented="no" id="HA3E6D069427E415E8E6C8FDE3F1EEC14"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (d)—</text> <clause commented="no" id="H07DEF61E79854BEFA90C41807A3E5288"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">account</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">subaccount</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H62B8DB074007452CB4684CF4C799029E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Account</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="H03C496A60A8E47F3817144F02A75FD43"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (e)(1), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="HE7136F9512024AFE8F58E48C08764F25"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 8 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669g">16 U.S.C. 669g</external-xref>), in subsection (a), by striking <quote>Account</quote> and inserting <quote>Subaccount</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H9821A52EB6B84624BEFDDD5B129DEFE8"><enum>103.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Pittman-Robertson Wildlife Restoration Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/669">16 U.S.C. 669 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text>
<paragraph id="HB1CD42D37B264E32A594277800863C5F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating section 14 as section 16; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDD4FC4CF73364DCF83644FE1CDD5849E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after section 13 the following:</text>
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD8D3D92055E940CD8949A6BFEBE2AE4E">
<section id="HCF03B79ED0484ADCABD4D3B7BFDE31DB"><enum>14.</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Nothing in this Act shall be construed to enlarge or diminish the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of a State to manage, control, or regulate fish and wildlife under the law and regulations of the State on lands and waters within the State, including on Federal lands and waters.</text></section> <section id="HCE6502670AC24A5F91F0A4891DF95F6B"><enum>15.</enum><header>Statutory construction with respect to Alaska</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If any conflict arises between any provision of this Act and any provision of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), then the provision in the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act or the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act shall prevail.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></title>
<title id="HCFC79D664D194AC297303C512FADECAA"><enum>II</enum><header>Tribal Wildlife Conservation and Restoration</header>
<section id="H412C4676B99B4C2E9F1DBE5EB92B0A46"><enum>201.</enum><header>Indian Tribes</header>
<subsection id="H535ECD98DEB7455292386D541D1119E1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HC4F3A27F86D64AD79094279839B7F5ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Account</header><text>The term <term>Account</term> means the Tribal Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account established by subsection (b)(1).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H93E9BF898AB84A00B9E68659ABA27A8D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Indian tribe</header><text>The term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given such term in section 4 of the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/25/5304">25 U.S.C. 5304</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H400A43E011BE46B9A9B5F3DB8FCB1E68"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H3A49367B15FE40A5ABA1E62D81CEE114"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Tribal species of greatest conservation need</header><text>The term <term>Tribal species of greatest conservation need</term> means any species identified by an Indian Tribe as requiring conservation management because of declining population, habitat loss, or other threats, or because of their biological or cultural importance to such Tribe.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H88AE415422814E39ABFF66FA685E7167"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Wildlife</header><text>The term <term>wildlife</term> means—</text>
<subparagraph id="H3DF09F63545B4466BD8C301BD6018FC0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any species of wild flora or fauna including fish and marine mammals;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDCC61A51317844D3905B122A46BB9059"><enum>(B)</enum><text>flora or fauna in a captive breeding, rehabilitation, and holding or quarantine program, the object of which is to reintroduce individuals of a depleted indigenous species into previously occupied range or to maintain a species for conservation purposes; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H55BE2F5CEFF74969BEEAF4E325C5C4B8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>does not include game farm animals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H4D84801A738E4C60A43E52F33A10C469"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Tribal wildlife conservation and restoration account</header> <paragraph id="HC6021B590F8540C4BBCBB268711F18D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Treasury an account to be known as the <quote>Tribal Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account</quote>.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H601CD8A711C245179CD9F8B8297F2117"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Amounts in the Account shall be available for each fiscal year without further appropriation for apportionment in accordance with this title.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H81FA973B48144EF09F701259FCF4E812"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Deposits into Account</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Beginning in fiscal year 2023, and for each fiscal year thereafter, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer $97,500,000 from the general fund of the Treasury to the Account.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H256F705C5C7F419AB4F6D149A8C20E64"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Distribution of funds to Indian tribes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each fiscal year, the Secretary of the Treasury shall deposit funds into the Account and distribute such funds through a noncompetitive application process according to guidelines and criteria, and reporting requirements determined by the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the Bureau of Indian Affairs, in consultation with Indian Tribes. Such funds shall remain available until expended.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HAE89BB916FDF422A88F9DC2E09C5C603"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Wildlife management responsibilities</header><text>The distribution guidelines and criteria described in subsection (c) shall be based, in part, upon an Indian Tribe's wildlife management responsibilities. Any funding allocated to an Indian Tribe in Alaska may only be used in a manner consistent with the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>), and <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/85/508">Public Law 85–508</external-xref> (commonly known as the <quote>Alaska Statehood Act</quote>) (48 U.S.C. note prec. 21). Alaska Native Corporations or Tribes may enter into cooperative agreements with the State of Alaska on conservation projects of mutual concern.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HEC9B09B1770D435C9755E32DA6C7FA31"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header>
<paragraph id="HB8847C01F3C04482A569D4CF5F5F4F5C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), the Secretary may distribute funds from the Account to an Indian Tribe for any of the following purposes:</text> <subparagraph id="H1F77F05CC88C4B1D85EC1081BD5411F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>To develop, carry out, revise, or enhance wildlife conservation and restoration programs to manage Tribal species of greatest conservation need and the habitats of such species, as determined by the Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA1D04938146C4BCBB2B9D9E87BA84991"><enum>(B)</enum><text>To assist in the recovery of species listed as an endangered or threatened species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDD8CDD13C8C84AC78308A2562E7727CD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>For wildlife conservation education and wildlife-associated recreation projects.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H04299D15E6144EB1805DA4BB26474159"><enum>(D)</enum><text>To manage a Tribal species of greatest conservation need and the habitat of such species, the range of which may be shared with a foreign country, State, or other Indian Tribe.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8C6699FEDC464D9E94466800E603554B"><enum>(E)</enum><text>To manage, control, and prevent invasive species as well as diseases and other risks to wildlife.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H76CA9682D6B146ECB73D0763253E44BE"><enum>(F)</enum><text>For law enforcement activities that are directly related to the protection and conservation of wildlife.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H4EE9CA8C0BC044C6AEE97DA611456E07"><enum>(G)</enum><text>To develop, revise, and implement comprehensive wildlife conservation strategies and plans for such Tribe.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1E2DFA91591F462E9537BFA5C5994443"><enum>(H)</enum><text>For the hiring and training of wildlife conservation and restoration program staff.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB0032E6EB4F740AB858B63608DABDB4A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conditions on the use of funds</header> <subparagraph id="H85F4A0A4F1344DA68A4FE9E123465BAB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Required use of funds</header><text>In order to be eligible to receive funds under subsection (c), a Tribe’s application must include a proposal to use funds for at least one of the purposes described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1271687EA7694B2CB8F20E434E2DCDB7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Imperiled species recovery</header><text>In distributing funds under this section, the Secretary shall distribute not less than 15 percent of the total funds distributed to proposals to fund the recovery of a species, subspecies, or distinct population segment listed as a threatened species, endangered species, or candidate species under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) or Tribal law.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H207A032E9BAC4F56A49257D9AD2E3721"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text>In distributing funds under this section, the Secretary shall distribute not more than 15 percent of all funds distributed under this section for the purpose described in paragraph (1)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H43A466994FFB48F785DBD2CD9B1413B0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No matching funds required</header><text>No Indian Tribe shall be required to provide matching funds to be eligible to receive funds under this Act.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H9CF0AB1464CA4E6892BA140FD0F8FB88"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Public access not required</header><text>Funds apportioned from the Tribal Wildlife Conservation and Restoration Account shall not be conditioned upon the provision of public or non-Tribal access to Tribal or private lands, waters, or holdings.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H1CD0158D3FD5421699F72C0444BA49C0"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text>Of the funds deposited under subsection (b)(3) for each fiscal year, not more than 3 percent shall be used by the Secretary for administrative costs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD5C67383F9DC4F82B636A1D31E41D559"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations to Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of the Interior <fraction>1/2 </fraction>of 1 percent of the amounts made available this section for the purposes of providing oversight and accountability with respect to expenditure of funds authorized under this section, to remain available until September 30, 2029.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H56E4443D754D49F3ABC7FFA23F3E11E0" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Savings clause</header><text>Nothing in this Act shall be construed as modifying or abrogating a treaty with any Indian Tribe, or as enlarging or diminishing the authority, jurisdiction, or responsibility of an Indian Tribe to manage, control, or regulate wildlife.</text></subsection> <subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H993EA6DAF1DA4048BFD13DA14C1F0FB6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Statutory construction with respect to Alaska</header><text>If any conflict arises between any provision of this Act and any provision of the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3101">16 U.S.C. 3101 et seq.</external-xref>) or the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/43/1601">43 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>), then the provision in the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act or the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act shall prevail.</text></subsection></section></title>
<title id="H18BC3FB02C424ECB83AEC26AABB2043D" style="OLC"><enum>III</enum><header>Endangered Species Recovery and Habitat Conservation Legacy Fund</header>
<section id="HB7F482CD2D2041B594CDF2C2D3BDF5C5"><enum>301.</enum><header>Endangered Species Recovery and Habitat Conservation Legacy Fund</header>
<subsection id="H340A9A8E270F41688AD35B3A9BE8A049"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established in the Treasury of the United States a fund, to be known as the <quote>Endangered Species Recovery and Habitat Conservation Legacy Fund</quote> (referred to in this section as the <term>Fund</term>).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA29701ED912441FA9A2120E684903D02"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Funding</header><text>For each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026, the Secretary of the Treasury shall transfer from the general fund of the Treasury to the Fund $187,500,000.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H6FB7AC1B3944436F9292671CC84C0BE0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of funds</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall be available to the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service (referred to in this section as the <term>Secretary</term>), as provided in subsection (e), without further appropriation or fiscal year limitation.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HDB8977AC3E6545F39E9A29C40E42F784"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Investment of amounts</header> <paragraph id="H8B75511EBF064CC39219800322058663"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may request the Secretary of the Treasury to invest any portion of the Fund that is not, as determined by the Secretary, required to meet the current needs of the Fund.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HFFACA34F39CD4CC7BC352D3DAF1FB13D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirement</header><text>An investment requested under paragraph (1) shall be made by the Secretary of the Treasury in a public debt security—</text> <subparagraph id="H9D55BC8DA9BB4550B1DAD4E272E2C8AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a maturity suitable to the needs of the Fund, as determined by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE2ED68F24C6140C7A7E53E2227275E7C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>bearing interest at a rate determined by the Secretary of the Treasury, taking into consideration current market yields on outstanding marketable obligations of the United States of comparable maturity.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H97AEE79F497940CDAF76E461C99F824A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Credits to Fund</header><text>The income on investments of the Fund under this subsection shall be credited to, and form a part of, the Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HA4F0A2416C8A45E785D73E95F205AD6C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Amounts in the Fund shall be used for recovering the species managed under the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>), in addition to amounts otherwise available for such purposes, as follows:</text> <paragraph id="HD3975058DB144337B720E23C6B5C73DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Endangered Species Recovery Grant Program</header><text>$75,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026, to remain available until expended, shall be used to establish and implement a grant and technical assistance program, to be known as the <term>Endangered Species Recovery Grant Program</term>, to provide competitive matching grants for the purpose of recovering species listed as a threatened species or an endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>) by addressing the backlog in the development of recovery plans, and implementing the backlog of activities identified in existing recovery plans, under subsection (f) of that section (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(f)</external-xref>). The Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation to establish and cooperatively manage the Endangered Species Recovery Grant Program in accordance with the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1531">16 U.S.C. 1531 et seq.</external-xref>) and the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/3701">16 U.S.C. 3701 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HBD819C9359C849918AC07A9D37FB2BF3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Interagency consultation responsibilities</header><text>$75,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026, to remain available until expended, shall be used for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to address interagency consultation responsibilities under section 7 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1536">16 U.S.C. 1536</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H25046DB01B1B4931900CD92A0069831A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conservation activities</header><text>$28,125,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026, to remain available until expended, shall be used for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to work with non-Federal entities, including through, but not limited to, the Partners for Fish and Wildlife Program, the Coastal Program, and the North American Wetlands Conservation Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/4401">16 U.S.C. 4401 et seq.</external-xref>)—</text>
<subparagraph id="H316236B931974A4FADB86DBDB3912308"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to conserve at risk species, species that are candidates or proposed for listing, and species that are listed as threatened or endangered species under section 4 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533</external-xref>), including through rescue and rehabilitation efforts and efforts to manage, control, and prevent invasive species, disease, and other risks to such species; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7FA6C6BA5EAF49ADAFBB796D45AF55B0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to conserve wildlife habitat.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9934395DF5F1477397F1939F41A6CFE2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Voluntary conservation agreements</header><text>$9,375,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2026, to remain available until expended, shall be used for the United States Fish and Wildlife Service to address the development and permitting of voluntary conservation agreements under section 10 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1539">16 U.S.C. 1539</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H791995A4AD754428ACBE1D49EBDEABDE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Amounts made available under this section shall supplement and not supplant any other Federal amounts made available to carry out activities described in this section in an annual appropriations Act of Congress.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HB7F34A4D76824982B46D1A04C933F18B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Submission of species lists to Congress</header>
<paragraph id="H29C0BCA2CF7E4CA7B32CB6AB34CC98AB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Priority list of species</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary, shall submit to the Committees on Environment and Public Works and Appropriations of the Senate and the Committees on Natural Resources and Appropriations of the House of Representatives a list of threatened species and endangered species for which recovery plans described in subsection (e)(1) will be developed or implemented for fiscal year 2023.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB682D2EEA7F444EC8F9CAB64B3206168"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual list of species</header><text>Until the date on which all of the amounts in the Fund are expended, the President shall annually submit to Congress, together with the annual budget of the United States, a list of threatened species and endangered species for which recovery plans described in subsection (e)(1) will be developed or implemented with amounts from the Fund.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7673DE468A7042D3A491077B0D1EB9B1"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Public donations</header>
<paragraph id="HF88E4381A0E2401C8F62B6247DC4DFC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may accept public cash donations that advance efforts—</text> <subparagraph id="H7AB4822ADE164D26B7D15404816F6A5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address the backlog in the development and implementation of recovery plans; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H94E22797E5FE46F0A41FCF120CBE9C84"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to encourage relevant public-private partnerships.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1B9DEB8BCAB342C694E82ABFC820F07A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Credits to fund</header><text>Any cash donations accepted under paragraph (1) shall be credited to, and form a part of, the Fund.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H28B58944C8A340819456FF92E65FDBD7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rejection of donations</header><text>The Secretary may reject a donation under this section when the rejection is in the interest of the Federal Government, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H613854E5A6A14A5DA89AAF9D38EB6ACC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Allocation authority</header> <paragraph id="H3F8E589C87F74B7DAB8278C9B705A0A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission of cost estimates</header><text>The President shall submit to Congress detailed allocations by program element of the amount recommended for allocation in a fiscal year from amounts made available under subsection (c), consistent with the use of funds under subsection (e), as follows:</text>
<subparagraph id="H44FECF00070D4B7CA6CF7D4773C733B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2023, not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB73E7C50D7F24F33BF8038E3E01246FD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>For each fiscal year thereafter, until the date on which all of the amounts in the Fund are allocated, as part of the annual budget submission of the President under section 1105(a) of title 31, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H00C7242386B045C090E66EA3E1741D33"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Alternate allocation</header>
<subparagraph id="H63FAF95541364D6D8CA9C954656A7408"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committees on Appropriations of the Senate and House of Representatives may provide for alternate allocation of amounts recommended for allocation in a given fiscal year from amounts made available under subsection (c), consistent with the use of funds under subsection (e), including allocations by program element.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3154A80A639B4A77A28F7408C78B8A72"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Allocation by President</header> <clause id="H397A38E877E14F3496B69B8A9931AC62"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No alternate allocations</header><text>If Congress has not enacted legislation establishing alternate allocations, including by program, by the date on which the Act making full-year appropriations for the Department of the Interior, Environment, and Related Agencies for the applicable fiscal year is enacted into law, only then shall amounts recommended for allocation for that fiscal year from amounts made available under subsection (c), consistent with the use of funds under subsection (e), be allocated by the President or apportioned or allotted by program pursuant to title 31, United States Code.</text></clause>
<clause id="H8726AC0521494B4A97303394F4D61455"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Insufficient alternate allocation</header><text>If Congress enacts legislation establishing alternate allocations, including by program, for amounts recommended for allocation in a given fiscal year from amounts made available under subsection (c), consistent with the use of funds under subsection (e), that are less than the full amount recommended for allocation for that fiscal year, the difference between the amount recommended for allocation and the alternate allocation shall be allocated by the President and apportioned and allotted by program pursuant to title 31, United States Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H48CD36C3B1B349D2AFB3ED8E9FAA9330"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Prohibitions</header><text>No amounts from the Fund shall be used—</text>
<paragraph id="H09C34A7DCE9941FB9E7EC7EB441C8E3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>to make any listing determination relating to the endangered or threatened status of any species pursuant to section 4(a) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1533">16 U.S.C. 1533(a)</external-xref>);</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA745FB20855A4414A2F6A55423C55303"><enum>(2)</enum><text>on any experimental population (as defined in paragraph (1) of section 10(j) of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1539">16 U.S.C. 1539(j)</external-xref>)) of a threatened or endangered species that is determined to be nonessential under that section;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H993B02F564F74EA09C3C811FE72B0DC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>outside of the United States (as defined in section 3 of the Endangered Species Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/1532">16 U.S.C. 1532</external-xref>)); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6AB5E9F8FF5B4BC4BB5527DA909FCD14" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(4)</enum><text>to acquire any Federal land.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H10EF2C20C7AE470B859941C08D2178DA"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Administrative costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Of the funds made available under each of paragraphs (1) and (3) of subsection (e), not more than 1.85 percent may be used by the Secretary for administrative costs.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H6B4E163CCAEA4969A5795CDC11646718"><enum>(l)</enum><header>Inspector general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated to the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of the Interior <fraction>1/2</fraction> of 1 percent of the amounts made available under subsection (c) for the purposes of providing oversight and accountability with respect to expenditure of funds authorized under such subsection, to remain available until September 30, 2029.</text></subsection></section></title>
<title id="H5BDEA6B4E559433CBA6598717039167E"><enum>IV</enum><header>Report</header>
<section id="HD867D8B9F51C4FC585EAC8B045A516FE"><enum>401.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of the Interior shall, not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this section, and annually thereafter, submit a report to the Committee on Environment and Public Works of the Senate and the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives providing detailed information on the dollar amount of grants and contracts (including subcontracts), and the percentage of total awards and grants, that were awarded or allocated under this Act to Historically Black Colleges and Universities, Hispanic-serving educational institutions, Tribally-controlled colleges and universities, minority-serving educational institutions, minority-owned business enterprises, women-owned business enterprises, and community-based organizations that are principally administered by, operated by, or serving minority communities.</text></section></title> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220614" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives June 14, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

