<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD03C3A0A561A4F4997B60168E16E7D9E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7497 IH: Make Medicine Affordable Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-11</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7497</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220411">April 11, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001208">Ms. Slotkin</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Education and Labor</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for lower prices for drugs through drug price negotiation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA0956BB72A5F40F898731027B0AE8A56" style="OLC"><section id="HBAB853DD855F4370BB292496A759B3B5" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H2280D0B2671E4B81A32C2D5CD58AA612"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Make Medicine Affordable Act</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H67027191852D4BBA8886963F7E923817"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text>The table of contents for this Act is as follows: </text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="HBAB853DD855F4370BB292496A759B3B5" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB7FC697482984201A66EA381383BEB0A" level="title">Title I—Lowering Prices Through Drug Price Negotiation</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H130FC650A75C43A1BB999849590CA2FD" level="section">Sec. 101. Providing for lower prices for certain high-priced single source drugs.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HB725839030F4457DA07251D200F3E402" level="section">Sec. 102. Selected drug manufacturer excise tax imposed during noncompliance periods.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9C451A5801C240F8ADFB9D8C44A1D2AB" level="section">Sec. 103. Funding.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HAADAC0F62F8A42CA8F41C2687D01ED5A" level="title">Title II—Prescription Drug Inflation Rebates</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H83232D2EE0914B19B8F35AD655492356" level="section">Sec. 201. Medicare part B rebate by manufacturers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3C376C04E3584DBC8AC8E463D33744C7" level="section">Sec. 202. Medicare part D rebate by manufacturers.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9BD89E3D02CB4E60B1FA296BEA2F9318" level="title">Title III—Part D Improvements and Maximum Out-of-Pocket Cap for Medicare Beneficiaries</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H5A5CAA1E765243A1A8A4D32BA624580D" level="section">Sec. 301. Medicare part D benefit redesign.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H352AEA84A0334543AB63F5F151F6DFF3" level="section">Sec. 302. Maximum monthly cap on cost-sharing payments under prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HFD55DC81296F479F8BCD5204921AAC2A" level="title">Title IV—Repeal of Certain Prescription Drug Rebate Rule</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4514C6E6C60A487A85E7C87855D8CFBC" level="section">Sec. 401. Prohibiting implementation of rule relating to eliminating the anti-kickback statute safe harbor protection for prescription drug rebates.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF40B01E2172F4F40AAA556202DC8D5CD" level="title">Title V—Miscellaneous</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H483800329CAA43FAA1AB3F56D3315C44" level="section">Sec. 501. Appropriate cost-sharing for certain insulin products under Medicare part D.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0C49B23B802541BBB1E401C9F6D90521" level="section">Sec. 502. Coverage of adult vaccines recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices under Medicare part D.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H64403C339C8C4A088AA4D3BD2CC91182" level="section">Sec. 503. Payment for biosimilar biological products during initial period.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2A76F194E30B43FF946F1DE9D0147326" level="section">Sec. 504. Temporary increase in Medicare part B payment for certain biosimilar biological products.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HE203B698F42046FAAAD2326D577B6E14" level="section">Sec. 505. Improving access to adult vaccines under Medicaid and CHIP.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HA4DECB66DC2844A5A5BE301EECFEA3B8" level="title">Title VI—Additional Insulin Policies</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HDEA8CEA535974C1BA5DF38D35221CD1F" level="section">Sec. 601. ERISA requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H1AD773AAF38A422483BAD96F19E52097" level="section">Sec. 602. Public Health Service Act requirements with respect to cost-sharing for insulin products.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC4966A2CE04C407DB16EFDC7F181C77E" level="section">Sec. 603. IRC requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><title id="HB7FC697482984201A66EA381383BEB0A"><enum>I</enum><header>Lowering Prices Through Drug Price Negotiation</header><section id="H130FC650A75C43A1BB999849590CA2FD"><enum>101.</enum><header>Providing for lower prices for certain high-priced single source drugs</header><subsection id="H311C66ACF46E4BCFA77F387044BAEEB2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program To lower prices for certain high-Priced single source drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title XI of the Social Security Act is amended by adding after section 1184 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320e-3">42 U.S.C. 1320e–3</external-xref>) the following new part:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F6917ADDDBA488691CC96EA27B76283" style="OLC"><part id="H3A29110F0DE047DEAAAF2092506B0BFB"><enum>E</enum><header>Price Negotiation Program to Lower Prices for Certain High-Priced Single Source Drugs</header><section id="H46F3AB0024F74BA5B7C2BFD38841E6A6"><enum>1191.</enum><header>Establishment of program</header><subsection id="HB2A402805A144350B060F74230E8AE34"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a Drug Price Negotiation Program (in this part referred to as the <quote>program</quote>). Under the program, with respect to each price applicability period, the Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="H9F5232E8E3494DD7A784EB14327F7FF6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>publish a list of negotiation-eligible drugs and selected drugs in accordance with section 1192;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D2350E5AF8B4757A58A6A0CE856C557"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">enter into agreements with manufacturers of selected drugs with respect to such period, in accordance with section 1193;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66FF8E626005404EB78A885288FB4DEA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>negotiate and, if applicable, renegotiate maximum fair prices for such selected drugs, in accordance with section 1194; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AF097A9E5734E2E90135F00EE0BF967"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">carry out the administrative duties described in section 1196.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD26455346AF4D359F9F63B0D7AAA77F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions relating to timing</header><text>For purposes of this part:</text><paragraph id="H879487B25D17455EB090E01C03A539C8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial price applicability year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>initial price applicability year</term> means a year (beginning with 2025).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA212F1A6A1704D6BA26F005BE90A8E83"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Price applicability period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>price applicability period</term> means, with respect to a qualifying single source drug, the period beginning with the first initial price applicability year with respect to which such drug is a selected drug and ending with the last year during which the drug is a selected drug.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3FB9892CC043AAA404BDD9C9EE8F3E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selected drug publication date</header><text>The term <term>selected drug publication date</term> means, with respect to each initial price applicability year, February 1 of the year that begins 2 years prior to such year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28F2D1D85892439CB1D366695F25FB9A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Negotiation period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>negotiation period</term> means, with respect to an initial price applicability year with respect to a selected drug, the period—</text><subparagraph id="HB6338D3EDC624783B02617A4B6BC4777"><enum>(A)</enum><text>beginning on the sooner of—</text><clause id="HA0987A00B5684F56BEB375125335442D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the date on which the manufacturer of the drug and the Secretary enter into an agreement under section 1193 with respect to such drug; or</text></clause><clause id="H1E1FFA0072F147C0B182AEC91CF61C01"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>February 28 following the selected drug publication date with respect to such selected drug; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB5EEFB82875946BCB37C16ED724215D6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ending on November 1 of the year that begins 2 years prior to the initial price applicability year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBD73321211FB42D8BD1AFA66EC57CA71"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this part:</text><paragraph id="HFC6596EF4D0B40E6BB8C3B48F67A314B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Maximum fair price eligible individual</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>maximum fair price eligible individual</term> means, with respect to a selected drug—</text><subparagraph id="H0E7770607EBF4A5E8E90C109ADD0AA21"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case such drug is dispensed to the individual at a pharmacy, by a mail order service, or by another dispenser, an individual who is enrolled under a prescription drug plan under part D of title XVIII or an MA–PD plan under part C of such title if coverage is provided under such plan for such selected drug; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34889E61374E43608008F1D08209087C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case such drug is furnished or administered to the individual by a hospital, physician, or other provider of services or supplier, an individual who is enrolled under part B of title XVIII, including an individual who is enrolled under an MA plan under part C of such title, if such selected drug is covered under such part.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F4C447D73AD4F2D859C60EAA40BD299"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Maximum fair price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>maximum fair price</term> means, with respect to a year during a price applicability period and with respect to a selected drug (as defined in section 1192(c)) with respect to such period, the price published pursuant to section 1195 in the Federal Register for such drug and year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB97C9C5FBCD4E7AB5A48F4A7D8017D8"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unit</term> means, with respect to a drug or biological, the lowest identifiable amount (such as a capsule or tablet, milligram of molecules, or grams) of the drug or biological that is dispensed or furnished. The determination of a unit, with respect to a drug or biological, pursuant to this paragraph shall not be subject to administrative or judicial review.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C90F837354B462BB8288A17528E8496"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Total expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>total expenditures</term> includes, in the case of expenditures with respect to part D of title XVIII, ingredient costs, dispensing fees, sales tax, and if applicable, vaccine administration fees. The term <term>total expenditures</term> excludes, in the case of expenditures with respect to part B of such title, expenditures for a drug or biological that are bundled or packaged into the payment for another service.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0EE43D3025FF4906AF82F41057D3E0D5" commented="no"><enum>1192.</enum><header>Selection of negotiation-eligible drugs as selected drugs</header><subsection id="H13E1466B8CB74C7A959EE437FFD099A1" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the selected drug publication date with respect to an initial price applicability year, in accordance with subsection (b), the Secretary shall select and publish in the Federal Register a list of—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H462DC1AE5083461E8AFA9B1928F32DFA"><enum>(1)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H2BA86C3B1C9D4397ACA79B0CAB21EB0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the initial price applicability year 2025, not more than 10 negotiation-eligible drugs described in subparagraph (A)(i) of subsection (d)(1), but not subparagraph (B) of such subsection, with respect to such year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37C056140FF648348B5915800D531A25" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to the initial price applicability year 2026, not more than 15 negotiation-eligible drugs described in subparagraph (A)(i) of subsection (d)(1), but not subparagraph (B) of such subsection, with respect to such year;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8D6C7E00C2E84875AD45EE7CE2F63BA3" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the initial price applicability year 2027, not more than 15 negotiation-eligible drugs described in subparagraph (A) of subsection (d)(1), but not subparagraph (B) of such subsection, with respect to such year; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA249ED82CE9413CA6702FBD3E050119" indent="up1" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to the initial price applicability year 2028 or a subsequent year, not more than 20 negotiation-eligible drugs described in subparagraph (A) of subsection (d)(1), but not subparagraph (B) of such subsection, with respect to such year; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C4E9C89FE79425791B71E108637A7D7" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>all negotiation-eligible drugs described in subparagraph (B) of such subsection with respect to such year.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection" commented="no">Subject to subsection (c)(2) and section 1194(f)(5), each drug published on the list pursuant to the previous sentence shall be subject to the negotiation process under section 1194 for the negotiation period with respect to such initial price applicability year (and the renegotiation process under such section as applicable for any subsequent year during the applicable price applicability period). </continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H078A104B87C84ECAA482CA634AAD2A9B" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Selection of drugs</header><paragraph id="H4A121A0885F64354BD48E700470EAFB7" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out subsection (a)(1), subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall, with respect to an initial price applicability year—</text><subparagraph id="HCA831CF1B8874886B1F6A4D84C229EC4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rank a combined list of negotiation-eligible drugs described in subsection (d)(1)(A) according to the total expenditures for such drugs under parts B and D of title XVIII, as determined by the Secretary, during the most recent period of 12 months prior to the selected drug publication date (but ending not later than October 31 of the year prior to the year of such drug publication date), with respect to such year, for which data are available, with the negotiation-eligible drugs with the highest total expenditures being ranked the highest; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFF430149A9943D6996464F42E9DFB4C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">select from such ranked combined list for inclusion on the published list described in subsection (a) with respect to such year the negotiation-eligible drugs with the highest such rankings.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H54982CBC0B5A4CBFBA3E2E6BBC5226AA" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>High spend part D drugs for 2025 and 2026</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to the initial price applicability year 2025 and with respect to the initial price applicability year 2026, the Secretary shall apply paragraph (1) as if the reference to <quote>negotiation-eligible drugs described in subsection (d)(1)(A)</quote> were a reference to <quote>negotiation-eligible drugs described in subsection (d)(1)(A)(i)</quote> and as if the reference to <quote>total expenditures for such drugs under parts B and D of title XVIII</quote> were a reference to <quote>total expenditures for such drugs under part D of title XVIII</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEF6A71D843CF432A9507A32F415EC4CE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selected drug</header><paragraph id="H9109ACCB7B814BABB96EA70F988B8598"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this part, consistent with subsection (e)(2) and subject to paragraph (2), each negotiation-eligible drug included on the list published under subsection (a) with respect to an initial price applicability year shall be referred to as a <quote>selected drug</quote> with respect to such year and each subsequent year beginning before the first year that begins after the date on which the Secretary determines at least one drug or biological product—</text><subparagraph id="HD6D4D6E6E6AA46789A8DFD9F0659A0F4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is approved or licensed (as applicable)—</text><clause id="H29CBC32A6258433196796AE015793580" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act using such drug as the listed drug; or</text></clause><clause id="H7D5F4E5D58F8418CABC7049EC9FE2359" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>under section 351(k) of the Public Health Service Act using such drug as the reference product; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8196AD27726B49D58766AE5D2D4A1EAE" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is marketed pursuant to such approval or licensure.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H75950FB112C64B12BAD35D086C2A09D4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A negotiation-eligible drug—</text><subparagraph id="HFCECC773035C4DD0969F3E8578D98A0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that is included on the list published under subsection (a) with respect to an initial price applicability year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0385D83908A140FA9A7AA4017F3F28CB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for which the Secretary makes a determination described in paragraph (1) before or during the negotiation period with respect to such initial price applicability year, </text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">shall not be subject to the negotiation process under section 1194 with respect to such negotiation period and shall continue to be considered a selected drug under this part with respect to the number of negotiation-eligible drugs published on the list under subsection (a) with respect to such initial price applicability year. </continuation-text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H12D47904B6464785B012DBD142901B7F" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Negotiation-Eligible drug</header><paragraph id="H4C36747720CE458A9EE84E0621ECFFB8" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this part, subject to paragraph (2), the term <term>negotiation-eligible drug</term> means, with respect to the selected drug publication date with respect to an initial price applicability year, a qualifying single source drug, as defined in subsection (e), that is described in either of the following subparagraphs (or, with respect to the initial price applicability year 2025 or 2026, that is described in subparagraph (A)(i) or (B)): </text><subparagraph id="H6E0643DD20DB4F7680A83EB4A2ECFA10" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>High spend drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The qualifying single source drug is, determined in accordance with subsection (e)(2)—</text><clause id="H927BC9A3EC16414A91FAF39228970D7C" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">among the 50 qualifying single source drugs with the highest total expenditures under part D of title XVIII, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (3), during the most recent period for which data are available of at least 12 months prior to the selected drug publication date (but ending no later than October 31 of the year prior to the year of such drug publication date), with respect to such year; or</text></clause><clause id="H4131152F62824DD38EC3F79B238CFD72" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">among the 50 qualifying single source drugs with the highest total expenditures under part B of title XVIII, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (3), during such most recent period, as described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA3FA171471FB4622AED3AEA076D7C894"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Insulin</header><text>The qualifying single source drug is described in subsection (e)(1)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H89644B57ACC342CD96FF121E2BF1697C" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Exception for small biotech drugs</header><subparagraph id="H9F4B7AD260A2405E9565ADCFCC817AB0" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (C), the term <term>negotiation-eligible drug</term> shall not include, with respect to the initial price applicability years 2025, 2026, and 2027, a qualifying single source drug that meets either of the following:</text><clause id="H67796A78B8BA4087B0E84F73E4C24AB5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Part D drugs</header><text>The total expenditures for the qualifying single source drug under part D of title XVIII, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (3), during 2021—</text><subclause id="H413B318C8C75470EAF6D62AA748EF400" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are equal to or less than 1 percent of the total expenditures under such part D, as so determined, for all covered part D drugs during such year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H74D3A61902FB4386831A9CCB227DC814" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are equal to at least 80 percent of the total expenditures under such part D, as so determined, for all covered part D drugs for which the manufacturer of the drug has an agreement in effect under section 1860D–14A during such year.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFCD0BC94EE7C4D0085B784B2A0D328B3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Part B drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The total expenditures for the qualifying single source drug under part B of title XVIII, as determined by the Secretary in accordance with paragraph (3), during 2021—</text><subclause id="H259A1C0555D14835BF18CA2614C25EDF" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are equal to or less than 1 percent of the total expenditures under such part B, as so determined, for all qualifying single source drugs covered under such part B during such year; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD773AC753D7E428198F61FBEAE363429" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">are equal to at least 80 percent of the total expenditures under such part B, as so determined, for all qualifying single source drugs of the manufacturer that are covered under such part B during such year. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H154C1ECB00964E2B8F0C83C233C4B9C6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarifications relating to manufacturers</header><clause id="H2ECEE9E32E9F4D7FA4257EC21F5C4CB0"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be treated as one manufacturer for purposes of this paragraph. </text></clause><clause id="H5C03AE9076FA44CBB2E85EBECF4EBAC8"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying single source drug described in subparagraph (A) shall not include a qualifying single source drug of a manufacturer if such manufacturer is acquired after 2021 by another manufacturer that does not meet the definition of a specified manufacturer under section 1860D–14C(g)(4)(B)(ii), effective at the beginning of the plan year immediately following such acquisition or, in the case of an acquisition before 2024, effective January 1, 2024.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF9B369533194DDEAF41A4D5796C81C3" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Drugs not included as small biotech drugs</header><text>The following shall not be considered a qualifying single source drug described in subparagraph (A):</text><clause id="H5BB926E602D941B3A77FAF3B942A7F9D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A vaccine that is licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act and is marketed pursuant to such section.</text></clause><clause id="H100A9D9DDF294FC4B07703B1CE8B44D2" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A new formulation, such as an extended release formulation, of a qualifying single source drug.</text></clause><clause id="H0AC7E194B16F49679DAC689C68B6EA36"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A qualifying single source drug described in subsection (e)(1)(C).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBDD969439F4AE3953F27D5245F68AA" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Clarifications and determinations</header><subparagraph id="HA244EA3919E34197AB39A49C23B54D10" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Previously selected drugs and small biotech drugs excluded</header><text>In applying clauses (i) and (ii) of paragraph (1)(A), the Secretary shall not consider or count—</text><clause id="H23350B38CA09405D96681A9BC24287A8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>drugs that are already selected drugs; and</text></clause><clause id="HDAD66A24377D49178C1274593C057020"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for initial price applicability years 2025, 2026, and 2027, qualifying single source drugs described in paragraph (2)(A).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H34C6924840374F49A0337838FEF29234" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Use of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether a qualifying single source drug satisfies any of the criteria described in paragraph (1) or (2), the Secretary shall use data that is aggregated across dosage forms and strengths of the drug, including new formulations of the drug, such as an extended release formulation, and not based on the specific formulation or package size or package type of the drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0093614F08E645BC8CC82B0AC2C3F2A0" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Publication</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than the selected drug publication date with respect to an initial price applicability year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register a list of negotiation-eligible drugs with respect to such selected drug publication date.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H3069CFDF016D4390B525DFD114B58191"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Qualifying single source drug</header><paragraph id="H64061A3D173D424DAB3F98BFCCB70374" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this part, the term <term>qualifying single source drug</term> means, with respect to an initial price applicability year, subject to paragraphs (2) and (3), a covered part D drug (as defined in section 1860D–2(e)) that is described in any of the following or a drug or biological product covered under part B of title XVIII that is described in any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC79A8E2715174A85B85C276DA27D0904" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Drug products</header><text>A drug—</text><clause id="H2EC0305003BC430BBCCA161745F570BB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that is approved under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and is marketed pursuant to such approval;</text></clause><clause id="H70A5F591E6064F8F90B6CCB5B407DE96"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which, as of the selected drug publication date with respect to such initial price applicability year, at least 7 years will have elapsed since the date of such approval; and</text></clause><clause id="HE2CF5FAA5B2143B98A5AD39F6B2ECF44" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that is not the listed drug for any drug that is approved and marketed under section 505(j) of such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8D06D9EE7094CC3B272FBA7B1452368" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Biological products</header><text>A biological product—</text><clause id="HBA7493D3D97640C28A7AEEBC9478F9E8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is licensed under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act and is marketed under section 351 of such Act;</text></clause><clause id="H02DC08C1C0194C749402C535D639A04E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for which, as of the selected drug publication date with respect to such initial price applicability year, at least 11 years will have elapsed since the date of such licensure; and</text></clause><clause id="H1A23BD6B0CC941A18D23CD16345085D4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is not the reference product for any biological product that is licensed and marketed under section 351(k) of such Act.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC8EBD3575954C01A3BE7F726489EFE9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Insulin product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any insulin product that is approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act and marketed pursuant to such approval or licensure, including any insulin product that has been deemed to be licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act pursuant to section 7002(e)(4) of the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act of 2009 and is marketed pursuant to such section, regardless of whether such insulin product would be described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8CF02A6248534A8FA8AA90BAEEA1C544" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of authorized generic drugs</header><subparagraph id="HC0AC0C955005451CAF113214492DDA7A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualifying single source drug described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of paragraph (1) that is the listed drug (as such term is used in section 505(j) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act) or the reference product (as defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act), with respect to an authorized generic drug, in applying the provisions of this part, such authorized generic drug and such listed drug or reference product shall be treated as the same qualifying single source drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2F40AFB5349404A9A2FE47A2A803F18"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Authorized generic drug defined</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>authorized generic drug</term> means—</text><clause id="H4001A1877C854DB8961DB37298DA6725"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a drug, an authorized generic drug (as such term is defined in section 505(t)(3) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act); and</text></clause><clause id="H2BEA8F486B9D468880FAF27195245740"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a biological product, a reference product (as such term is defined in section 351(i) of the Public Health Service Act) that—</text><subclause id="HC7F0EB1C11CD4B988D8F1CE5EA166A90"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has been licensed under section 351(a) of such Act; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD48ACD5F705346DFAD572A4A757F1C4B"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is marketed, sold, or distributed directly or indirectly to retail class of trade under a different labeling, packaging (other than repackaging as the reference product in blister packs, unit doses, or similar packaging for use in institutions), product code, labeler code, trade name, or trade mark than the reference product.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD8DB50B891240F88C69D5F7D78DAA40" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>In this part, the term <term>qualifying single source drug</term> does not include any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H41026F8FCDA848CDA312FF29BEF0C765" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Certain orphan drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A drug that is designated as a drug for only one rare disease or condition under section 526 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and for which the only approved indication (or indications) is for such disease or condition.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3C7D2AD1E7DE48B2A4C0D6498ABEA6E8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Low spend Medicare drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A drug or biological product (other than an insulin product described in paragraph (1)(C)) with respect to which the total expenditures under parts B and D of title XVIII, as determined by the Secretary, during the most recent period for which data are available of at least 12 months prior to the selected drug publication date (but ending no later than October 31 of the year prior to the year of such drug publication date), with respect to such year is less than—</text><clause id="H3318D8167DFD4EBB8975C20FEE3916FF"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to 2021, $200,000,000; or</text></clause><clause id="HB3D489AD677241568AD100E981506260"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a subsequent year, the dollar amount specified in this subparagraph for the previous year increased by the annual percentage increase in the consumer price index (all items; U.S. city average) as of December of such previous year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB76119D555A44DE7B503AB65AC485F74" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No administrative or judicial review of determinations and selections</header><text>The determination of negotiation-eligible drugs under subsection (d) and the selection of drugs under this section are not subject to administrative or judicial review. </text></subsection></section><section id="H51F2BEC9310E4DB080B9DFB06ED4A83A"><enum>1193.</enum><header>Manufacturer agreements</header><subsection id="H7613F488497A4CADB4DB16622C86FB17"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1191(a)(2), the Secretary shall enter into agreements with manufacturers of selected drugs with respect to a price applicability period, by not later than February 28 following the selected drug publication date with respect to such selected drug, under which—</text><paragraph id="H94175D481C134BD580F8BE8E41C91B8F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>during the negotiation period for the initial price applicability year for the selected drug, the Secretary and manufacturer, in accordance with section 1194, negotiate to determine (and, by not later than the last date of such period, agree to) a maximum fair price for such selected drug of the manufacturer in order for the manufacturer to provide access to such price—</text><subparagraph id="H67D6B84B5119454995ED495AAB645D8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (A) of section 1191(c)(1) and are dispensed such drug (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs) during, subject to subparagraph (2), the price applicability period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB8F851D61CE84F33B1F97E4F3EE96921"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (B) of such section and are furnished or administered such drug during, subject to subparagraph (2), the price applicability period;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D34D5E99E0E4C1CAC72C27273DBFC9E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary and the manufacturer shall, in accordance with section 1194, renegotiate (and, by not later than the last date of such period, agree to) the maximum fair price for such drug, in order for the manufacturer to provide access to such maximum fair price (as so renegotiated)—</text><subparagraph id="HB8B1AF97771545B0BC8B2EB949CBCD08"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (A) of section 1191(c)(1) and are dispensed such drug (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs) during any year during the price applicability period (beginning after such renegotiation) with respect to such selected drug; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEB99151E0374ACE9D4ED93D0CFDD854"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (B) of such section and are furnished or administered such drug during any year described in subparagraph (A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H20719F3110E541E68B84461FA7444ACD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">access to the maximum fair price (including as renegotiated pursuant to paragraph (2)), with respect to such a selected drug, shall be provided by the manufacturer to—</text><subparagraph id="HBABC826143114F1B9406E328CAD38912"><enum>(A)</enum><text>maximum fair price eligible individuals, who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (A) of section 1191(c)(1), at the pharmacy, mail order service, or other dispenser at the point-of-sale of such drug (and shall be provided by the manufacturer to the pharmacy, mail order service, or other dispenser, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs), as described in paragraph (1)(A) or (2)(A), as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB35C1017549F4F879F543A1EE31CC570"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">hospitals, physicians, and other providers of services and suppliers with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug are described in subparagraph (B) of such section and are furnished or administered such drug, as described in paragraph (1)(B) or (2)(B), as applicable;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H02F4ED00432F470985EC376E1F6CF290"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufacturer, subject to subsection (d), submits to the Secretary, through an online portal established by the Secretary or other form and manner specified by the Secretary, for the negotiation period for the price applicability period (and, if applicable, before any period of renegotiation pursuant to section 1194(f)) with respect to such drug—</text><subparagraph id="H54EB4B61D7E04EB1AC147323003F03B2" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the non-Federal average manufacturer price for the drug for the applicable year or period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3A6325714CEE4B939EFA38B21A72A128"><enum>(B)</enum><text>all other information that the Secretary requires to carry out the negotiation (or renegotiation process) under this part, including information described in section 1194(e)(1); and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE979968A671C4A9E95C52E4B12B08E5A"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufacturer complies with requirements imposed by the Secretary for purposes of administering the program, including with respect to the duties described in section 1196.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF3128296A944F208E4FC994CC65A56C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Agreement in effect until drug is no longer a selected drug</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An agreement entered into under this section shall be effective, with respect to a selected drug, until such drug is no longer considered a selected drug under section 1192(c).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA548F1D5943145BA8C77B13D979F4E30"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Confidentiality of information</header><text>Information submitted to the Secretary under this part by a manufacturer of a selected drug that is proprietary information of such manufacturer (as determined by the Secretary) shall be used only by the Secretary or disclosed to and used by the Comptroller General of the United States or the Medicare Payment Advisory Commission for purposes of carrying out this part.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5B8D0FEE73CD4E579111397ED72A383C" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation for 2025 and 2026</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, the Secretary shall implement this section for 2025 and 2026 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3A3DBC8B8866414D9C24CDD2498E34E0"><enum>1194.</enum><header>Negotiation and renegotiation process</header><subsection id="H9CDEEF0E22C74154A8DB49C3828A50B6"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this part, under an agreement under section 1193 between the Secretary and a manufacturer of a selected drug, with respect to the period for which such agreement is in effect and in accordance with subsections (b), (c), and (d), the Secretary and the manufacturer—</text><paragraph id="HD5677401AA4C4564B32CAF4CBA6A8E27"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall during the negotiation period with respect to such drug, in accordance with this section, negotiate a maximum fair price for such drug for the purpose described in section 1193(a)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F2D687F2FE54AE9948A92F5C7D46DA6"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">renegotiate, in accordance with the process specified pursuant to subsection (f), such maximum fair price for such drug if such drug is a renegotiation-eligible drug under such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDBBFFD59A034230875C43E30ACE413E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Negotiation process requirements</header><paragraph id="H3C60CD8D656C4656B359F82F18B3ED6C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Methodology and process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall develop and use a consistent methodology and process, in accordance with paragraph (2), for negotiations under subsection (a) that aims to achieve the lowest maximum fair price for each selected drug.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA173CDCC48AB450AB1FAE664B19ED52E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Specific elements of negotiation process</header><text>As part of the negotiation process under this section, with respect to a selected drug and the negotiation period with respect to the initial price applicability year with respect to such drug, the following shall apply: </text><subparagraph id="H43803F73D4A44999B2DD7EC20D749B2B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Submission of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than March 1 of the year of the selected drug publication date, with respect to the selected drug, the manufacturer of the drug shall submit to the Secretary, in accordance with section 1193(a)(4), the information described in such section. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CBCE7AE68414D9BAD03DA044042722B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial offer by Secretary</header><text>Not later than the June 1 following the selected drug publication date, the Secretary shall provide the manufacturer of a selected drug with a written initial offer that contains the Secretary’s proposal for the maximum fair price of the drug and a list of the considerations described in section 1194(e) that were used in developing such offer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3CDE996CFE4A447D8905CA9277700099"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Response to initial offer</header><clause id="H123CF2714BF34E65854183C7E80A6F72"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the date of receipt of an initial offer under subparagraph (B), the manufacturer shall either accept such offer or propose a counteroffer to such offer.</text></clause><clause id="HC884BC19AAAB4A95A22F18422473377F" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Counteroffer requirements</header><text>If a manufacturer proposes a counteroffer, such counteroffer—</text><subclause id="HE0146F784423431A940377C48E31BB12" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be in writing; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD034DE49E7B54E7DA26856B99C1881B9" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>shall be justified based on the factors described in subsection (e).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFBD6E5730104FC896041BAD6E4DEFFF"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Response to counteroffer</header><text>After receiving a counteroffer under subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall respond in writing to such counteroffer.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FBABDC38AB44E849C2CDEACCFCB12EE"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Deadline</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All negotiations shall end prior to the first day of November following the selected drug publication date, with respect to the initial price applicability year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H03821E5AAFDF4986B6A097B3593C20BB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Limitations on offer amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In negotiating the maximum fair price of a selected drug, with respect to an initial price applicability year for the selected drug, and, as applicable, in renegotiating the maximum fair price for such drug, with respect to a subsequent year during the price applicability period for such drug, the Secretary shall not offer (or agree to a counteroffer for) a maximum fair price for the selected drug that—</text><clause id="HEDADCE4A26BD41AFB7FEE29B1E9F19E2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>exceeds the ceiling determined under subsection (c) for the selected drug and year; or</text></clause><clause id="HD3AEE9B166DB486EB45273EEEF2FB857"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as applicable, is less than the floor determined under subsection (d) for the selected drug and year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6066DF83DDA348C7AEC5E67F454BF556" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Treatment of determination</header><text>The establishment of a maximum fair price under this section is not subject to administrative or judicial review. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6259D52A17CA48CBB2308159F5B71D4E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ceiling for maximum fair price</header><paragraph id="H583EA16018824F4283CFC6FACB8E4BA5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The maximum fair price negotiated under this section for a selected drug, with respect to the first year of the price applicability period with respect to such drug, shall not exceed the applicable percent described in paragraph (2), with respect to such drug, of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H96C73EC48FED4CC0922E4AB21D2D34BE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Initial price applicability year 2025</header><text>In the case of a selected drug with respect to which such initial price applicability year is 2025, the average of the non-Federal average manufacturer price for such drug for the first 3 calendar quarters of 2021 (or, in the case that there is not a non-Federal average manufacturer price available for such drug for any of such first 3 calendar quarters of 2021, for the first full year following the market entry for such drug), increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) from September 2021 (or such first full year following the market entry), as applicable, to the year prior to the selected drug publication date with respect to such initial price applicability year. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H937572FA8BC541B282C25871F6A078E2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Initial price applicability year 2026 and subsequent years</header><text>In the case of a selected drug with respect to which such initial price applicability year is 2026 or a subsequent year, the lower of—</text><clause id="H7F6A9B9D6BAA4D3CBA18B9A131E48F43"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the average of the non-Federal average manufacturer price for such drug for the first 3 calendar quarters of 2021 (or, in the case that there is not a non-Federal average manufacturer price available for such drug for any of such first 3 calendar quarters of 2021, for the first full year following the market entry for such drug), increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) from September 2021 (or such first full year following the market entry), as applicable, to the year prior to the selected drug publication date with respect to such initial price applicability year; or</text></clause><clause id="H05B8F5085CE145C7A53CD8655DD009FE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the non-Federal average manufacturer price for such drug for the year prior to the selected drug publication date with respect to such initial price applicability year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H620DA649C8F24C288498BA6B44BD7953"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable percent described</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the applicable percent described in this paragraph is the following:</text><subparagraph id="HE996F10A5534442E9C9733443D5FBC8D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Short-monopoly drugs</header><text>With respect to a selected drug (other than a post-exclusivity drug and a long-monopoly drug), 75 percent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC01C17A7E4FA4D5AA965F86E531651B2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Post-exclusivity drugs</header><text>With respect to a post-exclusivity drug, 65 percent.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2FC10F264CDE4623816F8E0090011398"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Long-monopoly drugs</header><text>With respect to a long-monopoly drug, 40 percent.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D4748A4F2B74C9BADF18CCA2512A791" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Post-exclusivity drug defined</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9E0E80EF78634395820E1BA4F67AEC45"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this part, subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>post-exclusivity drug</term> means, with respect to an initial price applicability year, a selected drug for which at least 12 years, but fewer than 16 years, have elapsed since the date of approval of such drug under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or since the date of licensure of such drug under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1B53727C7E534863A5356C3EEF5511BD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>post-exclusivity drug</term> shall not include any of the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="HACF891F6BAA1457BA81E6A322C8155CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A vaccine that is licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act and marketed pursuant to such section.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H4503471BCABD489192BE1320F8C8F44C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>A selected drug that had an agreement under this part with the Secretary prior to the initial price applicability year 2030.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8E17CEF2BE454530B71B8ED760D95A32"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text>Nothing in subparagraph (B)(ii) shall limit the transition of a selected drug described in paragraph (2)(A) to a long-monopoly drug if the selected drug meets the definition of a long-monopoly drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6AE125735AF84F1BA22959C5B87FE247" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Long-monopoly drug defined</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H400CF496A56B47BCA00E4BC0F4CD02D6"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this part, subject to subparagraph (B), the term <term>long-monopoly drug</term> means, with respect to an initial price applicability year, a selected drug for which at least 16 years have elapsed since the date of approval of such drug under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or since the date of licensure of such drug under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act, as applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE738A7FC9E974DA99ACF2E1AC4538468"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text>The term <term>long-monopoly drug</term> shall not include a vaccine that is licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act and marketed pursuant to such section. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HACF4C816EF1240A394325A4AD94DB88F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Non-Federal average manufacturer price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this part, the term <term>non-Federal average manufacturer price</term> has the meaning given such term in section 8126(h)(5) of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06D8BE56A8BE44328A124CDE4D28C4A9" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Temporary floor for small biotech drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a selected drug that is a qualifying single source drug described in section 1192(d)(2) and with respect to which the first initial price applicability year of the price applicability period with respect to such drug is 2028 or 2029, the maximum fair price negotiated under this section for such drug for such initial price applicability year may not be less than 66 percent of the average of the non-Federal average manufacturer price for such drug (as defined and applied in subsection (c)(4)) for the first 3 calendar quarters of 2021 (or, in the case that there is not a non-Federal average manufacturer price available for such drug for any of such first 3 calendar quarters of 2021, for the first full year following the market entry for such drug), increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; United States city average) from September 2021 (or such first full year following the market entry), as applicable, to the year prior to the selected drug publication date with respect to the initial price applicability year. </text></subsection><subsection id="HED90707950AD4A4C977B02844E469B9F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>For purposes of negotiating the maximum fair price of a selected drug under this part with the manufacturer of the drug, the Secretary shall consider the following factors (and, with respect to post-exclusivity drugs and long-monopoly drugs, shall not consider factors other than those described in subparagraphs (B) and (C) of paragraph (1)):</text><paragraph id="H8D82D9B6B51E41C1A273EB16745DD3AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Manufacturer-specific information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The following information, with respect to such selected drug, including as submitted by the manufacturer:</text><subparagraph id="HF6389A714AB74283AC1B44CF9B4B4DBE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Research and development costs of the manufacturer for the drug and the extent to which the manufacturer has recouped research and development costs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F3DFC59A13444C5BC80078D59D898E9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Market data for the drug, including the distribution of sales across different programs and purchasers and projected future revenues for the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H101DC20C2536405B921E5E351914253C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Unit costs of production and distribution of the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE73670654FB455188EEF0650B58F7F3"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Prior Federal financial support for novel therapeutic discovery and development with respect to the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB4751D131D94D54805866353E0DF5F7"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Data on patents and on existing and pending exclusivity for the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5FDBE33A23D7465E8C9656F0671B5D75" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>National sales data for the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6B45CDBF6E724808BF57A25141E57838"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on clinical trials for the drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H773FBCA1D27E4713BEA7C92173D8BE40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on unmet medical needs and alternative treatments</header><text>The following information, with respect to such selected drug:</text><subparagraph id="HC939346DAD0248E9AF54C36E8FCC3694" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the drug represents a therapeutic advance as compared to existing therapeutic alternatives and, to the extent such information is available, the costs of such existing therapeutic alternatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B2555AD5432477CB92DC1B41C8181A4" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information on approval by the Food and Drug Administration of alternative drug products or biological products.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7B9BA84B0664F279344F3615065B9C4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on comparative effectiveness analysis for such products, taking into consideration the effects of such products on specific populations, such as individuals with disabilities, the elderly, the terminally ill, children, and other patient populations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8230F50F94DD45AEA1ECDB669FF0EA12" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The extent to which the drug addresses unmet medical needs for a condition for which treatment or diagnosis is not addressed adequately by available therapy.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">In considering information described in subparagraph (C), the Secretary shall not use evidence or findings from comparative clinical effectiveness research in a manner that treats extending the life of an elderly, disabled, or terminally ill individual as of lower value than extending the life of an individual who is younger, nondisabled, or not terminally ill. </continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H73145BD972984295B3BEBF9F647847F3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Additional information</header><text>Information submitted to the Secretary, in accordance with a process specified by the Secretary, by other parties that are affected by the establishment of a maximum fair price for the selected drug.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7468CDBFAFD843F48E92FE9713C08E4F" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Renegotiation process</header><paragraph id="HD39A0CE2E1344400AFDB30948E1299D4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of a renegotiation-eligible drug (as defined in paragraph (2)) that is selected under paragraph (3), the Secretary shall provide for a process of renegotiation (for years (beginning with 2027) during the price applicability period, with respect to such drug) of the maximum fair price for such drug consistent with paragraph (4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCDE36FB189944404A58872179C686990" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Renegotiation-eligible drug defined</header><text>In this section, the term <term>renegotiation-eligible drug</term> means a selected drug that is any of the following: </text><subparagraph id="H5253CBE1D7BA4242AAC905E7E8E4B3C4" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Addition of new indication</header><text>A selected drug for which a new indication is added to the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H53B28D15F90141E09205FE37FB9C021E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Change of status to a post-exclusivity drug</header><text>A selected drug that is described in section 1192(d)(1)(A) that—</text><clause commented="no" id="H72E2AF1CDDE8432BA11044B6D1CE182E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not a post-exclusivity drug or a long-monopoly drug; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HE13F83FF20C2480EBECBEEEED6DE5345"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which there is a change in status to that of a post-exclusivity drug. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA167294D5C2C4E5FA91E0488807F43F1" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Change of status to a long-monopoly drug</header><text>A selected drug that is described in section 1192(d)(1)(A) that—</text><clause id="H7E2159ED29404AB99D3C1480A945030A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is not a long-monopoly drug; and</text></clause><clause id="HE08561385AEF47B8AA02BD04B4084817"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for which there is a change in status to that of a long-monopoly drug.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD0417AC97EB24A62A0E7F1B888CF8D1D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Material changes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A selected drug for which the Secretary determines there has been a material change of factors described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H673C579F6E744D73AD0825BABE536C92" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Selection of drugs for renegotiation</header><text>Each year the Secretary shall select among renegotiation-eligible drugs for renegotiation as follows: </text><subparagraph id="H80E1DAA4799B45E9BB8995AEC0E74B04"><enum>(A)</enum><header>All post-exclusivity negotiation-eligible drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select all renegotiation-eligible drugs described in paragraph (2)(B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9BD8B1C9CEE24A829E217802F7EFB9B1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>All long-monopoly negotiation-eligible drugs</header><text>The Secretary shall select all renegotiation-eligible drugs described in paragraph (2)(C).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF677A43DD1A6450AAE28C630EC39EF2E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Remaining drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Among the remaining renegotiation-eligible drugs described in subparagraphs (A) and (D) of paragraph (2), the Secretary shall select renegotiation-eligible drugs for which the Secretary expects renegotiation is likely to result in a significant change in the maximum fair price otherwise negotiated. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H567E441A14FF4818A242F751BDD0214F" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Renegotiation process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall specify the process for renegotiation of maximum fair prices with the manufacturer of a renegotiation-eligible drug selected for renegotiation under this subsection. Such process shall, to the extent practicable, be consistent with the methodology and process established under subsection (b) and in accordance with subsections (c) and (d), and for purposes of applying subsections (c) and (d), the reference to the first initial price applicability year of the price applicability period with respect to such drug shall be treated as the first initial price applicability year of such period for which the maximum fair price established pursuant to such renegotiation applies, including for applying subsection (c)(2)(B) in the case of renegotiation-eligible drugs described in paragraph (3)(A) of this subsection and subsection (c)(2)(C) in the case of renegotiation-eligible drugs described in paragraph (3)(B) of this subsection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCFFC44B0E2E041AC8443FD61B313A02C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A renegotiation-eligible drug for which the Secretary makes a determination described in section 1192(c)(1) before or during the period of renegotiation shall not be subject to the renegotiation process under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H427B6F5F3C414867922EB31B3EE409B0"><enum>(6)</enum><header>No administrative or judicial review</header><text>The determination of renegotiation-eligible drugs under paragraph (2) and the selection of renegotiation-eligible drugs under paragraph (3) are not subject to administrative or judicial review. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB91A694EB3264D8FB98F6F1C9378C348"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Request for information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of negotiating and, as applicable, renegotiating (including for purposes of determining whether to renegotiate) the maximum fair price of a selected drug under this part with the manufacturer of the drug, with respect to a price applicability period, and other relevant data for purposes of this section—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HE025011529F94C38B0E6153D44D75E16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary shall, not later than the selected drug publication date with respect to the initial price applicability year of such period, request drug pricing information from the manufacturer of such selected drug, including information described in subsection (e)(1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H0ABA3A6E214E423182306D8D12268A1B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by not later than March 1 following the selected drug publication date, the manufacturer of such selected drug shall submit to the Secretary such requested information in such form and manner as the Secretary requires.</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">The Secretary shall request, from the manufacturer or others, all additional information needed to carry out the negotiation and renegotiation process under this section. </continuation-text></subsection><subsection id="H3D3ED64185FB4901ADBE694D4DC40782"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In no case shall the maximum fair price negotiated under this section for a selected drug that is a qualifying single source drug described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1192(e)(1) apply before—</text><paragraph id="H4A3465B3D14947D390C17ACE884B2E7C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case the selected drug is a qualifying single source drug described in such subparagraph (A), the date that is 9 years after the date on which the drug was approved under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB0F6416F10E54527BB5CA8C82EC76306"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case the selected drug is a qualifying single source drug described in such subparagraph (B), the date that is 13 years after the date on which the drug was licensed under section 351(a) of the Public Health Service Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5EC4E418A3E04F6287CFEFD694ABE33E" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Implementation for 2025 and 2026</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, the Secretary shall implement this section for 2025 and 2026 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection></section><section id="H60B99E92650B4280BE3FA3127EF8F450"><enum>1195.</enum><header>Publication of maximum fair prices</header><subsection id="H76301F6E5206486DBD7FAC617406B0A7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to an initial price applicability year and a selected drug with respect to such year—</text><paragraph id="HF404E09E798742D585B9945E5BC7C36A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than November 15 of the year that is 2 years prior to such initial price applicability year, the Secretary shall publish on CMS.gov the maximum fair price for such drug negotiated under this part with the manufacturer of such drug;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE774339753FD496E838C9405FFC202C5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than November 30 of the year that is 2 years prior to such initial price applicability year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the maximum fair price for such drug described in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8CB643C6C9C4D9990EBE674071F59E4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">not later than March 1 of the year prior to such initial price applicability year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register, subject to section 1193(c) and based on the considerations as described in section 1194(e), the explanation for the maximum fair price for such drug described in paragraphs (1) and (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20766E57A8F24761A06EF555EB07C4EA"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Updates</header><paragraph id="H856C37A82CB449559D6C9BD0AE137F44"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Subsequent year maximum fair prices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For a selected drug, for each year subsequent to first initial price applicability year of the price applicability period with respect to such drug, with respect to which an agreement for such drug is in effect under section 1193, not later than November 30 of the year that is 2 years prior to such subsequent year, the Secretary shall publish in the Federal Register the maximum fair price applicable to such drug and year, which shall be—</text><subparagraph id="H5E04309B835F40C49255A1A265B71FAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>subject to subparagraph (B), the amount equal to the maximum fair price published for such drug for the previous year, increased by the annual percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (all items; U.S. city average) as of September of such previous year; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A9563603C874B6D9D63C83FA4F8C87A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case the maximum fair price for such drug was renegotiated, for the first year for which such price as so renegotiated applies, such renegotiated maximum fair price.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDCE0AA1389B14EA09F22CE3ADB00EC8E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prices negotiated after deadline</header><text>In the case of a selected drug with respect to an initial price applicability year for which the maximum fair price is determined under this part after the date of publication under this section, the Secretary shall publish such maximum fair price in the Federal Register by not later than 30 days after the date such maximum price is so determined.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HCDADD4E776EA4D4ABCB6B2B942E11F53"><enum>1196.</enum><header>Administrative duties; coordination provisions</header><subsection id="H678B214FDCA4440A844DB82663089596"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Administrative duties</header><paragraph id="H5CFF7DB055BE4069ACC8E944096C55FC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of section 1191, the administrative duties described in this section are the following:</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC75CC8021B1645ECBC7FEEF7BE46BC51"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The establishment of procedures to ensure that the maximum fair price for a selected drug is applied before—</text><clause id="H306FBDDDF2FB4EBF9F637CB1C8EB6779"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any coverage or financial assistance under other health benefit plans or programs that provide coverage or financial assistance for the purchase or provision of prescription drug coverage on behalf of maximum fair price eligible individuals; and</text></clause><clause id="HA8ADCEB1A3AE4E648CDBE152E89460F3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other discounts.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00310C4B72BC4C6CA0D36B5F53996441"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment of procedures to compute and apply the maximum fair price across different strengths and dosage forms of a selected drug and not based on the specific formulation or package size or package type of the drug.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D0E5742DAF94C4196AA2EA39E884D0D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The establishment of procedures to carry out the provisions of this part, as applicable, with respect to—</text><clause id="H4B2FF411F8854BEE875C138B268A0782"><enum>(i)</enum><text>maximum fair price eligible individuals who are enrolled under a prescription drug plan under part D of title XVIII or an MA–PD plan under part C of such title; and</text></clause><clause id="H7D695D15EC464A868340A0393DDCFC4C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>maximum fair price eligible individuals who are enrolled under part B of such title, including who are enrolled under an MA plan under part C of such title.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD974DFD1F65146E58F3B10B86D657A03"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The establishment of a negotiation process and renegotiation process in accordance with section 1194, including a process for acquiring information described in subsection (e) of such section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1404B02CE46443F18964B21218AD4F6B"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment of an online portal which manufacturers shall be required to use to submit information described in section 1194(b)(2)(A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H933EB86C635A482BB0F315665BC2268B"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The sharing with the Secretary of the Treasury of such information as is necessary to determine the tax imposed by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4192">section 4192</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 (relating to enforcement of this part).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC81071338F9A4B93B0DACFECDC7E056E"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The establishment of an attestation and verification process for purposes of applying section 1192(d)(2)(B). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEF0CCC2C6704035BB6D21DC5F6F4661"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monitoring compliance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall monitor compliance by a manufacturer with the terms of an agreement under section 1193, including by establishing a mechanism through which violations of such terms shall be reported.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4E0A139E466B4FAABB73F5B389539721" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation for 2025 and 2026</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding any other provision of this part, the Secretary shall implement this section for 2025 and 2026 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection></section><section id="HDF94CD768B494439BAB814F45D852E87"><enum>1197.</enum><header>Civil monetary penalty</header><subsection id="H289D3014969243FC98786F6F82B5C4A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Violations relating to offering of maximum fair price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any manufacturer of a selected drug that has entered into an agreement under section 1193, with respect to a year during the price applicability period with respect to such drug, that does not provide access to a price that is not more than the maximum fair price (or a lesser price) for such drug for such year—</text><paragraph id="H71BF2A7F7579407BA10187FFFD64A2B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to a maximum fair price eligible individual who with respect to such drug is described in subparagraph (A) of section 1191(c)(1) and who is dispensed such drug during such year (and to pharmacies, mail order services, and other dispensers, with respect to such maximum fair price eligible individuals who are dispensed such drugs); or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H745DB1FF0BF34D65A00850EC525EF55D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to a hospital, physician, or other provider of services or supplier with respect to maximum fair price eligible individuals who with respect to such drug is described in subparagraph (B) of such section and is furnished or administered such drug by such hospital, physician, or provider or supplier during such year,</text></paragraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subsection">shall be subject to a civil monetary penalty equal to ten times the amount equal to the product of the number of units of such drug so furnished, dispensed, or administered during such year and the difference between the price for such drug made available for such year by such manufacturer with respect to such individual or hospital, physician, provider of services, or supplier and the maximum fair price for such drug for such year. </continuation-text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HC1F63D7E78B8433AADB9939D5DD7664C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Violations of certain terms of agreement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any manufacturer of a selected drug that has entered into an agreement under section 1193, with respect to a year during the price applicability period with respect to such drug, that is in violation of a requirement imposed pursuant to section 1193(a)(5), including the requirement to submit information pursuant to section 1193(a)(4), shall be subject to a civil monetary penalty equal to $1,000,000 for each day of such violation. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEBD73D1B71F04D929C27438E30A9A7F4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>False information</header><text>Any manufacturer that knowingly provides false information for the attestation process or verification process established pursuant to section 1196(a)(1)(H), shall be subject to a civil monetary penalty equal to $100,000,000 for each item of such false information.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE9BFF08EB4764299A8B386D3DC1ADF78"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil monetary penalty under this section in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H7F4FE6CEC0DD4D63BDEEF8F87457C22D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application of maximum fair prices and conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HBB5D053914CF497F8A5BEBFF4E222D12"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Under Medicare</header><subparagraph id="H264FF735793D4A5580D2D5C86DB5A386"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Application to payments under part B</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1847A(b)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(b)(1)(B)) is amended by inserting <quote>or in the case of such a drug or biological that is a selected drug (as referred to in section 1192(c)), with respect to a price applicability period (as defined in section 1191(b)(2)), 106 percent of the maximum fair price (as defined in section 1191(c)(2)) applicable for such drug and a year during such period</quote> after <quote>paragraph (4)</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H755D276E794840AC8237C9C9ED37167F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application under MA of cost-sharing for part B drugs based off of negotiated price</header><text>Section 1852(a)(1)(B)(iv) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-22">42 U.S.C. 1395w–22(a)(1)(B)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="H4191F10253B349D29515564BCBA0860F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by redesignating subclause (VII) as subclause (VIII); and</text></clause><clause id="H6A766B81019140379AC9F059465A39AE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting after subclause (VI) the following subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H04E2A221D9DB4870AD83B07216210F13" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="H500D93D27C56499883B73F0CC174BDCD"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A drug or biological that is a selected drug (as referred to in section 1192(c)).</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9812A82EFE2D4CD7A4FB98EE412E9DB9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exception to part D non-interference</header><text>Section 1860D–11(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="H25FFB97CEFA744DE898BEDCA676BA579"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; </text></clause><clause id="H6E6FABFD189C4EFAA6A3353D6D0F3D23"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>or institute a price structure for the reimbursement of covered part D drugs</quote> and inserting <quote>for covered part D drugs; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HC43DB4580C3848AAA720EEDDD6C48978"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HAC081D4E522C4F6F8250B2AE9C3D62B4"><paragraph id="H0AFD06978AE8421A8455AE53C254CE20"><enum>(3)</enum><text>may not institute a price structure for the reimbursement of covered part D drugs, except as provided under part E of title XI.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3FB63A6ACE45441FA0D0306783CB39CA"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application as negotiated price under part D</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–2(d)(1) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(d)(1)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="H8C73F9F8B2014419B9E7913EB0BA47E5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>, subject to subparagraph (D),</quote> after <quote>negotiated prices</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H6043D8948E6A4E0FBA4BF230936A4004"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H98D751AE126640528902867FF951B8DE" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H3C0D4E7BA9B04190B527D806798B6116"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Application of maximum fair price for selected drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In applying this section, in the case of a covered part D drug that is a selected drug (as referred to in section 1192(c)), with respect to a price applicability period (as defined in section 1191(b)(2)), the negotiated prices used for payment (as described in this subsection) shall be no greater than the maximum fair price (as defined in section 1191(c)(2)) for such drug and for each year during such period plus any dispensing fees for such drug.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E3C11BED1594AC5A0D6254661E8CF1D"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Coverage of selected drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–4(b)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-104">42 U.S.C. 1395w–104(b)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5E452451E7CC4DA5AF9E199678F1D479" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H6AA5399F22AB432886FF24FBABA91185"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Required inclusion of selected drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For 2025 and each subsequent year, the PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan shall include each covered part D drug that is a selected drug under section 1192 for which an agreement for such drug is in effect under section 1193 with respect to the year.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC449928D3704FB3811A9245F397E4DB"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Information from prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans required</header><clause id="HF1CE79E4391B41B5AC2F49958A2D5163"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Prescription drug plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–12(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-112">42 U.S.C. 1395w–112(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3D226758D16140D3A7EA38C752DC191B" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H1CE75660C1644AB9B24CA79D5450A38B"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Provision of information related to maximum fair prices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each contract entered into with a PDP sponsor under this part with respect to a prescription drug plan offered by such sponsor shall require the sponsor to provide information to the Secretary as requested by the Secretary in accordance with section 1194(g).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H9A022D0A343E4B0B9CE432B1B44AEE84"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>MA–PD plans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1857(f)(3) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-27">42 U.S.C. 1395w–27(f)(3)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3356AD58C6974E4FB265DA80304572EB" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H13BF04D5DFAF448BBD3116472D3AEC92"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Provision of information related to maximum fair prices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–12(b)(8).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E407AB7DAE745B48252BDC302E8E328" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Drug price negotiation program prices included in best price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(c)(1)(C) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(c)(1)(C)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HC6A19A1FE4F449918785B7C0FDB7BDEE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in clause (i)(VI), by striking <quote>any prices charged</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to clause (ii)(V), any prices charged</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF938924030C4EE4A41F6BD42628D3B0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii)—</text><clause id="H03F7DD73A7EF488D8D971438744ED32F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subclause (III), by striking at the end <quote>; and</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H4E3A4A7C8BB545938FC1708C3E2ADE80" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subclause (IV), by striking at the end the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HB393159064334E328D343EC65CDD3FE7" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA284097E19C348C9B100A6DB80B37360"><subclause id="H82058CB36DC24F9782C86D28033F98F1" commented="no"><enum>(V)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a rebate period and a covered outpatient drug that is a selected drug (as referred to in section 1192(c)) during such rebate period, shall be inclusive of the maximum fair price (as defined in section 1191(c)(2)) for such drug with respect to such period.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HB725839030F4457DA07251D200F3E402" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>102.</enum><header>Selected drug manufacturer excise tax imposed during noncompliance periods</header><subsection id="HC6229EC3B2AA4271A5E3724DB7D1474F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/32">Chapter 32</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new subchapter:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H4E1DA319A87C410EA1F1087398236C39" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subchapter id="H7FD541E051F94A678E8E72ED7BE14DF5"><enum>E</enum><header>Other items</header><toc container-level="subchapter-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" idref="H7FD541E051F94A678E8E72ED7BE14DF5" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H6F58C84ABA4747DA866053963959B7AE" level="section">Sec. 4192. Selected drugs during noncompliance periods.</toc-entry></toc><section id="H6F58C84ABA4747DA866053963959B7AE"><enum>4192.</enum><header>Selected drugs during noncompliance periods</header><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE642207262314749BA5B0C86A542766F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is hereby imposed on the sale by the manufacturer, producer, or importer of any selected drug during a day described in subsection (b) a tax in an amount such that the applicable percentage is equal to the ratio of—</text><paragraph id="H5EF2214770ED4D32BB2549FAC4329355"><enum>(1)</enum><text>such tax, divided by</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D51363F4FF54816B60F08846C89D142"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the sum of such tax and the price for which so sold.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2BE182B9479E478782CB3CE7715E6AFD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Noncompliance periods</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A day is described in this subsection with respect to a selected drug if it is a day during one of the following periods:</text><paragraph id="HE4C7A05DB69E4F0D869C072B9AA86F5A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The period beginning on the March 1st immediately following the selected drug publication date and ending on the first date during which the manufacturer of the drug has in place an agreement described in subsection (a) of section 1193 of the Social Security Act with respect to such drug.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBBC7069C09E04508B365FD0FE44E7C03"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The period beginning on the November 2nd immediately following the March 1st described in paragraph (1) and ending on the first date during which the manufacturer of the drug and the Secretary have agreed to a maximum fair price under such agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AC35BBD445344CD8C8DD938FD9527AD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a selected drug with respect to which the Secretary of Health and Human Services has specified a renegotiation period under such agreement, the period beginning on the first date after the last date of such renegotiation period and ending on the first date during which the manufacturer of the drug has agreed to a renegotiated maximum fair price under such agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90023B2C542C401DBAFFBAA6FD68D801"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to information that is required to be submitted to the Secretary of Health and Human Services under such agreement, the period beginning on the date on which such Secretary certifies that such information is overdue and ending on the date that such information is so submitted.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8B13DD6297F54A33857B9E58848EB59E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicable percentage</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>applicable percentage</term> means—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="H8EED3A20769641B5A8191095E3578F3B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the case of sales of a selected drug during the first 90 days described in subsection (b) with respect to such drug, 65 percent,</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H128A9B4B74944A028C6C9D4249FF3220"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case of sales of such drug during the 91st day through the 180th day described in subsection (b) with respect to such drug, 75 percent,</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8304DFA59B574FBEB92149CBF25EAC42"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in the case of sales of such drug during the 181st day through the 270th day described in subsection (b) with respect to such drug, 85 percent, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H94C652B2900C461EA35055B4863B785B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>in the case of sales of such drug during any subsequent day, 95 percent.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F60D608387E478DAF6F3ADD9AD15CA1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selected drug</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="H7EA4F99FCEED4ADDB61BC423B128CE09"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>selected drug</term> means any selected drug (within the meaning of section 1192 of the Social Security Act) which is manufactured or produced in the United States or entered into the United States for consumption, use, or warehousing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0F2A700AC83246AE9590D18E3259A1BE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>United States</header><text>The term <term>United States</term> has the meaning given such term by section 4612(a)(4).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD175F6F77D46AE9F4AC1D593FE5FBE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with rules for possessions of the United States</header><text>Rules similar to the rules of paragraphs (2) and (4) of section 4132(c) shall apply for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H143F8C573FFB40B5B660CFD9FBD72244"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Other definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the terms <term>selected drug publication date</term> and <term>maximum fair price</term> have the meaning given such terms in section 1191 of the Social Security Act.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HFC530E970664434A99A2B3B61D5E05E5"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Anti-Abuse rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a sale which was timed for the purpose of avoiding the tax imposed by this section, the Secretary may treat such sale as occurring during a day described in subsection (b).</text></subsection></section></subchapter><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H0089747C8E2A470AA574E9B1F912EBEC"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No deduction for excise tax payments</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/275">Section 275(a)(6)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by inserting <quote>or by section 4192</quote> before the period at the end.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1CC534D9DA3A40F19D9176E1E99791A0"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Certain exemptions from tax not applicable</header><paragraph id="HD2A35E7523714EC49FE9636802DF6107"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/4221">Section 4221(a)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In the case of the tax imposed by section 4192, paragraphs (3), (4), (5), and (6) shall not apply.</quote>. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H173A1B70A37B4B58B5D5DD299C50EAB5"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 6416(b)(2) of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>In the case of the tax imposed by section 4192, subparagraphs (B), (C), (D), and (E) shall not apply.</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H186F03AE79D84FD08B5EB4A8A9DE236B"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of subchapters for chapter 32 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H279EB96F91634BBB83F13D9CEA3FF52B" style="OLC"><toc><toc-entry bold="off" level="subchapter">Subchapter E. Other items</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H031B2A551D614E20BE399B2CA7F39AE8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to sales after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9C451A5801C240F8ADFB9D8C44A1D2AB" commented="no"><enum>103.</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there is appropriated for fiscal year 2022, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, to remain available until expended—</text><paragraph id="H76D8331AE1744EEBB44D7B9D218D7B3A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2022;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B21A1480FDC4EE7BD013F2E94457F60" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2023;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA52B5BD65DE14739AED22EA02D1F5152" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2024;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAFC3CBAA13AA4E5D9FCA1D179553FF69" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2025; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC037B6B50A6045E2A2C2BF52F23037E0" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2026;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D615479986E4B42BCD1CFE0CFB0EFA1" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2027;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B2880D491AC4685AE490AAC2A42E936" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2028;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H92CF64D04D5745C7A45FC0D6C2E89F16" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2029;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18B4E428ABDE4DCB81F6C43D5E9B6F2D" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2030; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F68F4B2890E4AF6B3A565FBC31A7FA2" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$300,000,000 to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this part in fiscal year 2031.</text></paragraph></section></title><title id="HAADAC0F62F8A42CA8F41C2687D01ED5A"><enum>II</enum><header>Prescription Drug Inflation Rebates</header><section id="H83232D2EE0914B19B8F35AD655492356"><enum>201.</enum><header>Medicare part B rebate by manufacturers</header><subsection id="HF792D3BAB1B14873B0263BFB8928FC40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1847A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-3a">42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCE558537AB57445583CA7C08FFD0D845"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (h) as subsection (i) and by inserting after subsection (g) the following subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HBDE3C89D22F044B2B2807DC3B9FA410C" style="OLC"><subsection id="H19B7A29ED5384BF99D05F46B1BBF2317"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Rebate by manufacturers for single source drugs and biologicals with prices increasing faster than inflation</header><paragraph id="HC9FDE4D6BB69431EA520E13A84F73E25"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA23AF206329B4C2088A4ABDB22F176F8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretarial provision of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the end of each calendar quarter beginning on or after July 1, 2023, the Secretary shall, for each part B rebatable drug, report to each manufacturer of such part B rebatable drug the following for such calendar quarter:</text><clause id="H7B58F7C5A76249F48F3CA13849D85668"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the total number of billing units of the billing and payment code described in subparagraph (A)(i) of paragraph (3) with respect to such drug and calendar quarter.</text></clause><clause id="H4BAB7B9939324C7E8E091326F4292823"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Information on the amount (if any) of the excess average sales price increase described in subparagraph (A)(ii) of such paragraph for such drug and calendar quarter.</text></clause><clause id="H86565DE3F59D44C4806E607B7992C498"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The rebate amount specified under such paragraph for such part B rebatable drug and calendar quarter.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47B26F8176A043D5B92603B8E437E2BE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Manufacturer requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each calendar quarter beginning on or after July 1, 2023, the manufacturer of a part B rebatable drug shall, for such drug, not later than 30 days after the date of receipt from the Secretary of the information described in subparagraph (A) for such calendar quarter, provide to the Secretary a rebate that is equal to the amount specified in paragraph (3) for such drug for such calendar quarter. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H8AC2D5EF68594E6C8D61045CC543942B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Part B rebatable drug defined</header><subparagraph id="H0EB1E0C2F3394430A928CD3BB8B69288"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>part B rebatable drug</term> means a single source drug or biological (as defined in subparagraph (D) of subsection (c)(6)), including a biosimilar biological product (as defined in subparagraph (H) of such subsection) but excluding a qualifying biosimilar biological product (as defined in subsection (b)(8)(B)(iii)), that would be payable under this part if such drug were furnished to an individual enrolled under this part, except such term shall not include such a drug or biological—</text><clause commented="no" id="H010ED8EBA85542A4886842CEB49F1F03"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if, as determined by the Secretary, the average total allowed charges for such drug or biological under this part for a year per individual that uses such a drug or biological are less than, subject to subparagraph (B), $100; or</text></clause><clause id="H6ED46C8B7DB349C1970ECFA3108B45B0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that is a vaccine described in subparagraph (A) or (B) of section 1861(s)(10).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H14D9504C10084BA4BDD11053D03ECB41"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>The dollar amount applied under subparagraph (A)(i)—</text><clause commented="no" id="HF3BD101EE5E04777B44D23D9104B6992"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024, shall be the dollar amount specified under such subparagraph for 2023, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period ending with June of the previous year; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HFBFC0905AED74C748DA8521BC73C08E5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a subsequent year, shall be the dollar amount specified in this clause (or clause (i)) for the previous year (without application of subparagraph (C)), increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period ending with June of the previous year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC48FEF88C18C45B0AE13A18B9E3CEBDB"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>Any dollar amount determined under subparagraph (B) that is not a multiple of $10 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $10.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF1F854DAA76946A9B69530F758C2F51D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rebate amount</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H7F658A41FAD24968BEE0991F2B038E4C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of paragraph (1), the amount specified in this paragraph for a part B rebatable drug assigned to a billing and payment code for a calendar quarter is, subject to subparagraphs (B) and (G) and paragraph (4), the amount equal to the product of—</text><clause commented="no" id="H0B9216C80B344A0C8BC82DE23735B8F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of billing units determined under subparagraph (B) for the billing and payment code of such drug; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0AA3C3F8982749DE9005E5A1E4941312"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount (if any) by which—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H3FE2C4A923E64E0CB952148F96A079AB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount equal to—</text><item id="H5B4BDA08D595497BBC717393B7BBC5DA"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>in the case of a part B rebatable drug described in paragraph (1)(B) of section 1847A(b), 106 percent of the amount determined under paragraph (4) of such section for such drug during the calendar quarter; or</text></item><item id="H9BCEB1A4A8B345ECB0A8C223EBE97EE9"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in the case of a part B rebatable drug described in paragraph (1)(C) of such section, the payment amount under such paragraph for such drug during the calendar quarter; exceeds </text></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H6DEAA8788D974A77B4DD1BF2D231BB28"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the inflation-adjusted payment amount determined under subparagraph (C) for such part B rebatable drug during the calendar quarter.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7D0BBA0614544A0C81489155D2983259"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Total number of billing units</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the total number of billing units with respect to a part B rebatable drug is determined as follows:</text><clause id="H34A75227340B44A7AA7367A86FA788CB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Determine the total number of units equal to—</text><subclause id="HFFA43755E35048E1A1260ECA08C2EA5D"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of units, as reported under subsection (c)(1)(B) for each National Drug Code of such drug during the calendar quarter that is two calendar quarters prior to the calendar quarter as described in subparagraph (A), minus</text></subclause><subclause id="H4D8036D624C6416D8CF35B0A975DC13B"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of units with respect to each National Drug Code of such drug for which payment was made under a State plan under title XIX (or waiver of such plan), as reported by States under section 1927(b)(2)(A) for the rebate period that is the same calendar quarter as described in subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H80713BD691224C05A976CABF64C2FF7D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Convert the units determined under clause (i) to billing units for the billing and payment code of such drug, using a methodology similar to the methodology used under this section, by dividing the units determined under clause (i) for each National Drug Code of such drug by the billing unit for the billing and payment code of such drug.</text></clause><clause id="H999B1756EE31485ABB796CA33CE8D5ED"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Compute the sum of the billing units for each National Drug Code of such drug in clause (ii). </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9ABAD9C8842F43E39EDC206F42CDEFE9"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Determination of inflation-adjusted payment amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The inflation-adjusted payment amount determined under this subparagraph for a part B rebatable drug for a calendar quarter is—</text><clause id="HF02D726582814DE781B25601AD0EC2EA"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the payment amount for the billing and payment code for such drug in the payment amount benchmark quarter (as defined in subparagraph (D)); increased by</text></clause><clause id="H15D22B403A55485DBE11CC2EFFFDA982"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage by which the rebate period CPI–U (as defined in subparagraph (F)) for the calendar quarter exceeds the benchmark period CPI–U (as defined in subparagraph (E)).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABC620A6FB4F4FB6B345487A5941BB7B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Payment amount benchmark quarter</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>payment amount benchmark quarter</term> means the calendar quarter immediately prior to the calendar quarter beginning October 1, 2021.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1AAFADA185874AD380CF57A48D9C2638"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Benchmark period CPI–U</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>benchmark period CPI–U</term> means the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the last month of the calendar quarter beginning October 1, 2021.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CD53B70E1024A02AAE5E8EBFACC1E51"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rebate period CPI–U</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>rebate period CPI–U</term> means, with respect to a calendar quarter described in subparagraph (C), the greater of the benchmark period CPI–U and the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the first month of the calendar quarter that is two calendar quarters prior to such described calendar quarter.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BC784E75B4E4C2FB61C93E27389C800"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Exemption for shortages and severe supply chain disruptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reduce or waive the amount under subparagraph (A) with respect to a part B rebatable drug that is described as currently in shortage on the shortage list in effect under section 506E of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or in the case of a biosimilar biological product, when the Secretary determines there are severe supply chain disruptions. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H55650838D8D147FE90CC143C7523B402"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Special treatment of certain drugs and exemption</header><subparagraph id="HB7D34D8243F8429692697B317FF3D1B5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Subsequently approved drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part B rebatable drug first approved or licensed by the Food and Drug Administration after March 1, 2021, clause (i) of paragraph (3)(C) shall be applied as if the term <term>payment amount benchmark quarter</term> were defined under paragraph (3)(D) as the third full calendar quarter after the day on which the drug was first marketed and clause (ii) of paragraph (3)(C) shall be applied as if the term <term>benchmark period CPI–U</term> were defined under paragraph (3)(E) as if the reference to <quote>the last month of the calendar quarter immediately prior to the calendar quarter beginning October 1, 2021</quote> under such paragraph were a reference to <quote>the first month of the first full calendar quarter after the day on which the drug was first marketed</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9ED230C32E2940EEACEBA3FFBEA33BBB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Timeline for provision of rebates for subsequently approved drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part B rebatable drug first approved or licensed by the Food and Drug Administration after March 1, 2021, paragraph (1)(B) shall be applied as if the reference to <quote>July 1, 2023</quote> under such paragraph were a reference to the later of the 6th full calendar quarter after the day on which the drug was first marketed or July 1, 2023.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H788AA64AED6849DEA4DC91D01A2EAD28"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Selected drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part B rebatable drug that is a selected drug (as defined in section 1192(c)) for a price applicability period (as defined in section 1191(b)(2)), in the case such drug is determined (pursuant to such section 1192(c)) to no longer be a selected drug, beginning the first calendar quarter after the price applicability period with respect to such drug, clause (i) of paragraph (3)(C) shall be applied as if the term <term>payment amount benchmark quarter</term> were defined under paragraph (3)(D) as the calendar quarter beginning January 1 of the last year beginning during such price applicability period with respect to such selected drug and clause (ii) of paragraph (3)(C) shall be applied as if the term <term>benchmark period CPI–U</term> were defined under paragraph (3)(E) as if the reference to <quote>the last month of the calendar quarter immediately prior to the calendar quarter beginning October 1, 2021</quote> under such paragraph were a reference to the March of the year preceding such last year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H64DEAAFC371C4857B14778F58305298E"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Application to beneficiary coinsurance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part B rebatable drug, if the payment amount described in paragraph (3)(A)(ii)(I) (or, in the case of a part B rebatable drug that is a selected drug (as defined in section 1192(c)), the payment amount described in subsection (b)(1)(B) for such drug) for a calendar quarter exceeds the inflation adjusted payment for such quarter—</text><subparagraph id="H068A06C91DC84784B29F7AEE171F6DB9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in computing the amount of any coinsurance applicable under this part to an individual to whom such drug is furnished, the computation of such coinsurance shall be equal to 20 percent of the inflation-adjusted payment amount determined under paragraph (3)(C) for such part B rebatable drug; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCEEA452DB6CB4E6C97E49629013BE284"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the amount of such coinsurance for such calendar quarter, as computed under subparagraph (A), shall be applied as a percent, as determined by the Secretary, to the payment amount that would otherwise apply under subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE20501BC8F774F64B0AA8AB42686CBB6"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rebate deposits</header><text>Amounts paid as rebates under paragraph (1)(B) shall be deposited into the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1841.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8FFD897AA9F5468FB89E5A1E54B8E664"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Civil money penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a manufacturer of a part B rebatable drug has failed to comply with the requirements under paragraph (1)(B) for such drug for a calendar quarter, the manufacturer shall be subject to, in accordance with a process established by the Secretary pursuant to regulations, a civil money penalty in an amount equal to at least 125 percent of the amount specified in paragraph (3) for such drug for such calendar quarter. The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) (with respect to amounts of penalties or additional assessments) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H488FD2D19E79406D86E7DFC733D1B4B7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i), as redesignated by paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HAD4A435B77144EC0A010B5C4E20BA82B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (4), by striking at the end <quote>and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H905F9F1B3F9740D8B78B57B5DB9E34AE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking at the end the period and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H874777B1CEB1493287F6CDD1BA89E2F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraphs:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC505E33396004511BBCF1A4FE4A1499B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H7D52D1129E7C45739854BA2018200316"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the determination of units under subsection (h);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F42A7E3C30648C2865C8D546B267849"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the determination of whether a drug is a part B rebatable drug under subsection (h); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB30AC362F8764D569F74E0AAFFB1F227"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the calculation of the rebate amount under subsection (h);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA33F2A9350244DAA9C9302C821D691D"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the computation of coinsurance under subsection (h)(5); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H62F59A49AA9B49A69FF46A9223D65CA3"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the computation of amounts paid under section 1833(a)(1)(EE).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H63BF0A23B3224AE49591CF09C863F2ED"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Amounts payable; cost-Sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1833 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H44A727BF692244BA89658A81EB6C0B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(1)—</text><subparagraph id="H392697461AA240CCB11939406AAC795B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by inserting <quote>, subject to subsection (i)(9),</quote> after <quote>the amounts paid</quote>; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F58B73B70C9461BADB67D0A7A3ABC98"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (S), by striking <quote>with respect to</quote> and inserting <quote>subject to subparagraph (EE), with respect to</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1F7C19E8DDF443EB8516D253E45D19BC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (DD)</quote> and inserting <quote>(DD)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99C3049082C94FA880C0004FA9A5749E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting before the semicolon at the end the following: <quote>, and (EE) with respect to a part B rebatable drug (as defined in paragraph (2) of section 1847A(h)) for which the payment amount for a calendar quarter under paragraph (3)(A)(ii)(I) of such section (or, in the case of a part B rebatable drug that is a selected drug (as defined in section 1192(c)) for which, the payment amount described in section 1847A(b)(1)(B)) for such drug for such quarter exceeds the inflation-adjusted payment under paragraph (3)(A)(ii)(II) of such section for such quarter, the amounts paid shall be equal to the percent of the payment amount under paragraph (3)(A)(ii)(I) of such section or section 1847A(b)(1)(B), as applicable, that equals the difference between (i) 100 percent, and (ii) the percent applied under section 1847A(h)(5)(B)</quote>; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H674B327638194E27B3C4330824D5BDC6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (i), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB7ABB67FC3AF477D9BA7461CBAB3B37B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HD9D903C899C040289842FFD50CDD4EE6" indent="up1"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part B rebatable drug (as defined in paragraph (2) of section 1847A(h)) for which payment under this subsection is not packaged into a payment for a service furnished on or after July 1, 2023, under the revised payment system under this subsection, in lieu of calculation of coinsurance and the amount of payment otherwise applicable under this subsection, the provisions of section 1847A(h)(5) and paragraph (1)(EE) of subsection (a), shall, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, apply under this subsection in the same manner as such provisions of section 1847A(h)(5) and subsection (a) apply under such section and subsection.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H82185D98658240B0A5F2AF9E65C212C0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (t)(8), by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HB66E190797A54E55A13642394B3AEC29" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H7D0469BE46B747B495DA6AABC4F8DACE"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Part B rebatable drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part B rebatable drug (as defined in paragraph (2) of section 1847A(h), except if such drug does not have a copayment amount as a result of application of subparagraph (E)) for which payment under this part is not packaged into a payment for a covered OPD service (or group of services) furnished on or after July 1, 2023, and the payment for such drug under this subsection is the same as the amount for a calendar quarter under paragraph (3)(A)(ii)(I) of section 1847A(h), under the system under this subsection, in lieu of calculation of the copayment amount and the amount of payment otherwise applicable under this subsection (other than the application of the limitation described in subparagraph (C)), the provisions of section 1847A(h)(5) and paragraph (1)(EE) of subsection (a), shall, as determined appropriate by the Secretary, apply under this subsection in the same manner as such provisions of section 1847A(h)(5) and subsection (a) apply under such section and subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4407165ACC694E9E851F62244888FF13"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HFB51C42B21934748A48331E3C568888F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>To part B ASP calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1847A(c)(3) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(3)) is amended by inserting <quote>subsection (h) or</quote> before <quote>section 1927</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H364E4E2970BE47FDB22CE6C6F2702017" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excluding part B drug inflation rebate from best price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(c)(1)(C)(ii)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(c)(1)(C)(ii)(I)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>or section 1847A(h)</quote> after <quote>this section</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5AC79F584D684118A997B07B02D1A2AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with Medicaid rebate information disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(b)(3)(D)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(b)(3)(D)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>and the rebate</quote> after <quote>the payment amount</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H05F24DC13077466590DB1954F82A4ED1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Excluding part B drug inflation rebates from average manufacturer price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(k)(1)(B)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(k)(1)(B)(i)</external-xref>), as previously amended, is further amended—</text><subparagraph id="HDD34B91D02A845AC9B67F80FE8AA356D"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (IV), by striking <quote>and</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2899BFAFB53541BB8A2E5462EC8764FF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDBE543490F38465F80C7BC1030FEECF5"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H24DC08C1932E46DEAC4FE52363696BC0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="HD217EE38A1694E699B99D84A71EE85B5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rebates paid by manufacturers under section 1847A(h); and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H247D17E63F864AA19C220623E5755C95"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $12,500,000 for fiscal year 2022 and $7,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2031, to remain available until expended, to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H3C376C04E3584DBC8AC8E463D33744C7" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>202.</enum><header>Medicare part D rebate by manufacturers</header><subsection id="HF1505678E97E49239E9C69CBC841B6C8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act is amended by inserting after section 1860D–14A (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-114a">42 U.S.C. 1395w–114a</external-xref>) the following new section:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H27B0B02DDFE64EBC8263A2541211CDE2" style="OLC"><section id="H2DB0EF01BDAD48389C4282135DD13F5F"><enum>1860D–14B.</enum><header>Manufacturer rebate for certain drugs with prices increasing faster than inflation</header><subsection id="H9218BBA6789E459B83F231C008E150D1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="H453DD6E443664847AA9E16793E8A2408" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Secretarial provision of information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 9 months after the end of each applicable year (as defined in subsection (g)(7)), subject to paragraph (3), the Secretary shall, for each part D rebatable drug, report to each manufacturer of such part D rebatable drug the following for such year:</text><subparagraph id="HABF8C24681A34403A045651794C4844D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The amount (if any) of the excess annual manufacturer price increase described in subsection (b)(1)(A)(ii) for each dosage form and strength with respect to such drug and year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7EC6FEAB1C5D4E1FBCE231491683A7A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The rebate amount specified under subsection (b) for each dosage form and strength with respect to such drug and year.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC73222721C4898BD7CFFCAA1875842"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Manufacturer requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each applicable year, the manufacturer of a part D rebatable drug, for each dosage form and strength with respect to such drug, not later than 30 days after the date of receipt from the Secretary of the information described in paragraph (1) for such year, shall provide to the Secretary a rebate that is equal to the amount specified in subsection (b) for such dosage form and strength with respect to such drug for such year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19E657C228F5401EB5F4E4332E1D9BEA"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Transition rule for reporting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary may, for each rebatable covered part D drug, delay the timeframe for reporting the information and rebate amount described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of such paragraph for the applicable year of 2023 until not later than September 30, 2025.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H2FA1AD34B49F4FC1929C4A855F0259F8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Rebate amount</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H44E6BBEDCD9349F199DF29438157E89D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph id="H22942B00D24C4C3899333B59175E8057"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the amount specified in this subsection for a dosage form and strength with respect to a part D rebatable drug and applicable year is, subject to subparagraph (C), paragraph (5)(B), and paragraph (6), the amount equal to the product of—</text><clause id="H5E55CE33194C41969023A355A61897FD" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">subject to subparagraph (B) of this paragraph, the total number of units that are used to calculate the average manufacturer price of such dosage form and strength with respect to such part D rebatable drug, as reported by the manufacturer of such drug under section 1927 for each month, with respect to such year; and</text></clause><clause id="H2DC2A120E8D1468E8A2AA2A2063041E6" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount (if any) by which—</text><subclause id="H785EF90BDE1C4771AAC090C38D9049D0" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the annual manufacturer price (as determined in paragraph (2)) paid for such dosage form and strength with respect to such part D rebatable drug for the year; exceeds</text></subclause><subclause id="H1B8AD9775F0C4435BD616D7B8AAA8A4A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the inflation-adjusted payment amount determined under paragraph (3) for such dosage form and strength with respect to such part D rebatable drug for the year.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H345D538F9C004591AA347CC364A49994"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excluded units</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subparagraph (A)(i), the Secretary shall exclude from the total number of units for a dosage form and strength with respect to a part D rebatable drug, with respect to an applicable year, the following:</text><clause id="HA5A32213D92143A88E4069796396762E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Units of each dosage form and strength of such part D rebatable drug for which payment was made under a State plan under title XIX (or waiver of such plan), as reported by States under section 1927(b)(2)(A).</text></clause><clause id="HEA31620820814607A70F95F0C97DD8AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Units of each dosage form and strength of such part D rebatable drug for which a rebate is paid under section 1847A(h).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83F85D9651B6448FBCB1BD3CF16E8CD0"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Exemption for shortages and severe supply chain disruptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall reduce or waive the amount under subparagraph (A) with respect to a part D rebatable drug that is described as currently in shortage on the shortage list in effect under section 506E of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or in the case of a generic drug, when the Secretary determines there are severe supply chain disruptions. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H25246314F24B4B418E5810882A32BD4B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination of annual manufacturer price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The annual manufacturer price determined under this paragraph for a dosage form and strength, with respect to a part D rebatable drug and an applicable year, is the sum of the products of—</text><subparagraph id="H7575F60BDB5B4B55AC2CC8740F17B5A0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the average manufacturer price (as defined in subsection (g)(6)) of such dosage form and strength, as calculated for a unit of such drug, with respect to each of the calendar quarters of such year; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A10EE5DE3C24C14942D64078CCF0599"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ratio of—</text><clause id="H4237A346B104426B81222004DF657A63"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the total number of units of such dosage form and strength reported under section 1927 with respect to each such calendar quarter of such year; to</text></clause><clause id="HC91485F0E0AF4603BD3822FDC380225A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of units of such dosage form and strength reported under section 1927 with respect to such year, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8E59AEA1FCF6473B873D54B52B9C164C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Determination of inflation-adjusted payment amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The inflation-adjusted payment amount determined under this paragraph for a dosage form and strength with respect to a part D rebatable drug for an applicable year, subject to paragraph (5), is—</text><subparagraph id="HC6BC5C5743E94441BCC3830F4515B178"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the benchmark year manufacturer price determined under paragraph (4) for such dosage form and strength with respect to such drug and year; increased by</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H279C6BF9E0404CD38CD23A8930FEEDBD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the percentage by which the applicable year CPI–U (as defined in subsection (g)(5)) for the year exceeds the benchmark period CPI–U (as defined in subsection (g)(4)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H548177771C954255A2FA30C3ACBB3EB6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Determination of benchmark year manufacturer price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The benchmark year manufacturer price determined under this paragraph for a dosage form and strength, with respect to a part D rebatable drug and an applicable year, is the sum of the products of—</text><subparagraph id="H9031CDC77AF64A53ACF4C52CCCDCC736"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the average manufacturer price (as defined in subsection (g)(6)) of such dosage form and strength, as calculated for a unit of such drug, with respect to each of the calendar quarters of the payment amount benchmark year (as defined in subsection (g)(3)); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E20D07D90F34997AFBCA31400A79ACD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the ratio of—</text><clause id="HD1C5B50F25254ABFAB3FAEB6B9383533"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of units reported under section 1927 of such dosage form and strength with respect to each such calendar quarter of such payment amount benchmark year; to</text></clause><clause id="HE10F297EDDB84098BCDF85BA6E2273B2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of units reported under section 1927 of such dosage form and strength with respect to such payment amount benchmark year.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4E0DDF9D4FA848FD9431F035E629BDF8"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Special treatment of certain drugs and exemption</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3EB347A469814EA79E3217C16F401185"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Subsequently approved drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part D rebatable drug first approved or licensed by the Food and Drug Administration after October 1, 2021, subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (4) shall be applied as if the term <term>payment amount benchmark year</term> were defined under subsection (g)(3) as the first calendar year beginning after the day on which the drug was first marketed by any manufacturer and subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3) shall be applied as if the term <term>benchmark period CPI–U</term> were defined under subsection (g)(4) as if the reference to <quote>the month immediately prior to October 2021</quote> under such subsection were a reference to <quote>January of the first year beginning after the date on which the drug was first marketed by any manufacturer</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB39B1A079DA54469946C42308BF3B43B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Treatment of new formulations</header><clause commented="no" id="H61EED937765248F9945300CD053D404C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part D rebatable drug that is a line extension of a part D rebatable drug that is an oral solid dosage form, the Secretary shall establish a formula for determining the rebate amount under paragraph (1) and the inflation adjusted payment amount under paragraph (3) with respect to such part D rebatable drug and an applicable year, consistent with the formula applied under subsection (c)(2)(C) of section 1927 for determining a rebate obligation for a rebate period under such section.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0606C8D071614B7FA710AE65662E919B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Line extension defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>line extension</term> means, with respect to a part D rebatable drug, a new formulation of the drug, such as an extended release formulation, but does not include an abuse-deterrent formulation of the drug (as determined by the Secretary), regardless of whether such abuse-deterrent formulation is an extended release formulation.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D486CC7B4BD42C987A23A43A6DEC10D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Selected drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a part D rebatable drug that is a selected drug (as defined in section 1192(c)) for a price applicability period (as defined in section 1191(b)(2)), in the case such drug is determined (pursuant to such section 1192(c)) to no longer be a selected drug, for each applicable year beginning after the price applicability period with respect to such drug, subparagraphs (A) and (B) of paragraph (4) shall be applied as if the term <term>payment amount benchmark year</term> were defined under subsection (g)(3) as the last year beginning during such price applicability period with respect to such selected drug and subparagraph (B) of paragraph (3) shall be applied as if the term <term>benchmark period CPI–U</term> were defined under subsection (g)(4) as if the reference to <quote>the month immediately prior to October 1, 2021</quote> under such subsection were a reference to January of the last year beginning during such price applicability period with respect to such drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7AE6DCA880E45DBA8505717A0EE790A" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Reconciliation in case of revised AMP reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall provide for a method and process under which, in the case of a manufacturer of a part D rebatable drug that submits revisions to information submitted under section 1927 by the manufacturer with respect to such drug, the Secretary determines, pursuant to such revisions, adjustments, if any, to the calculation of the amount specified in this subsection for a dosage form and strength with respect to such part D rebatable drug and an applicable year and reconciles any overpayments or underpayments in amounts paid as rebates under this subsection. Any identified underpayment shall be rectified by the manufacturer not later than 30 days after the date of receipt from the Secretary of information on such underpayment.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H890D5786F8A741B3812C10E565E372B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rebate deposits</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Amounts paid as rebates under subsection (b) shall be deposited into the Medicare Prescription Drug Account in the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund established under section 1841.</text></subsection><subsection id="H15A46495173F4A18BABF390A9E5640AC"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Information</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of carrying out this section, the Secretary shall use information submitted by manufacturers under section 1927(b)(3) and information submitted by States under section 1927(b)(2)(A).</text></subsection><subsection id="H6657C33F8C484699B443C52044D82ED5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Civil money penalty</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a manufacturer of a part D rebatable drug has failed to comply with the requirement under subsection (a)(2) with respect to such drug for an applicable year, the manufacturer shall be subject to, in accordance with a process established by the Secretary pursuant to regulations, a civil money penalty in an amount equal to 125 percent of the amount specified in subsection (b) for such drug for such year. The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) (with respect to amounts of penalties or additional assessments) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this subsection in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a). </text></subsection><subsection id="H48BEFAA194754B43811772290F25DF1B"><enum>(f)</enum><header>No administrative or judicial review</header><text>There shall be no administrative or judicial review of the following:</text><paragraph id="HD42BDCEAF5554D3B841B852239934641"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The determination of units under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D69EC1EBBD04A519CDD0C9F0A8360DC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The determination of whether a drug is a part D rebatable drug under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD89EC2D948F4EDFB7A6A5E75E678527"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The calculation of the rebate amount under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5586A7484B0C4E50BA1840EF79169B79"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HAE5384A527844DF0BD6F45FA076A1326"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Part D rebatable drug</header><subparagraph id="HB4E84BDFF1FC41CDB6C7F2979CA98AC7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>part D rebatable drug</term> means a drug or biological that would (without application of this section) be a covered part D drug, except such term shall, with respect to an applicable year, not include such a drug or biological if the average annual total cost under this part for such year per individual who uses such a drug or biological, as determined by the Secretary, is less than, subject to subparagraph (B), $100, as determined by the Secretary using the most recent data available or, if data is not available, as estimated by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD29EDF2FEBCD4BD38A49F24A603F46FD"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Increase</header><text>The dollar amount applied under subparagraph (A)—</text><clause commented="no" id="H0937718CE0F145DCA6243D0EB59FF7FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024, shall be the dollar amount specified under such subparagraph for 2023, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period beginning with January of 2023; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H91BA5CD6419544A7A03F009236C45AD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a subsequent year, shall be the dollar amount specified in this subparagraph for the previous year, increased by the percentage increase in the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the 12-month period beginning with January of the previous year.</text></clause><continuation-text commented="no" continuation-text-level="subparagraph">Any dollar amount specified under this subparagraph that is not a multiple of $10 shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $10. </continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFD1AC8AE21B24D02A41DE75C3E2E008A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Unit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>unit</term> means, with respect to a part D rebatable drug, the lowest dispensable amount (such as a capsule or tablet, milligram of molecules, or grams) of the part D rebatable drug, as reported under section 1927.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAA1C3209A92544C3AC8399E4F7F42526"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Payment amount benchmark year</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>payment amount benchmark year</term> means the year ending in the month immediately prior to October 1, 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39A95EEA07CD4FCEA8D0EA09A2CDB569"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Benchmark period CPI–U</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>benchmark period CPI–U</term> means the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for the month immediately prior to October 2021.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H099CC31EB1A74880B18E96DE9A90EF4B"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicable year CPI–U</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>applicable year CPI–U</term> means, with respect to an applicable year, the consumer price index for all urban consumers (United States city average) for January of such year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E9D389A31154294B41C2AFA696FEA60"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Average manufacturer price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>average manufacturer price</term> has the meaning, with respect to a part D rebatable drug of a manufacturer, given such term in section 1927(k)(1), with respect to a covered outpatient drug of a manufacturer for a rebate period under section 1927.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38F17EBA2D514E47A0E93E4CFFF112C2"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Applicable year</header><text>The term <term>applicable year</term> means a calendar year beginning with 2023.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA97ED4153EE441F29E4F9046B706E57E" commented="no"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Implementation for 2023 and 2024</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary shall implement this section for 2023 and 2024 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF62477A3D82244B09412994E1B1434EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="HE6640FDB5CD74897A3481CC6D9F8F8A5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>To part B ASP calculation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1847A(c)(3) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(3)), as amended by section 201(c)(1), is further amended by striking <quote>subsection (h) or section 1927</quote> and inserting <quote>subsection (h), section 1927, or section 1860D–14B</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H52828F8B360A459AA70FCD74035F20A1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Excluding part D drug inflation rebate from best price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(c)(1)(C)(ii)(I) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(c)(1)(C)(ii)(I)</external-xref>), as amended by section 201(c)(2), is further amended by striking <quote>or section 1847A(h)</quote> and inserting <quote>, section 1847A(h), or section 1860D–14B</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB39C0F48FC004220B61F82C0AE17FB3D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination with Medicaid rebate information disclosure</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(b)(3)(D)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(b)(3)(D)(i)</external-xref>), as amended by section 201(c)(3), is further amended by striking <quote>or to carry out section 1847B</quote> and inserting <quote>or to carry out section 1847B or section 1860D–14B</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E457C6D0833451BAEFEC947EC389C4E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Excluding part D drug inflation rebates from average manufacturer price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927(k)(1)(B)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8(k)(1)(B)(i)</external-xref>), as previously amended, is further amended by adding at the end the following new subclause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD973C074E3E74D3F9E7A4B042831FCB9" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subclause id="H3696322662D646EBABA2695394B6A5BF"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">rebates paid by manufacturers under section 1860D–14B.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF08B01ECC55B4C20ABE201F591518F52"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $12,500,000 for fiscal year 2022 and $7,500,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2031, to remain available until expended, to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this section.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="H9BD89E3D02CB4E60B1FA296BEA2F9318"><enum>III</enum><header>Part D Improvements and Maximum Out-of-Pocket Cap for Medicare Beneficiaries</header><section id="H5A5CAA1E765243A1A8A4D32BA624580D"><enum>301.</enum><header>Medicare part D benefit redesign</header><subsection id="H1791C72DBD0C48F39C23127EF34B9EBA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Benefit structure redesign</header><text>Section 1860D–2(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HE14B42FBC3FB43C09A767EC95B1EA847"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H137D623972974907B918FD96963E17E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>for a year preceding 2024 and for costs above the annual deductible specified in paragraph (1) and up to the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in paragraph (4)(B) for 2024 and each subsequent year</quote> after <quote>paragraph (3)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1A9A441A2565421C9BF030FD71980F05"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)—</text><clause id="HC6DD0C59B5EA43DA9C41615351A59F5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i), in the matter preceding subclause (I), by inserting <quote>for a year preceding 2024, </quote> after <quote>paragraph (4),</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H3B5B576B2157422797C26D956A253224"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(III), by striking <quote>and each subsequent year</quote> and inserting <quote>through 2023</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9003BA9BBB9144728179271A82C55203"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)—</text><clause id="H3217C5D83AD9489B84156944C88E326E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H578616D6D2C24AF382A905344E012AA4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subclause (I), by inserting <quote>for a year preceding 2024, </quote> after <quote>paragraph (4),</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H7F42898CB7E249038BBDF24A2F88174E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclause (I)(bb), by striking <quote>a year after 2018</quote> and inserting <quote>each of years 2019 through 2023</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H201D17F0C13C40DD926DDE4F8898E86C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii)(V), by striking <quote>2019 and each subsequent year</quote> and inserting <quote>each of years 2019 through 2023</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A7BD19EE9D947C0AB7E5138990A7181"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A)—</text><subparagraph id="HBC177C8CAEDC4763A54BD66A87742272"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by inserting <quote>for a year preceding 2024,</quote> after <quote>and (4),</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H677DDF01099847BF90446598C198E2A2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>for a subsequent year</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of years 2007 through 2023</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBA03FB93C14048869340169B22565A2C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H4E7E1041A466440CAC410215D383FF26"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H8527692776DA4A668AF7CC4F445DB7D4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><subclause id="H8ADFFD0358544218B89A5119E44E952A"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by redesignating subclauses (I) and (II) as items (aa) and (bb), respectively, and moving the margin of each such redesignated item 2 ems to the right;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA6B1123EABA9485991B47995F2D0B63A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the matter preceding item (aa), as redesignated by subclause (I), by striking <quote>is equal to the greater of—</quote> and inserting “is equal to—</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE70AE33844A94FEAAAD917576CB6D866" style="OLC"><subclause id="H6D8E42EAFFB842D08BA3D6654C48C0F5"><enum>(I)</enum><text>for a year preceding 2024, the greater of—</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="H61E8F3E7D78041B0821DCF838C33FFF1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end of item (bb), as redesignated by subclause (I), and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H56A08686791D47AEB42BA760FC1ACAA6"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H1304568E57AB42D6A7F8AF271F55049C" style="OLC"><subclause id="H20F7BCEE58484950A2D92D608944BD6F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for 2024 and each succeeding year, $0.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="H8404857BAC2E42D080084362464228D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in clause (ii)—</text><subclause id="HCD30A4D5CE4A46DDB345DC24A3C65E16"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>clause (i)(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (i)(I)(aa)</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB338FAF940A341E9B55974966B3C9D52"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>The Secretary shall continue to calculate the dollar amounts specified in clause (i)(I)(aa), including with the adjustment under this clause, after 2023 for purposes of section 1860D–14(a)(1)(D)(iii).</quote>; </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5473F343C3414B7088F3ED1D7276B4F4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="HA768786C2FDB4CDBAC43ED8D2EEE4319"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in clause (i)—</text><subclause id="HB22134C93C95454F88F868554E0281D6"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subclause (V), by striking <quote>or</quote> at the end;</text></subclause><subclause id="HD22D22782AED4E3FA2F6B01A0DEB8E33"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subclause (VI)—</text><item id="H1B71067E5ADC4C2E87F7B948FBE34450"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>by striking <quote>for a subsequent year</quote> and inserting <quote>for each of years 2021 through 2023</quote>; and</text></item><item id="H94B85FAF511E452BACB89860EAE3A89D"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H9210A2E2A43843EE8D3A9032D345662B"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subclauses:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDD81898C0A0441DFB49F8A1E3AD80C96" style="OLC"><subclause id="H28E5AC5FEC2A4408A8585C7411C55E0E"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>for 2024, is equal to $2,000; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H1374CCEFBB1141BD8DBA94D4EE6A3005"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>for a subsequent year, is equal to the amount specified in this subparagraph for the previous year, increased by the annual percentage increase described in paragraph (6) for the year involved.</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="HC0CA90A958194912AC3DA147F3268CEC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by striking <quote>clause (i)(II)</quote> and inserting <quote>clause (i)</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H616511022D6844B792068B2DC6BF8DEC"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C)(i), by striking <quote>and for amounts</quote> and inserting <quote>and, for a year preceding 2024, for amounts</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB4E451CA250442819893A13831FE27CB"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>In applying</quote> and inserting <quote>For each of years 2011 through 2023, in applying</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6A0A47D5E8A744A19A9443C87604A41C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Reinsurance payment amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–15(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-115">42 U.S.C. 1395w–115(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB5B10C3FFCBF41DF92A22821EA7F607B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H94258874A7BD4ABB97D0657028A53424"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>equal to 80 percent</quote> and inserting “equal to—</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2B94346DDDC3497690D2FB6B1CB69AB8"><subparagraph id="H10D3FC6AD0044B0CADDC1A91B79D71F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for a year preceding 2024, 80 percent</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCDCF489E8D7241DFA6FE24C614A761BD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), as added by subparagraph (A), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE99E2B95BB7B4ACABEB76C989281D4A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H81ACDCBF45FB43DABA88F2B0CCF7380B"><subparagraph id="H93B3B0808F8F41B9AAE333B3FE97E8AB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for 2024 and each subsequent year, the sum of—</text><clause id="H6F212BCD2CA248E6AB2764ECD466B7D8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an amount equal to 20 percent of such allowable reinsurance costs attributable to that portion of gross prescription drug costs as specified in paragraph (3) incurred in the coverage year after such individual has incurred costs that exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B) with respect to applicable drugs (as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(2)); and</text></clause><clause id="HB4CA57D14C3045E5B657FD75DAFCEF1A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>an amount equal to 40 percent of such allowable reinsurance costs attributable to that portion of gross prescription drug costs as specified in paragraph (3) incurred in the coverage year after such individual has incurred costs that exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B) with respect to covered part D drugs that are not applicable drugs (as so defined). </text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19EAD84FDB3C46828AFE26C1296E334E"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H29F8B24AC8214525B75AB13494281E2F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">COSTS</header-in-text>.—For purposes</quote> and inserting </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1A9A7A4A077D4D239E4AD7A63D0DF534" display-inline="yes-display-inline"><text><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">Costs.—</header-in-text></text><subparagraph id="H966BF161B2044B6FAC5CF3B82DD707F2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (B), for purposes</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5204EE2FCEBA4B39A1E02EF2B6C72E13"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HC92F0F19F4D546E9B02050A078A4F28D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H864DC3E3946F4B94B6B5F5BD50C6C62D"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusion of manufacturer discounts on applicable drugs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of applying subparagraph (A), the term <term>allowable reinsurance costs</term> shall include the portion of the negotiated price (as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(6)) of an applicable drug (as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(2)) that was paid by a manufacturer under the manufacturer discount program under section 1860D–14C.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE7D8BB453F49474EB453EE155B172D6C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)—</text><subparagraph id="H902514B552384AB5AE016D8AAEC27C71"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the first sentence, by striking <quote>For purposes</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (2)(B), for purposes</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBC56A5F0D054BBFBE095C8623523D0F"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the second sentence, by inserting <quote>(or, with respect to 2024 and subsequent years, in the case of an applicable drug, as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(2), by a manufacturer)</quote> after <quote>by the individual or under the plan</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC257F09BC80043CF955E6F18DA9DE166"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reduced cost-Sharing; beneficiary premium percentage</header><paragraph id="H108A7633F75548C5B8A774500B0DA832"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Cost-sharing</header><subparagraph id="HD569A1D91E354164948A236192C3078E"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–2(b)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(b)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="H9EDB08012E9F49DDB747E92D168D95D7" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph header, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">25 percent coinsurance</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Coinsurance</header-in-text></quote>; </text></clause><clause id="H1C38B279A1384E03AFCE6D7BB8BE3B58"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 23 percent)</quote> after <quote>25 percent</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H9B3423CD00BE41068F0BDC7107522C6C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in clause (ii), by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 23 percent)</quote> after <quote>25 percent</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H422798FB4B2044D5A8368A898826AEEA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 1860D–14(a)(2)(D) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-114">42 U.S.C. 1395w–114(a)(2)(D)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, instead of coinsurance of <quote>23 percent</quote>)</quote> after <quote>instead of coinsurance of <quote>25 percent</quote></quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC3F710CEFFD4D98A44024850152F36B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Beneficiary premium percentage</header><subparagraph id="H7F1350D395BE4C44836832D4D057FA9A"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–13(a)(3)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-113">42 U.S.C. 1395w–113(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 23.5 percent)</quote> after <quote>25.5 percent</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H71B722CD048942A9BF854C3453751C87"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><clause id="HDDC2A8371A2745F692CD27C27049043A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–11(g)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111(g)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 23.5 percent)</quote> after <quote>25.5 percent</quote>.</text></clause><clause id="H75C3F12A83F7462C95840764540B58E2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–13(a)(7)(B)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-113">42 U.S.C. 1395w–113(a)(7)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subclause id="HA355726939494F41AF4BDD663C033F6E"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (I), by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 23.5 percent)</quote> after <quote>25.5 percent</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD2E2360CD8034CE5B5667632FE297176"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subclause (II), by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 23.5 percent)</quote> after <quote>25.5 percent</quote>.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H02834C3456A34E37A61E7F677548CFE7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–15(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-115">42 U.S.C. 1395w–115(a)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>(or, for 2024 and each subsequent year, 76.5 percent)</quote> after <quote>74.5 percent</quote>. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCDF46B39489B4ECBA6D89E04152B3B9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Manufacturer discount program</header><paragraph id="H39F94A2E356F49AEB33276BD51AA20A6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–101 through <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-153">42 U.S.C. 1395w–153</external-xref>), as amended by section 202, is further amended by inserting after section 1860D–14B the following new sections:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D3B8B2F3FC34426807DE1D7D0D1C460" style="OLC"><section id="HFC7613C1A1F149E0B67F9E6344802060"><enum>1860D–14C.</enum><header>Manufacturer discount program</header><subsection id="H87B174FF2AEC4ECB99CFB59158A537B0"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a manufacturer discount program (in this section referred to as the <quote>program</quote>). Under the program, the Secretary shall enter into agreements described in subsection (b) with manufacturers and provide for the performance of the duties described in subsection (c). The Secretary shall establish a model agreement for use under the program by not later than January 1, 2023, in consultation with manufacturers, and allow for comment on such model agreement.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2AC52737E54649B6A1B5956EC47EB59E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Terms of agreement</header><paragraph commented="no" id="H882262F8B9804EEAB2874789B8D3021E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB2268D4C16E9494DB608EB6D3CC59850"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Agreement</header><text>An agreement under this section shall require the manufacturer to provide, in accordance with this section, discounted prices for applicable drugs of the manufacturer that are dispensed to applicable beneficiaries on or after January 1, 2024. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC69E60A350324C50853B91BF94CBEBED"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed as affecting—</text><clause id="HB946EF2C368A4CEC8C1EB01A0B446870"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the application of a coinsurance of 23 percent of the negotiated price, as applied under paragraph (2)(A) of section 1860D–2(b), for costs described in such paragraph; or</text></clause><clause id="H3F6E0BCB02984F019BC987BCF3CC4CBC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the application of the copayment amount described in paragraph (4)(A) of such section, with respect to costs described in such paragraph.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H5B3B35591D37446BAA952A030864D560"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Timing of agreement</header><clause commented="no" id="HFEE6AF09C9EA4DC59F93ED790A9A3021"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Special rule for 2024</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order for an agreement with a manufacturer to be in effect under this section with respect to the period beginning on January 1, 2024, and ending on December 31, 2024, the manufacturer shall enter into such agreement not later than 30 days after the date of the establishment of a model agreement under subsection (a).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H6904916F0A2844D59708CCA4381BAE9C"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>2025 and subsequent years</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In order for an agreement with a manufacturer to be in effect under this section with respect to plan year 2025 or a subsequent plan year, the manufacturer shall enter into such agreement not later than a calendar quarter or semi-annual deadline established by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4234E1755D084BC88BC86AFEEBE0FDD1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Provision of appropriate data</header><text>Each manufacturer with an agreement in effect under this section shall collect and have available appropriate data, as determined by the Secretary, to ensure that it can demonstrate to the Secretary compliance with the requirements under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HB6C63959060946E9ACE0B152E3D5A64B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Compliance with requirements for administration of program</header><text>Each manufacturer with an agreement in effect under this section shall comply with requirements imposed by the Secretary or a third party with a contract under subsection (d)(3), as applicable, for purposes of administering the program, including any determination under subparagraph (A) of subsection (c)(1) or procedures established under such subsection (c)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC91840F885B4710A28EBCDC5383E451"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Length of agreement</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HACE98967F0DD447BA2AA374809E8044C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An agreement under this section shall be effective for an initial period of not less than 12 months and shall be automatically renewed for a period of not less than 1 year unless terminated under subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C92E7F3827749BD8C3DB5C2C5DF6221"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Termination</header><clause id="HA61DA1513EA3432A97D45661EEA886BD"><enum>(i)</enum><header>By the Secretary</header><text>The Secretary shall provide for termination of an agreement under this section for a knowing and willful violation of the requirements of the agreement or other good cause shown. Such termination shall not be effective earlier than 30 days after the date of notice to the manufacturer of such termination. The Secretary shall provide, upon request, a manufacturer with a hearing concerning such a termination, and such hearing shall take place prior to the effective date of the termination with sufficient time for such effective date to be repealed if the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></clause><clause id="HBFF038B7FE9741549CF6964B892385AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>By a manufacturer</header><text>A manufacturer may terminate an agreement under this section for any reason. Any such termination shall be effective, with respect to a plan year—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H7E7A312010A6451A9B80BB7F53C652B4"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the termination occurs before January 31 of a plan year, as of the day after the end of the plan year; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="HD80873251C024BF690A39A4211F0CB0A"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the termination occurs on or after January 31 of a plan year, as of the day after the end of the succeeding plan year.</text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5CA234C7482D4D37A19D108D5BC819BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Effectiveness of termination</header><text>Any termination under this subparagraph shall not affect discounts for applicable drugs of the manufacturer that are due under the agreement before the effective date of its termination.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HAF908D6156D74C6B9E042AD0FC7D4864"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Notice to third party</header><text>The Secretary shall provide notice of such termination to a third party with a contract under subsection (d)(3) within not less than 30 days before the effective date of such termination.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H19A31307D6164D5DAF5D3F95C94E168E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Duties described</header><text>The duties described in this subsection are the following:</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HF7B346B343AA40CE8D8C0C25341FE0F6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administration of program</header><text>Administering the program, including—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H77FA7E94E70E4F2B88A3165778B5C418"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the determination of the amount of the discounted price of an applicable drug of a manufacturer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HBFB46C0913DD473AB94E0133AE8CABA0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the establishment of procedures to ensure that, not later than the applicable number of calendar days after the dispensing of an applicable drug by a pharmacy or mail order service, the pharmacy or mail order service is reimbursed for an amount equal to the difference between—</text><clause commented="no" id="H6C38CA48DC084C03BB4B52FEACC3223F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the negotiated price of the applicable drug; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H949126C325EC43C7B85747DF3FEDAEC3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the discounted price of the applicable drug;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFBCFE13AAA9D4927B27604702AF76B66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the establishment of procedures to ensure that the discounted price for an applicable drug under this section is applied before any coverage or financial assistance under other health benefit plans or programs that provide coverage or financial assistance for the purchase or provision of prescription drug coverage on behalf of applicable beneficiaries as specified by the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC4CAE9885C54476F9D73FE4B9DA10B80"><enum>(D)</enum><text>providing a reasonable dispute resolution mechanism to resolve disagreements between manufacturers, applicable beneficiaries, and the third party with a contract under subsection (d)(3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6938FD6650824A98912E56E22EC652FC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Monitoring compliance</header><subparagraph id="HF354A6B4DA9A4F82B0AE17A16FA3AE40"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall monitor compliance by a manufacturer with the terms of an agreement under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H33DBB8F82F534208A6B975CBEE0C5E75"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Notification</header><text>If a third party with a contract under subsection (d)(3) determines that the manufacturer is not in compliance with such agreement, the third party shall notify the Secretary of such noncompliance for appropriate enforcement under subsection (e).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3F669B950E14FC4A2ED1160B84B3EBB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Collection of data from prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans</header><text>The Secretary may collect appropriate data from prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans in a timeframe that allows for discounted prices to be provided for applicable drugs under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H20D150F9AF314DDBB32208C420342260"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Administration</header><paragraph id="HD2D3D6F84C8D479AB011EF9377BDB315"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to paragraph (2), the Secretary shall provide for the implementation of this section, including the performance of the duties described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4F17004A23B14EA892A12FC0BB1C29B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In providing for the implementation of this section, the Secretary shall not receive or distribute any funds of a manufacturer under the program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38DA1C831399439A8521FC971B6CAB93"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Contract with third parties</header><text>The Secretary shall enter into a contract with 1 or more third parties to administer the requirements established by the Secretary in order to carry out this section. At a minimum, the contract with a third party under the preceding sentence shall require that the third party—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3E8E6585B4CF44C9B5FDE1DBF9903C9E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>receive and transmit information between the Secretary, manufacturers, and other individuals or entities the Secretary determines appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3BB59B79706B4BC6B1258C26BC5B43D8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>receive, distribute, or facilitate the distribution of funds of manufacturers to appropriate individuals or entities in order to meet the obligations of manufacturers under agreements under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H964CEAED80EB4ECE8ADABF4D722B2890"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide adequate and timely information to manufacturers, consistent with the agreement with the manufacturer under this section, as necessary for the manufacturer to fulfill its obligations under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC13E4C0001D94DF5A78F237733854EE4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>permit manufacturers to conduct periodic audits, directly or through contracts, of the data and information used by the third party to determine discounts for applicable drugs of the manufacturer under the program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H587E4A149D3C4B7086A71F1BB8878A45"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Performance requirements</header><text>The Secretary shall establish performance requirements for a third party with a contract under paragraph (3) and safeguards to protect the independence and integrity of the activities carried out by the third party under the program under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HDCB9DAD5787A48EC8AF0FD0E3EBFDF16"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall implement the program under this section for 2024 and 2025 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE5A04DD952824EB3B715BDBB026E47C0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H683F6402A44B4881AD4A29FB2E90A5EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>Each manufacturer with an agreement in effect under this section shall be subject to periodic audit by the Secretary.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE805052127B7473B858F13343896A35D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civil money penalty</header><subparagraph id="H95BB2D192B36432C9543DE772331DFE9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A manufacturer that fails to provide discounted prices for applicable drugs of the manufacturer dispensed to applicable beneficiaries in accordance with such agreement shall be subject to a civil money penalty for each such failure in an amount the Secretary determines is equal to the sum of—</text><clause id="HAA7D41C4B5A841F9B2A0A78C3547CD59"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the amount that the manufacturer would have paid with respect to such discounts under the agreement, which will then be used to pay the discounts which the manufacturer had failed to provide; and</text></clause><clause id="HB6CE110C90E24438B59B7D688C44A354"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>25 percent of such amount.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H8ECFBCD0A7104DC181A2BD407FE679A8"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application</header><text>The provisions of section 1128A (other than subsections (a) and (b)) shall apply to a civil money penalty under this paragraph in the same manner as such provisions apply to a penalty or proceeding under section 1128A(a).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H386ACCD34E844D2294A96304E6F36352"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Clarification regarding availability of other covered part D drugs</header><text>Nothing in this section shall prevent an applicable beneficiary from purchasing a covered part D drug that is not an applicable drug (including a generic drug or a drug that is not on the formulary of the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan that the applicable beneficiary is enrolled in).</text></subsection><subsection id="H47111652B87646C594BFA97F1C391F19"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H5A835DC380EC4DFC95B8D8875D54F7C5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Applicable beneficiary</header><text>The term <term>applicable beneficiary</term> means an individual who, on the date of dispensing a covered part D drug—</text><subparagraph id="HCB6EEF175B3949448E1A67C339712BCB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is enrolled in a prescription drug plan or an MA–PD plan;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5A3E093DAB814831A84228F40F4F8CB8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is not enrolled in a qualified retiree prescription drug plan; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2477310EFE9340768E243CEFAD857C3E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has incurred costs, as determined in accordance with section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C) as if clause (iii) of such section included a reference to costs reimbursed through insurance, a group health plan, or certain other third-party payment arrangements, for covered part D drugs in the year that exceed—</text><clause id="HD65D0677EA644CDF86A2C7E86BCA75D9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of an individual not described in clause (ii) or (iii), the annual deductible for such year, as specified in section 1860D–2(b)(1);</text></clause><clause id="HED36BE6A493E4172A8ED9392114B7A8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a subsidy eligible individual described in section 1860D–14(a)(1), the annual deductible for such year, as specified in subparagraph (B) of such section; and</text></clause><clause id="H08758F660F3142ABB585012D0E95924A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in the case of a subsidy eligible individual described in section 1860D–14(a)(2), the annual deductible for such year, as specified in subparagraph (B) of such section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBCFB7030285D41C0BB50196199C3FAD0"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicable drug</header><text>The term <term>applicable drug</term>, with respect to an applicable beneficiary—</text><subparagraph id="HB5B0880025AC4BBDBE624C75D15AA6E4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means a covered part D drug—</text><clause id="H72404C60C502483A82AA1CA33D3E7DDF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>approved under a new drug application under section 505(c) of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or, in the case of a biologic product, licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H76C0BE57A8694F98A6F1FB292B5506CB"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H9E5A6631AF5648388CF6823E73E15091"><enum>(I)</enum><text>if the PDP sponsor of the prescription drug plan or the MA organization offering the MA–PD plan uses a formulary, which is on the formulary of the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan that the applicable beneficiary is enrolled in;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC91A4694952F43ACBCB477311F439AC8" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>if the PDP sponsor of the prescription drug plan or the MA organization offering the MA–PD plan does not use a formulary, for which benefits are available under the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan that the applicable beneficiary is enrolled in; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H954090D344014EE3B4B59B6349A2EF3D" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is provided through an exception or appeal; and</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2382630AC026496D93094C7C42762AF0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>does not include a selected drug (as referred to under section 1192(c)) during a price applicability period (as defined in section 1191(b)(2)) with respect to such drug.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H36C455255DFF4A119F9DBD4A5F29BF29"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Applicable number of calendar days</header><text>The term <term>applicable number of calendar days</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H70D52935EDDF494B98146A4111E0EBED"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to claims for reimbursement submitted electronically, 14 days; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HFFE25229597E4C8B974CD876425B5EAC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to claims for reimbursement submitted otherwise, 30 days.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0D0E1A8B7D034290A4624A07DA093CC5"><enum>(4)</enum><header display-inline="yes-display-inline">Discounted price</header><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4E5D3181574441EEAAAE3BDBE60DC096"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>discounted price</term> means, subject to subparagraphs (B) and (C), with respect to an applicable drug of a manufacturer dispensed during a year to an applicable beneficiary—</text><clause commented="no" id="H6725E7732CE5433C836C0AB8DDA58A5D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">who has not incurred costs, as determined in accordance with section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C), for covered part D drugs in the year that are equal to or exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i) for the year, 90 percent of the negotiated price of such drug; and </text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HAA54E34115F24FC99DB51ED8464D5681"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>who has incurred such costs, as so determined, in the year that are equal to or exceed such threshold for the year, 80 percent of the negotiated price of such drug.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC66D7E95EE54D8FBD612B450A841E45" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Phase-in for certain drugs dispensed to LIS beneficiaries</header><clause id="HA210FC853D314FD08F8386B35CAF45D0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of an applicable drug of a specified manufacturer (as defined in clause (ii)) that is marketed as of the date of enactment of this subparagraph and dispensed for an applicable beneficiary who is a subsidy eligible individual (as defined in section 1860D–14(a)(3)), the term <term>discounted price</term> means the specified LIS percent (as defined in clause (iii)) of the negotiated price of the applicable drug of the manufacturer.</text></clause><clause id="H0836098FBFDC4E7FA50786713CBC3810" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Specified manufacturer</header><subclause id="H36F8114AAC994B16AD69DFE88797E09C"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, subject to subclause (II), the term <term>specified manufacturer</term> means a manufacturer of an applicable drug for which, in 2021—</text><item id="H7E4CC985EA554110B70F1C44BB9E8422" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the manufacturer had a coverage gap discount agreement under section 1860D–14A;</text></item><item id="HC08DAF19DC524AABB8B39B49E1EE5B91" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total expenditures for all of the specified drugs of the manufacturer covered by such agreement or agreements for such year and covered under this part during such year represented less than 1.0 percent of the total expenditures under this part for all covered Part D drugs during such year; and</text></item><item id="H278C14EC941E45CD835F11BEAFA92548" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total expenditures for all of the specified drugs of the manufacturer that are single source drugs and biological products covered under part B during such year represented less than 1.0 percent of the total expenditures under part B for all drugs or biological products covered under such part during such year.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HECD48DFF85E7483685C3A70B88BCEF62"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Specified drugs</header><item id="H2664CE9C054646A49C6BA58B053C3316"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <term>specified drug</term> means, with respect to a specified manufacturer, for 2021, an applicable drug that is produced, prepared, propagated, compounded, converted, or processed by the manufacturer.</text></item><item id="H108E79A5F19048CFBA788EDD61AA1C13"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be treated as one manufacturer for purposes of this subparagraph. For purposes of making a determination pursuant to the previous sentence, an agreement under this section shall require that a manufacturer provide and attest to such information as specified by the Secretary as necessary.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HFE3A6D6F377B429B95B501C7A90CC9E7"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specified manufacturer</term> shall not include a manufacturer described in subclause (I) if such manufacturer is acquired after 2021 by another manufacturer that is not a specified manufacturer, effective at the beginning of the plan year immediately following such acquisition or, in the case of an acquisition before 2024, effective January 1, 2024.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HF8AA958114444F90B6B448D2C10AD42B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Specified LIS percent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, the <quote>specified LIS percent</quote> means, with respect to a year—</text><subclause id="HBA258F7C0DEA46BEA7E815136887A11A" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for an applicable drug dispensed for an applicable beneficiary described in clause (i) who has not incurred costs, as determined in accordance with section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C), for covered part D drugs in the year that are equal to or exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i) for the year—</text><item id="H51F44E24683D4AF888720C5154DB4E7B"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>for 2024, 99 percent;</text></item><item id="H87EA0A276A8F498E9C3132C224B2FE5E" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for 2025, 98 percent;</text></item><item id="H7C04B9AB6BCB4C18A6FAF3166360F7EC" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for 2026, 95 percent;</text></item><item id="HD99281DA761D44D2B190893F86D47D0B" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>for 2027, 92 percent; and</text></item><item id="H95538B22D78446BCAFC22603556EA8A8" commented="no"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>for 2028 and each subsequent year, 90 percent; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE6898109987D4689A92F9AC0BBCE2DB7"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for an applicable drug dispensed for an applicable beneficiary described in clause (i) who has incurred costs, as determined in accordance with section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C), for covered part D drugs in the year that are equal to or exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i) for the year—</text><item id="HAF130586D6BC4513908A32694AE900A6"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024, 99 percent;</text></item><item id="H1B2C2137A1FA419BB18715CBD42DBF17"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for 2025, 98 percent;</text></item><item id="HDCAC4172323A472A8E61719B388740A0"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for 2026, 95 percent;</text></item><item id="H09C9086F8FEE42B6BDBD90C6F1F3E943"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>for 2027, 92 percent;</text></item><item id="HEDF03F127C304B2BAC88AA27C089961A"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>for 2028, 90 percent;</text></item><item id="HCDC05C5C93B04969AD3A92F36F134CFE"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>for 2029, 85 percent; and</text></item><item id="H9816C693ED51421BB3D9C15688176F58"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>for 2030 and each subsequent year, 80 percent.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H52D4F0D5A5B447E996AB6C8744370F84"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Phase-in for specified small manufacturers</header><clause id="H013B4D9E61FB4D63AA26CC805786DDAF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of an applicable drug of a specified small manufacturer (as defined in clause (ii)) that is marketed as of the date of enactment of this subparagraph and dispensed for an applicable beneficiary, the term <term>discounted price</term> means the specified small manufacturer percent (as defined in clause (iii)) of the negotiated price of the applicable drug of the manufacturer.</text></clause><clause id="H7A8EA79A01A04C64A123C28CCA7C78B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Specified small manufacturer</header><subclause id="H36CBEA8EAD2048DA83FE70B2FEBA70B7"><enum>(I)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, subject to subclause (III), the term <term>specified small manufacturer</term> means a manufacturer of an applicable drug for which, in 2021—</text><item id="HEE24BF23DCA34971A988BFD96FD4CF93"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the manufacturer is a specified manufacturer (as defined in subparagraph (B)(ii)); and </text></item><item id="HABA7AC2454514EED9E92B7811FC9A0D6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total expenditures under part D for any one of the specified small manufacturer drugs of the manufacturer that are covered by the agreement or agreements under section 1860D–14A of such manufacturer for such year and covered under this part during such year are equal to or more than 80 percent of the total expenditures under this part for all specified small manufacturer drugs of the manufacturer that are covered by such agreement or agreements for such year and covered under this part during such year.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H2AC264C1790349188CAC0EEED00785EA"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Specified small manufacturer drugs</header><item id="HAA981A0F734343EC9FF140876021770E"><enum>(aa)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this clause, the term <term>specified small manufacturer drugs</term> means, with respect to a specified small manufacturer, for 2021, an applicable drug that is produced, prepared, propagated, compounded, converted, or processed by the manufacturer.</text></item><item id="H2252D61A7B6D4AECB46618CF0322C330"><enum>(bb)</enum><header>Aggregation rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">All persons treated as a single employer under subsection (a) or (b) of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/52">section 52</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall be treated as one manufacturer for purposes of this subparagraph. For purposes of making a determination pursuant to the previous sentence, an agreement under this section shall require that a manufacturer provide and attest to such information as specified by the Secretary as necessary.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H86CFF0396D8B48498D318322406C75DA"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Limitation</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>specified small manufacturer</term> shall not include a manufacturer described in subclause (I) if such manufacturer is acquired after 2021 by another manufacturer that is not a specified small manufacturer, effective at the beginning of the plan year immediately following such acquisition or, in the case of an acquisition before 2024, effective January 1, 2024.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD0560850049A42B09BF42621F228662E"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Specified small manufacturer percent</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subparagraph, the term <term>specified small manufacturer percent</term> means, with respect to a year—</text><subclause id="H61D3586DF9EE49338224C1DC5B57A576"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for an applicable drug dispensed for an applicable beneficiary who has not incurred costs, as determined in accordance with section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C), for covered part D drugs in the year that are equal to or exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i) for the year—</text><item id="HE79F228F0007433F85EED37168428727"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024, 99 percent;</text></item><item id="H9FE49B6B590644C08A72A55BA7098C98"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for 2025, 98 percent;</text></item><item id="H32AC64AA75424E23B5DBF105FCD238C1"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for 2026, 95 percent;</text></item><item id="HD48684B9A7774A5DA1138959ED331003"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>for 2027, 92 percent; and</text></item><item id="H4070020054D64FB2AF18B34B106449C5"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>for 2028 and each subsequent year, 90 percent; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB84B638F8AF247A7A2EA0B149DFE9300"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for an applicable drug dispensed for an applicable beneficiary who has incurred costs, as determined in accordance with section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C), for covered part D drugs in the year that are equal to or exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i) for the year—</text><item id="H5D21DE6DDFA54349B54199959AEFD891"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024, 99 percent;</text></item><item id="H9D7A8E776ED04787BCC0EC5B6F2D2BFE"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>for 2025, 98 percent;</text></item><item id="HC35A2650CA7947B4966870147E65C36D"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>for 2026, 95 percent;</text></item><item id="HD6AB7BE55CC741DCAE4ACD5E60267F30"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>for 2027, 92 percent;</text></item><item id="H781EEEE4E8E4419BB955942E5AD93D8E"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>for 2028, 90 percent;</text></item><item id="HDCB7E19D0D794E4299425C9AB7ADA3A6"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>for 2029, 85 percent; and</text></item><item id="H450B9CF91CB84A11B25BABC695247F8B"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>for 2030 and each subsequent year, 80 percent.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCBC6E15942464F379326E7D5FD3F9AB5"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Total expenditures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>total expenditures</term> includes, in the case of expenditures with respect to part D, ingredient costs, dispensing fees, sales tax, and, if applicable, vaccine administration fees. The term <term>total expenditures</term> excludes, in the case of expenditures with respect to part B, expenditures for a drug or biological that are bundled or packaged into the payment for another service.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEC54BDE13FB043DCB67BB46E3A775131"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Special case for certain claims</header><clause commented="no" id="H6FEFA347FBFB4679950574C42CC9163C"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Claims spanning deductible</header><text>In the case where the entire amount of the negotiated price of an individual claim for an applicable drug with respect to an applicable beneficiary does not fall above the annual deductible specified in section 1860D–2(b)(1) for the year, the manufacturer of the applicable drug shall provide the discounted price under this section on only the portion of the negotiated price of the applicable drug that falls above such annual deductible.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H48ABEF025E9949B4A7D8C66C78017D56"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Claims spanning out-of-pocket threshold</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case where the entire amount of the negotiated price of an individual claim for an applicable drug with respect to an applicable beneficiary does not fall entirely below or entirely above the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i) for the year, the manufacturer of the applicable drug shall provide the discounted price—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H08A8BDA82DFB41479869140E8B7BF204"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in accordance with subparagraph (A)(i) on the portion of the negotiated price of the applicable drug that falls below such threshold; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H2EAF2D4394C941EB8C669DC7639BAE45"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in accordance with subparagraph (A)(ii) on the portion of such price of such drug that falls at or above such threshold.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H072952685EB84DFE9A9A75443519FE2A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Manufacturer</header><text>The term <term>manufacturer</term> means any entity which is engaged in the production, preparation, propagation, compounding, conversion, or processing of prescription drug products, either directly or indirectly by extraction from substances of natural origin, or independently by means of chemical synthesis, or by a combination of extraction and chemical synthesis. Such term does not include a wholesale distributor of drugs or a retail pharmacy licensed under State law.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HBD82A8E3CDF3460894E55B4699AEA15B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Negotiated price</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>negotiated price</term> has the meaning given such term in section 423.100 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation) and, with respect to an applicable drug, such negotiated price shall include any dispensing fee and, if applicable, any vaccine administration fee for the applicable drug.</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HF3D8C1668672497ABC430A4DB5879BEC"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Qualified retiree prescription drug plan</header><text>The term <term>qualified retiree prescription drug plan</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1860D–22(a)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H585B09CE187C4891A401D4BEA7C51D58"><enum>1860D–14D.</enum><header>Selected drug subsidy program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">With respect to covered part D drugs that would be applicable drugs (as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(2)) but for the application of subparagraph (B) of such section, the Secretary shall provide a process whereby, in the case of an applicable beneficiary (as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(1)) who, with respect to a year, is enrolled in a prescription drug plan or is enrolled in an MA–PD plan, has not incurred costs that are equal to or exceed the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i), and is dispensed such a drug the Secretary (periodically and on a timely basis) provides the PDP sponsor or the MA organization offering the plan, a subsidy with respect to such drug that is equal to 10 percent of the negotiated price (as defined in section 1860D–14C(g)(6)) of such drug.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H97EC8DA909E8460FBAEACF44D817E44D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Sunset of Medicare coverage gap discount program</header><text>Section 1860D–14A of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395-114a">42 U.S.C. 1395–114a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H5985D953B7D84B73B22AA5CC55DFE518"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), in the first sentence, by striking <quote>The Secretary</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to subsection (h), the Secretary</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6570667D11824F2B8A12CBAA4F11534C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H26B7639C60F34E5EA55AA658CC9A2AE8" style="OLC"><subsection id="HFA007F70B3D0420BA78259AA5821401E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Sunset of program</header><paragraph id="H2D76BA95470644E0985891C55232FF57"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The program shall not apply with respect to applicable drugs dispensed on or after January 1, 2024, and, subject to paragraph (2), agreements under this section shall be terminated as of such date.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A4F75B236484B75BA53AA8BEEE8DE9B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Continued application for applicable drugs dispensed prior to sunset</header><text>The provisions of this section (including all responsibilities and duties) shall continue to apply on and after January 1, 2024, with respect to applicable drugs dispensed prior to such date.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H34E15640124D41E0973A49A7CF6288E7"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Inclusion of actuarial value of manufacturer discounts in bids</header><text>Section 1860D–11 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-111">42 U.S.C. 1395w–111</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD8EDB8DF855D4EC7AC9A2A0C7A9D2F22"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)(C)(iii)—</text><clause commented="no" id="H130DEEC8263E4B33A8DD06EEEA273278"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>assumptions regarding the reinsurance</quote> and inserting “assumptions regarding—</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE0F2A27BE6CA4A4FB472C0970F0A2792" style="OLC"><subclause commented="no" id="HBB4E59CAF2934BBCB1C55D8F3F257AB2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the reinsurance</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause commented="no" id="H167FDB67FDD14C82BF62B333CCD91CFD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H04FCAF3DAB0D4C42AFBB88EB6DB34712" style="OLC"><subclause commented="no" id="HAE94EDEEAEFE46218C4D87FCC9BF6BDC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024 and each subsequent year, the manufacturer discounts provided under section 1860D–14C subtracted from the actuarial value to produce such bid; and</text></subclause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0050CD142E2B41F28508059ED01E391D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(C)—</text><clause commented="no" id="HDBD88305961147BAB359D838DC175A28"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>an actuarial valuation of the reinsurance</quote> and inserting “an actuarial valuation of—</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB365625B15724DD8A7E2579E7E9D67DD" style="OLC"><clause commented="no" id="HF095BBAAA4CE41FF8F7DF45FEB0E3BC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the reinsurance</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause commented="no" id="HA82E635E7B3145D7863D1B6817BCB547"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in clause (i), as inserted by clause (i) of this subparagraph, by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HBBAEFF28343046DB8C493B854B365A70"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9C7F2992C42B4CD0A72723FF9CD15E01" style="OLC"><clause commented="no" id="H82CB21D967CF46308C8A0CD71AF499B5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for 2024 and each subsequent year, the manufacturer discounts provided under section 1860D–14C;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H190635F42B7C4E03AF4637D56CF9A9DC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Conforming amendments</header><paragraph id="H84BECF0FD3BF49DE8456475761CF32AF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Section 1860D–2 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H954C12C3ADF44E9BB387C7B24E4924AF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)(A)(i)(I), by striking <quote>, or an increase in the initial</quote> and inserting <quote>or, for a year preceding 2024, an increase in the initial</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H383DDDDAB90C4884813C8FCCB3914145"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1)(C)—</text><clause id="H94FD1069156C48B4945775256539C1CD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">at initial coverage limit</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H3D72A64EF1234A1CAAD847B127DC76E7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>for a year preceding 2024 or the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in subsection (b)(4)(B) for the year for 2024 and each subsequent year</quote> after <quote>subsection (b)(3) for the year</quote> each place it appears; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF774093E736436383AFDAB719F41686"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subsection (d)(1)(A), by striking <quote>or an initial</quote> and inserting <quote>or, for a year preceding 2024, an initial</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9E97881AC814C86864AC5B9D528A6F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Section 1860D–4(a)(4)(B)(i) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-104">42 U.S.C. 1395w–104(a)(4)(B)(i)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the initial</quote> and inserting <quote>for a year preceding 2024, the initial</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D8C75342D10417C889109FB38552EDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Section 1860D–14(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-114">42 U.S.C. 1395w–114(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H83288BD9A2A048D991810B52CA01419C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="HE6FFB446EB574CBB970B97760BCE879A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>The continuation</quote> and inserting <quote>For a year preceding 2024, the continuation</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H69B2F99AEB7F47159BA0B9BCEA6975FA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(iii), by striking <quote>1860D–2(b)(4)(A)(i)(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>1860D–2(b)(4)(A)(i)(I)(aa)</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HEF57E8A4E5ED4E38992FB66A180AA236"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>The elimination</quote> and inserting <quote>For a year preceding 2024, the elimination</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6BB0A004F7924DC3ADF3B9D0DF10F095"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="H7F40EFDE6CC947F99AFFE0B2ECB9DEC2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>The continuation</quote> and inserting <quote>For a year preceding 2024, the continuation</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H5052495D90BF49A6B3ADDF1DB43BA2FD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>1860D–2(b)(4)(A)(i)(I)</quote> and inserting <quote>1860D–2(b)(4)(A)(i)(I)(aa)</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H956CAAF50BDB46B1A3962593B254C51B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–21(d)(7) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-131">42 U.S.C. 1395w–131(d)(7)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>section 1860D–2(b)(4)(B)(i)</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1860D–2(b)(4)(C)(i)</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A4AB64B22684C069B7FEA973501B411"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–22(a)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-132">42 U.S.C. 1395w–132(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HCD89995B11FD4EF08FE1B19B82540958"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by striking <quote>the value of any discount</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H836683E229D646A5840DEFD2AA7D9777" style="OLC"><text>the value of—</text><clause id="H9EF0AF797B984B14ACFA01E58FF52E5A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for years prior to 2024, any discount</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5ECD23B90FB84871BD82218E37FC9211"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in clause (i), as inserted by subparagraph (A) of this paragraph, by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAF2453F206B1468A8900FECCDB27C69F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3472AE82DC0746CAB17D97A25956BCF5" style="OLC"><clause commented="no" id="HB565F0F8BD8D4B89949A2F52B409210B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for 2024 and each subsequent year, any discount provided pursuant to section 1860D–14C.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D8DE64EC33D4C508BF788288DA25A00"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Section 1860D–41(a)(6) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-151">42 U.S.C. 1395w–151(a)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H4326554AFCD7405581B3C36580FB1555"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>for a year before 2024</quote> after <quote>1860D–2(b)(3)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB156FE489FFE4AB392A0F20D49A0145E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>for such year</quote> before the period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5A09E135E5344A4994FE705CF268691A"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–43 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-153">42 U.S.C. 1395w–153</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H2AC37D23FF3D43E7AE99E6C24DA095B9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="H81179AD3388F4E39A64055BF3A854A14"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC7D00C8666E941DFBA7E8123F6F7DA55" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HE1D94DEF82C14F109EC3560CAF8B6705"><enum>(1)</enum><text>participate in—</text><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5051E79C96BD4BA5BE786BA32228C570"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for 2011 through 2023, the Medicare coverage gap discount program under section 1860D–14A; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H884F307CD8164166B554D29CF15C1AF4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for 2024 and each subsequent year, the manufacturer discount program under section 1860D–14C;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H4A88676BDDDE44E29A308CBA9679033E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (2) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE8AFC4DC07B04E5880E53AE54CAC2F84" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H37FEB2EDFDA94636B069D007924C1938"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have entered into and have in effect—</text><subparagraph id="HA77BCCC70F45490E910997C7DB8F45F7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for 2011 through 2023, an agreement described in subsection (b) of section 1860D–14A with the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFFDC24B7AEC04F968D66AF6183D0E2BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for 2024 and each subsequent year, an agreement described in subsection (b) of section 1860D–14C with the Secretary; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause><clause id="H1B871F29ADC54889A264B7756FE8C189"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (3) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HE31CE3F27AE94B2BBA43C5DFCAD16AB0" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="HBF76342922C8441690EE0E18B79D6F18"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">have entered into and have in effect, under terms and conditions specified by the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="HBB58F1B5347D4D68BF8AFB79AD33FFCE"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2011 through 2023, a contract with a third party that the Secretary has entered into a contract with under subsection (d)(3) of section 1860D–14A; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D12A16F82E24EF4B8710235DD6EBC26"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for 2024 and each subsequent year, a contract with a third party that the Secretary has entered into a contract with under subsection (d)(3) of section 1860D–14C.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA7BCBEF88F6942CE8F910373EA14E45B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subsection (b) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H94BADD3203F14055956152369B286631" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H69F952318B3B491EA945584C9E39B661"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Paragraphs (1)(A), (2)(A), and (3)(A) of subsection (a) shall apply to covered part D drugs dispensed under this part on or after January 1, 2011, and before January 1, 2024, and paragraphs (1)(B), (2)(B), and (3)(B) of such subsection shall apply to covered part D drugs dispensed under this part on or after January 1, 2024.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9FC11CA0B914A5B8D45EF96738E34CC"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1927 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396r-8">42 U.S.C. 1396r–8</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HC8B5C982084B4FF9B6CE65C6CD418B4C"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (c)(1)(C)(i)(VI), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>or under the manufacturer discount program under section 1860D–14C</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB62678F2D4A34A2DBBF303D24DD7F491"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (k)(1)(B)(i)(V), by inserting before the period at the end the following: <quote>or under section 1860D–14C</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7DA03148F3554783A3BF192DB67B336E" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Implementation for 2024 and 2025</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this section, the Secretary shall implement this section, including the amendments made by this section, for 2024 and 2025 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection><subsection id="H221A2ECF90094E468BD83CDC9579B84B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $44,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, $38,000,000 for fiscal year 2023, and $32,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2031, to remain available until expended, to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H352AEA84A0334543AB63F5F151F6DFF3"><enum>302.</enum><header>Maximum monthly cap on cost-sharing payments under prescription drug plans and MA–PD plans</header><subsection id="H1B00D0A05BDA4793A871193DD84AFBCC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1860D–2(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(b)</external-xref>), as amended by <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/301">section 301,</external-xref> is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCBAB972DC3D34E338DB6E7418EA89710"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H7707B3495A3B47B093A8E5B52763D8E5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>, (D), and (E)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H564486D9257840CCBF937E3CA4C71F82"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="H41FACA5B6F03428B9F09D20666289696" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H6BC7FD36BDB14E388B6F922017B071ED"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Maximum monthly cap on cost-sharing payments</header><clause id="H43EE80CDF0ED4DE8AD1ADA22192FA307"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2025, each PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan and each MA organization offering an MA–PD plan shall provide to any enrollee of such plan, including an enrollee who is a subsidy eligible individual (as defined in paragraph (3) of section 1860D–14(a)), the option to elect with respect to a plan year to pay cost-sharing under the plan in monthly amounts that are capped in accordance with this subparagraph.</text></clause><clause id="H7DB14F24F3384C0B87CE83BDF80AD17B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Determination of maximum monthly cap</header><text>For each month in the plan year for which an enrollee in a prescription drug plan or an MA–PD plan has made an election pursuant to clause (i), the PDP sponsor or MA organization shall determine a maximum monthly cap (as defined in clause (iv)) for such enrollee.</text></clause><clause id="H6C3C5E596C684E34A30070E87F0167B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Beneficiary monthly payments</header><text>With respect to an enrollee who has made an election pursuant to clause (i), for each month described in clause (ii), the PDP sponsor or MA organization shall bill such enrollee an amount (not to exceed the maximum monthly cap) for the out-of-pocket costs of such enrollee in such month.</text></clause><clause id="HD29758A2E5EE4177B5E934BD9834032E"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>Maximum monthly cap defined</header><text>In this subparagraph, the term <term>maximum monthly cap</term> means, with respect to an enrollee—</text><subclause id="HDD682CAA5CA94CDFB2C96DDC959F6D3B"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for the first month for which the enrollee has made an election pursuant to clause (i), an amount determined by calculating—</text><item id="H01957AF958DD4734BEF52A4F51AC9BEF"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in paragraph (4)(B) minus the incurred costs of the enrollee as described in paragraph (4)(C); divided by</text></item><item id="H0CCF4C396EDF4861AF87147CFF3AC3E8"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of months remaining in the plan year; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H3A3A055BD2C149AB96752F034413BD3D"><enum>(II)</enum><text>for a subsequent month, an amount determined by calculating—</text><item id="H19196EE1E2A1454C87BC5E98693401D3"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the sum of any remaining out-of-pocket costs owed by the enrollee from a previous month that have not yet been billed to the enrollee and any additional out-of-pocket costs incurred by the enrollee; divided by</text></item><item id="HD588AD4A5432418E9802E35760174445"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the number of months remaining in the plan year.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H754836EF1F2946B28F20FBAF1FA399DE"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Additional requirements</header><text>The following requirements shall apply with respect to the option to make an election pursuant to clause (i) under this subparagraph:</text><subclause id="H7350B46BF83D4A0789AD6096BDE78C79"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Secretarial responsibilities</header><text>The Secretary shall provide information to part D eligible individuals on the option to make such election through educational materials, including through the notices provided under section 1804(a).</text></subclause><subclause id="HE7E9BAD74F934393AA5CDA2C28BBE36C"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Timing of election</header><text>An enrollee in a prescription drug plan or an MA–PD plan may make such an election—</text><item id="H73C0F91F61014073AD40519EE177C257"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>prior to the beginning of the plan year; or</text></item><item id="HEB2CDE62D2174035A95DDFF9FD0A5543"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>in any month during the plan year.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HD376477856D845E0AB88C2DF1E7B81F3"><enum>(III)</enum><header>PDP sponsor and ma organization responsibilities</header><text>Each PDP sponsor offering a prescription drug plan or MA organization offering an MA–PD plan—</text><item id="H774FF684B02048CD95D8F046651688B4"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>may not limit the option for an enrollee to make such an election to certain covered part D drugs;</text></item><item id="HE541877D07B6480E96372FBE324926CD"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>shall, prior to the plan year, notify prospective enrollees of the option to make such an election in promotional materials;</text></item><item id="H35AB3540DEAA400599B05FBA4CB905B7"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>shall include information on such option in enrollee educational materials;</text></item><item id="H3AA6872E18C94E668CEC353911B201ED"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>shall have in place a mechanism to notify a pharmacy during the plan year when an enrollee incurs out-of-pocket costs with respect to covered part D drugs that make it likely the enrollee may benefit from making such an election;</text></item><item id="H5FF5E0FDCBD542268D89111C13A9E0EF"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>shall provide that a pharmacy, after receiving a notification described in item (dd) with respect to an enrollee, informs the enrollee of such notification;</text></item><item id="H3DB77FA55B3E47119AE29D8B84C5A143"><enum>(ff)</enum><text>shall ensure that such an election by an enrollee has no effect on the amount paid to pharmacies (or the timing of such payments) with respect to covered part D drugs dispensed to the enrollee; and</text></item><item id="HBD231A334A424AF3926E02C263E48E66"><enum>(gg)</enum><text>shall have in place a financial reconciliation process to correct inaccuracies in payments made by an enrollee under this subparagraph with respect to covered part D drugs during the plan year.</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HE577E4F016C64C2D8C8E97D220D8D84A"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Failure to pay amount billed</header><text>If an enrollee fails to pay the amount billed for a month as required under this subparagraph, the election of the enrollee pursuant to clause (i) shall be terminated and the enrollee shall pay the cost-sharing otherwise applicable for any covered part D drugs subsequently dispensed to the enrollee up to the annual out-of-pocket threshold specified in paragraph (4)(B).</text></subclause><subclause id="H312968E8100D4A01AE2738BA9B69A733"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Clarification regarding past due amounts</header><text>Nothing in this subparagraph shall be construed as prohibiting a PDP sponsor or an MA organization from billing an enrollee for an amount owed under this subparagraph.</text></subclause><subclause id="H6BF1C08B6FDA47E7B0A42F3B25EB115C"><enum>(VI)</enum><header>Treatment of unsettled balances</header><text>Any unsettled balances with respect to amounts owed under this subparagraph shall be treated as plan losses and the Secretary shall not be liable for any such balances outside of those assumed as losses estimated in plan bids.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H44BE85CE19294126897BB9543B8F9011"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)—</text><subparagraph id="H3763820AD0524481B5705F27FA2ABBE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by striking <quote>in subparagraph (E)</quote> and inserting <quote>in subparagraph (E) and subject to subparagraph (F)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H759833B61DED46ABBB4798A468088D37"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block id="HD7968B0C4C734C70AC5A1B274656D46E" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H8838DEBFEF7C4C0DAB4090E4E5D25D56"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Inclusion of costs paid under maximum monthly cap option</header><text>In applying subparagraph (A), with respect to an enrollee who has made an election pursuant to clause (i) of paragraph (2)(E), costs shall be treated as incurred if such costs are paid by a PDP sponsor or an MA organization under the option provided under such paragraph.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCAB9D6A1827E4512AF57D0C374258FD6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application to alternative prescription drug coverage</header><text>Section 1860D–2(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="H926E941E67034CDEAE800164079B7DB1" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H3C1BCB0624E045C09564D3CBE47B1B2F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Same maximum monthly cap on cost-sharing</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2025, the maximum monthly cap on cost-sharing payments under the option provided under subsection (b)(2)(E) shall apply to such coverage.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H92CA259EB8E9429CB1DFF2AC15EBEE82"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation for 2025</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement this section, including the amendments made by this section, for 2025 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection><subsection id="H84997FE2100D4CB0846A1BD05580E820"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Funding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In addition to amounts otherwise available, there are appropriated to the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services, out of any money in the Treasury not otherwise appropriated, $1,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2022 through 2031, to remain available until expended, to carry out the provisions of, including the amendments made by, this section.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HFD55DC81296F479F8BCD5204921AAC2A"><enum>IV</enum><header>Repeal of Certain Prescription Drug Rebate Rule</header><section id="H4514C6E6C60A487A85E7C87855D8CFBC" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>401.</enum><header>Prohibiting implementation of rule relating to eliminating the anti-kickback statute safe harbor protection for prescription drug rebates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning January 1, 2026, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall not implement, administer, or enforce the provisions of the final rule published by the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Health and Human Services on November 30, 2020, and titled <quote>Fraud and Abuse; Removal of Safe Harbor Protection for Rebates Involving Prescription Pharmaceuticals and Creation of New Safe Harbor Protection for Certain Point-of-Sale Reductions in Price on Prescription Pharmaceuticals and Certain Pharmacy Benefit Manager Service Fees</quote> (85 Fed. Reg. 76666).</text></section></title><title id="HF40B01E2172F4F40AAA556202DC8D5CD" commented="no"><enum>V</enum><header>Miscellaneous</header><section id="H483800329CAA43FAA1AB3F56D3315C44" commented="no"><enum>501.</enum><header>Appropriate cost-sharing for certain insulin products under Medicare part D</header><subsection id="HBCD3F580A9E944A3A79F4326DC063AA3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1860D–2 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1BC84DB310994C65A723918AAD59719D" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H05C63454170942DCA3E18F7B93427546" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>The coverage</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (8), the coverage</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF9D24EF101C4006B0F70670D4DAD224" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>and (D)</quote> and inserting <quote>and (D) and paragraph (8)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8F6B69B983D94D389BC96D623C007291" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>and (4)</quote> and inserting <quote>(4), and (8)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7F9E52E9D74E49D9BCE39FF60CB2E14F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)(i), by striking <quote>The coverage</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (8), the coverage</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5D6351844A894F719E880217EE67CBA3" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H9E7D1F596134411D8D07FB4B6E9B78EB"><paragraph id="H8496762F683245B2A4180A051FB4B341" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Treatment of cost-sharing for certain insulin products</header><subparagraph id="H106F2F073B0D45A0B568763C8BBEE401" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2023, the following shall apply with respect to insulin products (as defined in subparagraph (B)):</text><clause id="HD5D2BBEFA3CA46B9AD0F2ACA5317BEF8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No application of deductible</header><text>The deductible under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to such insulin products.</text></clause><clause id="HC0E3D1B223B54A94956244096441DCF5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Application of cost-sharing</header><subclause id="H68C4A00170904F1EA742E4F5FC3A5E09" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Plan year 2023</header><text>For plan year 2023, the coverage provides benefits for such insulin products, regardless of whether an individual has reached the initial coverage limit under paragraph (3) or the out-of-pocket threshold under paragraph (4), with cost-sharing that is equal to the applicable copayment amount.</text></subclause><subclause id="H5380A7A0167A4AF99D1644201606485A" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Plan year 2024 and subsequent plan years</header><text>For plan year 2024 and subsequent plan years, the coverage provides benefits for such insulin products, prior to an individual reaching the out-of-pocket threshold under paragraph (4), with cost-sharing that is equal to the applicable copayment amount.</text></subclause><subclause id="HC4362B7FE06C435C9D6848B621FFEDA2" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Applicable copayment amount</header><text>For purposes of this clause, the term <term>applicable copayment amount</term> means, with respect to an insulin product under a prescription drug plan or an MA–PD plan, an amount that is not more than $35.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C1ED6799526497B808ACFB6E61476D2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Insulin product</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>insulin product</term> means an insulin product that is approved under section 505 of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act or licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act and marketed pursuant to such approval or licensure, including any insulin product that has been deemed to be licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act pursuant to section 7002(e)(4) of the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act of 2009 and marketed pursuant to such section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H681F787FDA9E43D9B453FB1B1153EB72" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8B01653611624A0F9076566585176C61"><paragraph id="H88824D15B28D428E8472C98BEF050853" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Treatment of cost-sharing for insulin products</header><text>The coverage is provided in accordance with subsection (b)(8).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9070F67463EC46EDAFB1D2924799A416" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to cost-Sharing for low-Income individuals</header><text>Section 1860D–14(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-114">42 U.S.C. 1395w–114(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H4DB85008EEEE4EB499BA2E413A1B1CC4" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="HCED9FA4BBA8347849665274C500C2BBC" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D)(iii), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For plan year 2023 and subsequent plan years, the copayment amount applicable under the preceding sentence to an insulin product (as defined in section 1860D–2(b)(8)(B)) furnished to the individual may not exceed the applicable copayment amount for the product under the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan in which the individual is enrolled.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCAEEA28C38764D5190C9BDE790DC2492" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by inserting the following before the period at the end <quote>or under section 1860D–2(b)(8) in the case of an insulin product (as defined in subparagraph (B) of such section)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B90784CDE4C4D169E27B06DDCC8F51E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="HE773AD7B994343C1A551631C4C0A4516" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For plan year 2023 and subsequent plan years, the amount of the coinsurance applicable under the preceding sentence to an insulin product (as defined in section 1860D–2(b)(8)(B)) furnished to the individual may not exceed the applicable copayment amount for the product under the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan in which the individual is enrolled.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F84D6A3DFFE4BABB03A5350F1E81E9B" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by adding at the end the following new sentence: <quote>For plan year 2023, the amount of the copayment or coinsurance applicable under the preceding sentence to an insulin product (as defined in section 1860D–2(b)(8)(B)) furnished to the individual may not exceed the applicable copayment amount for the product under the prescription drug plan or MA–PD plan in which the individual is enrolled.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFF3F1C75821D440FBA38E297FDF8A12F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Secretary shall implement this section for plan years 2023 and 2024 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection></section><section id="H0C49B23B802541BBB1E401C9F6D90521" commented="no"><enum>502.</enum><header>Coverage of adult vaccines recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices under Medicare part D</header><subsection id="H89E67713E2CA46A3BC030F4262A173DB" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Ensuring treatment of cost-Sharing is consistent with treatment of vaccines under medicare part b</header><text>Section 1860D–2 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-102">42 U.S.C. 1395w–102</external-xref>), as amended by section 501, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H33845F60E5EB4FB48CC16760EF532DDC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H7BC87E72C05840B6908899B167D36B6E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(A), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95F103BB7FA24B87A90FD2A304EDDD50" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)(A), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H635C0759976C4F0A88C693AC0A03AADE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in paragraph (3)(A), by striking <quote>and (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>(8), and (9)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60850E1BE5BF4BD1A6A78B13AAAB2152" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>in paragraph (4)(A)(i), by striking <quote>paragraph (8)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraphs (8) and (9)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCF3047125274D8C95729A4D3198C164" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HCAB6507A350B4D5DBB278FD565041317" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HE8FD4751D7304F628EDCDC1541E34750" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Treatment of cost-sharing for adult vaccines recommended by the advisory committee on immunization practices consistent with treatment of vaccines under part b</header><subparagraph id="H55C93C57150D47C4A25687722C270584" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2024, the following shall apply with respect to an adult vaccine recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (as defined in subparagraph (B)):</text><clause id="H2B0282688F4245E7938607D8022F8227" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>No application of deductible</header><text>The deductible under paragraph (1) shall not apply with respect to such vaccine.</text></clause><clause id="H62D2EB4FD36140E2982A31258833D694" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>No application of coinsurance or any other cost-sharing</header><text>There shall be no coinsurance or other cost-sharing under this part with respect to such vaccine, regardless of whether for costs below, at, or above the initial coverage limit under paragraph (3) or the out-of-pocket threshold under paragraph (4).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H06874AE46F5A4352A4D1F54A8D39E361" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Adult vaccines recommended by the advisory committee on immunization practices</header><text>For purposes of this paragraph, the term <term>adult vaccine recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices</term> means a covered part D drug that is a vaccine licensed under section 351 of the Public Health Service Act for use by adult populations and administered in accordance with recommendations of the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0D221A610DF4B28B5B57A8DFEB5CBD3" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following new paragraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H66364A0A69DE41058D0EAB353707FF63" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H4DF055462F7D4EFDA58E94C5E2AA5E9E" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Treatment of cost-sharing for adult vaccines recommended by the advisory committee on immunization practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The coverage is in accordance with subsection (b)(9).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H90BF4991CE7C432DBB4B0DBA26B88740" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendments to cost-Sharing for low-Income individuals</header><text>Section 1860D–14(a) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395w-114">42 U.S.C. 1395w–114(a)</external-xref>), as amended by section 501, is further amended—</text><paragraph id="H1FD2955DAC6C4BF580833C3EE03CDF97" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)(D), in each of clauses (ii) and (iii), by striking <quote>In the case</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (6), in the case</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0262F23FA13C4CCB9BA96A7391B1BBE1" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="H5E1901A25AA9452E8D7D3B16D315E971" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>A reduction</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (6), a reduction</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF3AF07D8227C485DB40ADE728D22E075" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (D), by striking <quote>The substitution</quote> and inserting <quote>Subject to paragraph (6), the substitution</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC3499E39B21B4AE29BEE77ECFD761C2C" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in subparagraph (E), by striking <quote>subsection (c)</quote> and inserting <quote>paragraph (6) and subsection (c)</quote>; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC29CB2EFCFA947688F932F8F0A4DBB6B" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HCE8B51FE87DC4324830AE8026C6063D8" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H538702E0DEAB4372A5A81E26B6D12816" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>No application of cost-sharing for adult vaccines recommended by the advisory committee on immunization practices</header><text>For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2024, there shall be no cost-sharing under this section, including no annual deductible applicable under this section, with respect to an adult vaccine recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices (as defined in subparagraph (B) of such section).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDCB6EA0D0BD8463E9F4C251B552BA975" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting coverage under part D of title XVIII of the Social Security Act for vaccines that are not recommended by the Advisory Committee on Immunization Practices.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC223FE09B9B2448C86ED2385D8780414" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Implementation for 2024</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall implement this section, including the amendments made by this section, for 2024 by program instruction or otherwise.</text></subsection></section><section id="H64403C339C8C4A088AA4D3BD2CC91182"><enum>503.</enum><header>Payment for biosimilar biological products during initial period</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1847A(c)(4) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(c)(4)) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC1FDE5E93DD94284B849237778822C21"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in each of subparagraphs (A) and (B), by redesignating clauses (i) and (ii) as subclauses (I) and (II), respectively, and moving such subclauses 2 ems to the right;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA9200D5975C4D74AEBC717B99373215"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii) and moving such clauses 2 ems to the right;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C6D07C7415B476FB11AEFA499E1C357"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">unavailable</header-in-text>.—In the case</quote> and inserting “<header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">unavailable</header-in-text>.—</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB7243E76FF904BBA96B54D9EC839FE03" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HC3DD115E43DF4122978A866B811B7411"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), in the case</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HF895F4C6DB0C4212A8BCA3FAC3A42434"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5E47595A9B3E4A58956D7E9B10E1B3C3" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="HB766D52DC02D4027B98998FA8EB81F21"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitation on payment amount for biosimilar biological products during initial period</header><text>In the case of a biosimilar biological product furnished on or after July 1, 2023, during the initial period described in subparagraph (A) with respect to the biosimilar biological product, the amount payable under this section for the biosimilar biological product is the lesser of the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H19D38EFD408F465B8D69255BAA89968C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The amount determined under clause (ii) of such subparagraph for the biosimilar biological product.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H0A05883EA6014B46AE7A50402B25CD8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The amount determined under subsection (b)(1)(B) for the reference biological product.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="H2A76F194E30B43FF946F1DE9D0147326"><enum>504.</enum><header>Temporary increase in Medicare part B payment for certain biosimilar biological products</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 1847A(b)(8) of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1395w–3a(b)(8)) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H5CF854FA06054EAD89964FB7794A2241"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by redesignating subparagraphs (A) and (B) as clauses (i) and (ii), respectively, and moving the margin of each such redesignated clause 2 ems to the right;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51ADB96E922A411194C00BE78A8EF0B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote><header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">product</header-in-text>.—The amount</quote> and inserting the following: “<header-in-text level="paragraph" style="OLC">product</header-in-text>.—</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H642A100C61074D64B477177009599C15" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H4CE042D1C27343FF83CE964E31944C84"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (B), the amount</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H09486F6A26094A809485E5E34624E42F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6F9EBB63802E4843B61D96A33CE2466B" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H511296CF79414223B49F67E20999C8AC"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Temporary payment increase</header><clause id="HD2852FFCC7A74EA7A91C40A0ABDCF8EC"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a qualifying biosimilar biological product that is furnished during the applicable 5-year period for such product, the amount specified in this paragraph for such product with respect to such period is the sum determined under subparagraph (A), except that clause (ii) of such subparagraph shall be applied by substituting <quote>8 percent</quote> for <quote>6 percent</quote>.</text></clause><clause id="H2298B3B08BDD4C82B3F5356E9E8ACA3F"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Applicable 5-year period</header><text>For purposes of clause (i), the applicable 5-year period for a qualifying biosimilar biological product is—</text><subclause id="HD72A6A4FB8734F20ADC963911C48B874"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of such a product for which payment was made under this paragraph as of March 31, 2022, the 5-year period beginning on April 1, 2022; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7D8DA75C7F7543A8BD7F5D6B440B17A1"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of such a product for which payment is first made under this paragraph during a calendar quarter during the period beginning April 1, 2022, and ending March 31, 2027, the 5-year period beginning on the first day of such calendar quarter during which such payment is first made.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1B39894A985843D18AAA30D0646F4C2B"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Qualifying biosimilar biological product defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>qualifying biosimilar biological product</term> means a biosimilar biological product described in paragraph (1)(C) with respect to which—</text><subclause id="H13B0FFDC272149F99C5AFF9E1E49746F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in the case of a product described in clause (ii)(I), the average sales price under paragraph (8)(A)(i) for a calendar quarter during the 5-year period described in such clause is not more than the average sales price under paragraph (4)(A) for such quarter for the reference biological product; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H36EB44FF5AED4638B6795085A54D9FAC"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in the case of a product described in clause (ii)(II), the average sales price under paragraph (8)(A)(i) for a calendar quarter during the 5-year period described in such clause is not more than the average sales price under paragraph (4)(A) for such quarter for the reference biological product.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section><section id="HE203B698F42046FAAAD2326D577B6E14"><enum>505.</enum><header>Improving access to adult vaccines under Medicaid and CHIP</header><subsection id="H8B04C75FA9234089B51CA2C28642E11B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Medicaid</header><paragraph id="HB16D4EEFEDB7448B88CF41ACE45F1790"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring coverage of adult vaccinations</header><subparagraph id="H473575EB51374C4E977EBEFDB32DB82F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1902(a)(10)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(A)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding clause (i) by inserting <quote>(13)(B),</quote> after <quote>(5),</quote>.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD2392D05F7CB4E61AFAF952923BAC187" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Medically needy</header><text>Section 1902(a)(10)(C)(iv) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a(a)(10)(C)(iv)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, (13)(B),</quote> after <quote>(5)</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF75F0A2878D4497CA5D42FFE1B932DFA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No cost-sharing for vaccinations</header><subparagraph id="HF44AEDB4E20D41EB93936BF3F45B6334"><enum>(A)</enum><header>General cost-sharing limitations</header><text>Section 1916 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o">42 U.S.C. 1396o</external-xref>) is amended—</text><clause id="HB8EBEAF20BE8497FBBC049CFFA2FFACD"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(2)—</text><subclause id="HFEA7BE5D96294B389E93C31B901EC065"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by inserting a comma after <quote>State plan</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA35F0B46A51A47EF93A3D19A6DF26E01"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a comma;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8AE4BE696AAF43B1A7C6AEF48C8717ED"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H90CD9DA8667E4CF49A546296223B85D0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H7F7F0E2E4DEA4BD095F483689C264E29"><subparagraph id="H5749AE2410B44C2DBDE6D569FAC7B2FC"><enum>(J)</enum><text>vaccines described in section 1905(a)(13)(B) and the administration of such vaccines; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="H3CEB2472048B409097607B04F7ED3E75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(2)—</text><subclause id="H59240621CB0D47078ADDAA001D190A82"><enum>(I)</enum><text>in subparagraph (G), by inserting a comma after <quote>State plan</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC6E1D54155A44D9C818EFD4103BA43EB"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in subparagraph (H), by striking <quote>; or</quote> and inserting a comma;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBE38AE2A78654CDFB4F6BB997FF8CFF5"><enum>(III)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting <quote>, or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H99707603FE7C4FF28BB167B22AE67C54"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB66924E2A9974EB5B7EFC6E4A3DA992C"><subparagraph id="H4CBA7D2A9BA142349B7648E66997B1CF"><enum>(J)</enum><text>vaccines described in section 1905(a)(13)(B) and the administration of such vaccines; and</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6C862985CDC744FB9EE6129D3267198F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Application to alternative cost-sharing</header><text>Section 1916A(b)(3)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396o-1">42 U.S.C. 1396o–1(b)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new clause:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H34A6A559D198489086ED6FEEA3048DB3"><clause id="H53B16403141545B0B42EE5125E608835"><enum>(xiv)</enum><text>Vaccines described in section 1905(a)(13)(B) and the administration of such vaccines.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H95B1EF38197541559D7D665B3A0613FD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Increased FMAP for adult vaccines</header><text>Section 1905(b) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(b)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HFD6B40752B694D10B12DDD741ED66E30"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and (5)</quote> and inserting <quote>(5)</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H908006A55C99457B82A628160D7DE94B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>services and vaccines described in subparagraphs (A) and (B) of subsection (a)(13), and prohibits cost-sharing for such services and vaccines</quote> and inserting <quote>services described in subsection (a)(13)(A), and prohibits cost-sharing for such services</quote>;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2D7D30B977C40378BACB1FDF8595289"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by striking <quote>medical assistance for such services and vaccines</quote> and inserting <quote>medical assistance for such services</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72E5DCD4D66F4A809C2B1D6C53CEF4EE" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(D)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>, and (6) during the first 8 fiscal quarters beginning on or after the effective date of this clause, in the case of a State which, as of the date of enactment of the Act titled <quote>An Act to provide for reconciliation pursuant to title II of S. Con. Res. 14</quote>, provides medical assistance for vaccines described in subsection (a)(13)(B) and their administration and prohibits cost-sharing for such vaccines, the Federal medical assistance percentage, as determined under this subsection and subsection (y), shall be increased by 1 percentage point with respect to medical assistance for such vaccines</quote> before the first period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB3668A9FCAEB4269B42A0EB8651E5D06"><enum>(b)</enum><header>CHIP</header><paragraph id="H4DD83DA1FCB44E71B32E81EEB8307216"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requiring coverage of adult vaccinations</header><text>Section 2103(c) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc(c)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H42DE2F7C66F141DBAEEDE02B9AAF000D"><paragraph id="H9E3267C9238046509476CDF970B72A95"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Required coverage of approved, recommended adult vaccines and their administration</header><text>Regardless of the type of coverage elected by a State under subsection (a), if the State child health plan or a waiver of such plan provides child health assistance or pregnancy-related assistance (as defined in section 2112) to an individual who is 19 years of age or older, such assistance shall include coverage of vaccines described in section 1905(a)(13)(B) and their administration.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D12D19E20CC4541901A77157210CAC6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>No cost-sharing for vaccinations</header><text>Section 2103(e)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1397cc">42 U.S.C. 1397cc(e)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>vaccines described in subsection (c)(12) (and the administration of such vaccines),</quote> after <quote>in vitro diagnostic products described in subsection (c)(10) (and administration of such products),</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H35CC4C1502054A1BA167C4691E701EE5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section take effect on the 1st day of the 1st fiscal quarter that begins on or after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act and shall apply to expenditures made under a State plan or waiver of such plan under title XIX of the Social Security Act (42 U.S.C. 1396 through 1396w–6) or under a State child health plan or waiver of such plan under title XXI of such Act (42 U.S.C. 1397aa through 1397mm) on or after such effective date.</text></subsection></section></title><title id="HA4DECB66DC2844A5A5BE301EECFEA3B8"><enum>VI</enum><header>Additional Insulin Policies</header><section id="HDEA8CEA535974C1BA5DF38D35221CD1F"><enum>601.</enum><header>ERISA requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products</header><subsection id="HEAA214BF1D424DE9A5170401D506316B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subpart B of part 7 of subtitle B of title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1185">29 U.S.C. 1185 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H980D9A4D6A684A3BBE6553EB3B5197FC"><section id="H3702D0A38D7440E490BF9318062ED6B2"><enum>726.</enum><header>Requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products</header><subsection id="HF8386E9CF6B5431488D2C86328900290"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2023, a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group health insurance coverage shall provide coverage of selected insulin products, and with respect to such products, shall not—</text><paragraph id="H07F8A0C37D894155837C8A10E8F0CCE2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply any deductible; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85F44F05AF44415794F9068B13F500B6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose any cost-sharing in excess of the lesser of, per 30-day supply—</text><subparagraph id="H95371C72E3174B68B3DFBF3727A0F422"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$35; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEAE1D683396F46A39B586D9F43B7E6A4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount equal to 25 percent of the negotiated price of the selected insulin product net of all price concessions received by or on behalf of the plan or coverage, including price concessions received by or on behalf of third-party entities providing services to the plan or coverage, such as pharmacy benefit management services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBEECEB780C964BB7A2E6B138DB872042"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HA3A0177C2E064CDB844F8102671094F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selected insulin products</header><text>The term <term>selected insulin products</term> means at least one of each dosage form (such as vial, pump, or inhaler dosage forms) of each different type (such as rapid-acting, short-acting, intermediate-acting, long-acting, ultra long-acting, and premixed) of insulin (as defined below), when available, as selected by the group health plan or health insurance issuer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9B98F9A96F78474BAB0B87E369835E68"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insulin defined</header><text>The term <term>insulin</term> means insulin that is licensed under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) and continues to be marketed under such section, including any insulin product that has been deemed to be licensed under section 351(a) of such Act pursuant to section 7002(e)(4) of the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) and continues to be marketed pursuant to such licensure. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B979BB54246401EAD7BB49AD32CE95B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Out-of-Network providers</header><text>Nothing in this section requires a plan or issuer that has a network of providers to provide benefits for selected insulin products described in this section that are delivered by an out-of-network provider, or precludes a plan or issuer that has a network of providers from imposing higher cost-sharing than the levels specified in subsection (a) for selected insulin products described in this section that are delivered by an out-of-network provider.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1A07D901CFD8411BBC5CF2F65D802795"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not be construed to require coverage of, or prevent a group health plan or health insurance coverage from imposing cost-sharing other than the levels specified in subsection (a) on, insulin products that are not selected insulin products, to the extent that such coverage is not otherwise required and such cost-sharing is otherwise permitted under Federal and applicable State law.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HB96B8C206F4C4F0895DADCF501DE035A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of cost-Sharing towards deductibles and out-of-Pocket maximums</header><text>Any cost-sharing payments made pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall be counted toward any deductible or out-of-pocket maximum that applies under the plan or coverage.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H1883C18C76564AA68A14F8F4E2AC5B7F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 1 of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/1001">29 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 725 the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D15BF78A04B404EB52E36A99DA3A00F" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 726. Requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>. </after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H1AD773AAF38A422483BAD96F19E52097"><enum>602.</enum><header>Public Health Service Act requirements with respect to cost-sharing for insulin products</header><subsection id="H0A74F0AB8C1B450685C499DFA54BE87F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part D of title XXVII of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300gg-111">42 U.S.C. 300gg–111 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21CB53159F5F4D67A4949F0908F612AD"><section id="H133B9E20B78D4B68B90246D3F6F408EA"><enum>2799A–11.</enum><header>Requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products</header><subsection id="HC6C5E9A57A0A40CE93024C1BEFE15379"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2023, a group health plan or health insurance issuer offering group or individual health insurance coverage shall provide coverage of selected insulin products, and with respect to such products, shall not—</text><paragraph id="HEB3DDDDB05C0409B92ECBCC96E8C8C96"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply any deductible; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H31B843A1E84A44368B845E59CDEE4632"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose any cost-sharing in excess of the lesser of, per 30-day supply—</text><subparagraph id="H7A2724EEA65B49CCB7D7EA71BFE19B16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$35; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D4439B327F049FABA5D5DC14FE279F6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount equal to 25 percent of the negotiated price of the selected insulin product net of all price concessions received by or on behalf of the plan or coverage, including price concessions received by or on behalf of third-party entities providing services to the plan or coverage, such as pharmacy benefit management services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H29323A59278749E8AC947385119CDBC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HB06984AD8020482C8C02E3DB6B142AAD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selected insulin products</header><text>The term <term>selected insulin products</term> means at least one of each dosage form (such as vial, pump, or inhaler dosage forms) of each different type (such as rapid-acting, short-acting, intermediate-acting, long-acting, ultra long-acting, and premixed) of insulin (as defined below), when available, as selected by the group health plan or health insurance issuer.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C5D19CACAA44A8A1D358082981F393"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insulin defined</header><text>The term <term>insulin</term> means insulin that is licensed under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 and continues to be marketed under such section, including any insulin product that has been deemed to be licensed under section 351(a) pursuant to section 7002(e)(4) of the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act of 2009 and continues to be marketed pursuant to such licensure. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1B256BE5D5E742B18D430A012DF52213"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Out-of-Network providers</header><text>Nothing in this section requires a plan or issuer that has a network of providers to provide benefits for selected insulin products described in this section that are delivered by an out-of-network provider, or precludes a plan or issuer that has a network of providers from imposing higher cost-sharing than the levels specified in subsection (a) for selected insulin products described in this section that are delivered by an out-of-network provider.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC1D8529BF58B4F24A79E27DE85FC6880"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not be construed to require coverage of, or prevent a group health plan or health insurance coverage from imposing cost-sharing other than the levels specified in subsection (a) on, insulin products that are not selected insulin products, to the extent that such coverage is not otherwise required and such cost-sharing is otherwise permitted under Federal and applicable State law.</text></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="HA8852805862A4AAE825808387A8A2C58"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of cost-Sharing towards deductibles and out-of-Pocket maximums</header><text>Any cost-sharing payments made pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall be counted toward any deductible or out-of-pocket maximum that applies under the plan or coverage.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H6ED1ABCF3CB44BA395C072E07D3D55EB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>No effect on other cost-Sharing</header><text>Section 1302(d)(2) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(d)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEDDC37029C594D0D9BC59AE0E246CA84" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HF770E733BE6645D6A6C5FB32DDA8E33D"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Special rule relating to insulin coverage</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The exemption of coverage of selected insulin products (as defined in section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act) from the application of any deductible pursuant to section 2799A–11(a)(1) of such Act, section 726(a)(1) of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974, or <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/9826">section 9826(a)(1)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 shall not be considered when determining the actuarial value of a qualified health plan under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H3DE2713AB54542F98A8CF94B350A403E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Coverage of certain insulin products under catastrophic plans</header><text>Section 1302(e) of the Patient Protection and Affordable Care Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/18022">42 U.S.C. 18022(e)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HEF8ACF27815E4E8CA14DBFC39258D9CB"><paragraph id="HCEA5FD0165464B82B5BCA902D3D33D4D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coverage of certain insulin products</header><subparagraph id="H97405204139A48BC9A429BF61ED08F34"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding paragraph (1)(B)(i), a health plan described in paragraph (1) shall provide coverage of selected insulin products, in accordance with section 2799A–11 of the Public Health Service Act, for a plan year before an enrolled individual has incurred cost-sharing expenses in an amount equal to the annual limitation in effect under subsection (c)(1) for the plan year.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37EEF6FE2FCB44FBBC525BDDD46A5A5B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terminology</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H740E58FB4D5D46BFADB4B46B5E9C2F20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the term <term>selected insulin products</term> has the meaning given such term in section 2799A–11(b) of the Public Health Service Act; and</text></clause><clause id="H6A3D6F471A004D5492D56A83B6EC8BC7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the requirements of section 2799A–11 of such Act shall be applied by deeming each reference in such section to <quote>individual health insurance coverage</quote> to be a reference to a plan described in paragraph (1). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HC4966A2CE04C407DB16EFDC7F181C77E"><enum>603.</enum><header>IRC requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products</header><subsection id="H56A09293A2A74506990A6F1FC05E3C25"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H290E42D3ECDE49FEBC9A4A61B80BDFDC"><section id="HA8A97A0A0CC1481D99408CA47603D1E4"><enum>9826.</enum><header>Requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products</header><subsection id="H06DB56AD79E847DFAF4E43A22595FD27"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For plan years beginning on or after January 1, 2023, a group health plan shall provide coverage of selected insulin products, and with respect to such products, shall not—</text><paragraph id="H32FDE592EC724D2D90052451D01ACF16"><enum>(1)</enum><text>apply any deductible; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01B5A99217D94551BB5CC6339B4EA1F8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>impose any cost-sharing in excess of the lesser of, per 30-day supply—</text><subparagraph id="HBF75092C523A465AA711DE051BAC28F4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$35; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0E07B51A70CF44839326194C96DBEFED"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the amount equal to 25 percent of the negotiated price of the selected insulin product net of all price concessions received by or on behalf of the plan, including price concessions received by or on behalf of third-party entities providing services to the plan, such as pharmacy benefit management services.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H378C427DBE904D37ABA9A85304ED6AC0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H21949AA9D8E943C39CB7F94ABF244342"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selected insulin products</header><text>The term <term>selected insulin products</term> means at least one of each dosage form (such as vial, pump, or inhaler dosage forms) of each different type (such as rapid-acting, short-acting, intermediate-acting, long-acting, ultra long-acting, and premixed) of insulin (as defined below), when available, as selected by the group health plan.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H641B079B363742F4AB0C61AE3AC20523"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Insulin defined</header><text>The term <term>insulin</term> means insulin that is licensed under subsection (a) or (k) of section 351 of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/262">42 U.S.C. 262</external-xref>) and continues to be marketed under such section, including any insulin product that has been deemed to be licensed under section 351(a) of such Act pursuant to section 7002(e)(4) of the Biologics Price Competition and Innovation Act of 2009 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/111/148">Public Law 111–148</external-xref>) and continues to be marketed pursuant to such licensure. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0506282DA82C40069AAEC78E35A649EE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Out-of-Network providers</header><text>Nothing in this section requires a plan that has a network of providers to provide benefits for selected insulin products described in this section that are delivered by an out-of-network provider, or precludes a plan that has a network of providers from imposing higher cost-sharing than the levels specified in subsection (a) for selected insulin products described in this section that are delivered by an out-of-network provider.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFD7F7FF1E4DA4FFCA16E23C8820AF9FF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Subsection (a) shall not be construed to require coverage of, or prevent a group health plan from imposing cost-sharing other than the levels specified in subsection (a) on, insulin products that are not selected insulin products, to the extent that such coverage is not otherwise required and such cost-sharing is otherwise permitted under Federal and applicable State law.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1295A1E53CE14AB1989762DB6BB21460" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application of cost-Sharing towards deductibles and out-of-Pocket maximums</header><text>Any cost-sharing payments made pursuant to subsection (a)(2) shall be counted toward any deductible or out-of-pocket maximum that applies under the plan.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H26FA5E94760647E3BDFA0A32100AF65E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subchapter B of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/100">chapter 100</external-xref> is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H45546C45702E4EFFA9B6ECC9C6086BB2" style="OLC"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 9826. Requirements with respect to cost-sharing for certain insulin products.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></title></legis-body></bill> 

