<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H026E7F27744245ECA5FC758D91574E01" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6821 IH: United States-Russian Federation Seafood Reciprocity Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6821</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220222">February 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="Y000033">Mr. Young</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation of seafood and seafood products from the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H58E83597C0DB448F968F0AF1A6D1B20A" style="OLC"><section id="HE10E65D0FC0349C1BBA7D4E85DA59AC2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>United States-Russian Federation Seafood Reciprocity Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H9BDCFA96195A4708A52437B60DD7BF8F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text><paragraph id="H158C5E65AC4B404A9AF2A41BD7DCFC92"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2014, the Russian Federation invaded and annexed the Crimean Peninsula from Ukraine.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8A5BB2E1163249F1A316CFB4CA2FD2CA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The United States and its allies imposed sanctions with respect to the Russian Federation as a result of that hostile and illegal action.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEB8B035AE38438B899EA1F2BF28AFE1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In retaliation, the Government of the Russian Federation imposed an embargo on agricultural products, including seafood, imported from the United States, the European Union, Australia, Canada, and Norway.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB9C18313DB34A0BA4F5375429672890"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before imposing the embargo, the Russian Federation was an important export market for United States seafood products.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5DE80EBD0F847CC98CEA7B2EE3B5DE3"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russian-origin seafood products continue to enter into the United States market without restriction and imports of such products increased roughly 173 percent in value between 2013, the year before the imposition of the embargo, and 2020.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H3DB615B6EE07468896FBBADAF5A545AC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Prohibition on importation of seafood and seafood products from the Russian Federation</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The importation into the United States from the Russian Federation of any article classifiable under chapter 3 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States is prohibited.</text></section><section id="HCEB446DFEE7E48C6A0448F4BD64468CC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Termination</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The prohibition under section 3 shall terminate on the date on which the President determines and certifies Congress that the Government of the Russian Federation has terminated its prohibition on the importation of seafood products from the United States. </text></section><section id="HAB2EC6D014C84D3CAFB2CDFD32F54E95"><enum>5.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 3 applies with respect to articles entered, or withdrawn from warehouse for consumption, on or after the date that is 15 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

