<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1231C18053564328AEAE177BE22D65FF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6723 IH: Gateway to Careers Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6723</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220215">February 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="S001157">Mr. David Scott of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000391">Mr. Krishnamoorthi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a career pathway grant program.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H81AFC478225F4D969BA9FA52EEB95067" style="OLC"><section id="H63D356A660984E9090F6D9BD74797563" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Gateway to Careers Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDBC94D7F3F664F369A6F7C1378CF850A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Career Pathways Grant Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VIII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1161a">20 U.S.C. 1161a et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H06F449D5CE134717AF0C6ECD16E2263B" style="OLC"><part id="H8E072265A9544246B0971A33D30E2D82" style="OLC"><enum>BB</enum><header>Career Pathway Grant Program</header><section id="HEC851FE95056456CB41DE2CBB23FB6F9"><enum>899.</enum><header>Career Pathway Grant Program</header><subsection id="H8C946EDB13584175B72166038BBD7DE8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H2DDD3BEC2FE7445F8ED03D118529605D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>WIOA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>area career and technical education school</term>, <term>career pathway</term>, <term>in-demand industry sector or occupation</term>, <term>individual with a barrier to employment</term>, <term>industry or sector partnership</term>, <term>integrated education and training</term>, <term>local board</term>, <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term>, and <term>State board</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3102">29 U.S.C. 3102</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FC4F38F99E440679BF63D816E7ACB01"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Career pathway partnership</header><subparagraph id="HB180E5C82F014A7ABD74ED66C1286DCA"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In General</header><text>The term <term>career pathway partnership</term> means a partnership—</text><clause id="H223BA734FD70465097FE6C119E3A562C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>between an eligible institution, a workforce development partner described in subparagraph (B), and an education partner described in subparagraph (C);</text></clause><clause id="H02C1EDE4B6B043BA8977FF4D5A73EAA5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>evidenced by a formal agreement between partners; and</text></clause><clause id="HD0E9C275502B4CF88BDCDA4C544842CC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>that is intended to support the development and implementation of a career pathway program.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC51F18DA2CDF45418807CD0173F381AF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Workforce development partner</header><text>A workforce development partner described in subparagraph (A) means one or more of the following:</text><clause id="H3D3D25D55B324DAAA01BCBACA3E234AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A local board or a State board.</text></clause><clause id="HB3CB80B0C60B4156895F3792277ABD75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An industry association or other representative of multiple employers in the target industry, including an industry or sector partnership.</text></clause><clause id="HABDE02BE1C6342239C60E3159519B320"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A community-based organization with experience in providing employment, education, or support services relevant to the career pathway and student populations receiving services under the grant under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC7BAA057BA3F4A5A87D254010517934E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Education partner</header><text>An education partner described in subparagraph (A) means one or more of the following:</text><clause id="HC921AA74F5AA44A6B9E83F4ABB56DABA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A local educational agency, as defined under section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H462D30385AD6463CAB098F4E750D0CC5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An eligible provider, as defined under section 203 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/3272">29 U.S.C. 3272</external-xref>).</text></clause><clause id="HBE23D6AFBDBA44119783DB1D370F4D34"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>An institution of higher education, as defined in section 101, or a postsecondary vocational institution, as defined in section 102(c).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H631FF6651443407CBE676EF5421EB339"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible institution</header><text>The term <term>eligible institution</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HC183FF8ACC0B456CADBC54988BAE2CB3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a public institution of higher education at which the highest degree that is predominantly awarded to students is an associate’s degree, including 2-year Tribal Colleges or Universities under section 316 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c</external-xref>) and public 2-year State institutions of higher education;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HF9759DC407EA4472B3677A98053F212C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an area career and technical education school that provides education at the postsecondary level; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H515D55AFE33C4016BD4EFB36CFCF5462"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a consortium of institutions described in subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H23D413783B8E4FDB9F28D3D6C23F1A1F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Evidence-based</header><text>The term <term>evidence-based</term> means an activity, strategy, or intervention that—</text><subparagraph id="H97FF3DDFF3304F78906F733ECFF08B04"><enum>(A)</enum><text>demonstrates a statistically significant effect on improving student outcomes or other relevant outcomes based on—</text><clause id="HBEA2D1B7ECB34B928A987E61112BDAD9"><enum>(i)</enum><text>strong evidence from not less than 1 well-designed and well-implemented experimental study;</text></clause><clause id="H9CDA73FAB1064B43B735B3628D7E24A6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>moderate evidence from not less than 1 well-designed and well-implemented quasi-experimental study; or</text></clause><clause id="HB941E6A5E5444558B07A879DFF2C671A"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>promising evidence from not less than 1 well-designed and well-implemented correlational study with statistical controls for selection bias;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF119A61CB05E45ADBBA0B4F77A356AD9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>demonstrates a rationale based on high-quality research finding or positive evaluation that such activity, strategy, or intervention is likely to improve student outcomes or other relevant outcomes; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H274C047346344A13A332262A8E2F9F66"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes ongoing efforts to examine the effects of such activity, strategy, or intervention.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3A010E735D314795850421DDEBFCC404"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Measurable skill gains</header><text>The term <term>measurable skill gains</term> has the meaning given the term in section 361.155(a)(1)(v) of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (or successor regulations).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72B123F2E30F4501A61A680F0E0E783B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91C60609FE954089A53722A0534226F9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program established</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, shall establish a career pathway grant program, through which the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible institutions in order to enable eligible institutions to carry out the activities described in subsection (e).</text></subsection><subsection id="HBE13C8310523495F8C1FB224E51B2642"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible institution desiring to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application, at such time and in such manner as the Secretary may require, that includes the following information:</text><paragraph id="HC86B5F74ED1D4787973C4EA8921626D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>A description of the career pathway partnership, including the roles and responsibilities of each partner.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF23D475146DB457A8765B5F7BAFE1BC8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A description of the career pathway program that will be supported under the grant, including a description of the in-demand industry sectors or occupations that will be targeted and the recognized postsecondary credentials to be awarded.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAC9B836CC7647C88C47B371C325EC53"><enum>(3)</enum><text>A description of how the career pathway program supported under the grant are aligned and coordinated with other employment, education, and support services offered in the geographic area served under the grant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5241F0FE36734BCB99510AB3CBDDC140"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of the student populations that will be served under the grant, including an analysis of any barriers to postsecondary access and completion that such populations face, and an analysis of how the services to be provided under the grant will address those barriers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8601AB36D6614CDD9956BDE69CA48D17"><enum>(5)</enum><text>A description of the activities and services to be provided under this grant, consistent with subsection (e).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDEFD8622BE394C68AC925D4A91E40E1D"><enum>(6)</enum><text>A description of the performance outcomes that the eligible institution plans to achieve, including a description of how the eligible institution will evaluate and measure student progress and measurable skill gains along a career pathway.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H10A98BF75E894241AB4949348BF6FE0B"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Such other information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED570D0499E04C7FAA6D26204991022E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priority in awarding grants</header><text>The Secretary shall award grants under this part in a manner that—</text><paragraph id="HE198922649844F5B935613C755B10F58"><enum>(1)</enum><text>supports geographic diversity among grantees;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD7D50DBE830249A4A8F4333F3A56094C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>gives priority to eligible institutions that seek to serve individuals with a barrier to employment or individuals with a barrier to postsecondary education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB13D4160D6FD43E0882E39CCE8BBEDCF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>gives priority to eligible institutions that will use grant funds for evidence-based activities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1354EEA6157740A0A309888B99FAC4A2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><paragraph id="H64A0E22E42B4462686AC26FE45B11782"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Developing and implementing career pathway programs</header><text>An eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds to carry out activities that support the development and implementation of career pathway programs, which shall include one or more of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H448BAFB7D8F54EB08E41670EBB94EBDF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The planning and implementation of agreements between the eligible institution and other partners in the career pathway partnership to support seamless transitions between elements of the career pathway program offered by different partners, as appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE22060152CE149388085325888034171"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The development and expansion of new or existing programs at the eligible institution that utilize integrated education and training strategies, and support multiple entry and exit points for working learners, which may include—</text><clause id="H138F61DAB2BF4A08BC307D82476EE79C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dual-enrollment approaches for secondary students or disconnected youth seeking to participate in a career pathway program; and</text></clause><clause id="H1370DFE25E2042B6B7817B7E9FD1D705"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>strategies that help working students and other nontraditional and adult student populations access skills and recognized postsecondary credentials.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0630BFBCC0A64786AB17CFA75F482B02"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The provision of evidence-based professional development for faculty and other staff at the eligible institution or at partner organizations described under subparagraph (B) or (C) of subsection (a)(2) on the development and implementation of career pathways.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA8FA734F9D1543198686D8CDF226F958"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The acquisition of equipment necessary to support the delivery of career pathway programs supported through a grant under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0D5C52EEF4F449089D278B04F43F4CBD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Any other evidence-based activities identified by the eligible institution or partners as necessary to support the development or implementation of career pathway programs, as long as such activities are clearly outlined in the grant application.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D4FB9E7AC6F436DA23A8124B9212387"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Student support services</header><text>In addition to the activities described in paragraph (1), an eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall use grant funds to provide student support services to students engaged in career pathway programs, which shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HD96778A41EEC443FA0BC2B275347F31D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the provision of direct support services such as childcare, transportation, mental health and substance use disorder treatment, assistance in obtaining health insurance coverage, and assistance in accessing the supplemental nutrition assistance program established under the Food and Nutrition Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/7/2011">7 U.S.C. 2011 et seq.</external-xref>), the special supplemental nutrition program for women, infants, and children established by section 17 of the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1786">42 U.S.C. 1786</external-xref>), housing, and other benefits, as appropriate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB8F162B946D4C21B21662D6409856CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>offering career pathway navigation and case management services, including providing information and outreach to target populations to encourage individuals to take part in programs and service offerings; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0BAB5947A4224754913895D4167BBD86"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the provision of emergency grants to help students facing financial hardships that may impact enrollment or completion of an element of a career pathway program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H670AD8A122A54A9DBD14E8CF7768FA75"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Duration of award</header><text>A grant under this section shall be for a period of not more than 4 years. An eligible institution may apply for subsequent grants after the completion of a grant period.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB4571FA894F84B6A93D00FF4B98136BE"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph id="H4F1BD893D6ED44CD94429C5B40E6E750"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Report to the Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each eligible institution receiving a grant under this section shall submit a report to the Secretary, on an annual basis, describing—</text><subparagraph id="HF2C45D7247064EF092EE152F0FFFAF59"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the activities provided under the grant, including activities carried out directly by the eligible institution and activities carried out by partner organizations;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8FDE76D993345D49E2E6E63B8DF8DCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the students receiving services under the grant, disaggregated by age, race or ethnicity, gender, barriers to employment, and income; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFB551B9465A4497DA1B8583716301061"><enum>(C)</enum><text>indicators of performance for students receiving services through a career pathway program carried out through a grant under this part, disaggregated by participant type as described in paragraph (2), including, at a minimum—</text><clause id="H8906FDA6DE4144DA8D6ABEFF2A2FCAD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment prior to enrollment in the career pathway program;</text></clause><clause id="H52BBA582EB7E404791D3C48D3AF40625"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program;</text></clause><clause id="H79D453110644488298F49AF7407C3FB4"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the fourth quarter after exit from the program;</text></clause><clause id="HEE6F6E2F983B43C08D4750D52F49EA35"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the median earnings of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment prior to enrollment in the career pathway program;</text></clause><clause id="H1ACF3DBFE4994262883F4CA063487DCB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the median earnings of program participants who are in unsubsidized employment during the second quarter after exit from the program;</text></clause><clause id="H943632A0C2394101A662289F4D3704BA"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who obtain a recognized postsecondary credential, or a secondary school diploma or its recognized equivalent, during participation in or within 1 year after exit from the program;</text></clause><clause id="H5647FAE25AA1494186C92A7E72C3523E"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants who, during a program year, are in an education or training program that leads to a recognized postsecondary credential or employment and who are achieving measurable skill gains toward such a credential or employment; and</text></clause><clause id="H76C2F15A4D464A89A4D0B2C43B250B57"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>the percentage of program participants receiving support services, disaggregated by type of service.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2C4C029C68F643FF96CDE1D33F81A89A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text>The Secretary shall submit a report to Congress, on a biennial basis, containing a summary of the information described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7B4EA6B05214BDB9F3E7582B0C36485"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>The Secretary shall reserve not less than 1 percent and not more than 3 percent of the funds made available under subsection (i) for each fiscal year to—</text><paragraph id="H4C17A57FDADF473290CC9B537F44C6FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a rigorous, independent evaluation of the activities funded under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAEDDF1A1993B4284BE805DACF6609609"><enum>(2)</enum><text>disseminate and promote the utilization of evidence-based practices related to career pathway programs for postsecondary students.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD8296EA7E00840D7830DC5C273F4480B"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out the activities described in this section, such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2022 and for each subsequent fiscal year thereafter.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

