<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H9FAFA70D545D42DDB73B65B352E238FE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7990 IH: Healthy Homes Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7990</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220608">June 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="W000815">Mr. Wenstrup</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001210">Mr. Murphy of North Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to temporarily expand the low-income housing tax credit for healthcare-oriented housing.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H21DCD7A05DAF43D18EE9DFC5651197B8" style="OLC"><section id="HB7558356D11B4F9193DE2EC00F92CA7B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Healthy Homes Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H178779752A434CAD929AEFA490585D49"><enum>2.</enum><header>Temporary expansion of low-income housing tax credit for healthcare-oriented housing</header><subsection id="H867C95AF75C14712B426B2EBB09114C2"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">Section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by redesignating subsection (n) as subsection (o) and inserting after subsection (m) the following new subsection: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H63C0B0FCC69F47939F93C0ECB53ECB8B" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H3D4DE57E4CA04A7096A2086DEB6C418B"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Special rules for healthcare-Oriented housing</header><paragraph id="H73D35EB0B53946B78961632284CB8972"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Additional basis adjustment for healthcare-oriented housing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to housing credit amounts allocated to healthcare-oriented housing during the specified period—</text><subparagraph id="H70FD1881347C400A9D62E8345CCA2E47"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the case of a new building, the eligible basis of such building as otherwise determined under this section (determined without regard to this paragraph and subsection (d)(5)(B)), shall be increased by 50 percent of such eligible basis (as so determined), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA57E466B431241FA865F66FE5BDC8160"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in the case of an existing building, the rehabilitation expenditures otherwise taken into account under subsection (e) (determined without regard to this paragraph and subsection (d)(5)(B)), shall be increased by 50 percent of such expenditures (as so determined).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC7B72A9320E94F5EA39E366C0658E74B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Additional housing credit dollar amount for healthcare-oriented housing</header><subparagraph id="H6E2C8B0B1871406BB9E3C802145E54BB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In the case of the specified period, the State housing credit ceiling otherwise determined under this section shall be increased by the lesser of—</text><clause id="HDBFB73739EB5443CA8A84C665475DF92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the aggregate housing credit dollar amount allocated by the State housing credit agency of such State to healthcare-oriented housing for such calendar year, or</text></clause><clause id="H423455B51A2043A6B17E1109B9BC97E6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the healthcare-oriented housing amount for such State for such calendar year.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC9465C3406D84591A341217B59EC6FCF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Healthcare-oriented housing amount</header><text>For purposes of subparagraph (A), the term <quote>healthcare-oriented housing amount</quote> means $1.00 multiplied by the State population.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E37F7F4734741FCB195C3EE32180475"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Carryover</header><text>Any excess of the healthcare-oriented housing amount for a calendar year over the amount in subparagraph (A)(i) for such calendar year shall be taken into account as an increase in the healthcare-oriented housing amount for the following calendar year. The preceding sentence shall not result in an increase with respect to any calendar year after 2025.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8626FBD47D184AE484153DDA7DAF56F4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Specified period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term ‘specified period’ means the period beginning 210 days after the date of the enactment of this subsection and ending on the last day of the third full calendar year beginning after the start of the specified period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66FEE3C1AEED46AE9C98495873FDBEF7"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Healthcare-oriented housing</header><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>healthcare-oriented housing</quote> means any qualified low-income building which meets at least three of the following the additional requirements:</text><subparagraph id="H919DF6E017BC426682F4589828E3C452"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Social determinants of health screenings</header><text>The developer partners with a hospital, health center, or other healthcare institution to conduct social determinants of health screenings on the building premises for each new resident upon move-in and annually thereafter, unless the resident elects not to have such a screening.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2754BC500EF54F2C93F5C4F4F2DC95F7"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Healthcare onsite</header><text>The building contains sufficient physical space and proper equipment for physicians or other appropriate licensed healthcare providers to hold regular health screenings on-site for residents and community members.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H89DA0D80163E4F46845A902D7AA9A342"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Telehealth component</header><text>The building contains broadband infrastructure and physical hardware sufficient to ensure that video conferencing capabilities for telehealth interactions will be available to residents and the developer has partnered with healthcare providers to participate in the provision of telehealth services and outreach.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H51F96345D21F4E97A86B98F620A9D98E"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Classroom and kitchen</header><text>The building has classroom space to conduct community health and nutrition workshops and a demonstration kitchen to facilitate healthy cooking demonstrations for residents and the community and the developer has partnered with a hospital, health center, or other healthcare institution to provide such workshops and demonstrations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB23F55C752741AB9917F6EB39BC3680"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Healthcare service coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A medical assistant or trained healthcare worker who connects residents to both healthcare and community services is located in the building on at least a part-time basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1916E70BFD2E4065A8F926DC74F3DDE4"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Adjusted basis</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding subsection (d)(4), the adjusted basis of healthcare-oriented housing shall include nonresidential space used to satisfy the requirements in paragraph (5).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E1214BBD38A48E4AB8B9C9CA9B0C38A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Placed in service date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The placed in service date for healthcare-oriented housing shall be determined based on the residential portion of the property.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HF07CDBF5E38A4FE490CC6F74461DA4B6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Coordination with high-Cost areas</header><text>Section 42(d)(5)(B)(i) of such Code is amended—</text><paragraph id="H803F3FE7612E40679A8865E5E3E40640"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>shall be 130 percent of such basis determined without regard to this subparagraph</quote> in subclause (I) and inserting <quote>as otherwise determined under this section (determined without regard to this subparagraph and subsection (n)(1)), shall be increased by 30 percent of such eligible basis (as so determined)</quote>, and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7AEEA464959A4DAD8A2174D7919B90D3"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>taken into account under subsection (e) shall be 130 percent of such expenditures determined without regard to this subparagraph</quote> in subclause (II) and inserting <quote>otherwise taken into account under subsection (e) (determined without regard to this subparagraph and subsection (n)(1)), shall be increased by 30 percent of such expenditures (as so determined)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44FD0F22EF754B688E2D74A4780C71D3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply to housing credit amounts allocated during the specified period (as defined in section 42(n)(3) of such Code).</text></subsection><subsection id="HEAFEFE7AD1F641B1928A16B2EED5D076"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Study and report</header><paragraph id="H013571D768DD4CF784F24ED0F2479AFB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Study</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall conduct a study on the utilization of the low income housing tax credit under <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/42">section 42</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to healthcare-oriented housing. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F9A4C09EE8C4CF98EE5A244AF6A75AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Finance of the Senate and the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives a report on the study conducted under paragraph (1). Such report shall include an examination of the utilization of the low income housing tax credit in each State with respect to healthcare-oriented housing, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE7CC559D771742DFA2DA53AAE6D3F27E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the frequency with which the additional one dollar housing credit amount allocated to each State for such low income housing tax credit development projects is claimed,</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B3839158DBA4365BDDC9E8248A6B67A"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of projects and units funded in each State, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF0651C4F26B04BD5B0DBBB149FC04622"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the use of the additional 50 percent basis boost in securing such healthcare-oriented low income housing development projects.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

