<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF4E6840344204CD5895CD95BB81D99C5" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>104 HR 9539 IH: Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9539</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001091">Mr. Castro of Texas</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000474">Mrs. Torres of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the development of an inter-agency strategy and the submission of certain reports relating to the illegal export and trafficking of firearms from the United States to recipients in Mexico and certain Central American and Caribbean countries, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HFE553415ECA048CF8E78E6E75759DBF9" style="OLC"><section id="HD05F257178EA4B97A1EEBA7DFC873AF1" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Americas Regional Monitoring of Arms Sales Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>ARMAS Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2F7A78D7888E406DA53CEEA9543C5A50"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HDBB607E14965482DB750C895BDA667B9"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Violence in Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean is exacerbated by firearms originating in the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89D971C04CA043AD807A48638A672083"><enum>(2)</enum><text>While firearms are trafficked to Mexico from a variety of countries, firearms originating in the United States account for 70 percent of the firearms recovered and traced from crimes in Mexico, according to the 2021 GAO report <quote>Firearms Trafficking: U.S. Efforts to Disrupt Gun Smuggling into Mexico Would Benefit from Additional Data and Analysis</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76D7ED7D730E41D8AE06FC5983A749CB"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">United States-origin firearm flows contribute to human rights violations, organized crime and gang violence, extrajudicial killings, high homicide rates, domestic violence, and femicides in Mexico, Central America, and the Caribbean.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFB3DBBA76D84BD8B7DCCDAC15CDCCE7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>According to the Executive Secretariat of National System for Public Security of Mexico, during the period beginning in 2012 and ending in 2021, Mexico experienced more than 168,000 firearms homicides.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD8A46D3BBB634F8F87ECD6E0C97ED0C4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">According to the United Nations Regional Centre for Peace, Disarmament and Development in Latin America and the Caribbean, firearms are used in 70 percent of homicides in the Caribbean compared to 30 percent globally; the Caribbean has less than one percent of the world’s population, but 23 percent of all recorded homicides.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA621EE27ADD4B138E9BCBED3F9CA979"><enum>(6)</enum><text>In an August 2022 press conference, U.S. authorities from Homeland Security Investigations reported a <quote>marked uptick in the number of weapons</quote>, and an increase in the caliber and type of weapons, being illegally trafficked to Haiti and the rest of the Caribbean.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B5C7A6D2225445CA41C410547D44340"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Caribbean Basin Security Initiative of the Department of State that commenced in 2009 is the regional U.S. foreign assistance program that seeks to reduce illicit trafficking in the region and advance public safety and security. The program includes improving the capacity of Caribbean countries to intercept smuggled weapons at airports and seaports, as well as support for forensic ballistics and firearms destruction and stockpile management. Assistance under the Caribbean Basin Security Initiative has also included support for regional organizations, including—</text><subparagraph id="H90231FEDDC894CCFA0C043470DB10A94"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Caribbean Community Implementation Agency for Crime and Security (CARICOM IMPACS), based in Trinidad and Tobago, the lead agency involved in the issue of illicit arms trafficking and increasing the capacity of member states to detect and prevent firearms trafficking; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FC65DFED0A740E39F097DD84773321B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Eastern Caribbean’s Regional Security System, based in Barbados.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D3051E748F74DE0969FD55F70E4C45A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Firearms trafficking from the United States and firearm violence are key drivers of immigration and asylum claims from Central America.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H563A5F775C064EF68BD7B60E031B2977"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Two GAO reports (published in 2021 and 2022, respectively) on firearms trafficking have affirmed that firearms trafficking to Mexico and Central America continues to represent a security concern to the United States, as United States-origin firearms are diverted from legitimate owners and end up in the hands of violent criminals, including drug traffickers and other transnational criminal organizations. A GAO report on the effect of firearms trafficking in the Caribbean has not yet been compiled.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E447AC10D5A489DB5F38FA25C1C5297"><enum>(10)</enum><text>In these reports, the Comptroller General found that Federal departments and agencies lacked information and analysis of the firearms trafficking networks in Mexico and Central America, that few efforts of the United States Government in the region focused on firearms trafficking, and that, as a result, such agencies lack a detailed understanding of the firearms trafficking that fuels violence and enables criminals in Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, and Mexico.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF4553DB03194E8281E29FE2B07B4A28"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the 2022 GAO report <quote>Firearms Trafficking: More Information Needed to Inform U.S. Efforts in Central America</quote>, the Comptroller General found that efforts of the United States Government focused on firearms trafficking in Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, and Honduras lacked information about relevant country conditions and performance measures to ensure such efforts were designed and implemented to achieve the intended objectives and, as a result, the Comptroller General recommended that the Secretary of State obtain information about the conditions in such countries, to support the development of effective programs to reduce the availability of illicit firearms.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4065AD6E32A044A6A4153ECFCA0C3DE6"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Data on firearms trafficking is limited and to understand the problem, data compilation is crucial.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E9525130F5B44B39DBEA94F670C29E7"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In 2021 and 2022, the annual Country Reports on Human Rights Practices of the Department of State included <quote>unlawful and arbitrary killings</quote> as a significant human rights issue in Guatemala, yet despite such inclusion, the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security has authorized approximately 99,270 firearms exports to Guatemala since assuming responsibility for firearms licensing in 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E22B1D9E97445CEBF9F3416C05E34D5"><enum>(14)</enum><text>When firearms were controlled under the United States Munitions List and the licensing of firearms was the responsibility of the Secretary of State, the average number of firearms licensed for export to Guatemala was approximately 4,000 per year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE14FF8B7EC2B4AB3B449AA757CBD6D5A"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The current number of exports specified in paragraph (10) represents an extraordinary increase (as much as 25 times the average) from the number specified in paragraph (11), and the Under Secretary of Commerce for Industry and Security has only been able to conduct a very limited number of end-use checks, according to the 2022 GAO report <quote>Firearms Trafficking: More Information Needed to Inform U.S. Efforts in Central America</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H85C8F30407B143DEB19D732D40D42BA2"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The proposed security cooperation plan titled <quote>U.S.-Mexico Bicentennial Framework for Security, Public Heath, and Safe Communities</quote> and other new initiatives to address root causes of migration from Central America offer an opportunity to reaffirm commitments and strengthen cooperation on addressing firearms trafficking.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H45304C3A8A67445CBF0D1EC781865F87"><enum>3.</enum><header>Reports and strategy on disruption of illegal export and trafficking of firearms to Mexico and certain Central American countries</header><subsection id="H51E19F8AC91A4289869E8A498EA6D80F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of State (in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce, the Attorney General, the Director of the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives, and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of State may determine relevant) shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the efforts of the Secretary of State and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies to disrupt the illegal export or diversion of firearms from the United States to unauthorized recipients in countries designated as covered countries under section 4 (including through unauthorized third-party transfers), and the illegal trafficking of firearms obtained in the United States to such recipients. Such report shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H51F0AA76C3F241DDBF2AB719BBDD65DE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>An identification of any such efforts, including efforts to accomplish the following objectives:</text><subparagraph id="HB67FCE384807430D8003BC4AB82644BF"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tracking and verifying information regarding the end-users of firearms so exported, including by entering into data-sharing agreements with appropriate counterparts from the governments of such covered countries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39FAD6BE8C1548F2B454458767A8F8AF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring the destruction of surplus firearms so exported.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69F70F97DB2A41DCAE6D6D4B29DBACE7"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring that firearms so exported are not used to commit extrajudicial killings or other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE592D66DA7142FB9CF22DFE971228A8"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Building the capacity of such covered countries to prevent the trafficking of firearms so exported, including through current programs supported or implemented by the United States Government.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDC702EABA864EEEA21EBFB8F02B08C8"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Tracking and verifying information regarding the end-users of firearms obtained in the United States and illegally trafficked to such covered countries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42B2F863FA784F32AED7EEF6AB9EE87E"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Combating all forms of cross-border smuggling of firearms from the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27990779DE01405784D6C17F66F12C2F"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engaging with subnational government officials in such covered countries to effectively implement and enforce agreements relating to the trafficking of firearms that have been concluded between the United States Government and the national government of the respective covered country.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1968D70DB3364993875D239C22E82066"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Identifying the origin of trafficked weapons, including through the serial numbers of trafficked firearms.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8871EFFF688D487BBBEFD905E1007AB9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>An assessment of the results of the efforts identified pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5061CEAF3BF2420592EB009AE1E05BAD"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of how homicides, extrajudicial killings, and other gross violations of internationally recognized human rights committed in such covered countries using firearms exported from or obtained in the United States have been investigated.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H47AD919993D34DBAA29A001CFD345F7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inter-Agency strategy</header><paragraph id="HF50CF884A1274049B872AF3EB18D41AA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of State, taking into account the findings of the report under subsection (a), shall jointly develop an inter-agency strategy for the disruption of the trafficking of firearms exported from the United States to recipients in countries designated as covered countries under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90FCAB71B5BA4DC18210377EA91F2E9E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Elements</header><text>The strategy under paragraph (1) shall include the following:</text><subparagraph id="H2F99F2FB9404430687DCE91B5AE7E03F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A plan for the Secretaries to accomplish each of the objectives specified in subsection (a)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H35043E92E9C14EEBBE54C68A5DB03AB4"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An identification of specific performance measures, targets (including the baselines for such targets), and timelines with respect to such objectives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H38A7EA47BACA4475A7B4C271B6FEB85B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>An estimate of the resources and personnel necessary to carry out the strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D61F05469B74BD3845160E4FAF69308"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Required considerations; consultations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In developing the strategy under paragraph (1), the Secretaries shall—</text><subparagraph id="H2175F9907A254EC8BA13BA68193B9B3F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider how the strategy may support or otherwise align with broader efforts of the Secretaries relating to security assistance, anti-corruption, and the prevention of organized crime and drug and gang violence;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1079A6E1685E449F8FFE8F790BD4B51A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider whether the placement in the Western Hemisphere of an export control officer of the Bureau of Industry and Security of the Department of Commerce, or other personnel of the Department of Commerce or the Department of State, would support the strategy; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEC746C9D3F1241DAB3E664E30828541A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">seek to consult with appropriate counterparts from the government of each country designated as a covered country under section 4.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2EAA28CC48174875BAF109E78E57224A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1 of the year following the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce and the Secretary of State shall jointly submit to the appropriate congressional committees the strategy under paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD92160A4F4E546D3A8412F16E4177B94"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Annual report</header><paragraph id="H5EEE49C71D254E0E87A21F639B7BB4C9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Submission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, and annually thereafter, the Secretary of Commerce (in consultation with the Secretary of State and the heads of such other Federal departments or agencies as the Secretary of Commerce may determine relevant) shall submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the export of covered items to countries designated as covered countries under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4491FB582164B80B610B7C3D8F856C4" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Matters</header><text>Each report under paragraph (1) shall include, with respect to the year for which the report is submitted, the following information (disaggregated by country):</text><subparagraph id="H645DC30ECCB946408AFDB81DA5D84C23" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information regarding license applications approved or denied, and previously issued licenses modified or revoked, for the export of covered items to proposed recipients in covered countries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCD6F7E649674F05BA3DA0B6434C5464" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Information regarding how evolving country contexts, including with respect to developments in human rights, affected the approval of license applications for such exports.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H132C7B29BBC8436B90E32685923B6987" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of licenses issued for the export of covered items to proposed recipients in covered countries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H071BD34A50C94E9DBF5E83C5301AF73A" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of covered items exported to recipients in covered countries.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83610B07B71A49F293F15EEB4EC8650A" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">With respect to end-user checks for covered items exported to recipients in covered countries under section 38(g)(7) of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2778">22 U.S.C. 2778(g)(7)</external-xref>) (commonly referred to as the <quote>Blue Lantern</quote> program), the monitoring program established under the second section 40A of the Arms Export Control Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2785">22 U.S.C. 2785</external-xref>) (as added by section 150(a) of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/104/164">Public Law 104–164</external-xref>), or other applicable programs of the Department of Commerce or Department of State, the following information:</text><clause id="H5CB1C41ECA6D4EBFB57D6998AA796B76"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The number of such end-user checks requested.</text></clause><clause id="H80BC0C6EC4A94C1596E2654F71D8ECC4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The number of such end-user checks conducted.</text></clause><clause id="HD91DD807E8494CB7A5B07D076A1DB8CB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The type of such end-user checks conducted.</text></clause><clause id="H1EDC6B9A32D54C81A6B3D46901DCE4A1"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The results of such end-user checks conducted.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HABE7E6908286462892322618735FC24B" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Information on the extent to which the heads of the governments of covered countries shared with the Secretary of Commerce and the heads of other relevant Federal departments and agencies (such as the Bureau of Alcohol, Tobacco, Firearms and Explosives) data relating to the receipt and end-use of covered items exported from the United States, and the type of data so shared.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCE28391089C8491FB9525B5765ABC040" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each covered country, a description of the U.S. funding and resources allocated for the purpose of disrupting trafficking of covered items.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H840524ABAB4441EE9D3338DDB10760C7"><enum>4.</enum><header>Designation of covered countries</header><subsection id="H8C3C39F41DCB4BAA97277B454332B278"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall designate each country that the Secretary determines meets the requirements under subsection (b) as a covered country for purposes of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9B557831B36C463A8909B8F2B5E3F793"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>A country meets the requirements under this subsection if the country—</text><paragraph id="HA7A7FE3D9F964F24BF05928F9BD069C7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is located in North America, South America, or the Caribbean;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1BD3F90F63E14839AA5F8860663AE072"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is not a member state of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEBBDB9340ED4BF4BE7B5EC96C92834D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>meets such other requirements as the Secretary of State may determine appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB90EB2E97BAE4C19BCC5B94907427E61"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Initial designations</header><text>The Bahamas, Belize, El Salvador, Guatemala, Honduras, Mexico, Haiti, Jamaica, and Trinidad and Tobago—</text><paragraph id="HD57A833DCC70439296F6AC87EC4F08EF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall be deemed to have been so designated by the Secretary of Commerce as of the date of the enactment of this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB24444C32BCB416797C3BD2BF986C5F2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall continue to be deemed so designated for a five-year period, during which time the designation may not be terminated under subsection (d).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H269470374EFC41DEA512E5F61AE4635C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination of designation</header><text>Subject to subsection (c)(2), the Secretary of Commerce may terminate the designation of a country under this section only if, at least 180 days prior to such termination, the Secretary submits to the appropriate congressional committees a notification of such termination.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD245E996DF4544AF92A310599373DE85"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on licenses and other authorizations for export of certain items removed from the United States Munitions List and included on the Commerce Control List</header><subsection id="H5A94DF9D6A934CDEBE43B4530437D070"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Commerce may not grant a license or other authorization for the export of a covered item unless, before granting the license or other authorization, the Secretary submits to the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives and the chairman and ranking member of the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the Senate a written certification with respect to such proposed export license or other authorization containing—</text><paragraph id="H1D0D0F036F5D4DAE823ACCB32DE2C4E8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the name of the person applying for the license or other authorization;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFC315D484B80486EBF1F6B2A90A53889"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the name of the person who is the proposed recipient of the export;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C10679E0FB7431DAA7F360BFF1FEA89"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the name of the country or international organization to which the export will be made; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD7AFF69586E43799F358101AB5BD58F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>a description of the items proposed to be exported; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H935BDAAD0C04442AA67AA13FE91B4D33"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the value of the items proposed to be exported.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H174CA200C8454EE1858E20126254D050"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form</header><text>A certification required under subsection (a) shall be submitted in unclassified form, except that information regarding the dollar value and number of items proposed to be exported may be restricted from public disclosure if such disclosure would be detrimental to the security of the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H225B387B28F14A2E9A2087C4C568BF3C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Deadlines</header><text>A certification required under subsection (a) shall be submitted—</text><paragraph id="HD595B5FF2488456EB27B4A7D80FF08ED"><enum>(1)</enum><text>at least 15 calendar days before a proposed export license or other authorization is granted in the case of a transfer of items to a country which is a member of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization or Australia, Japan, the Republic of Korea, Israel, or New Zealand; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CF4F4D0BC8F467C9216586C3F382BE1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>at least 30 calendar days before a proposed export license or other authorization is granted in the case of a transfer of items to any other country.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE133B953A7B4F62BA3874BF85A70175"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Congressional resolution of disapproval</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A proposed export license or other authorization described in paragraph (1) of subsection (c) shall become effective after the end of the 15-day period described in such paragraph, and a proposed export license or other authorization described in paragraph (2) of subsection (c) shall become effective after the end of the 30-day period specified in such paragraph, only if the Congress does not enact, within the applicable time period, a joint resolution prohibiting the export of the covered item for which the export license or other authorization was proposed.</text></subsection></section><section id="H764443C0F1AD40278A1BC3169588B72B"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3D2CE7F805B847358A48149187687921"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H38DEBED31DAD4DA5B1066996E7E4CA4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H206690F3437B448C9FDA6B81403F4C32"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB7C4C1A8C6B40D491AB9D15F419DD18"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered item</header><text>The term <quote>covered item</quote> means any item that—</text><subparagraph id="H3AC36C4B30A340E78D62CE194786B882" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">as of March 8, 2020, was included in Category I, II, or III of the United States Munitions List; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA99765948DCD4C8184B19B95A827F56C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is included on the Commerce Control List. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50A1A8E0385742D3BED5F9CFFAD95454" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Firearm</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>firearm</quote> includes—</text><subparagraph id="HBF23D54768E347CC80086534E455697B" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">any item that is included in Category I, II, or III of the United States Munitions List; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C2312EB31D94B74B34B8EBF830D0B0F" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any covered item.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3E474A511DE4AE595B4E87C9FD703F2"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>gross violations of internationally recognized human rights</quote> has the meaning given that term in section 502B(d) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304(d)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCD94E43C3F1F4031B8304CC92DA2E044"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Security assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>security assistance</quote> includes—</text><subparagraph id="H3D1D0D18E3CF43D1BE240390FDBB4E70"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the types of assistance specified in section 502B(d)(2) of the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2304">22 U.S.C. 2304</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC61F5CF53A0645348F7A8AE2ED7283B6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>assistance furnished under an international security assistance program of the United States conducted under any other provision of law, including under the authorities under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/16">chapter 16</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC4B00C99BA704691B070042B4C443C37"><enum>(6)</enum><header>United States Munitions List</header><text>The term <quote>United States Munitions List</quote> means the list maintained pursuant to part 121 of title 22, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

