<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA56763C81CD24B31ABB8111D31056D04" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8567 IH: Student Apprenticeship Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220728">July 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to support apprenticeship programs.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8FB9E6269B3541679AF20AFE903CAE38" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H6AE7D5D859E84B9BA7382E5F7E3DB849"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Student Apprenticeship Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H62DCD0B98F8F49278DEA9FCBAFE538F8"><enum>2.</enum><header>Apprenticeship programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title VII of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1133">20 U.S.C. 1133 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H2277F0257D544E5DAFE5363E331165CB"><part id="HF6912E5D36C343D28CE984F2F86BBBA2" style="OLC"><enum>F</enum><header>Apprenticeship programs</header><section id="H11AF7EE52C3E43AAAE556983B9C2952B"><enum>791.</enum><header>Grants to support apprenticeship programs</header><subsection id="HDD89DA79C2054E9193A88FF8C453DF70"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section: </text><paragraph id="H874D0F436A2B4168B2D87D16D50C93F1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>apprenticeship program</term> means a program that is registered under the Act of August 16, 1937 (commonly known as the <quote>National Apprenticeship Act</quote>; 50 Stat. 664, chapter 663; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/50">29 U.S.C. 50 et seq.</external-xref>), as of the date of enactment of this Act, and is in compliance with the regulations promulgated to carry out the Act of August 16, 1937, under part 29 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFF776A8E4FAE45F7A076DF7F3B5274D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Postsecondary apprenticeship program</header><text>The term <term>postsecondary apprenticeship program</term> means an apprenticeship program—</text><subparagraph id="HCC2803DF4F4E45F5911C2C6721543BD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that meets the requirements of a recognized postsecondary credential conferred by an institution of higher education; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DEE805AEDDF4A3D98C1CDE9AE9FEF73"><enum>(B)</enum><text>established by the relevant State agency in the State where the program is delivered.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H26137DC8A6B8497690621E2610814376"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Recognized postsecondary credential</header><text>The term <term>recognized postsecondary credential</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H22274153D5214390AA3A645BFF700224"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a credential consisting of an industry-recognized certificate that is credit-bearing toward a postsecondary degree at the institution of higher education from which it is conferred;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31AB49D10B5747B7A5D5463BC8B5C74D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an associate degree; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19B14EFE808244C78C867856AAA6DC03"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a baccalaureate degree.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H93BA798390094E0EB44679D60B2B855C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Student apprentice</header><text>The term <term>student apprentice</term> means an individual who is—</text><subparagraph id="H137B207FC01B40DC8B765125A9CF0F84"><enum>(A)</enum><text>enrolled or accepted for enrollment at an institution of higher education for the purpose of obtaining a recognized postsecondary credential offered by that institution and is a participant in a postsecondary apprenticeship program; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA7CD58222DE44EEA4434664736A26B2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a worker at least 16 years of age, except where a higher minimum age standard is otherwise fixed by law, who is employed to learn an apprenticeable occupation, as described in section 29.4 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act), under standards of apprenticeship fulfilling the requirements of section 29.5 of title 29, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the date of enactment of this Act).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H403BFD1891B14BE399B700C80D4A200F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Workforce intermediary</header><text>The term <term>workforce intermediary</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H390FDB54146542E399FA864778F83E32"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means an entity, which may be part of an industry or sector partnership, that demonstrates expertise in building, connecting, sustaining, and measuring the performance of partnerships in order for the entity to broker services, resources, and supports for development, delivery, expansion, or improvement of postsecondary apprenticeship programs, and of the organizations and systems that are designed to serve covered student apprentices and employer partners, including—</text><clause id="H46403797416245828433A5A776F41319"><enum>(i)</enum><text>connecting employers to apprenticeship opportunities;</text></clause><clause id="H7305C685AF414F4BB1ED99CAC5EFB590"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>assisting in the design and implementation of postsecondary apprenticeship programs, including curriculum development and delivery for related instruction;</text></clause><clause id="HF87DCFB231914BBB83EB79F5CF3309C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>supporting entities, and sponsors or program administrators, in meeting the registration and reporting requirements;</text></clause><clause id="H7296C3ED0E6D4774B6FEC93D3BF0ED2C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>providing professional development activities such as training to mentors;</text></clause><clause id="H9889B8D874B9447FBD877F9114ADD2F7"><enum>(v)</enum><text>connecting students or workers to apprenticeship opportunities; and</text></clause><clause id="H288A59C860F94898965822005E7D6AE1"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>developing and providing personalized covered apprentice supports, including supportive services and financial advising; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA338391B82C249D882699317CDFB5ED2"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a State workforce development board or local workforce development board, as established under title I of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act, or State workforce agency.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6F9172EBDE3A4C458540C09365D7D439"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header><paragraph id="H2BC0EBF35B6A41A78E0D9F834030E33D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in collaboration with the Secretary of Labor, shall award grants to eligible partnerships to enable the partnerships to develop and implement a postsecondary apprenticeship program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9534A6BDB1BC40B2BF7780147CE9590E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>Grants awarded under this section shall be 4 or 5 years in duration.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H171D68BAFF0C4F3DAF39A6925D5B1AE3"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible partnership</header><subparagraph id="H7C60B41534DF41108B1718D2BF69C442"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In this section, the term <term>eligible partnership</term> means a partnership that—</text><clause id="H8DBC61E08BB149CEB69B8AEEFE637CA5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall include—</text><subclause id="H720608F0D5544D04BE4B33587C4A0F47"><enum>(I)</enum><text>an institution of higher education or a consortium of such institutions;</text></subclause><subclause id="H67153AE0A9D64481AA1E43BB41A1C46F"><enum>(II)</enum><text>an individual employer or consortium of employers; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HB0EB21B0ECC647599120A0EB211363AE"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a workforce intermediary, unless waived by the Secretary because the partnership demonstrates that a high-quality program is in place or it would be a hardship to include a workforce intermediary; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HFA0164EE4ECD45D2A2E6F32C5C256BCC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may include—</text><subclause id="H467BD9F7E54F4244BF7D9AFE45E638AD"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a State agency responsible for the administration of career and technical education in the State or for the supervision of the administration of career and technical education in the State;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBB6FEB6B6E65425A9FD070D9CA3F9B36"><enum>(II)</enum><text>a labor organization;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3C192C53752949418753451588DBFEC6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>an economic development agency or organization, such as a chamber of commerce, business alliance, or industry association;</text></subclause><subclause id="H083FD492A05C481F930F603E689F1085"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a community-based organization;</text></subclause><subclause id="HDA1BFEC2AE204FD79AA669CBE92E2D1D"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a State educational agency; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HAFFE8E7947414591BB65446C19A195FB"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a local educational agency.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDBDAAFABDDD34A4EBEF39FBE34D5BC82"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fiscal agent</header><text>The lead fiscal agent of an eligible partnership shall be any of the following:</text><clause commented="no" id="H6F39FFB1220A482ABB212A36DC04D502"><enum>(i)</enum><text>An institution of higher education.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H5A48261D673749AB80079993FF80CDF7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>An industry association.</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H44F0F56E0F7C4FBFA31F6037E2E09F77"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A workforce intermediary that is an entity that is described in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/501">section 501(c)(3)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and exempt from taxation under section 501(a) of such Code.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED50604588A646AFB182B9506B317245"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Application</header><subparagraph id="H290728484B484892AD21CC0B3C4FE39F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible partnership that desires to receive a grant under this section shall submit an application to the Secretary at such time, in such manner, and accompanied by such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91BBC8A26F1E436B835DD1AFF5D0B281"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Inclusions</header><text>An application submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include—</text><clause id="HCD81AADFCA8549EEBE7702EEA00C4C06"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a plan to recruit and retain a high number or high percentage of participants who are from nontraditional apprenticeship populations, including women, minorities, individuals with disabilities, veterans, and individuals with barriers to employment, such as opportunity youth, low-income youth and adults, young adults and adults of color, and individuals who have been impacted by the criminal justice system;</text></clause><clause id="HCE574351E19F48F1861406A5FAC5B2F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>letters of support and a labor market analysis that demonstrate that the occupation for which the program prepares participants—</text><subclause id="HE8798BA9F2694A45AF644E6F778DA910"><enum>(I)</enum><text>is feasible and in demand;</text></subclause><subclause id="H5E0FAA8DC685416796B3B165326D24D6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>is a high-growth, high-wage occupation; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H00C7E9C58FEA4070BD066F9F0DBC8720"><enum>(III)</enum><text>is a response to in-demand industry sectors or occupations as determined by the State or local workforce boards;</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H0E48CF05DE794E2496C06BDF3D589F90"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a plan for reaching desired outcomes, as described in paragraph (7);</text></clause><clause id="H6C42CC000A7B404983C4F1145ADAF463"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a plan for ensuring that the partnership has the capacity to access data to measure desired outcomes and the outcomes described in clause (v); and</text></clause><clause id="H3F2FE1C458FD47B2A276FECBCF205433"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a plan for—</text><subclause id="H72F2473951164739BF8ECFE918FE13BF"><enum>(I)</enum><text>increasing associate or baccalaureate degree and credential attainment;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC9538DDFA95641B9ACE656AC320EC613"><enum>(II)</enum><text>sustaining the program for at least 20 months beyond the grant period; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HAD384E45D3664D0387E5A95501327378"><enum>(III)</enum><text>including a provider of support or specialized services, such as financial counseling.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40DCB61925B444B1BAEAAB787F08366A"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Description of instruction</header><text>In addition to the information described in subparagraph (B), an application submitted under subparagraph (A) shall include a description of the organized, related instruction the apprentice will receive in technical subjects related to the occupation for which the program prepares participants, which—</text><clause id="HDC01BDE644DC40E79EF17F03E830EFEF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall include not less than 2000 hours of on the job learning and a recommended 144 hours for each year (with an allowance for a student to spread it out over 2 years) of related technical instruction unless an alternative requirement is put forth by the employer and sponsor that reflects industry standards and is accepted by the Secretary;</text></clause><clause id="HF63F2612EAA04F7EB74B694F358873F7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>may be accomplished through credit-bearing classroom instruction, occupational or industry courses, successful demonstration of acquired skills and knowledge as part of an approved competency-based program, instruction provided through electronic media, or other instruction approved by the registration agency;</text></clause><clause id="H7A05ADA28EFF4BF4A261BB9ED9C5BE31"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall be provided by one or more qualified instructors who—</text><subclause id="H032F2EEC7ED641DEA2AF370E81471C1C"><enum>(I)</enum><item commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HB315BFBE4DAA4144A921B8C5736DAD48"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>meet the career technical education instructor requirements of the applicable education agency of the State of registration; or</text></item><item id="H009FDA16358A41889B4F27C3F3266430" indent="up1"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>are subject matter experts, defined for purposes of this subparagraph as individuals (including journeyworkers) recognized within an industry as having expertise in a specific occupation; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="H4B95A8A45F45446AA8751023F963C1E3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>have training in teaching techniques and learning styles or will obtain such training before an instructor begins providing the related technical instruction; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDBF1B48406D246C9BC23ADA24E200C10"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>shall, to the maximum extent practicable, be aligned to a career pathway, as defined in section 3 of the Workforce Innovation and Opportunity Act.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9ACD41B89FA64F2AAA171009ABD4287F"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Secretary shall, in selecting eligible partnerships to receive grants under this section—</text><subparagraph id="H6FAB48A7EEB24061970B9E3D53702271"><enum>(A)</enum><text>consider the equitable geographic distribution of grants among rural and urban areas; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7066F7307FD4922B462F0858D53CC0E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>leverage significant State, local, institutional, or private resources, including in-kind contributions, to support the activities assisted under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE4D9E5DBC234DC196BCADB232D7ADC4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Use of grant funds</header><subparagraph id="H0A768497920D45798CF475D3E5D5F57C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to develop and implement a postsecondary apprenticeship program in high-skill, high-wage, or in-demand industry sectors or occupations.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE29C86F4AF44A88BCB8DBC8FDBD2A17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Permissible use of funds</header><text>An eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section to develop and implement a postsecondary apprenticeship program may use the grant funds for any of the following:</text><clause id="H080E43E4B6E94A3189474F5BA8AE157D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Program design and implementation costs, including—</text><subclause id="H8A6479F2A6924C71BED7EBEECA455F6C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>development of curricula and standards;</text></subclause><subclause id="HE5CF0D0B87674DBF97FB0C0FFF1B29E0"><enum>(II)</enum><text>development of a competency-based approach to awarding credits; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0D0DA0A0CEB3430B8FD83D7DFA992169"><enum>(III)</enum><text>use of subject matter experts in instructional delivery or curriculum design.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HE56F0AF2AABC489AA92F0B463A32E2A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Development of on-the-job learning, mentoring, and additional supervision structures and professional development for mentors and supervisors.</text></clause><clause id="HADF35576A37F4175B81E8ED4250B7C9D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Tuition for the related instruction of the apprenticeship.</text></clause><clause id="HF74871ACCAD14C2A9AA36EFF4C0607B9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Development of articulation agreements with institutions of higher education that result in awarding an associate's or higher degree.</text></clause><clause id="HAD30F419D5AA47E891EB46FA28EFB90B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Assessment of prior learning for the purpose of awarding credit.</text></clause><clause id="H8C3785CCBC474667AC6E201FDBCAFD29"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Certifying examinations.</text></clause><clause id="H1A7D3007F02C4983807A6345B4539BF2"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Recruitment of student apprentices or students participating in concurrent postsecondary programs while in high school.</text></clause><clause id="H11619891DC6F4DACAA738EA8107B8E97"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Need-based supportive services, including tutoring, transportation, child care, and housing subsidies.</text></clause><clause id="H8949419754F74372B2C5ABEDD2831C71"><enum>(ix)</enum><text>Not more than 20 percent of grant funds for the purchase of updated equipment.</text></clause><clause id="H8A36323858F349DAAB2C734A8810D2A5"><enum>(x)</enum><text>Not more than 10 percent of grant funds for administrative functions, such as program management and grant reporting.</text></clause><clause id="HD9CC00F0409E4522B6681C31844D04EF"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>Aligning data reporting for academic programs and apprenticeships.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H020A0EBD4636467F9B2CD82AC8C94372"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Wages</header><text>An eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section—</text><clause id="HF6DCC70763244D9E919F78FA96CF35C2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>may not use any of the grant funds directly to pay wages to a student apprentice; and</text></clause><clause id="H9B082204D112470DA8C1569498466E96" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall ensure that any wages paid to a student apprentice under the postsecondary apprenticeship program are not less than $15 an hour<italic>.</italic></text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B908B01DF9A47DFAFE97782E5FE8A3B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Assessment</header><text>An eligible partnership that receives a grant under this section shall monitor and report on the following participant-level outcomes:</text><subparagraph id="H819EBC18209C425FB8C32839E0421045"><enum>(A)</enum><text>With respect to interim outcomes—</text><clause id="H6C4D0B6D8A74433F8297FFA87BE9635C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the number of student apprentices in the program;</text></clause><clause id="H485560D43E9E43E4943C289EC895ED3E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the percentage of participants who are from nontraditional apprenticeship populations, including women, historically underrepresented groups, individuals with disabilities, veterans, and individuals with barriers to employment;</text></clause><clause id="H9F330B08432C412187ACB83579DF7C9E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>outcomes for the participants described in clause (ii);</text></clause><clause id="HD084C5CDE2D94B16B0D4FACA9C636D62"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the accumulation of postsecondary credit;</text></clause><clause id="H666816CB0493424F8B5BE72A44819141"><enum>(v)</enum><text>the attainment of a recognized postsecondary credential; and</text></clause><clause id="H76A9530A03634228962B94834A034517"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>wage increases realized during the course of the apprenticeship.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBB76007E56C64D53B4E710E349168A95"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Completions—</text><clause id="HBC621460B92B4EB6A367FB1E9EA3796A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>that are on time, disaggregated by credit, credential, or degree received; and</text></clause><clause id="H4D742F835ACF4A30B1B9FE118B25593D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>that are within 150 percent of the expected time of completion, disaggregated by credit, credential, or degree received.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BAA5CD6E7F24A4590858B26EC39D3D1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>With respect to end-of-program outcomes for both participants who complete the program and participants who do not complete the program each of the following:</text><clause id="HD18D210B03BD41DB800EE3AAC479AD92"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The accumulation of postsecondary credit toward a degree reported not later than one year after the end of the grant period.</text></clause><clause id="H6EB7227F0F1A41019794D9B70DFF55B3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The share of enrolled students who attain a postsecondary degree reported not later than one year after the end of the grant period.</text></clause><clause id="H2633ED696BFE472BB21446EAD6143569"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The share of enrolled students who attain a recognized postsecondary credential reported not later than one year after the end of the grant period.</text></clause><clause id="H64073D1742D946CBAED14FA2DD1FDAE9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Subsequent enrollment in advanced education, disaggregated by level.</text></clause><clause id="H4FBDAC0DF2A24167AA9BD59CE3DE96BA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Whether the place of employment for participants aligns with area of study disaggregated by students who completed the program and students who did not complete the program reported not later than one year after the end of the grant period. Such data may be collected through a survey.</text></clause><clause id="H6E613E54C3524085A20FDCE6AA5EEF7B"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Unsubsidized employment rate after the second quarter after exit from the program.</text></clause><clause id="H521FC1C0A2794DC2AA77DCB95475E966"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Unsubsidized employment rate after the fourth quarter after exit from the program.</text></clause><clause id="H3FCCC8958D3D460EA6B14A60060280F3"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Median earnings after the second and fourth quarters after exit from the program.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE3F42873E4BB4C17A59131936B993243"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section such sums as may be necessary for fiscal year 2023 and each of the 5 succeeding fiscal years.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HE6451DDF40F94FE594049AE274D3F52A"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal Work Study funding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 442 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087-52">20 U.S.C. 1087–52</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4C21B954EA0740539599031D342B1495"><subsection id="HA70A640D6BFB4CF2AD34BC332606975F"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Funding for student apprentices</header><paragraph id="H26A5A0611DDA4986BADD120C0CEB2FC5"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this part—</text><subparagraph id="H575B7D81389D401093A00F55E712D789"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the postsecondary apprenticeship program of a student apprentice (as defined in section 791) shall qualify as a work-study program that is eligible for assistance under this part; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9DD23523AE24485BA472D41F044D80A3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>funds appropriated to carry out this part may be used by the Secretary to pay the tuition of such student apprentices except that Federal work study should not supplant the wages of student apprentices.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H83AB7869ACE74D1F9FDD18FC0D96639F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Pell grant eligibility</header><text>A student apprentice who is a participant in a postsecondary apprenticeship program that qualifies as a work-study program under this part and is otherwise eligible to receive a Federal Pell Grant under subpart 1 of part A may receive a Federal Pell Grant for enrollment at the institution of higher education that awards the recognized postsecondary credential that is a part of such postsecondary apprenticeship program. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B36494B699A44C79EF3D2FB3FB5CA9F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Credit for apprentices</header><text>A student apprentice who is a participant in a postsecondary apprenticeship program that qualifies as a work-study program under this part shall receive credit toward a postsecondary degree for such participation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2E74B5E770694CFF9C2EF21B00663911"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>A student apprentice who is a participant in a postsecondary apprenticeship program that qualifies as a work-study program under this part shall receive pay for work in the postsecondary apprenticeship program that is not less than $15 an hour.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

