<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H9CF7D79F396D4A57B51296FFC0522CC0" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6611 RH: To authorize the Embassy of France in Washington, DC, to establish a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs to honor the extraordinary contributions of Jean Monnet to restoring peace between European nations and establishing the European Union, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 449</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6611</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–625, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220204">February 4, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="W000795">Mr. Wilson of South Carolina</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001047">Mr. Himes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To authorize the Embassy of France in Washington, DC, to establish a commemorative work in the District of Columbia and its environs to honor the extraordinary contributions of Jean Monnet to restoring peace between European nations and establishing the European Union, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H12288044A5C74DBB80F1BB6D362EDB57" style="OLC"><section id="H332D2FF6F1E2453A83EABC43D951D96F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Authorization to establish commemorative work</header><subsection id="HD2B05A9F90D74A97B527136892C7DC1B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H46EBC8A280F646E3BF46DC2B263401B2"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the United States and France share a long and mutually beneficial relationship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA4AB153FB42A4AF685F33D371247BF19"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the relationship between the United States and France is built on a shared commitment to the values of democracy, human rights, the rule of law, security, and prosperity;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC00B7CA80E1543AC8F4A3A4571F5F855"><enum>(3)</enum><text>France is—</text><subparagraph id="H14A851BF50DC4E279885BF6CE5936F03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a key North Atlantic Treaty Organization ally; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H215A0CB47EDD45CF83D4AB9A1CCAB764"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an important bilateral economic partner to the United States;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H57D036E4DC5A49B79BCA4555AD15575C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Jean Monnet was a French diplomat who played an influential role in—</text><subparagraph id="H098994FF68764B8D8D970B6604F66FAF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the founding of the European Union; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD005F00B7C4A4EF79F5C56674EC26917"><enum>(B)</enum><text>restoring and maintaining peace throughout Europe;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H418495ADB42D44A3B8A468AB7A8181AB"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Jean Monnet served as Deputy Secretary-General of the League of Nations, the first worldwide intergovernmental organization established to maintain world peace;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA17891C306A4CC0A25ABF5E410DC0F7"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Jean Monnet served as Chair of the Anglo-French Coordinating Committee during World War II to unite British and French war efforts;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3AC52719CF8C44F19A28DC74F41BDD29"><enum>(7)</enum><text>after France surrendered to Germany on June 22, 1940, Jean Monnet served on the British Purchasing Commission to facilitate the production and purchase of armaments for the war effort;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4596625150BC460488344F2191E087CD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Jean Monnet—</text><subparagraph id="H16555A100AB24B28B679C11DBB6CAB6A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>served as an advisor to President Franklin D. Roosevelt; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD5BD7F1FDED349298A46E3387BF2D5A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>played a critical role in the United States by providing necessary armaments and aid to European allies during World War II;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3876A88434954CE385072805B8040C67"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Jean Monnet led the development and implementation of the Modernization and Re-equipment Plan, which spurred economic recovery in France after World War II;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H75A252CAAF554C3E9BF03FB091F68D83"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Jean Monnet co-authored the Schuman Declaration—</text><subparagraph id="H23320E279E3E42EB84D2FB42F2C4FF0A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that—</text><clause id="H0BF5FBB68AF041BCAB8FB2A9CEBFEED5"><enum>(i)</enum><text>bound together French and German industries after World War II to revitalize the European economy and ensure peace; and</text></clause><clause id="HFE0E86F98B214CA1AF2F839167BD6AB2"><enum>(ii)</enum><text> led to the establishment of the European Coal and Steel Community; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4701C4D55A5C430BA73053678D0FD34F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the date of enactment of which, May 9, has been adopted as <quote>Europe Day</quote> by the European Union; </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H80AB584A43A141958B4ECA25244953AA"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Jean Monnet served as the first president of the High Authority of the European Coal and Steel Community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB32A5CD89B54EB885A8A823C80B7830"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Jean Monnet founded the Action Committee for the United States of Europe, which is recognized as having laid the foundation for the establishment of the European Union;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9DB4840BD1754EE2B9B1F7343D14FADA"><enum>(13)</enum><text>on April 2, 1976, the European Council of the European Union presented the first ever Honorary Citizen of Europe award to Jean Monnet for his extraordinary efforts to promote European cooperation;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13AA8DFF098E480183CFEC6AD332A52F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>in 1963, President Lyndon B. Johnson presented Jean Monnet with the Presidential Medal of Freedom; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28BC18D91B23498E8D8A4B81C3924C44"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Jean Monnet—</text><subparagraph id="HC3FB68FE66E5463EB22BEBE493A3A22F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>had a residence near Rock Creek Park in Washington, DC;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5469D2154756468FB7EE16F1B048887C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enjoyed taking long walks through Rock Creek Park; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6248FE5304484DC2BA83F14A0C4E7513"><enum>(C)</enum><text>affectionately referred to Rock Creek Park as <quote>my park</quote>; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C449043DA3C44E5A975FBB6EF4646F6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>claimed that long walks through Rock Creek Park helped him to think and develop plans to achieve peace and unity in Europe.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H434714B608654972957FF14FF4CFB07B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H83F1AB654207425A84A1B4AF091F4BAE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Embassy</header><text>The term <term>Embassy</term> means the Embassy of France in Washington, DC.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84D9E6CFA38443A2A6C5A21A4D140E88"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H480631FAACBA46918A8C9F381A77EC9C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization</header><paragraph id="H47EA21AF32444E958485707FAE9D09C3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Embassy may establish a commemorative work on Federal land in the District of Columbia and its environs to honor the extraordinary contributions of Jean Monnet with respect to—</text><subparagraph id="H180EE91597F041E5B1F0F4C60C9E7F6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>restoring peace between European nations; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBDE890222DE242079D44ABEC2318271F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>establishing the European Union.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC64823A49D3D4CC7919930C6E8DAEFDD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compliance with standards for commemorative works</header><text>The establishment of the commemorative work under this section shall be in accordance with <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/40/89">chapter 89</external-xref> of title 40, United States Code (commonly known as the <quote>Commemorative Works Act</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72490028516C40F5A3AB164F279D2023"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on the use of Federal funds</header><subparagraph id="H478B34AD5FB84A02AA94A1306FC48FB8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Federal funds may not be used to pay any expense of the establishment of the commemorative work under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3264F5C343764D588B5D6C9A10B807E4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Responsibility of the embassy of france in washington, DC</header><text>The Embassy shall be solely responsible for the acceptance of contributions for, and the payment of the expenses of, the establishment of the commemorative work under this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC05CAC8960048A98383244E882F6796"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Deposit of excess funds</header><subparagraph id="HE97F8E370498491381F1C87D94F7A1F9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, on payment of all expenses for the establishment of the commemorative work under this section (including the maintenance and preservation amount required by section 8906(b)(1) of title 40, United States Code), there remains a balance of funds received for the establishment of the commemorative work, the Embassy shall transmit the amount of the balance to the Secretary for deposit in the account provided for in section 8906(b)(3) of that title.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3996498854C64694A4C48C8A8014B641"><enum>(B)</enum><header>On expiration of authority</header><text>If, on expiration of the authority for the commemorative work under section 8903(e) of title 40, United States Code, there remains a balance of funds received for the establishment of the commemorative work under this section, the Embassy shall transmit the amount of the balance to a separate account with the National Park Foundation for memorials, to be available to the Secretary of the Interior or the Administrator of General Services, as appropriate, in accordance with the process provided in paragraph (4) of section 8906(b) of that title for accounts established under paragraph (2) or (3) of that section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF07427A1375445D7988FEC50312136EF"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Determination of budgetary effects</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The budgetary effects of this Act, for the purpose of complying with the Statutory Pay-As-You-Go Act of 2010, shall be determined by reference to the latest statement titled <quote>Budgetary Effects of PAYGO Legislation</quote> for this Act, submitted for printing in the Congressional Record by the Chairman of the Senate Budget Committee, provided that such statement has been submitted prior to the vote on passage.</text></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

