<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HFF97D9DD24E4425C82A0DE2605D25D0A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 4590 RH: Promoting New and Diverse Depository Institutions Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-20</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 163</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 4590</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–229]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210721">July 21, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001156">Mr. McHenry</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000479">Mr. Taylor</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000380">Mr. Kildee</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on July 21, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Federal banking regulators to jointly conduct a study and develop a strategic plan to address challenges faced by proposed depository institutions seeking de novo depository institution charters; and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H79717F3E9E0B42EC89B978F6301C21F5"><section id="H73C5E2036C504254B1321CEA75A18A97" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting New and Diverse Depository Institutions Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFB9613F32B334490A8D29A13094BE960"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and strategic plan</header><subsection id="H381DC9CC01E644DF83614A71BE4A67F3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Federal banking regulators shall jointly—</text><paragraph id="HF8355FC36F6745198FCFA65C39B68666"><enum>(1)</enum><text>conduct a study about the challenges faced by proposed depository institutions, including proposed minority depository institutions, seeking de novo depository institution charters; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H550C128C5F8E41169437F2E1C537E651"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and publish publically, not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section—</text><subparagraph id="H23DB723AEC774AA1A991B57DE3F610E3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an analysis based on the study conducted pursuant to paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H20646A845B3D4D4AA4F47FE1569707D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any findings from the study conducted pursuant to paragraph (1); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H57B10073B7DE4A7DAE4F0A5E3C949814"><enum>(C)</enum><text>any legislative recommendations that the Federal banking regulators developed based on the study conducted pursuant to paragraph (1).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H80DA92C26008429CBF889D9847C56BF5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Strategic plan</header><paragraph id="H5955E2EE77CF4719ADA3DE8CD3D73B7D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of the enactment of this section, the Federal banking regulators shall jointly submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate and publish publically a strategic plan based on the study conducted pursuant to subsection (a) and designed to help proposed depository institutions (including proposed minority depository institutions) successfully apply for de novo depository institution charters in a manner that promotes increased availability of banking and financial services, safety and soundness, consumer protection, community reinvestment, financial stability, and a level playing field.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD0E5646892E461C97F01D4A667802B8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of strategic plan</header><text>The strategic plan described in paragraph (1) shall—</text><subparagraph id="H94DEBA6C4F7A441D971A9F5C2C25F5B7"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">promote the chartering of de novo depository institutions, including—</text><clause id="HF221FF5016F649C0BFFCCBFDD0A05E9E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>proposed minority depository institutions; and</text></clause><clause id="H687E7F5DAC6B40F8A8E626F2D34B1B06"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">proposed depository institutions that could be certified as community development financial institutions; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H880BE90B7F7249659B3D5C1035199698"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe actions the Federal banking regulators may take that would increase the number of depository institutions located in geographic areas where consumers lack access to a branch of a depository institution.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H00717022C4EE43949782BB66B5826116"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public involvement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">When conducting the study and developing the strategic plan required by this Act, the Federal banking regulators shall invite comments and other feedback from the public to inform the study and strategic plan.</text></subsection><subsection id="H24516DBA7DC3422E9B54334B880CD945"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this Act:</text><paragraph id="HC8C9B7F13DD44A358298A797DA5529D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>depository institution</term> has the meaning given in section 3 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act, and includes a <quote>Federal credit union</quote> and a <quote>State credit union</quote> as such terms are defined, respectively, under section 101 of the Federal Credit Union Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90098E0E28204CEF9CD7E89D5FDA773B"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Community development financial institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>community development financial institution</term> has the meaning given in section 103 of the Riegle Community Development and Regulatory Improvement Act of 1994.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD02873DEF894CBC9EA13D78D137095A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal banking regulators</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Federal banking regulators</term> means the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System, the Comptroller of the Currency, the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation, the National Credit Union Administration, and the Director of the Bureau of Consumer Financial Protection.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3366E5886E5E4F7EAA7869E814604A4C"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Minority depository institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>minority depository institution</term> has the meaning given in section 308(b) of the Financial Institutions Reform, Recovery, and Enforcement Act of 1989.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220120">January 20, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

