<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HD38D8A055A724889AAB480BF4D44A978" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7409 IH: Territorial Relief Under Sustainable Transitions for Puerto Rico Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7409</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220405">April 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To modify the conditions for the termination of an oversight board, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H79DD0A54425645BA89EE4C0E6B7A040F" style="OLC"><section id="H586723425D3C4C60996BA7B97AB26C4A" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Territorial Relief Under Sustainable Transitions for Puerto Rico Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>TRUST for Puerto Rico Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H282D770765A0450D9D279EF5AB0A2D2F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modification to conditions for termination</header><subsection id="H526A37B25ABF43D9969684B8EC58200C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 209 of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2149">48 U.S.C. 2149</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HAF7DD3346694414AB208967A90CCF8CB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the matter preceding paragraph (1), by striking <quote>upon</quote> and inserting <quote>not later than 90 days after</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45999DB3B8EA4253BD543E82A1B4379F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC601F7A31E8F44EDB4C165462C9598D9"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><subparagraph id="HD81B484EAF22488AAD1B84F55F74AEB7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in the matter preceding subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>at least 4</quote> and inserting <quote>at least 2</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE904DB588CEC4847B2D681D646EA03D9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by inserting <quote>and without regard to whether the applicable Budget provides for the payment of debt service</quote> after <quote>standards</quote>. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0C073D100FE445EEB1435EBBDC47D0A9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each amendment made by subsection (a) shall take effect and apply as if enacted as part of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5AF968CCAF5443C9950BED6EEF633CF6"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Transfer of functions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon certification of an Oversight Board under section 209 of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2149">48 U.S.C. 2149</external-xref>), as amended by subsection (a), and upon the adoption of a resolution by the legislature of a territory and signed by that territory’s governor setting forth the manner in which such termination shall be implemented—</text><paragraph id="HC65125B24D4346668B076E2F185E7C76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all property, funds, assets, and records of the Oversight Board shall be transferred to the territorial government in accordance with the transition provisions established by such adopted resolution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H404E75FECD80413DB50A82D475F7A6ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a copy of all such records of the Oversight Board shall be transmitted to Congress;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H73A3E9B0BA664BA9AD7525F7C871A70B"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any pending action under title III of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2161">48 U.S.C. 2161 et seq.</external-xref>) as of the date of the adoption of such resolution, the duties and responsibilities of the Oversight Board (including the role and capacity set forth under section 315 of such title) with respect to such action, as of the day before such date of adoption, shall be transferred to the territorial government in accordance with the provisions of such adopted resolution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C55B457E05A4FA1B5E4DDCF8A85F8C9"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to any action taken pursuant to the authorities under title VI of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2191">48 U.S.C. 2191 et seq.</external-xref>) on or after the date of the adoption of such resolution, the duties, responsibilities, and all applicable powers and roles of the Oversight Board, including under any other provision of such Act relating to such action, shall become the duties, responsibilities, powers, and roles, respectively, of the territorial government in accordance with the provisions of such adopted resolution;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEB0DE19B0F8042A1814F3A7933BE1928"><enum>(5)</enum><text>section 302 of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2162">48 U.S.C. 2162</external-xref>) shall be applied with respect to such territorial government as if it read as follows:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H89911DBFEC3040E18DC39DDA699100FA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="H6DC367FC7E524BDDB73AB6988286A084"><enum>302.</enum><header>Who may be a debtor</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">An entity may be a debtor under this title if—</text><paragraph id="H5639DCE4D37C4046A298F368E0790F15"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the entity is—</text><subparagraph id="HAAF2DCFAAD3A4AAE9CDA93E5DB6A0C0E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a territory that has requested the establishment of an Oversight Board or has had an Oversight Board established for it by the United States Congress in accordance with section 101 of this Act; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF627F687DC3456790D58629CFB86004"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a covered territorial instrumentality of a territory described in paragraph (1)(A);</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB85936AB30884E03B2EBA4A3FA3E6787" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the Oversight Board—</text><subparagraph id="HFA9218BBC7044C65A374363637143C93"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has issued a certification under section 206(b) of this Act for such entity; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBC0D52B11BE1420296343BDC9709D6F3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has terminated pursuant to section 209 and the territorial government has undertaken all duties and responsibilities under this title that were formerly assigned to the Oversight Board; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B1C0D744F7C4998873BD541F5D9614E"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the entity desires to effect a plan to adjust its debts.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FE21EDE5FD84935AB155CB578195DF3"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the definition of <quote>covered territorial instrumentality</quote> in section 5(7) of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2104">48 U.S.C. 2104(7)</external-xref>) shall be applied as if <quote>or, upon termination of the Oversight Board pursuant to section 209, designated by the covered territory to be subject to such requirements</quote> were inserted before the period at the end; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEBD9B52F76241F294B480D785FAC6C5"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the definition of <quote>administrative supervisor</quote> in section 601(a)(1) of the Puerto Rico Oversight, Management, and Economic Stability Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/48/2231">48 U.S.C. 2231(a)(1)</external-xref>) shall be applied as if <quote>or, upon termination of the Oversight Board pursuant to section 209, the Territory Government Issuer</quote> were inserted before the period at the end.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

