<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H903296E240DD4DD3AD35049FE1870C7B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9326 IH: Enhancing Electric Grid Resilience Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9326</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221117">November 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Federal Power Act to authorize the allocation of the costs of certain interstate electric power transmission lines and electric power transmission lines that are located offshore, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD66385ABC62F4E609B3512DE217E4F2D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="HFAEA1C6B1D3F47DA9F365AECD1B57F77" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Enhancing Electric Grid Resilience Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF711E81512F649FF8B218A600826587F"><enum>2.</enum><header>Allocation of costs of certain transmission facilities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Part II of the Federal Power Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/824">16 U.S.C. 824 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" id="HEAF6C610602A4EC9AAFF16DD7A982E46" display-inline="no-display-inline"> 
<section id="H0B14984BD03D45B1A095B67D8917A02D"><enum>224.</enum><header>Allocation of costs of certain transmission facilities</header> 
<subsection id="H5FB09B1B5D78454096DF472D5A3D7770"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Allocation of costs</header> 
<paragraph id="H7C3BD917FD474F07A7B85E16898E7C02" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any entity that proposes to own, control, or operate a transmission facility of national significance may file a tariff with the Commission in accordance with section 205 and the regulations of the Commission allocating the costs of such transmission facility of national significance.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H294771E86A5049E3AC27FFED748CA658"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Cost causation principle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall require that any tariff filed under paragraph (1) allocate the costs of a transmission facility of national significance to customers within the applicable transmission planning region or regions in a manner that is at least roughly commensurate with the estimated anticipated benefits described in paragraph (3).</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8FB355CE12DC48E2A4E5B333C258BC2F"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Cost allocation principle</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall require that any tariff filed under paragraph (1) allocate costs based on the broad range of reliability, economic, public policy, resilience, and other reasonably anticipated benefits of the applicable transmission facility of national significance.</text> </paragraph> </subsection> <subsection id="HA8E608631BE94BB1AA2A1077F5E5427E" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Transmission facility of national significance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>transmission facility of national significance</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H65401FA6AFE24BFDA893341796001E1A" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an interstate electric power transmission line (and any facilities necessary for the operation of such electric power transmission line) or an electric power transmission line that is located offshore (and any facilities necessary for the operation of such electric power transmission line)—</text> <subparagraph id="HEA5A7794C976419087B190C18555AE1D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>that has a transmission capacity of not less than 1,000 megawatts; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H004D4640D6664D6D94F26998FE4FFF56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the construction of which is completed on or after the date of enactment of this section; or</text> </subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF1B60764C28A414F8B389B1696EFB629" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an expansion of, or upgrade to, an interstate electric power transmission line (and any facilities necessary for the operation of such electric power transmission line) or an electric power transmission line that is located offshore (and any facilities necessary for the operation of such electric power transmission line) that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HA6EEBD3C49914961A44025A5CB36E736" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>increases the transmission capacity of such electric power transmission line by at least 500 megawatts; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HFAE8458E81A4496798E0EEB6E67CCCC7" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is completed on or after the date of enactment of this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HC7D8569E7CFA485CB647CA6FE3FCE79E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Savings provision</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This section does not affect the authority of the Commission to approve the allocation of costs of transmission facilities other than transmission facilities of national significance.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section> </legis-body></bill>

