<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H5B30A288775E4A95BF7D712A5979DA48" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9242 IH: Legal Aid for Americans Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9242</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221028">October 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001309">Mr. Burchett</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a pro bono service requirement for individuals who borrow Federal student loans for graduate legal education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6BCAFF0B553B4A44A3128A6C8D3199E9" style="OLC"><section id="H24626BB954DB407695D744509610F804" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Legal Aid for Americans Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H2B2FF92004414964BFC7F79D6867D38A"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pro bono service requirement for law graduates</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 455 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1087e">20 U.S.C. 1087e</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H59A2ED3FEA964E6C9CA53CF7B3A3ADDF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HEE8DF86D798E40C9BA2C78E829ABAA1D"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Pro bono service requirement for law graduates</header><paragraph id="HC1321CA845774F0E93A157C98407CC3D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>As condition of receiving a loan under this part for graduate legal education, a borrower shall enter into an agreement with the Secretary pursuant to which the borrower agrees to perform legal work, on a pro bono basis, for not fewer than 50 hours per year during each year of the applicable service period.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF182A756B26C4B138AC7EA1D81D3C755"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual certifications</header><subparagraph id="H2FE532B4572149EDA1BEED0AA7936C3D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>On an annual basis during each year of the applicable service period, a borrower subject to an agreement under paragraph (1) shall submit to the Secretary a certification indicating whether or not the borrower has complied with the requirements of the agreement.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H17C2E94BD7CF434A988583DAEC078C85"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption for public service employees</header><text>A borrower who is employed in a public service job (as defined in subsection (m)) during the applicable service period, as demonstrated by an annual certification of such employment submitted to the Secretary by such borrower, shall be deemed to be in compliance with the pro bono service requirement under this subsection and shall not be required to perform any additional pro bono service pursuant to this subsection.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F08BB6A67764F7C964F104801E73204"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Noncompliance</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of this Act, a borrower subject to an agreement under paragraph (1) who does not comply with the terms of the agreement for any year of the applicable service period shall be treated as in default on any loan to which such agreement applies until the date on which the borrower certifies that the borrower is in compliance with the agreement.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0738C23318654EC1BF44ED06173009F1"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exceptions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement to perform pro bono legal service pursuant to an agreement under paragraph (1) shall not apply during any period in which the borrower—</text><subparagraph id="H0796E7D3E82D42E49535B53CC8D90DC6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is serving on active duty during a war or other military operation or national emergency;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3252C9DB1C044D6AB340413EB22709F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is performing qualifying National Guard duty during a war or other military operation or national emergency; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD91AFEFF8185420FBDECFB65D330A32A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is attending an institution of higher education on not less than a half-time basis.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9EABBB3F11C42E0A4AD4A124E3EC9FD"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The requirement under paragraph (1) shall apply to loans made under this part for graduate legal education after the date of enactment of the Legal Aid for Americans Act of 2022.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64D6B16D03C34F7A9685004F1619C90B"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection:</text><subparagraph id="H3E9359133D3347BBB391A8945874060B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Applicable service period</header><text>The term <term>applicable service period</term> means—</text><clause id="H8149F996BC434D45BBF74EB8D0427B8C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with respect to a borrower who is licensed to practice law in a State before receiving a loan under this part for graduate legal education, the first three years following the date on which the borrower completes the program of study for which the loan was obtained; and</text></clause><clause id="H89C070BCB3FF4F2A8E9F7B025112165F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to a borrower who is not licensed to practice law in a State before receiving a loan under this part for graduate legal education, the first three years following the date on which the borrower obtains a license to practice law in a State.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75D9DC33FCDA4A8DA24F8FB602D5612B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Graduate legal education</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>graduate legal education</term> means any program of study leading to a graduate degree or graduate certificate in a legal field (as determined by the Secretary), including any program of study leading to a Juris Doctor (JD) degree, Master of Laws (LLM) degree, or Doctor of Juridical Science (SJD) degree.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

