<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H71AE6F3D8BD64C568860662B9CE97CE6" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6381 IH: Comprehensive Resources for Entrepreneurs in the Arts to Transform the Economy Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-12</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6381</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220112">January 12, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="C000754">Mr. Cooper</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSM00">Committee on Small Business</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Financial Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To assist entrepreneurs and support development of the creative economy, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA99775CAC3EC430580E9CA62F934AD5A" style="OLC"><section id="H6490A96B27A54016BA1D49FA0569CC1F" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Comprehensive Resources for Entrepreneurs in the Arts to Transform the Economy Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CREATE Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HE28BC62175F44333BBAC2B371308DCDD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Microloan program expansion</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(m)(6) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(m)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H67C337A82CF04F239CC2E6845183C60F" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H1BB1F5865B254F86B916A99FF02900CF"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Loan criteria for artists and arts entrepreneurs</header><text>The Administration, in consultation with eligible intermediaries, shall develop loan criteria to ensure that small business concerns owned and controlled by artists and small business concerns that support the creative economy receive loan proceeds under this subsection.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3B1518088B0448C7B00A15BAEF8D441C"><enum>3.</enum><header>SBA business loans for the creative economy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 7(a) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/636">15 U.S.C. 636(a)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H326A1C3F89ED47F49A64F757DE4E6FDA" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HCDA20931318B46EF94F9D1B576EE0776"><enum>(38)</enum><header>Creative economy</header><text>In providing assistance under this subsection, the Administration shall develop procedures to evaluate the business proposals and business plans of non-employer businesses and small business concerns that focus on economic development, job creation, and community growth with respect to the creative economy.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H825C64B02C9C42B09015376F385F10D6"><enum>4.</enum><header>SBA technical assistance programs</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 21 of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/648">15 U.S.C. 648</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H6A8443B540044B279431F387E06E589F" style="OLC"><subsection id="H12D23516415648C7A45E5DF11A733A48"><enum>(o)</enum><header>Technical assistance programs for artists and arts entrepreneurs</header><text>The Administration, in consultation with relevant stakeholders, shall develop technical assistance programs to be carried out by small business development centers under this subsection that target the specific needs of artists and arts entrepreneurs.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H3CB4B14AB1D04965912E7A9F2F8534C4"><enum>5.</enum><header>Arts-focused economic development</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Title II of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3141">42 U.S.C. 3141 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H78AB528FB2884530A8ABEBE5131952DD" style="OLC"><section id="HCC87F466780147CF8C990C88F428DA56"><enum>219.</enum><header>Arts-focused economic development</header><subsection id="HFE4368B21A5E4FFD818B6A765D84677A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H445ABB85D8C94AE1B80892F8239E10FB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Business incubation program</header><text>The term <term>business incubation program</term> means a program that—</text><subparagraph id="H4DC225B2584E4FEF973DC86C2020EDAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>accelerates the successful development of entrepreneurial businesses through business support resources and services, developed or orchestrated by incubator management;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1E808C1637D241E7A7BCD299714FD07E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designed to produce successful businesses; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFE36735A92A645A6AB12FFF6AE6A1410"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provides management guidance, technical assistance, and consulting designed for young, growing businesses, including by providing—</text><clause id="H28145E3DCF8F4308B71FAA536958635A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>rental space and flexible leases;</text></clause><clause id="H3523298C00334CADB4D9822FB08D11AC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shared basic business services and equipment;</text></clause><clause id="H3CC55CADB1784DCF81B172C6C3F572FC"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>technology support services; and</text></clause><clause id="H9C7E1E38E1F3414282374A0F3E61D98D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>assistance in obtaining financing necessary for growth of the business.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H53CE543067604C7E88CC492A14126B9A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incubator</header><text>The term <term>incubator</term> means a multitenant facility with on-site management that directs a business incubation program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE073125A92D4445B971FDD2FD61424F2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Arts-Focused economic development</header><text>In providing grants and assistance under this Act (including through the local technical assistance, partnership planning, and comprehensive economic development strategies programs of the Economic Development Administration), the Secretary shall provide to State, regional, and local arts agencies, artists, and creative workers support through traditional economic development tools, including—</text><paragraph id="H9C89E8433DC3439BA726FA2C7FAA3411"><enum>(1)</enum><text>incubators; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE240FDF765314C7EBE89383185EC498F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>economic development planning and technical assistance, including assistance for State, regional, and local arts agencies in work related to comprehensive economic development strategies.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H4465A83CC3B540FD8A6BA98BA49DD111"><enum>6.</enum><header>Demonstration program to promote use of creative industries and occupations in certain economic planning</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Commerce shall establish a demonstration program to assess the feasibility and advisability of providing support to local arts agencies and nonprofits through planning grants under section 203 of the Public Works and Economic Development Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3143">42 U.S.C. 3143</external-xref>) and local technical assistance grants under section 207 of that Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/3147">42 U.S.C. 3147</external-xref>) to promote the use of creative industries and occupations in the economic planning of local governments, including in comprehensive economic development strategies.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

