<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H24D13344BF2841A2B5758BB958899D4F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9176 IH: To direct the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to convey to the Municipality of Belleville, Illinois, a parcel of real property located at the Army Reserve Facility in Belleville, Illinois, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-10-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9176</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221014">October 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, to convey to the Municipality of Belleville, Illinois, a parcel of real property located at the Army Reserve Facility in Belleville, Illinois, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H386C366B36EA438B8F0F951A5B9E821D" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H1498985BB39A4F038508F8C19C16646D" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Land conveyance, Army Reserve Facility, Belleville, Illinois</header> 
<subsection id="H32D1648EA3084BDBB436C4B5732CD7A3"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Conveyance authorized</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act and after completion of the survey and appraisal described in this section, the Secretary of the Army, acting through the Chief of Engineers, shall convey to the Municipality of Belleville, Illinois, by quitclaim deed for the consideration described in subsection (c), all right, title, and interest of the United States in and to a parcel of real property described in subsection (b).</text></subsection> <subsection id="HB69CF7F26E5E4AAB86574F1BAFBA2F10"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Property described</header> <paragraph id="HAA3FFC30F74A4143BE0AA83D8C390F4E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The parcel to be conveyed under subsection (a) consists of approximately 5.2 acres and improvements located at 500 South Belt East in Belleville, Illinois, that is administered by the Department of the Army.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H98871E6F73284218BEB723FA8C98F655"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Survey required</header><text>As soon as practicable after the date of enactment of this Act, the exact acreage and legal description of the real property to be conveyed under subsection (a) shall be determined by a survey that is satisfactory to the Chief of Engineers.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H243CBBD027CD4050BA5DB1CDEFCC54E5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration</header> <paragraph id="H2E2526734E4C4761898FA235ACD710D3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In exchange for the conveyance of the parcel of real property described in subsection (b), the Municipality of Belleville, Illinois, shall to pay to the Chief of Engineers nominal consideration.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HDC85211098A84BC1A8937FD553BE5D59"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Deposit</header><text>Any cash payment received by the United States under paragraph (1) shall be deposited in the special account in the Treasury referred to in subparagraph (A) of paragraph (5) of subsection (b) of section 572 of title 40, United States Code, and shall be available in accordance with subparagraph (B) of such paragraph. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HF10FD683068E4EE6BAC6E450CB738BA9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Costs of conveyance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Municipality of Belleville, Illinois, shall be responsible for paying—</text> 
<paragraph id="H01CCF586802546D59E5F2840FFED8A86"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the costs of the survey conducted under subsection (b)(2); and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB4324023901418D998E469971DEF83F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other costs relating to the conveyance of the parcel of real property under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H35DED98A2A334BF9B483B6428C3765CC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Additional terms and conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Chief of Engineers may establish such additional terms and conditions with respect to the conveyance under this section as the Chief of Engineers considers to be appropriate to protect the interests of the United States.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

