<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBFBB4B06ECA545029578E65278630470" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7624 IH: Spectrum Innovation Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7624</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000566">Mr. Latta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001257">Mr. Bilirakis</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000171">Mr. O'Halleran</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000615">Mr. Duncan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001216">Ms. Schrier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001200">Mr. McEachin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001067">Mr. Hudson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000558">Mr. Guthrie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000576">Mr. Long</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000378">Mr. Kinzinger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000382">Ms. Kuster</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000798">Mr. Walberg</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M001166">Mr. McNerney</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To make available additional frequencies in the 3.1–3.45 GHz band for non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HC19E8207514F499085BA741A7057D42F" style="OLC"><section id="HBB21AAD86F1D4F9C87D4D1DF941390EF" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Spectrum Innovation Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H45747A68F3124DAB9A143B6F5A4A2A49"><enum>2.</enum><header>Spectrum auctions and innovation</header><subsection id="H96510C0B3613498688F315638EF6B71C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H40F611A4B1474AD59BD0610351C27CB4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Assistant secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Assistant Secretary</quote> means the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Communications and Information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7881894973B248649D0EEF26AFA6DCA3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text>The term <quote>Commission</quote> means the Federal Communications Commission.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H84D7505E83594456BD2474884B626F91"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered band</header><text>The term <quote>covered band</quote> means the band of frequencies between 3100 megahertz and 3450 megahertz, inclusive.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD514A9505994A43B91868E49A4495A9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Federal entity</header><text>The term <quote>Federal entity</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 113(l) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/923">47 U.S.C. 923(l)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE1649B70F944A9C89695E9B5828981A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Relevant congressional committees</header><text>The term <quote>relevant congressional committees</quote> means—</text><subparagraph id="H05FBD398E56448C5BF44DD12F60496A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE61971DF793D4FBDA6B89079D3101897"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7408230BBBC49E2A1C82623423AFBEF"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC33682D578604B91862395E6417D2A98"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30F4F161BB6D45ED88CC35787D1ED6A5"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Commerce.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3587D478E952467CB4428FB95D13196E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>3.1–3.45 GHz band</header><paragraph id="H4125BE26CB064A2B99071098801BD088"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Pipeline funding</header><subparagraph id="H3DCEACFD9EEB4EF4B49B1AFDE1859AF9"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Immediately following the approval under subparagraph (E) of subsection (g)(2) of section 118 of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/928">47 U.S.C. 928</external-xref>) of a plan submitted under subparagraph (D)(i)(I) of such subsection by a Federal entity with operations in the covered band, the Director of the Office of Management and Budget shall transfer to such Federal entity from the Spectrum Relocation Fund established under such section $50,000,000 for such Federal entity to carry out activities described in subparagraph (A) of such subsection in order to make available the entire covered band for non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof, including by making available—</text><clause id="H00E8E61592BC43C68834EA99FFC82468"><enum>(i)</enum><text>frequencies in the covered band for identification by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(A); and</text></clause><clause id="H5D0AE87EB0BB4307A06653D9B4BFB761"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>frequencies in the covered band for identification by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H933858ACC0034948B2EB899CA4931BA2"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text>Section 118(g)(2)(D)(ii) of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration Organization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/928">47 U.S.C. 928(g)(2)(D)(ii)</external-xref>) shall not apply with respect to the payment required under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50C535AFD93B48C1B036A1B72D179BE7"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Oversight</header><text>The Assistant Secretary and the Executive Office of the President shall continuously review and provide oversight of the activities carried out using a payment under subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21D0D435A85B403589464D45C09D1A87"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Report to secretary of commerce and congress</header><text>Not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, for the purposes of aiding the Secretary in making the identification under paragraph (2) and informed by the activities carried out using a payment under subparagraph (A), any Federal entity receiving such a payment, in consultation with the Assistant Secretary and the Executive Office of the President, shall submit to the Secretary and the relevant congressional committees a report that—</text><clause id="H5B283CE1E9AE488F975E53A85F2C92FE"><enum>(i)</enum><text>contains the findings of the activities carried out using such payment; and</text></clause><clause id="H2EB27A3BD577469F858DD428491215C3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>recommends—</text><subclause id="H71A8B4C93D5947F29342121A3E13C3B3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>frequencies in the covered band for identification by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(A); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H4A0A24DA6B764846A140F3AA008B9AAE"><enum>(II)</enum><text>frequencies in the covered band for identification by the Secretary under paragraph (2)(B).</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H713E14E5AA1747E78C0AAE2D3DA99CDF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Identification</header><text>Not later than 24 months after the date of enactment of this Act, informed by the activities carried out using a payment under paragraph (1)(A) and the report required under paragraph (1)(D), the Secretary, in consultation with the Secretary of Defense, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, and the Commission, shall submit to the President, the Commission, and the relevant congressional committees a report that—</text><subparagraph id="HF90890AF41224C8BBB269586683D54B2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>identifies for inclusion in a system of competitive bidding under paragraph (3) at least 200 megahertz of frequencies in the covered band for non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA63695C420BE4A2A9C78658263BBE715"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identifies additional frequencies in the covered band that could be made available for non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H863CF6BB7F2D4B3F813693B3613A233D"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Auction</header><subparagraph id="H725EBBA5D4E549A2BF91BB06ED6AB0B2"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 7 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, shall commence a system of competitive bidding under section 309(j) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/309">47 U.S.C. 309(j)</external-xref>), in accordance with paragraph (2) of this subsection, of the frequencies identified under subparagraph (A) of that paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA5FC11082AC24E45A728847D00400651"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition</header><text>No entity that is on the list required by section 2 of the Secure and Trusted Communications Networks Act of 2019 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/1601">47 U.S.C. 1601</external-xref>) may participate in the system of competitive bidding required by subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDDD81A3831A4496DA93AF289D35073DA"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Scope</header><text>The Commission may not include in the system of competitive bidding required by subparagraph (A) any frequencies that are not in the covered band.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H34600D9D6E3A4F9CA581B961FF362E9D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Modification or withdrawal</header><subparagraph id="H9CEA1A7986EF4CDEA5AB43E337758475"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President shall modify or withdraw any assignment to a Federal Government station of the frequencies identified under paragraph (2)(A) to accommodate non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof in accordance with that paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H40E8ABF725484E25808EEA6BADE52C17"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Limitations</header><text>The President may not modify or withdraw any assignment to a Federal Government station as described in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H615EE228DBEA467EACCCE87CFF44A49A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>unless the President determines that such modification or withdrawal will not compromise the primary mission of a Federal entity operating in the covered band; or</text></clause><clause id="H5C2A8A3189F348019D4F589F0BD4D8AA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>before November 30, 2024.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC63CC135B85D4E8197F8202B058E0609"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Auction proceeds to cover 110 percent of federal relocation or sharing costs</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to relieve the Commission from the requirements under section 309(j)(16)(B) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/309">47 U.S.C. 309(j)(16)(B)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B22427ED13349E093098CD96D99BC52"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Rules authorizing additional use of spectrum in covered band</header><text>Not later than 4 years after the date of enactment of this Act, the Commission, in coordination with the Assistant Secretary, shall adopt rules that authorize the use of spectrum in the covered band identified under paragraph (2)(B) for non-Federal use, shared Federal and non-Federal use, or a combination thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8AFC6D0C547446459AEEC14EF314FFFA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>FCC auction authority</header><paragraph id="H6A3B6D6907A8413CB0104DE9E8658C4B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Section 309(j)(11) of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/309">47 U.S.C. 309(j)(11)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>2025</quote> and all that follows and inserting <quote>2025, and with respect to the electromagnetic spectrum identified under section 2(b)(2)(A) of the <short-title>Spectrum Innovation Act of 2022</short-title>, such authority shall expire on the date that is 7 years after the date of enactment of that Act.</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H822E2878115C44369C63AC8DAB1E7505"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Spectrum Pipeline Act of 2015</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1004 of the Spectrum Pipeline Act of 2015 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/74">Public Law 114–74</external-xref>; 129 Stat. 621; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/921">47 U.S.C. 921</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H3D7CF224B179430088529E075F6F180E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2024</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4E8562604D9449E38908F59D9F440243"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (b)(1), by striking <quote>2022</quote> and inserting <quote>2024</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDF0B9B8B38064860AAD60E89867773D1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Repeal</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 90008 of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/58">Public Law 117–58</external-xref>; 135 Stat. 1348; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/921">47 U.S.C. 921</external-xref> note), and the item relating to such section in the table of contents in section 1(b) of such Act, are repealed.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

