<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H33C731A1E9BA486BAB8164587014CE92" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6808 IH: Spending Every Nickel on Student Education Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6808</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220222">February 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000579">Mr. Gallagher</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To improve transparency relating to the expenditure of Federal emergency relief funds for elementary and secondary schools, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9D7E359EB27B4BD197B112292DB09044" style="OLC"><section id="H6249FC37D0FE4871BB1C5BFAA0FB0134" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Spending Every Nickel on Student Education Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SENSE Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H178F2960590742FA99781EC64E92D96B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Annual report on expenditure of elementary and secondary emergency relief funds</header><subsection id="H142F8916953E4ED2B5771C211103E68F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>LEA Reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On an annual basis, in accordance with subsection (d), each local education agency that received funds under section 2001 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401</external-xref> note) shall submit to the State in which the agency is located a report on the expenditure of such funds during the preceding year. Each report shall—</text><paragraph id="H5AB6C00B2D8F458E866090346C3CD602"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">describe the purposes for which the local educational agency expended such funds during the year covered by the report;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H088982E0312441DB9709DDADC6FD59B9"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">indicate whether such expenditures are consistent with the plan submitted by the agency pursuant to the interim final requirement of the Department of Education titled <quote>American Rescue Plan Act Elementary and Secondary School Emergency Relief Fund, LEA ARP ESSER Plans</quote> (86 Fed. Reg. 21198; April 22, 2021) and, if such expenditures are not consistent with that plan, provide an explanation for the inconsistency; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06A5D7F21B254280ABDD956A0B8F5B01"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide the information required under paragraphs (1) and (2) in a format and level of detail that is consistent with the State and Federal requirements applicable to the plans described in paragraph (2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4FE2119148A74BED9B8A54EFE733AB41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>State reports</header><text>On an annual basis, not later than 90 days after receiving the reports from local educational agencies under subsection (a), each State shall—</text><paragraph id="HC853CCA928DA42ED987B65BF81739FE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>compile the reports;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7097291F25C1429E8D852FF05453E590"><enum>(2)</enum><text>transmit the compiled reports to the Secretary of Education; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FA51F0343924469A42560068A36950F"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make the reports available on a publicly accessible website of the State in a format that is downloadable, searchable, and sortable.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HABF96AF6BBD64895B3280E289997CFCF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Posting by Secretary</header><text>The Secretary of Education shall make each report received from a State under subsection (b) available on a publicly accessible website of the Department of Education.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5080C640148641C8A1FA0ED623DA03F1"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual submittal and termination</header><paragraph id="HFAEA70A6E95B4CB781D70343BFB745D7"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Annual submittal date</header><text>The reports required under subsection (a) shall be submitted each year on a date determined by the Secretary of Education that is at least 30 days before funds are allocated to States under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary and Education Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) for the next school year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2651929355004CE6BCB079E1CC10318C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Termination of reporting requirement</header><subparagraph id="H99FF009732B540D9AEB443CD989CBBFF"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Final report</header><text>After the date specified in subparagraph (B), a local educational agency shall submit a final report in accordance with subsection (a). Following the submission of such final report, the requirement of a local educational agency to submit further reports under subsection (a) shall terminate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAC6CFFF9C54B4E2F9A959888B325CE15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Date described</header><text>The date specified in this subparagraph is the earlier of—</text><clause id="H5CA330E2B4D849C7A61974D0B8559694"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the date on which the local educational agency has obligated all funds received by the agency under section 2001 of the American Rescue Plan Act of 2021 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/2">Public Law 117–2</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/3401">20 U.S.C. 3401</external-xref> note); or</text></clause><clause id="H5B342DC04AD84AAFA229106A9E9CD769"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the date by which the local educational agency is required to obligate such funds in accordance with such section.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBB8C8066F2894DB994ACCA89DCB22443"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A local educational agency that does not submit a report required under subsection (a) by the date determined by the Secretary under subsection (d)(1), shall not be eligible to receive Federal funds under part A of title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/6311">20 U.S.C. 6311 et seq.</external-xref>) for the next year for which such funds are allocated.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB8B22BCB423247D6AC225D00F020AD6C"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section, the terms <term>local educational agency</term> and <term>State</term> have the meanings given those terms in section 8101 if the Elementary ad Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

