<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H1DD2F5DD991B464FB510AAC557A8F9BC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6638 IH: To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the Office of Accountability and Whistleblower Protection of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6638</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220208">February 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000871">Mr. Mann</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B001295">Mr. Bost</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Committee on Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HAP00">Appropriations</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements to the Office of Accountability and Whistleblower Protection of the Department of Veterans Affairs, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H189F3976B24D4D8A852C473F81AFE952" style="OLC"><section id="HD736AC0ADD324F7E9456B8033C68ABCB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Modifications and improvements to Office of Accountability and Whistleblower Protection</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 323 of title 38, United States Code, is amended—</text><paragraph id="HC3F81D1D27AB43B283C9DF3AAC7E51DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="H9E3C198CC21E457385B814CEFB491ACC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H34E792DBA10B449F8179ED3DAF7E594B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (A) and (B);</text></clause><clause id="HC72FB46BA4A3407BA3B27786B10A4561"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by redesignating subparagraphs (C) through (G) as subparagraphs (A) through (E), respectively;</text></clause><clause id="H99047B30682242B0897922CF2A7064E0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>in each of subparagraphs (A) and (B), as so redesignated, by inserting <quote>and allegations of whistleblower retaliation</quote> after <quote>disclosures</quote>;</text></clause><clause id="H0356C731089648E28EE0D5A9D01B746C"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), as so redesignated—</text><subclause id="H6F11CC1EBE3A41EF8185D9C7381E1142"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>subparagraph (C)</quote> and inserting <quote>subparagraph (A)</quote>; and </text></subclause><subclause id="HB1246127B90D461B88C02C4F5164B7F1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the Office of the Medical Inspector</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>the Office of Special Counsel.</quote>; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H1DF68FBF86D74A9782E4FAC74AC47E09"><enum>(v)</enum><text>by striking subparagraphs (H) and (I); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBCDCB99778C84FBD991FD6D5BE033773"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2)—</text><clause id="HB9D68390256649A09258399D0BC3896B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by striking <quote>a toll-free telephone number and Internet</quote> and inserting <quote>an internet</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HECC14477F1E74DE6A0EC76AF3F85359F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and allegations of whistleblower retaliation</quote> after <quote>disclosures</quote>;</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H852BB16F284C4A3F818FF2A5A0ACA78E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking subsection (f) and inserting the following new subsection (f):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H2C026796A582410183A25D0FBC1291A4" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H514663DD5DF34C0FA49B0C85F00B68A0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Reports</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H636E7E8EA08F4F029B9A63591A372D22"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the last day of each fiscal year, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the Senate and the Committee on Veterans' Affairs of the House of Representatives a report on the activities of the Office during that fiscal year.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43CF228954E449CB8906BF9596ECDC3A" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Each report submitted under paragraph (1) shall include, for the fiscal year covered by the report, the following: </text><subparagraph id="H18586C0014A64DABB1658F571A32B2EC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A full and substantive analysis of the activities of the Office, including such statistical information as the Assistant Secretary considers appropriate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2C6756748F18419388C67F645EB6AC83"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Identification of any issues reported to the Secretary under subsection (c)(1)(G), including such data as the Assistant Secretary considers relevant to such issues and any trends the Assistant Secretary may have identified with respect to such issues.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D02D1B6784849D29EDAAF8ADFC09944"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Identification of such concerns as the Assistant Secretary may have regarding the size, staffing, and resources of the Office and such recommendations as the Assistant Secretary may have for legislative or administrative action to address such concerns. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H830C01A7384848C89645CCC0209D5DA8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Such recommendations as the Assistant Secretary may have for legislative or administrative action to improve—</text><clause id="HB821F8796276437F96C72CC404B12C93"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the process by which concerns are reported to the Office; and </text></clause><clause id="H6F87B795352342A7A1F638CD9FECEE8D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the protection of whistleblowers within the Department.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E13D2CBA364429BB4D834E6921835C1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Such other matters as the Assistant Secretary considers appropriate regarding the functions of the Office or other matters relating to the Office.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H86EBCE2DC43646A6B6176FBBFECD4E58"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (g) as subsection (j);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA676F6A949A04DEFBFD4753E9FFDF901"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (f) the following new subsections:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HA5351EE840FA455EB87C947C7659CB99" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H194B266D7218406F93A712CAE9080094"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Transfer authority</header><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HE0DB4933F77D4806AF423333C93FECFF"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As the Secretary determines appropriate, of the amounts made available for the Department for any of fiscal years 2022 through 2026, the Secretary may transfer to the Office of Special Counsel not more than $5,000,000, to be available for the purpose of addressing whistleblower and retaliation claims, if the Comptroller General of the Office of Special Counsel enters into an agreement with the Secretary under which the Comptroller General agrees to ensure that amounts transferred under this paragraph will only be used—</text><subparagraph id="HEE14A973706F4ED780B94B2C0D0EACAF" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to address whistleblower and retaliation claims involving the Department; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4B8CF9F54C147ADB975D5F9C242C4A0" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to supplement and not to supplant amounts otherwise made available to the Office of Special Counsel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC069503F138442058DCCBE9B1416F468" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the last day of any fiscal year for which the Secretary transfers funds under this subsection, the Special Counsel shall submit to the Committees on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate and House of Representatives a report on the use of the funds transferred under this subsection during such fiscal year. Each such report shall include, for the fiscal year covered by the report—</text><subparagraph id="HB482CFDBFB464430BD9F68D1F8DFEC4E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the total amount transferred and an accounting of the expenditure of such funds demonstrating that such funds were used only to address complaints related to the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE494323F03AD4CDF86F12E13338D2A38"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the number of whistleblower complaints received by the Office of Special Counsel involving the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H143BF852272E468E90A6F2DB5FF9DF93"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the number of retaliation complaints received by the Office of Special Counsel involving the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H58B5930B99524AAEAD0374AA74AF3992"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the number of whistleblower complaints investigated by the Office of Special Counsel involving the Department;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7381E80398F340559BD33036A3925431"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the number of retaliation complaints closed by the Office of Special Counsel involving the Department and disposition of each such complaint, including—</text><clause id="HB024F27A431445F7B38B39B5F6E7A268"><enum>(i)</enum><text>whether each such complaint was settled, closed without a finding of retaliation, or received another disposition; and</text></clause><clause id="H2A0D9C0699BF4BC085D068AC3B17607F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for each such complaint that was settled, the amount of the settlement; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB6911DC206E44E118CA68E4DBA0F402C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>data regarding the amount of time it took the Office of Special Counsel to close whistleblower and retaliation claims involving the Department, including a distribution of the closed cases by type.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB57BD29243984888A2AA36FD41F3C7E9"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Training</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall—</text><paragraph id="HA982CEF36783426489AE9762F8019782"><enum>(1)</enum><text>provide training on whistleblower protection and related issues and make such training available to employees of the Department; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE60A43AF074F0CBF37FCF6617B085B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">disseminate training materials and information to employees on whistleblower rights, whistleblower disclosures, and allegations of whistleblower retaliation, including any materials created pursuant to section 733 of this title.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27B15222BB4F4D9FBCD3E3E49160FAB5"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Availability of information</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall make publicly available on an appropriate website of the Department the following information:</text><paragraph id="H349A83BE6ED749D4942683B5E7FB1A6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Templates that can be used to submit proper and complete whistleblower and retaliation claims.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB62C3C8C892541C98B3A49B342DFA8E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The standard operating procedures of the Office and any applicable regulations.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3EFD68AA26F450E9262A89BCEBBD26C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Each report submitted under subsection (f).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2DCF6193D3E4508B893AC44C2A71311"><enum>(5)</enum><text>in subsection (j), as so redesignated—</text><subparagraph id="H243D9EA0F92E4EE895E6F77432117509"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking paragraph (1);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62A4BC95B26D4576820ACADE65F9FC58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (2) and (3) as paragraphs (1) and (2), respectively; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D80C3ACE67B44888C2954935654966C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H1774E8B9F2114A3B95E2025A345A41B1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H82FB27CEAF414E29B813F4AA722C2852"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>whistleblower retaliation</quote> means the taking or failure to take, or the threat to take or not to take, by a supervisory employee (as such term is defined in section 7103(a) of title 5), of a personnel action because of a whistleblower disclosure.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HC339266200F948E2B895579497BACD5B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Pilot program on counseling for whistleblowers</header><subsection id="H196EA2F9E7EC4992A7A637A2D35F4C80"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Assistant Secretary of Veterans Affairs for Accountability and Whistleblower Protection shall carry out two-year pilot program under which the Assistant Secretary shall offer counseling to a Department of Veterans Affairs whistleblower regarding the relevant laws and policies that affect the whistleblower, the whistleblower’s disclosure, and any allegation of whistleblower retaliation.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB921F538F0374124B4DB2AFF871570E6"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation</header><text>The Assistant Secretary shall begin implementing the pilot program required under this section by not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF99A85ED380409593CBA4D5E1944079"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Upon the conclusion of the pilot program, the Assistant Secretary shall submit to Congress a report on the program, which shall include the number of employees who received counseling under the program, trends identified by the program, an analysis of the program, and such other matters as the Assistant Secretary determines relevant.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

