<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H43A23849B2EE478980B1A581871BE829" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 3858 RH: National Science and Technology Strategy Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-18</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 178</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 3858</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–248]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210611">June 11, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000823">Mr. Waltz</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000491">Mr. Lucas</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="J000126">Ms. Johnson of Texas</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S000344">Mr. Sherman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000630">Mr. Delgado</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="E000071">Mr. Ellzey</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220218">February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name>; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed<pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish a national science and technology strategy, a quadrennial science and technology review, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body id="H141A6B8A11CF48CE9F232B959823DE0E" style="OLC"><section id="H691622BFAEE74BA382CA728BFC215E02" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>National Science and Technology Strategy Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H11D41443EE3B41F5B7D5517106860A0B"><enum>2.</enum><header>National science and technology strategy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> Section 206 of the National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6615">42 U.S.C. 6615</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H0025FF779BF348DBA30039B7A01B7111" style="OLC"><section id="H342963339A844CA6B71B5263C32CD06B"><enum>206.</enum><header>National science and technology strategy</header><subsection id="H2C28CCF069FA4276BAA39768F68D919E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than the end of each calendar year immediately after the calendar year in which a review under section 206b is completed, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy, in consultation with the National Science and Technology Council, shall develop and submit to Congress a comprehensive national science and technology strategy of the United States to meet national research and development objectives for the following 4-year period (in this Act referred to as <quote>the national science and technology strategy</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H3A8597E323CF440FB114CA7588CFC9DE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>Each national science and technology strategy required by subsection (a) shall delineate a national science and technology strategy consistent with—</text><paragraph id="HC5C74607C72C4608A5012EC3347623E0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the recommendations and priorities developed by the review established in section 206b;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A0F0FFB09E04C9F9A36BD63255228A8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the most recent national security strategy report submitted pursuant to section 1032 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2012 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3043">50 U.S.C. 3043</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8F6D77C10963417C8BEBF69E34D0A67A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>other relevant national plans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C3E6E478D814CF99945A84539956B02"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the strategic plans of relevant Federal departments and agencies.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H389A8103F7314EB48C8B98ED6D3462F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Director shall consult as necessary with the Office of Management and Budget and other appropriate elements of the Executive Office of the President to ensure that the recommendations and priorities delineated in the science and technology strategy are incorporated in the development of annual budget requests.</text></subsection><subsection id="H481F2CFA64684DAAAC3FD9872C450840"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The President shall submit to Congress each year a comprehensive report on the national science and technology strategy of the United States. Each report on the national science and technology strategy of the United States shall include a description of—</text><paragraph id="HDBC7E6E53BA44EE8B57E843A4E2B1CC1"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">strategic objectives and priorities necessary to maintain the leadership of the United States in science and technology and to advance science and technology to address societal and national challenges, including near-term, medium-term, and long-term research priorities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C95F2B98C8648D1A82752200BA59811"><enum>(2)</enum><text>programs, policies, and activities that the President recommends across all Federal agencies to achieve the strategic objectives in paragraph (1); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H050D1562E43841BBA8EDD7C2E040DDB2"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">global trends in science and technology, including potential threats to the leadership of the United States in science and technology and opportunities for international collaboration in science and technology.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7B7CDFC85AF743499C8AE8ECFEE16CC2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Director shall, consistent with the protection of national security and other sensitive matters to the maximum extent practicable, make each report submitted under subsection (d) publicly available on an internet website of the Office.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H40CDBA12167D467287232BA850390EB5"><enum>3.</enum><header>Quadrennial science and technology review</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline"> The National Science and Technology Policy, Organization, and Priorities Act of 1976 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/6601">42 U.S.C. 6601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 206 the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7F8EEE3EF44C4408AF32124A40061D38" style="OLC"><section id="H50E0AAF6C3884BBB9EE64B1313E1CEB8"><enum>206b.</enum><header>Quadrennial science and technology review</header><subsection id="H92CB12260D554F5D9E29D6D2E1353F9A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Requirements</header><paragraph id="H2342F93AC5314078A8237B4A52C0484A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Quadrennial reviews required</header><text>Not later than December 31, 2022, and every 4 years thereafter, the Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall complete a review of the science and technology enterprise of the United States (in this section referred to as the <quote>quadrennial science and technology review</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H95BA8BDC12414F10BCD4E9CE27BDE563"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Scope</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The quadrennial science and technology review shall be a comprehensive examination of the science and technology strategy of the United States, including recommendations for maintaining global leadership in science and technology and advancing science and technology to address the societal and national challenges and guidance on the coordination of programs, assets, capabilities, budget, policies, and authorities across all Federal research and development programs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF297A6FE637B4FF3A1144634C8CD08A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>The Director of the Office of Science and Technology Policy shall conduct each quadrennial science and technology review under this subsection in consultation with—</text><subparagraph id="H0295A734A60C49B6B89E2012DB27E143"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the National Science and Technology Council;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7B3CCA2EB3D34079B7683BDB2F2D1B41"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the heads of other relevant Federal agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H528468E542DA4A96A1D044A7597615E3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the President’s Council of Advisors on Science and Technology;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF9C86F0A479244AB9387C4303B83A92F"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the National Science Board;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H501BCA4D4DFD44A48B933AEA23F12B36"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the National Security Council; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBACF9D9A67DF46E8B5A3CC52D5FA4AFD"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">other relevant governmental and nongovernmental entities, including representatives from industry, institutions of higher education, nonprofit organizations, Members of Congress, and other policy experts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6E68D58B0CD49DEBE45616BDAA055E6"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text>The Director shall ensure that each quadrennial science and technology review conducted under this section is coordinated with other relevant statutorily required reviews, and to the maximum extent practicable incorporates information and recommendations from existing reviews to avoid duplication.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3C89FCCDB11C465087F252988B1DA2FB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>In each quadrennial science and technology review, the Director shall—</text><paragraph id="H5D3D38F144504F85A90F35052E64B042"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide an integrated view of, and recommendations for, science and technology policy across the Federal Government, while considering economic and national security and other societal and national challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD98DAEA03F644A4C88B25B5214BB950B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>assess and recommend priorities for research, development and demonstration programs to maintain American leadership in science and technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1518B4FF3E7F43E3B8A4D5399551E692"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess and recommend priorities for research, development, and demonstration programs to address societal and national challenges;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H323FABF2486F4292B2B7D352E0198EDE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess the global competition in science and technology and identify potential threats to the leadership of the United States in science and technology and opportunities for international collaboration;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H504A3ED389A84A0E96AD669B8C29FF9D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>assess and make recommendations on the science, technology, engineering, mathematics and computer science workforce in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4FCA033AEF1549C28FE88A598EF755A1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>assess and make recommendations to improve regional innovation across the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H971D809543714E1DA1B9BBCE339B0E26"><enum>(7)</enum><text>assess and make recommendations to improve translation of basic research and the enhancement of technology transfer of federally funded research;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3C48021635AF4285A7F0E8D4DCB6EAC1"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assess and identify the infrastructure and tools needed to maintain the leadership of the United States in science and technology and address other societal and national challenges; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CFA028B6FDD4A018493C2685AF30435"><enum>(9)</enum><text>review administrative or legislative policies that affect the science and technology enterprise and identify and make recommendations on policies that hinder research and development in the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1D0C1C4209284FD0AEA1039268373ABA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H618E44DB441A4461B54AACA013FD33ED"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than December 31 of the year in which a quadrennial science and technology review is conducted, the Director shall submit a report of the review to Congress.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6B8AED9B5FD4D5088C46B51BB1BB87D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Publication</header><text>The Director shall, consistent with the protection of national security and other sensitive matters to the maximum extent possible, make each report submitted under paragraph (1) publicly available on an internet website of the Office of Science and Technology Policy.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date>February 18, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

