<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HFEF939C74EAD42CE98A61163165F6582" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7093 IH: To withdraw certain Federal land in the San Bernardino National Forest in California from location, entry, and patent under mining laws, and for other purposes.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7093</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220315">March 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000019">Mr. Obernolte</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To withdraw certain Federal land in the San Bernardino National Forest in California from location, entry, and patent under mining laws, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H0793595FADDE49C785E3D073CB2B3C60" style="OLC"><section id="H5AB2404D29A64EE98E45727D93B096A0" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H8E415D05D6184252BE46D64B0876A9A7"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Forest Service has implemented a strategy known as the Carbonate Habitat Management Strategy to conserve listed threatened and endangered species where minerals co-occur with those species’ habitats to allow for species conservation and efficient administration of mining activities on the San Bernardino National Forest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AE488774AEE40788DC1085064508E26"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The withdrawal of certain land in the San Bernardino National Forest will create a reserve for designated crucial habitat to protect four listed threatened and endangered plant species from the effects of mining.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC3115A49F5694120B65FEAC1CE22B627"><enum>2.</enum><header>Withdrawal of San Bernardino National Forest land from mining laws</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subject to valid existing rights, the approximately 3,055 acres of land generally depicted as <quote>Proposed Withdrawal</quote> on the map titled <quote>Proposed Withdrawal-San Bernardino National Forest-Mountaintop Ranger District</quote>, and dated October 19, 2020, is hereby withdrawn from—</text><paragraph id="HC2A65FA2BF44467EA2D0C80F538EAFDB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>all forms of entry, appropriation, and disposal under the public land laws; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67F9D43691FB42F8B53365894E3459EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>location, entry, and patent under the mining laws; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9496200FBC4E4C449EF86725F81D7035"><enum>(3)</enum><text>operation of the mineral leasing, mineral materials, and geothermal leasing laws. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

