<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H23023C2FDDF340418931A4A93A5B9DDD" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7707 IH: The Spc. Bishop E. Evans Border Security Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7707</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000376">Mr. Kelly of Pennsylvania</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Homeland Security</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To codify in statute the CDC title 42 expulsion order, which suspends the right for certain aliens to enter the United States along United States land borders, until February 1, 2025.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF8A3801C98A14D79AAE501C59EAD1178" style="OLC"><section id="H9E206FF5699346B0A4B56B615AF30AB7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>The Spc. Bishop E. Evans Border Security Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HC6EE2CD629FC4837BC14E0E89F0D6DCE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Extension and codification of title 42 expulsion order issued on October 13, 2020</header><subsection id="HAFE2E0D358CA40BC9A02913D62C245BC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HC5F20F85C2344AA692AED93B64FF6BE0"><enum>(1)</enum><text>On March 20, 2020, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC), pursuant to sections 362 and 365 of the Public Health Service Act (42 U.S.C. 265 and 268), issued the Order Suspending Introduction of Certain Persons from Countries Where a Communicable Disease Exists (85 Fed. Reg. 16567), which was extended on April 20, 2020, and amended on May 19, 2020.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49DD2EE0FC0845E18D9262E59FB29E9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>On October 13, 2020, the Director of the CDC, issued a similar order (85 Fed. Reg. 65806), which continued to protect the public health from an increase in the serious danger of the introduction of COVID–19 into the United States through ports of entry.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBDA77740D8E84D9395A795A4D0C1B9E0"><enum>(3)</enum><text>On April 1, 2022, the Director of the CDC announced that the policy implemented through the orders referred to in paragraphs (1) and (2), and commonly known as the title 42 expulsion policy, would be terminated beginning May 23, 2022.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAD815F89552049C485DA0285D773532D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Temporary extension of title 42 expulsion policy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding the Order Regarding the Right to Introduce Certain Persons From Countries Where a Quarantinable Communicable Disease Exists, issued by the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention on April 1, 2022, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that the following policy remains in place until February 1, 2025:</text><paragraph id="HE7BCED47DBBF4CB3A73F7535B5FD582F"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Any person not described in paragraph (2) who is traveling through Canada or Mexico and would otherwise be introduced into a congregate setting in a land or coastal port of entry or U.S. Border Patrol station at or near the United States border with Canada or with Mexico may not be placed in a congregate setting in the United States or otherwise admitted into the United States. It is anticipated that the vast majority of such persons will be aliens who are seeking to enter the United States at a port of entry who do not have proper travel documents, aliens whose entry is otherwise contrary to the immigration laws, and aliens who are apprehended at or near the United States border while seeking to unlawfully enter the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H448C3BAC6A3B4FDBB6162AE49ED422E0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A person described in this paragraph is—</text><subparagraph id="H6F8FB96636FA4C3FABA3F8AE9FC97B42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a United States citizen or lawful permanent resident;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9E23DE46C674C76A2F67B2C29135CEE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a member of the United States Armed Forces, including associated personnel, and the spouse and children of such members; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5CC63792706E4BD88AB59E8F7F720056"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a person from a foreign country who holds valid travel documents and arrives at a designated port of entry, including any person from a foreign country participating in the visa waiver program who is not subject to travel restrictions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

