<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBC473B9DB1BA4FEAB3C1762958D862FF" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7461 IH: Competency-Based Education Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7461</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="G000576">Mr. Grothman</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="O000086">Mr. Owens</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000395">Mr. Keller</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000165">Mr. Tiffany</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="S001213">Mr. Steil</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to clarify competency-based education.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA107763949254F0D8102CC3602F599F3" style="OLC"><section id="H930527556FBB4C92A0F16C6C3D17DE18" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Competency-Based Education Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CBE Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H5AADAEDB97284A7AB41DAC76C63956F9"><enum>2.</enum><header>Regulatory relief</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning on the date of the enactment of this Act—</text><paragraph id="H4EB8CC8F9ED945E98639CB1843E9E226"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the definition of the term <term>credit hour</term> in section 600.2 of title 34, Code of Federal Regulations (as in effect on the day before such date of enactment) shall have no force or effect;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF536E4AF31F14B4BA4A2C3F7EBEF603C"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for purposes of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq), the term <quote>credit hour</quote> shall have the meaning given that term by the Department of Education in regulation before the effective date of the regulations published by the Department of Education in the Federal Register on October 29, 2010 (75 Fed. Reg. 66946); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28B1AF8B686F4AED84E8E628F496C9F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Secretary of Education may not promulgate or enforce any additional regulations or rules with respect to the definition of the term <term>credit hour</term> for any purpose under the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section><section id="H356EF73632184B37905C92679B6E780F" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 103 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1003">20 U.S.C. 1003</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H44B73265F79D4EF4BD5A6512761405A3" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HDEC119B76A1B443199C790C6E7696E2E"><enum>(25)</enum><header>Competency-based education; competency-based education program</header><subparagraph id="HE2EF82D7B9FA4D8FA61B0C3960460F4C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Competency-based education</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the term <term>competency-based education</term> means education that—</text><clause id="HF67BAD4C320F48F39BDE809064AE58E3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>measures academic progress and attainment—</text><subclause id="HB08825BFDAE2494C9362984A0DCEE7B7"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by direct assessment of a student’s level of mastery of competencies;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2B558BDBD00F4C81B38950363E8573FC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by expressing a student’s level of mastery of competencies in terms of equivalent credit or clock hours; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HEDBA0D5B475543B6BDC4B242969F8CB3"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by a combination of the methods described in subclauses (I) or (II) and credit or clock hours; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HCCECF35A00B24B3A94C4D17BC7B19A55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>provides the educational content, activities, and resources, including substantive instructional interaction, including by faculty, and regular support by the institution, necessary to enable students to learn or develop what is required to demonstrate and attain mastery of such competencies, as assessed by the accrediting agency or association of the institution of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6190ECA6815340FDB02CCC07AB9B8D7E"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Competency-based education program</header><text>Except as otherwise provided, the term <term>competency-based education program</term> means a postsecondary program offered by an institution of higher education that—</text><clause id="HE2216D7D327949C2920C2BB24066D199"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provides competency-based education, which upon a student’s demonstration or mastery of a set of competencies identified and required by the institution, leads to or results in the award of a certificate, degree, or other recognized educational credential;</text></clause><clause id="HE0B5AA724574454795D579FD2DCDA72F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensures title IV funds may be used only for learning that results from instruction provided, or overseen, by the institution, not for the portion of the program of which the student has demonstrated mastery prior to enrollment in the program or tests of learning that are not associated with educational activities overseen by the institution; and</text></clause><clause id="HF74FEC0F27BA47B5944406274845551D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is organized in such a manner that an institution can determine, based on the method of measurement selected by the institution under subparagraph (A)(i), what constitutes a full-time, three-quarter time, half-time, and less than half-time workload for the purposes of awarding and administering assistance under title IV of this Act, or assistance provided under another provision of Federal law to attend an institution of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H67B6A8D5F4164922981D3E1A3A70C8EF"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Competency defined</header><text>In this paragraph, the term <term>competency</term> means the knowledge, skill, or ability demonstrated by a student in a subject area.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HC2A3BFFBA6F147C39E7CC9EE58109BDE"><enum>4.</enum><header>General provisions relating to student assistance</header><subsection id="HDA37674FA42B4FB1BC71053A2FF6FF8E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions of academic year and eligible program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 481 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1088">20 U.S.C. 1088</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H25DB8B0AD2C84A99BB010D47919A6067"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE6CAC1E98DBA40B09A4F3CBCFB986D87" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HCEA6FA3905D94C43BAE991F7C8BCFD1D" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5028A58F5B5D480FA23BE8E015119F6E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>For the purpose of a competency-based education program the term <term>academic year</term> shall be the published measured period established by the institution of higher education that is necessary for a student with a normal full-time workload for the course of study the student is pursuing (as measured using the value of competencies or sets of competencies required by such institution and approved by such institution’s accrediting agency or association) to earn—</text><clause id="H4FC3C4DE07154FE0AC9E75FD0B46BF1A" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>one-quarter of a bachelor’s degree;</text></clause><clause id="HD38E176432B04EBFAEBFE25A6F1C3EC5" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>one-half of an associate’s degree; or</text></clause><clause id="H8E06817BC9FE44858FE35AD8920792B7" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>with respect to a non-degree or graduate program, the equivalent of a period described in clause (i) or (ii).</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8ECFF77E1FC14AC3ADF2C22528E13858" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HBCB401F5D27D4418844D23CB59BC434C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A competency-based education program that is not a term-based program may be treated as a term-based program for purposes of establishing payment periods for disbursement of loans and grants under this title if—</text><subclause id="H7AAFE202A944438595CE00821FF6ED71" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the institution of higher education that offers such program charges a flat subscription fee for access to instruction during a period determined by the institution; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H0F6F5D64AB9F4BD3882CEF91021501C2" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the institution is able to determine the competencies a student is expected to demonstrate for such subscription period.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6159AABFFD464B74AB9A5F054F19980B" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Clause (i) shall apply even in a case in which instruction or other work with respect to a competency that is expected to be attributable to a subscription period begins prior to such subscription period.</text></clause><clause id="H5930C59EB644425BA4B839A7BF59D18A" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>In a case in which a competency-based education program offered by an institution of higher education is treated as a term-based program under clause (i), the institution shall review the academic progress of each student enrolled in such program in accordance with section 484(c), except that such review shall occur at the end of each payment period.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H4D0C0196700D48CA8027300794875984"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by striking paragraph (4) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H7DE4995ED2B0450FB1D26BCA1BA9926F" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="H13969F92056B441E96AD608EC13BF65C" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this title, the term <term>eligible program</term> includes a competency-based program that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H19C9BF934E0D460C9AE735B76D35E776"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has been evaluated and approved by an accrediting agency or association that—</text><clause commented="no" id="HA334839720AC4D51A74EC6821650162B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>is recognized by the Secretary under subpart 2 of part H; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HF19271781B5B45F5BEDD13AE0EAA3DC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>has evaluation of competency-based education programs within the scope of its recognition in accordance with section 496(a)(4)(C); or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H77833969FC214019A6979C3CEC46B6DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>as of the day before the date of enactment of the <short-title>CBE Act of 2022</short-title>, met the requirements of a direct assessment program under section 481(b)(4) (as such section was in effect on the day before such date of enactment).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2701C6D5F10C44FD8B506CDFC0B74E08"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Student eligibility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 484 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1091">20 U.S.C. 1091</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HC0F825E8BB5A4982B270042027315477"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HE8914ACB87E34D6A9CDF69B785C49843" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="H14986FC3919048BF83F8DD3E05C950A2" indent="up1"><enum>(6)</enum><text>For purposes of competency-based education, in order to be eligible to receive any loan under this title for an award year, a student may be enrolled in coursework attributable only to 2 academic years within the award year.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HC8A4C91CE5154E92A1384515D7630D01"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)—</text><subparagraph id="HEB1E6D3B7A3A472DBC569BF67B86B1F5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in paragraph (1)—</text><clause id="H2BE62E03B3164361B9B86B06D418DED7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><subclause commented="no" id="H8620975D8E8D4D80926B251137A87F07"><enum>(I)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the student has a cumulative</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>the student has—</quote></text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H459E446445FA4DE8B52F32B42CD8D8AF" style="OLC"><clause commented="no" id="H7ADB6FE3A90F49FCBCD936925C4E904C" indent="up1"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a cumulative;</text></clause><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause><subclause id="HB9B653BF091D44D58A9CCB6DFA97E1A2"><enum>(II)</enum><text>by striking <quote>the second</quote> and inserting <quote>each</quote>;</text></subclause><subclause id="HF53FBEB2EEA84B5390CFEEEE6377BAE0"><enum>(III)</enum><text>by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H2CD88F2BECF54E3CBAF4307E459A3AB4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H5D9DAC369DCF4E3A9544F167D7333C5D" style="OLC"><clause commented="no" id="H9E927747D5D845999745E93AAC2D7B66" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>for the purposes of competency-based programs, a non-grade equivalent demonstration of academic standing consistent with the requirements for graduation, as determined by the institution, at the end of each such academic year; and</text></clause><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subclause></clause><clause id="HE23DE808D9D54B9B96153601A50F2393"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HA356CF4DE964461CACCADFD63A084FEE" style="OLC"><subparagraph commented="no" id="HE592E0B346A3424194C0164F7A44C271" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the student maintains a pace in his or her educational program that—</text><clause commented="no" id="HCE07D5415E8F47FBB7E80F3C7802E347"><enum>(i)</enum><text>ensures that the student completes the program within the maximum timeframe; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H9A4CADAF1B204A0984456AF25E3F88BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is measured by a method determined by the institution which may be based on credit hours, clock hours, or competencies completed.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDF5FB28773B94C8599111B96D61A2FCB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>grading period</quote> and inserting <quote>evaluation period</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDAC40D243D7D4CB6A25D78798F40944C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H2D2A32C4AD35435882F9360B5600AEE5" style="OLC"><paragraph commented="no" id="HE1CAE503DD4045DFB235DFF342C4370C" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>For purposes of this subsection, the term <term>maximum timeframe</term> means—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H61A3E035214141FEA6C73BE3CD94500F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to an undergraduate program measured in credit hours, a period that is no longer than 150 percent of the published length of the educational program, as measured in credit hours;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H154A050618D64F589929813FFB94E1CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to an undergraduate program measured in competencies, a period that is no longer than 150 percent of the published length of the educational program, as measured in competencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H84EE441F6D5040E3A4E994E9B3E7BD6C"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to an undergraduate program measured in clock hours, a period that is no longer than 150 percent of the published length of the educational program, as measured by the cumulative number of clock hours the student is required to complete and expressed in calendar time; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H6049D26F567B4265A22850CD1F849ECA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>with respect to a graduate program, a period defined by the institution that is based on the length of the educational program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H53B22D83449A4A72A65089BCFDC272B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recognition of accrediting agency or association</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 496 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1099b">20 U.S.C. 1099b</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HB91A27F1325740CD9B6F0C691DAB6221"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(4)—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3648DC4D8E124926AFC10AA5409A14BE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDA1077FC61A94004B5321C5349B8F6A8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking subparagraph (B) and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block id="H57491438F8F94A54ACE4E016E942DAF3" style="OLC"><subparagraph commented="no" id="HA8F3C03CF55943E1816E606DB206BFD1" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>such agency or association demonstrates the ability to review, evaluate, and assess the quality of any instruction delivery model or method such agency or association has or seeks to include within its scope of recognition, without giving preference to or differentially treating a particular instruction delivery model or method offered by an institution of higher education or program except that, in a case in which the instruction delivery model allows for the separation of the student from the instructor—</text><clause commented="no" id="HE46E1E131E23483EB7F7CEB74125FC79"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the agency or association requires the institution to have processes through which the institution establishes that the student who registers in a course or program is the same student who participates in, including, to the extent practicable, testing or other assessment, and completes the program and receives the academic credit; and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H04C46DB1A8644E06AD84B6023EDDDE8A"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the agency or association requires that any process used by an institution to comply with the requirement under clause (i) does not infringe upon student privacy and is implemented in a manner that is minimally burdensome to the student; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H3FB37F2244FC4A67945C3221E1409768" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>if such an agency or association evaluates or assesses the quality of competency-based education programs, the agency’s or association’s evaluation or assessment—</text><clause commented="no" id="H758F78EC1D8D4C9E9A31051C7A910B27"><enum>(i)</enum><text>shall address effectively the quality of an institution’s competency-based education programs as set forth in paragraph (5), except that the agency or association is not required to have separate standards, procedures, or policies for the evaluation of competency-based education;</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="HD590CC160CCF4C57996AD0739B306387"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>shall establish whether an institution has demonstrated that its program satisfies the definitions in section 103(25); and</text></clause><clause commented="no" id="H63FAB58922F748EB8B7A53FA839D833B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>shall establish whether an institution has demonstrated that it has defined an academic year for a competency-based program in accordance with section 481(a)(3).</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H7A1AADBF13E74B72BEA1B89FF51999D8"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (c)(1), by inserting <quote>or competency-based education</quote> after <quote>distance education</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H86CE135B567341CC90CBD9CE1A56D40A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in subsection (n)(3), by inserting <quote>, or competency-based education programs,</quote> after each occurrence of <quote>distance education courses or programs</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H50D547FA14E7476D8153DB2C835F8717"><enum>(4)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="HBDEBD79F1FB1471EA5564D6D85109904" style="OLC"><subsection commented="no" id="H9B200257895A436C90DA9A63C6CBA3C7"><enum>(r)</enum><header>Waiver</header><text>The Secretary shall establish a process through which an agency or association may seek to have a requirement of this subpart waived, if such agency or association—</text><paragraph commented="no" id="HD572B191DB3C47AE90A75D1344A6A9FE"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrates that such waiver is necessary to enable an institution of higher education or program accredited by the agency or association to implement innovative practices intended to—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="H0AD7FADB05D64DA29F2EA1AF5FD32598"><enum>(A)</enum><text>reduce administrative burdens to the institution or program without creating costs for the taxpayer; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H1E50C6AF0731492CAEF7E7B92F269C25"><enum>(B)</enum><text>improve the delivery of services to students, improve instruction or learning outcomes, or otherwise benefit students; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H316C6C1752BD43CCAAF0B12E61C6A43D"><enum>(2)</enum><text>describes the terms and conditions that will be placed upon the program or institution to ensure academic integrity and quality.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

