<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7F6C5C8B653C45F392B6B16F2AC8296B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8173 IH: Fourth Amendment Restoration Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-22</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8173</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220622">June 22, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001302">Mr. Biggs</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="G000578">Mr. Gaetz</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001184">Mr. Massie</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000596">Mrs. Greene of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000565">Mr. Gosar</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000595">Mr. Good of Virginia</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Permanent Select Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HIG00">Intelligence</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To repeal the Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H5D2589E3EC3D422A97D8B711F936CC22" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H35AE823AF88A463CAF4C46D03AE89FFE" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fourth Amendment Restoration Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H50C65031C59543799F861E71A0589436"><enum>2.</enum><header>Repeal of foreign surveillance authorities</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Foreign Intelligence Surveillance Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/1801">50 U.S.C. 1801 et seq.</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></section> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H73550D2AA73249C297F3576B6280C26C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For the purposes of this Act—</text> <subsection id="H12C2765FF46F4892828E5D123E3880BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Pen register and trap and trace device</header><text>The terms <term>pen register</term> and <term>trap and trace device</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 3127 of title 18, United States Code.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H8A4CCE5DD6AB482E9943E696F6DBB699"><enum>(b)</enum><header>United States citizen</header><text>The term <term>United States citizen</term> means an individual who is a citizen of the United States.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H1D63B1F9461F4544AFCB65619E698CA3"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign intelligence information</header><text>The term <term>foreign intelligence information</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="H1D1811CF3DC842748454192BD74664DB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information that relates to, and if concerning a United States citizen is necessary to, the ability of the United States to protect against—</text> <subparagraph id="H029445C32B22412AAC8FC15530825B0C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>actual or potential attack or other grave hostile acts of a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power;</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2D9CF3B78FC400D9305FD9B40916BFA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>sabotage, international terrorism, or the intentional proliferation of weapons of mass destruction by a foreign power or an agent of a foreign power; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6F200FCA2A8147B7809597CED90DB3A7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>clandestine intelligence activities by an intelligence service or network of a foreign power or by an agent of a foreign power; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HE42CE1E1D89A470CBB7A30D73340A332"><enum>(2)</enum><text>information with respect to a foreign power or foreign territory that relates to, and if concerning a United States citizen, is necessary to—</text> <subparagraph id="H44EF15AFDD8148D3B679171164C389C5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the national defense or the security of the United States; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H84126968223144BF8CB5C21FB835D178"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the conduct of the foreign affairs of the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H2B9BF356B92E4040873236B222D4476D"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Electronic surveillance</header><text>The term <term>electronic surveillance</term> means—</text> 
<paragraph id="HC4FA1C767E0E4BF5AAD30CB75338ACF9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the acquisition by an electronic, mechanical, or other surveillance device of the contents of any wire or radio communication sent by or intended to be received by a particular, known United States citizen who is in the United States, if the contents are acquired by intentionally targeting that United States citizen, under circumstances in which a citizen has a reasonable expectation of privacy and a warrant would be required for law enforcement purposes; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F6BDD2FEE354BD6BEA0C29F8235BE2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the installation or use of an electronic, mechanical, or other surveillance device in the United States for monitoring to acquire information, other than from a wire or radio communication, under circumstances in which a citizen has a reasonable expectation of privacy and a warrant would be required for law enforcement purposes.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H665AEF48FCCC42E4A57B24367FB6F025"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Wire communication</header><text>The term <term>wire communication</term> means any communication while it is being carried by a wire, cable, or other like connection furnished or operated by any person engaged as a common carrier in providing or operating such facilities for the transmission of interstate or foreign communications.</text></subsection></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HBCD40AD25DB0410CAC3A611524C0ED86"><enum>4.</enum><header>Prohibitions on surveilling United States citizens</header> <subsection id="H6A7DC615DF254BBDB19F4A896A132141"><enum>(a)</enum><text>An officer of the United States must obtain a warrant issued using the procedures described in the Federal Rules of Criminal Procedure by a Federal court in order to conduct or request—</text> 
<paragraph id="H56FDF190B9EC42378F6FF218A936505D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>electronic surveillance of a United States citizen;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8F70B1BAB0F241C5BB04597D920482F0"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a physical search of a premises, information, material, or property used exclusively by, or under the open and exclusive control of, a United States citizen;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2A34C9A3541643BD9D08750D3E8D5224"><enum>(3)</enum><text>approval of the installation and use of a pen register or trap and trace device, a sole or significant purpose of which is to obtain foreign intelligence information concerning a United States citizen;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8ECA096D1B734860A9D5D30B2B4422E9"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the production of tangible things (including books, records, papers, documents, and other items) concerning a United States citizen to obtain foreign intelligence information; or</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H13607F9E689B4C91BC3CC68958E47076"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the targeting of a United States citizen for the acquisition of foreign intelligence information.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HD95C5D65AACF48C0A2C67DF9AB5D51F5"><enum>(b)</enum><text>Any information concerning a United States citizen acquired under Executive Order 12333 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/50/3001">50 U.S.C. 3001</external-xref> note; relating to United States intelligence activities) shall not be used in evidence against that United States citizen in any criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding or as part of any criminal, civil, or administrative investigation.</text></subsection></section> 
<section section-type="subsequent-section" id="HD301EC56DBBF4257AED115A2E13CE9D2"><enum>5.</enum><header>Limitation on use of information concerning United States citizens</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Any information concerning a United States citizen acquired during surveillance of a non-United States citizen shall not be used in evidence against that United States citizen in any criminal, civil, or administrative proceeding or as part of any criminal, civil, or administrative investigation.</text></section> <section section-type="subsequent-section" id="H4635465598604D7B90D0E0710078B304"><enum>6.</enum><header>Criminal sanctions</header> <subsection id="HED1D2CF697ED4AE48D501E46E371CB75"><enum>(a)</enum><text>A person is guilty of an offense if he intentionally— </text> 
<paragraph id="H1B5199617F0C47A1A03660E2C19A00D9"><enum>(1)</enum><text>engages in any of the offenses described in section 4, except as authorized by this Act, title 18, or any express statutory authorization that is an additional exclusive means for conducting electronic surveillance under section 1812 of title 50; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B7ED028F4E747DCB1756A0AF736CADC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>discloses or uses information obtained under color of law by any of the methods described in section 4, paragraph (1), knowing or having reason to know that the information was obtained without authorization by this chapter, title 18, or any express statutory authorization that is an additional exclusive means for conducting electronic surveillance under section 1812 of title 50.</text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE1D436F4CFF347E6BDBD957B54F227E9"><enum>(b)</enum><text>It is a defense to prosecution under subsection (a) that the defendant was a law enforcement officer or investigative officer engaging in the course of his official duties and the conduct was authorized and conducted pursuant to a search warrant or court order of a court of competent jurisdiction.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H69A1337178B8458597D4A34DE2B45697"><enum>(c)</enum><text>An offense described in this section is punishable by a fine of not more than $10,000 or imprisonment for not less than five years, or both.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H4400079524BE4CA5A3D52BB132573697"><enum>(d)</enum><text>There is a Federal jurisdiction over an offense under this section if the person committing the offense was an officer or employee of the United States at the time the offense was committed.</text></subsection></section> </legis-body></bill>

