<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HF3F111A35ADF4B13ACE2723EE5BAE35F" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8597 IH: Emergency Care Improvement Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-29</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8597</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220729">July 29, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="S000250">Mr. Sessions</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001291">Mr. Babin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000048">Mr. Pfluger</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000134">Ms. Van Duyne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000816">Mr. Williams of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000552">Mr. Gohmert</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000026">Mr. Nehls</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001082">Mr. Hern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000304">Mr. Jackson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001248">Mr. Burgess</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of services furnished by freestanding emergency centers, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDCE13B389FD2497DB237603EBF5A2551" style="OLC"><section id="H5149E32430184875821328A2000DD74B" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Emergency Care Improvement Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC91F5CC970F74B7A99CE0EDEDECD9CFC"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H97A4F32F086642C3AC471E1A9301809C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To expand provider capacity to respond to the COVID-19 pandemic, in April of 2020 the Centers for Medicare &amp; Medicaid Services issued a waiver allowing freestanding emergency centers (FECs) to enroll as Medicare-certified hospitals and receive Medicare reimbursement for the duration of the COVID-19 public health emergency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5788D7868BB4B908174AA18332C6CFA"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">FECs are fully licensed emergency departments that are staffed by both Emergency Medicine trained physicians and registered nurses who are on-site 24 hours a day, seven days a week, and possess licensed pharmacies, clinical laboratories, and advanced imaging services. FECs are State-licensed, and adhere to the same standards and provide the same level of care as Hospital Based Emergency Rooms, including State EMTALA regulations on treating all patients.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DED0435996144589EBAE58B84AC43F0"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Over 110 FECs, mostly located in Texas, have enrolled and provided high-quality emergency services for all kinds of emergency conditions at significant savings to the Medicare program to thousands of Medicare beneficiaries.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE456DD73C2C4EE5B09696ABEC35FA73"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An actuarial study of Medicare claims data found that FECs did not increase overall utilization of emergency care services and saved the Medicare program 21.8 percent in lower emergency care payments for patients of similar acuity. </text></paragraph></section><section id="HA397489231C94F79857AE803C9D9446B" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Coverage of freestanding emergency centers under medicare and medicaid</header><subsection id="HD6174CE3F7F74E2BBFA9861595C57E48" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coverage under medicare part B</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1832(a)(2) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395k">42 U.S.C. 1395k(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA2E6A1669C614ECDA487BB38C0FCE692" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subparagraph (I), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H18B266FA91AC4A85AFF2B71350DB6C03" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subparagraph (J), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C4A58121BAA42028C0FD1D25FF41AA4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H57AF4DCCF63A4954B8BC345C96741434" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HE3BC4E83E194405E93886F11769D2B7A" commented="no"><enum>(K)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">emergency services (as defined in section 2799A–1(a)(3)(C) of the Public Health Service Act) provided by a freestanding emergency center (as defined in section 1861(lll)).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D3EA9CD28434A829965FC41BEF3ED4D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Freestanding emergency center defined</header><text>Section 1861 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395x">42 U.S.C. 1395x</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HF9C4DF9FCDC44A9CA6B4DABCCCDD2F94" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H746D986ECC794957AB7348944709A12F" commented="no"><enum>(lll)</enum><header>Freestanding emergency center</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>freestanding emergency center</quote> means a health care facility that—</text><paragraph id="HC8E2493528DD4D7DAB2DCF2C1F3CCB42" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is an independent freestanding emergency department (as defined in section 2799A–1(a)(3)(D) of the Public Health Service Act);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D7A2731A7F64B87A73187FAD585AE53" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is operational 24 hours a day, 7 days a week, and 365 days a year with a physician (as defined in subsection (r)) onsite at all times;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H19CF774A8A5B4DEBA7693930E32352E7" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has in place mechanisms to allow for appropriate transfers and referrals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAB9AD6ED088645C89BCE3F157A05BD41" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develops, implements, and maintains an ongoing, data-driven quality assessment and performance improvement (QAPI) program;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAAC4BDE2B0914C2C99C309CBD866E193" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is located—</text><subparagraph id="H27B4C42F0B43430A9DB0CCEFA108FBA9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in a metropolitan statistical area; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H77969148179E4D90B02EC90F87FB2811" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H7AE5F8F2458E47448464C4C763800D13"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the case of a facility established prior to 2020, in a rural county; or</text></clause><clause id="HA6D9404FB5AD4D8C95DD65263D15C2D6" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of a facility established on or after January 1, 2020, in a rural county that does not have a Medicare-certified hospital or a rural emergency hospital (as defined in subsection (kkk)(2));</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA87CA60E8C2C43EAA0C9432C988A623F" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has established a governing body to determine, implement, and monitor policies governing the total operation of the facility, and has oversight and accountability for the QAPI program, ensuring that facility policies and such QAPI program are administered so as to provide quality health care in a safe environment; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9AF0096C09494667A43C2219F1BFC182" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets all State requirements applicable to facilities which furnish emergency medical services to individuals but do not typically provide for stays in excess of 24 hours, and meets such other requirements as the Secretary may prescribe not in excess of the conditions of participation under this title that are specifically applicable to off campus dedicated emergency departments of hospitals (as described in section 482.55 of title 42, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation)), and not the conditions of participation under this title that are applicable to hospitals (as defined in subsection (e)), including rural emergency hospitals (as defined in subsection (kkk)(2)), other than with respect to compliance with the requirements described in section 1867;</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H99C706B7C04F411F91FA0D46FD71B02F" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Payment under Medicare</header><text>Section 1833(t)(21) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1395l">42 U.S.C. 1395l(t)(21)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1EB4EF0CA80C49D5BD7CC106B57A3136" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H3A9BE6D682C24AE7A46016AC928255E8" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Treatment of freestanding emergency centers</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The facility payment rate for services of a freestanding emergency center (as defined in section 1861(lll)) for higher acuity evaluation or management level services (as represented by HCPCS codes 99283–99285, or any successor codes) shall be in an amount equal to the payment that would otherwise apply to a hospital outpatient department under this subsection, including the application of the geographic adjustment under paragraph (2)(D) and the OPD fee schedule increase factor under paragraph (3)(C)(iv).</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA1C65EFB3A6E4E6595D76B0B600313E2" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Coverage under Medicaid</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905(a)(2)(A) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(a)(2)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by inserting <quote>, which shall include the services of freestanding emergency centers, as defined in section 1861(lll)</quote> after <quote>outpatient hospital services</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4A8A29E4C28B482E9B0FA793E1C23558" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this Act shall apply to items and services furnished on or after January 1, 2023, or the first day following the termination of the emergency period (as defined in section 1135(g)(1)(B) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1320b-5">42 U.S.C. 1320b–5(g)(1)(B)</external-xref>)), whichever comes first.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

