<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39BAC15361C84048AE39DCE8E6BA74A9" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9693 IH: Lobbying Disclosure Reform Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9693</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221223">December 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 to assign unique identification numbers to each lobbyist who registers under such Act and to each client of the lobbyist and each person who provides strategic lobbying services in support of the lobbyist, to require the disclosure of information on any persons who provide strategic lobbying services in support of registered lobbyists under such Act, to require the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate to assign a unique identification number to each individual who registers as a lobbyist under such Act, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HCF98137E56D142B1B1A666A05ED03DD9" style="OLC"><section id="H7B1ACF50F0F145BBB443178284379848" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Lobbying Disclosure Reform Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB26C6BFA0AEB4FE493352EEEAAD6EFCF"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds that—</text><paragraph id="H8F05653F5ECD4BDAAF2512BDE6E72701"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the right to petition government for redress of grievances is a fundamental right in our representative democracy, which is often realized through lobbying;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70DA6C6D331F43B8903FA33A5E6DAA55"><enum>(2)</enum><text>responsible representative government requires public awareness of the efforts of paid lobbyists to influence the public decision-making process in both the legislative and executive branches of the Federal Government;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60D410998FE24C59B80CFD8897FA3D72"><enum>(3)</enum><text>existing lobbying disclosure laws have not been as effective as they could be because of unclear statutory language, weak administrative and enforcement provisions, and an absence of clear guidance as to who is required to register and what they are required to disclose;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DC945818863467DAEE84C17FE1CA0DF"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the effective public disclosure of the identity and extent of the efforts of paid lobbyists to influence Federal officials in the conduct of government actions will increase public confidence in the integrity of government; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H173D873B397D40AB8B5E08302DD3DE14"><enum>(5)</enum><text>experience with lobbying laws and regulations for nearly a half century led to substantial improvements in the law in 1995, and experience with the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 over the last decade provides a sound basis for new refinements today.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HB1348556B7CA4D47A179A2D27E6DF833"><enum>3.</enum><header>Assignment of unique identification numbers to lobbyists, clients, and providers of strategic lobbying services</header><subsection id="HB20E797F1E0B424FB0CC697E3C0C1CC4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Assignment of unique identification numbers</header><text>Section 6(a)(3) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H1FF3FC010D3E4BC5A193EB9AA9886F76"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (A);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD20647320895496BB3B6198B1E7149B2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> after the semicolon at the end of subparagraph (B); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1B1B1B99015347A89F7DD8C01FE107BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding after subparagraph (B) the following:</text><quoted-block id="H23A3CBACC49C4A049646F2837209AB9B" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H8B45F43D45B5421CA89AAFB1987750D3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a system that assigns an identification number for each lobbyist for whom a registration or report is filed under this Act, each client of such a lobbyist, and each provider of strategic lobbying services on behalf of such client;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EAEBEECDACC4512B7C6AF56E4B583B9"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion in registration statements</header><paragraph id="HEC19F2E7800B4BF5850A9E77C5C749DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information on registrants</header><text>Section 4(b)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>name,</quote> and inserting <quote>name, unique identification number (if available at the time of registration),</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B91FD71B32649F6ADE78F684F852916"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on clients</header><text>Section 4(b)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>name,</quote> and inserting <quote>name, unique identification number (if available at the time of registration),</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2ACB2B5594044F2182585598860CEB5C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Information on employees</header><text>Section 4(b)(6) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(b)(6)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the name</quote> and inserting <quote>the name and unique identification number (if available at the time of registration)</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEC0216EBF59549369AC15EA2CB11F299"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion in quarterly reports</header><paragraph id="HFC913C8BD6ED4739A43E31D274F5FBB2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information on registrants and clients</header><text>Section 5(b)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1604">2 U.S.C. 1604(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the name of the registrant, the name of the client</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>the name and unique identification number of the registrant, the name and unique identification number of the client</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H50B3C9CDBD7A44CF876E43899805E9AE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information on employees</header><text>Section 5(b)(2)(C) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1604">2 U.S.C. 1604(b)(2)(C)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>a list of the employees</quote> and inserting <quote>a list of the names and unique identification numbers of the employees</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0F0B7674325240138C2587B95D6D6879"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate shall implement the system described in subparagraph (C) of section 6(a)(3) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995, as added by subsection (a), not later than the first day of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress.</text></subsection></section><section id="H47154795A7DE480297678F91F768E5F4"><enum>4.</enum><header>Requiring disclosure of persons providing strategic lobbying services</header><subsection id="H88265CE68DAC4813848548AA299B4631"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Disclosure in lobbyist registration statements</header><text>Section 4(b)(6) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(b)(6)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA94FB837BDD7454D8C32AA25EA0161D8"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>expects to act as a lobbyist on behalf of the client and</quote> and inserting the following: <quote>expects to act as a lobbyist on behalf of the client, or who has been or who the registrant expects to be a provider of strategic lobbying services on behalf of the client, and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF8CB5A0FEA64A54BA80C2F5AE79A3C4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after <quote>first acted as a lobbyist</quote> the following: <quote>or was first a provider of strategic lobbying services</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H076252E1128849BF95D2BDE5FABCF558"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure in quarterly reports</header><text>Section 5(b)(2) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1604">2 U.S.C. 1604(b)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H62A3A3F55C9742B98EF12D7410107BAF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (C);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF31B12E9C3784300BED31CE1D1779A5B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end of subparagraph (D); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H39DA4EEB3A554763A1624679B70D6BE2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraphs:</text><quoted-block id="HF25FD6C41538464486156E96D543D2EA" style="OLC"><subparagraph id="H29D014874ADA45EEAF00F7616A3340DD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a list of the names and unique identification numbers of the employees of the registrant who were providers of strategic lobbying services in support of the registrant’s lobbying activities on behalf of the client during the quarterly period; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB875D9E3C8224D3E9572451E1A95301D"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a list of the names of all other persons who were retained as providers of strategic lobbying services in support of the registrant’s lobbying activities on behalf of the client during the quarterly period, together with—</text><clause id="HBFA95D373A0B403B9AC9A790A4613E9F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the nature of the strategic lobbying services provided, along with a brief summary of work performed;</text></clause><clause id="H5303AB9DEC7E4C23A8DC653E5F654123"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the amount paid to each such person for such services;</text></clause><clause id="HAA1487E6E95C4F16A1B08BACF5D0482B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the name of any individual employed by such person who supervised the provision of such services, and, if the individual served as a covered executive branch official or a covered legislative branch official in the previous 20 years, a statement describing the position in which such individual served; and</text></clause><clause id="H63853CD5E3C745528B031E2EC484FB8E"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the name of any individual employed by such person who provided such services during the quarterly period, and, if the individual served as a covered executive branch official or a covered legislative branch official in the previous 20 years, a statement describing the position in which such individual served.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDEB3FA98D25540B3918243416E701C6E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion in filing, coding, and cross-Indexing systems</header><text>Section 6(a)(3)(A) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605(a)(3)(A)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>and their clients</quote> and inserting <quote>and their clients and providers of strategic lobbying services</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H4C462B5485F54152997B9D8C72BE8610"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>Section 3 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF962A7D9C49C4AABB9A96F8ADEC3F3F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by redesignating paragraphs (15) and (16) as paragraphs (16) and (17); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D3746CF02C74A3B897DAD1FCE09F84F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting after paragraph (14) the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block id="HFDC23FBC581D4F029D3ED315C1DD4AA7" style="OLC"><paragraph id="H8EE0317621EF4C7DB17B5C0433E50C09"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Provider of strategic lobbying services</header><subparagraph id="HEB6FADBDCF2649CE8B1A3853EF130A35"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>provider of strategic lobbying services</term> means any person who, during a quarterly period described in section 5, provided a registrant under section 4 with 12 or more hours of services which are described in subparagraph (C) but which are not otherwise treated as lobbying activities or lobbying contacts.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD14FDB44A4A84E37B7EFC62E41FA84D9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Special rule for former officials</header><text>In the case of a person who served as a covered executive branch official or a covered legislative branch official in the previous 20 years and who, during a quarterly period described in section 5, provided a registrant under section 4 with services described in subparagraph (A) and also carried out lobbying activities on behalf of the registrant, such person shall be treated as a provider of strategic lobbying services if the combined time spent in providing services described in subparagraph (A) and lobbying activities on behalf of the registrant during the period was 12 hours or greater.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H466E565137B946678AF1E8356B1ADA6D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Services described</header><text>The services described in this subparagraph are the following:</text><clause id="H334BFAB3DCAD49F492FA4729A10BB357"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Providing strategic planning for lobbying activities or lobbying campaigns.</text></clause><clause id="H270941E3DFAD430E88884987AA345391"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Providing strategic advice regarding earned media or press coverage related to specific issues upon which a lobbyist employed by the registrant engaged in lobbying activities.</text></clause><clause id="HF24818FF1EE244E3B793CC48AEBBC89D"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Polling services enlisted by a registrant related to specific issues upon which a lobbyist employed by the registrant engaged in lobbying activities.</text></clause><clause id="H132CBC4C1A2B454DB18F6D2E46BC7253"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Providing advice on or producing public communications related to specific issues upon which a lobbyist employed by the registrant engaged in lobbying activities.</text></clause><clause id="HC370B5EF425F40838F8EF7DE26DF7BCB"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Encouraging persons to support or oppose legislative or administrative action or take action with regard to specific issues upon which a lobbyist employed by the registrant engaged in lobbying activities, including the costs of creating formal or informal coalitions of organizations for such purposes.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5D5A119CD7F746F2AC0CA09A35160441"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall apply with respect to statements and reports filed on or after the first day of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress.</text></subsection></section><section id="H18C70BA2491E47B4B0615E1E8DFC2786"><enum>5.</enum><header>Promoting enforcement by attorney general</header><subsection id="HA753C5F6B1DA4C769597A8F64666D5A5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reference of noncompliance to attorney general</header><text>Section 6(a) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605(a)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>the United States Attorney for the District of Columbia</quote> each place it appears in paragraph (8) and paragraph (11) and inserting <quote>the Attorney General</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB0E368B3655344F2A77DFE25E0D276BE"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Inclusion in enforcement reports of identification of individuals subject to imposition of sentence</header><text>Section 6(b)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605(b)(1)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>by case, any sentences imposed, except that such report shall not include the names of individuals, or personally identifiable information, that is not already a matter of public record</quote> and inserting <quote>by case and by the name of the individual and (if applicable) the lobbying firm involved, any sentences imposed</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H26E8A8B06A6F415DB9C689B10D6B1B57"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations To promote enforcement and compliance</header><text>Section 6 of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H3ED933FC016A43BD9A21FA57B3DB077C" style="OLC"><subsection id="H07CEA40154FA42E29A5816E3A77E00E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations To promote enforcement and compliance</header><text>The Attorney General, at any time, may make recommendations to Congress on steps to promote the enforcement of and compliance with this Act, including recommendations regarding the Attorney General’s need for resources to carry out the enforcement of this Act.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HDB0E1545E76D496591268DF8258692B1"><enum>6.</enum><header>Increasing transparency of system for filing, coding, and cross-indexing of reported information</header><subsection id="H0740E9E9D0D84AD785414AF8F2CAF43B"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Clarifying requirement To implement system</header><text>Section 6(a)(3) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605(a)(3)</external-xref>) is amended in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) by striking <quote>develop</quote> and inserting <quote>develop and implement</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H73AF0F36A17D46FF93D347C574344255"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability of information through software applications</header><text>Section 6(a)(3)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1605">2 U.S.C. 1605(a)(3)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking <quote>computerized systems</quote> and inserting <quote>computerized systems, including a system through which individuals may use software or web-based applications to obtain access to a searchable, sortable, and downloadable database of information,</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="H58ADBCC42BBD4934BCAA2F8FDD134A4F"><enum>7.</enum><header>Other reforms in regulation of lobbyists and lobbying activity</header><subsection id="H0DDF64F09D444530912644A5DC054B46"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Revision of threshold for exemption from treatment as lobbyist</header><paragraph id="H433A8A556C134EA496CCCAC5B8BC981E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Revision</header><text>Section 3(10) of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1602">2 U.S.C. 1602(10)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="HF9E419520FB44B37B424825439F6BAD1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>by a client</quote> and inserting <quote>by a client or by a registrant</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEBCCBB44455047EBA2F09951071258EA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>other than an individual</quote> and all that follows and inserting the following: <quote>other than an individual who, over a 3-month period, spends fewer than 12 hours engaged in lobbying activities for such client or such registrant.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H94078227E1A841A1A83DDF0E1B1D2D0E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to lobbying activities occurring on or after the first day of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB51A725650CB41EE8E00351EDE0B1115"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deadline for registration</header><paragraph id="H2823F3DC9C414F6CA71383555EBFB4A2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Revision of deadline</header><text>Section 4(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H859E229B5ABD40B5A37131B36FAFF152"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>45 days</quote> and inserting <quote>30 days</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD10ABBD1D5AB4712BAB3B7B059F0B166"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by striking <quote>45th day</quote> each place it appears and inserting <quote>30th day</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H893961331BC44EF58258B121D649330D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to lobbying contacts occurring on or after the first day of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6493ED385EEE47AAAFE87815F445B235"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Inclusion of specific information in registration statements on issues addressed in lobbying activities</header><paragraph id="H6AAFCEA55B0841FFB1EC0DF08ABC5655"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 4(b)(5)(B) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(b)(5)(B)</external-xref>) is amended by striking the semicolon at the end and inserting the following: <quote>, including any Federal rule, regulation, Executive order, or any other program, policy, or position of the United States Government, as well as any proposed Federal legislation or a description thereof;</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E1993EBB72F4C9B9D671CFE4B620DA2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendment made by paragraph (1) shall apply with respect to statements filed on or after the first day of the One Hundred Eighteenth Congress.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H245307595A054D64811029CEC90E2EA3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Clarification of timing of termination of registration</header><text>Section 4(d) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1603">2 U.S.C. 1603(d)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H6ACE9D4ECDB344F4877A04D908EF0034"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (1), by striking <quote>by a client</quote> and inserting <quote>by a client or by a registrant</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE0B0507A787448659EA063EFE4B471E2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (2), by striking <quote>for such client</quote> and inserting <quote>for such client or lobbying firm</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HAD0E863AB58C4833B6A49323E48D960B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Quadrennial reports on effectiveness of collection, storing, and release of information</header><subsection id="HFC387489DF164BD084584E5F25AB99EF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Inclusion in annual audits by comptroller general</header><paragraph id="H64D2538846B74C4DB713DF77321A549E"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 26 of the Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1614">2 U.S.C. 1614</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H9C472DFB3BE44D7F912F04989B6AA81E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by redesignating subsection (b) as subsection (c); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25F35098B265410681745CC374D45982"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (a) the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block id="H59604D392F8640A5977F904E07B3F767" style="OLC"><subsection id="H232292BE7CF149C4A9783960C27742A8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Quadrennial reports on modernization of reporting and disclosures</header><text>Beginning in 2023 and every 4 years thereafter, the Comptroller General shall include with the audit conducted under subsection (a) an evaluation of the technology and methods employed by the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House to collect, store, review, and electronically publish the information filed with the Secretary and Clerk under this Act, and shall include in such evaluation an analysis of—</text><paragraph id="H73FAC971D28545F7B001B799B95D99D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>whether additional technological means could be employed to reduce the burden on filers and increase the accuracy of filings;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4951AF09F8B5430A9389235882A63C27"><enum>(2)</enum><text>whether automated means are being maximally employed to allow the Secretary and the Clerk to automatically process, normalize, and verify the data they have received; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38ACAD62103B4FCA89CE8A82E8EAC914"><enum>(3)</enum><text>whether the Secretary and the Clerk could undertake other measures to improve how such information is collected, reviewed, and reported to the public.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H09E948266A0144F29C3863EE249EE03A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conforming amendment relating to submission of report to congress</header><text>Section 26(c)(1) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1614">2 U.S.C. 1614(c)(1)</external-xref>), as redesignated by paragraph (1), is amended in the matter preceding subparagraph (A) by striking the period at the end of the first sentence and inserting the following: <quote>, and, if applicable, the quadrennial evaluation conducted under subsection (b).</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF7C5A964C10941F0AC8B9136403E4175"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint review by secretary of senate and clerk of house of representatives</header><text>The Lobbying Disclosure Act of 1995 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/1601">2 U.S.C. 1601 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HD15B72603361418AA726390D837E34B9" style="OLC"><section id="HB6C39CFAA32E43C797B919FF57F56F71"><enum>27.</enum><header>Quadrennial review of information collection and dissemination by Secretary of Senate and Clerk of House of Representatives</header><subsection id="HE0E5EB1E54514D36967447783F923EED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Review</header><text>Not later than April 1, 2023, and every 4 years thereafter, the Secretary of the Senate and the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall jointly conduct and submit to Congress a review of how the Secretary and Clerk collect, store, review, and disseminate information filed with the Secretary and the Clerk under this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFB949E64264E4A318572C16735B57782"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Factors</header><text>In conducting the review under subsection (a), the Secretary and the Clerk—</text><paragraph id="H38DE3FC062244872A8CD16515AA01F3E"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall include an analysis of how the filing and public disclosure of the information filed under this Act can be improved, including a detailed plan with deadlines for improving filing and disclosure mechanisms; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0AEF9AC4D6F643E1A50CE874A8BE424E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>shall consult with members of the public, with an emphasis on those members of the public who regularly seek access to such information.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H27A04DB1B97A45FB80B8587377AD3320"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional or separate views permitted</header><text>The Secretary and the Clerk may each include additional or separate views in the review submitted to Congress under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

