<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA45AD5AD208C41578399C3E8AB4AED34" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8473 IH: Fashioning Accountability and Building Real Institutional Change Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8473</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220721">July 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to prohibit employers from paying employees in the garment industry by piece rate, to require manufacturers and contractors in the garment industry to register with the Department of Labor, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9607EF91609145D38DDA9F410BBF87A2" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HCC4274E02B3A4938966EE7BD9E868595"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Fashioning Accountability and Building Real Institutional Change Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>FABRIC Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H659493064FD043A7918C374BDEF9D940"><enum>2.</enum><header>Payment and liability requirements in the garment industry</header><subsection id="HF38E0B0ECBB64B9B9AB01356A81D87F5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HA74A4406835B4421B42F0D03655286C5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by inserting after section 7 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/207">29 U.S.C. 207</external-xref>) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB45BB1AF839C485581626B94BF88C950"><section id="H9FC297FBD3374D64B34F0F941BE9E48B"><enum>8.</enum><header>Requirements for the garment industry</header><subsection id="H16BE99BE061D4A639279BA31B830E440"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Prohibition against payment by piece rate</header><text>No employer shall pay an employee employed in the garment industry, who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, by the piece or unit, or by piece rate. </text></subsection><subsection id="H14987C55940F455CB9A87FF18224F698"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Hourly rates</header><paragraph id="HB84D29DFDFDD493AB7B96E109F381D37"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An employer shall pay each employee employed in the garment industry, who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, at an hourly rate that is not less than the rate in effect under section 6(a)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAC5C634621284C10915EE0ED64586419"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Incentive bonuses</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to prohibit incentive-based bonuses for employees employed in the garment industry. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6EA92B21623E43979E407D493CDF6A0D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint and several liability of brand guarantors</header><paragraph id="H73E3CE8AA8774AC79EF22B9007CC9A19" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A brand guarantor who contracts with an employer of an employee described in paragraph (2) for the performance of services in the garment industry shall share joint and several liability with such employer for any violations of the employer under this Act involving such employee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H663BE8BE678148B5A2704488D8A58102"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Employees</header><text>An employee described in this paragraph is any employee employed in the garment industry who in any workweek is engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce, or is employed in an enterprise engaged in commerce or in the production of goods for commerce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1E8EDE9C7FE948FC90B05618E53961A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subcontracts</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), an employer of an employee described in paragraph (2) includes any other person who, through 1 or more subcontracts, subcontracts with the employer of such an employee for the performance of services in the garment industry. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H396282D7670A45AD87D8E1868F1B59A3"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to preclude a determination of joint employment, in the garment industry or otherwise, for entities other than brand guarantors.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2B4BA503DFBA4373B5C6B4B2A2DAE931"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Nonapplicability</header><text>Subsections (a) and (b) shall not apply for purposes of an employee employed in the garment industry who is covered by a bona fide collective bargaining agreement that expressly provides for—</text><paragraph id="H3A365290B9BE4A849E58A47FD2F5A82A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>wages, hours of work, and working conditions of the employee;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAE3E75AF23DF472284439FC051BCB933" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><subparagraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H4E390AC9DFD7490FA35F00B5B3D6919E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a wage rate for all hours worked by the employee in excess of 40 hours in a week that is greater than one and one-half times the regular rate at which such employee is employed; and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph indent="up1" id="H2857394156BD488EA3959E9B9A54F6F9" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a minimum hourly rate of pay for the employee that is not less than 10 percent more than the higher of—</text><clause id="HAB74B3663BCF4E6D8168BFF125452265" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the minimum wage rate under an applicable State law; or</text></clause><clause id="H5758C2BBEBAB463EB73837BCDD2366C3" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the minimum wage rate in effect under section 6(a)(1); and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC934C7B4803A41E1B2294406FAA8A164"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a process to resolve disputes concerning nonpayment of wages.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2E57C105379C47238A619F46F824A7BD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC279FCE8CB074A9F9C69213A1EEE2034"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H18AC3750A74345E8840E2709AB91051B"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Brand guarantor</header><text>The term <term>brand guarantor</term> means any person contracting for the performance of garment manufacturing, including through licensing of a brand or name, regardless of whether the party with whom the person contracts performs the manufacturing operations or hires garment contractors to perform the manufacturing operations. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8293D9E5D2C9460F85E6B4D5330EEEE3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Garment</header><text>The term <term>garment</term> includes any article of wearing apparel or accessory designed or intended to be worn by an individual, including clothing, hats, gloves, handbags, hosiery, ties, scarfs, and belts.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE5BC03EE56314996A0FEAFEE658F90AD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Garment contractor</header><text>The term <term>garment contractor</term>—</text><subparagraph id="HBB78F3FD4D304E68B02AD0019795C6C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means any person who, with the assistance of an employee or any other individual, is primarily engaged in garment manufacturing for another person, including for another garment contractor, a garment manufacturer, or a brand guarantor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE8F9DB1DC5314429B05327FE119E8E92"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a subcontractor that is primarily engaged in garment manufacturing. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE98F8CC11B754C21A06A4A56BF0F7CD9"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Garment industry</header><text>The term <term>garment industry</term> means the industry of garment manufacturing.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HABB9068AE09B4FC6B566800F900A6748"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Garment manufacturer</header><text>The term <term>garment manufacturer</term> means any person who is engaged in garment manufacturing who is not a garment contractor.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D931A90D2034B5680BF51D83A00743D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Garment manufacturing</header><subparagraph id="HBDD6F97DA7684A44A78F66553F0230F5"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>garment manufacturing</term> means—</text><clause id="HDE26C32AA20D49918D5F070233330F35"><enum>(i)</enum><text>sewing, cutting, making, processing, repairing, finishing, assembling, pressing, or dyeing a garment, including a section or component of a garment, designed for or intended to be worn by an individual, which is to be sold or offered for sale or resale;</text></clause><clause id="HF0C175C8956A4124BEDE863CD6C2BC04"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>altering the design, or causing another person to alter the design, of a garment described in clause (i):</text></clause><clause id="H1AA88859D8D9405AACB4F642E3FB16C7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>affixing a label to a garment described in clause (i); </text></clause><clause id="H91AECBBFDADD4C6B97230821672C5DED"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>any other form of preparation of a garment described in clause (i) by any person contracting for such preparation; and </text></clause><clause id="H70584C44413D478199AA0D957CA60D60"><enum>(v)</enum><text>any other operation or practice as may be identified in regulations issued by the Secretary consistent with the purposes of this section. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA79B440ED4042A5B68F21CFC707971C" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>garment manufacturing</term> does not include—</text><clause id="H94753A5C204342E39055AFBF756A6D7D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>manufacturing of garments by an individual who manufactures the garments by his or her self without the assistance of a garment contractor, employee, or any other individual;</text></clause><clause id="H4823C538353446A992E8054E8D527099"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>cleaning, altering, or tailoring any garment, including a section or component of a garment, after the garment has been sold at retail; or</text></clause><clause id="HD2003CBFAE7B445CA663CDEA94F7A3C9"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>any other form of manufacturing as may be identified in regulations issued by the Secretary consistent with the purposes of this section. </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>;</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDD3B5BC454542CDBF2E43394CAE7C28"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in section 15 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/215">29 U.S.C. 215(a)</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="HD70D7C14005F4750B142CC2E361BA7B0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (a)—</text><clause id="HDBB3CB6C25494BAC9AA71D4AE3FE6728"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; or</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="HFDF43CA286F346B6940EBEED32ED0C8B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H21BD09165DE146BF824B7A601586F702"><paragraph id="H91FF035910D84B70945B79F5A7616438"><enum>(6)</enum><text>to violate section 8.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD8526FE186594DC097751A5AB73AA367"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC0A9DB27378C404B9628FB25ACE6F791"><subsection id="H3EBE6ED31C044EBDB813DE4442BAAFD4"><enum>(c)</enum><text>For the purposes of subsection (a)(6), it shall be an affirmative defense to an action under such subsection against a brand guarantor (as defined in section 8(f)) if such brand guarantor shows no knowledge of the violation of section 8 alleged in such action.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C2E2387AA9145BE960D1C615541F19D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>in section 16 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/216">29 U.S.C. 216</external-xref>)—</text><subparagraph id="H762EF2C9D8EE48D2A5148725D52BE3BB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><clause id="H688B4530AAF04695A4CB308F270B05AB"><enum>(i)</enum><text>by inserting after the third sentence the following: <quote>Any person who violates section 8 shall be liable for such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of such section, including the payment of wages lost and an additional equal amount as liquidated damages.</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H54D30A4DA8C241DC8E3F0D0509689974"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the last sentence, by inserting before the period at the end <quote>or 8</quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H59FFD79E03D249AAA8089F0CB85C33E7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subsection (c), by adding at the end the following: <quote>The authority and requirements described in this subsection shall apply with respect to a violation of section 8, as appropriate, and the person in such violation shall be liable for such legal or equitable relief as may be appropriate to effectuate the purposes of such section, including the payment of wages lost and an additional equal amount as liquidated damages.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H81CAF1CFD0E64E868C6C1052951F2D14"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text>Section 10 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/210">29 U.S.C. 210</external-xref>) is repealed.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1C0BAEBFA294CACA9B1B6101622E9F1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text>The amendments made by this section shall take effect on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H8DAE4A275C5E4320993FAAF6A8FBA425"><enum>3.</enum><header>Registration of garment manufacturers and contractors</header><subsection id="HD78AFDE01DA8412AB742EB77608D2611"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HC74154FCD42B451E836F7F60DAC34B33" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Employee</header><text>The term <term>employee</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/203">29 U.S.C. 203</external-xref>). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H438B5E3EA6D84D42949232E4FE755F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Garment contractor; garment industry; garment manufacturer; garment manufacturing</header><text>The terms <term>garment contractor</term>, <term>garment industry</term>, <term>garment manufacturer</term>, and <term>garment manufacturing</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8(f) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/208">29 U.S.C. 208(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F57DDF066B6495285C2B59E8DEBF8AB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Production employee</header><text>The term <term>production employee</term>, with respect to a garment manufacturer or garment contractor, means any employee of the manufacturer or contractor who is engaged in the garment industry. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9143C19B37149A6A5DEF27B4ABBF193"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Undersecretary of the Garment Industry appointed under section 4(b). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H50D6ACFA8867447BA7029FA1F4D0474B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirement To register with the Department of Labor</header><text>Beginning on the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act, no garment manufacturer or garment contractor shall engage in the garment industry during any year unless the manufacturer or contractor has registered for such year with the Secretary in accordance with this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="H0FECCFEB21D64F03BE43FA9956CB4E28"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Registration requirements</header><paragraph id="HFBE20921EE55420DB6D3991CACDA0EAC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A garment manufacturer or garment contractor registering under this section shall submit to the Secretary—</text><subparagraph id="H5D7430F800344E53A804B66A46771031"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a form, in writing, containing the information described in paragraph (2); </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E83E26819504EBB84BE511AE8E3B9D7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>photographic verification of the identify of—</text><clause id="H8ADE2FE49087457CAA60C0F26E53E2F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each owner or partner of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor; and</text></clause><clause id="H409694A994F5461D95D3CA2D96A1D9AB"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case the garment manufacturer or garment contractor is a corporation, each officer of the corporation;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9D9E4272635D41039FADBE1BA7739246"><enum>(C)</enum><text>verification that the garment manufacturer or garment contractor has in effect a workers’ compensation insurance policy for all production employees of the manufacturer or contractor; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDC25A1BF1653418BB747CA303E2917D5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>payment of the applicable registration fee described in paragraph (3).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD718105EA33C49989879C0A35C68A94C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Information in form</header><text>The information described in this paragraph is each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HC24AAC04C0CD4D1E84E088F012A7C0CF"><enum>(A)</enum><text>A statement of whether the garment manufacturer or garment contractor is a sole proprietorship, partnership, or corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEE1B7C6B11A24925B74F048C6C1FBC91"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The name, residential address, and phone number of all production employees of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H78A1AC16F3A54EA885EA368FE99E92C8"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The name, residential address, phone number, and social security number of—</text><clause id="HD76ECCE2571347309AD87D7EDA537062"><enum>(i)</enum><text>each owner or partner of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor;</text></clause><clause id="HEBB1EE41099B4ED9BCA3BEE178C5561E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>if applicable, each officer of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor; and</text></clause><clause id="H62C3AD2931394EA4BE424A4CCB2193D6"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>if applicable, each of the 10 largest shareholders of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73CFF79FAB7848F7895774E493418E7F" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The name, residential address, and social security number of each person with a financial interest in the business of the garment manufacturer in the garment industry, and the amount of that interest (if any). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8DAB063E80454BB38FDE35F9246CAD15"><enum>(E)</enum><text>In the case in which the garment manufacturer or garment contractor is a corporation, a statement ensuring that no shares of the corporation are listed on a national securities exchange or regularly quoted in an over-the-counter market by one or more members of a national or an affiliated securities association.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H98E8C7E3995E42AEBECD8E95E0C7BF3C"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A statement of how long the garment manufacturer or garment contractor has been in business in the garment industry.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H37073814727F467484927E9CF2974F0B"><enum>(G)</enum><text>If applicable, the tax identification number of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD544B67ADDAB49A48CAB7B5E339FC8E1"><enum>(H)</enum><text>A statement of the status of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor as a manufacturer or contractor. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0C3E8FC8386426598651E270CBDC04C"><enum>(I)</enum><text>A statement of whether the garment manufacturer or garment contractor has contracted with a labor organization, and, if so, the name and address of such labor organization.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D09F462B01F479A96244F336087F951"><enum>(J)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H6E14B41195DD48C7888843F74E31130D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A statement as to whether, within the preceding 3-year period, any of the following persons or entities have been found by a court or the Secretary to have violated the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/201">29 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>):</text><subclause id="H8E92175DE9684325985FAF23CB16EF57" indent="up1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The garment manufacturer or garment contractor.</text></subclause><subclause id="H49BC73EEE7114A829956A33F69B78F30" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Any owner of or any partner of the garment manufacturer or garment contractor.</text></subclause><subclause id="H740E9D1CE8AF4EB792FF836627C8A6CA" indent="up1"><enum>(III)</enum><text>In the case the garment manufacturer or garment contractor is a corporation, any officer of the corporation or any of the 10 largest shareholders of the corporation.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H4B9FDDCAA7BB4268967EDBBFD27F6584" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>If any person or entity described in any of subclauses (I) through (III) of clause (i) has violated the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 within the period described in such clause, a statement of the nature of such violation and the date on which such violation occurred. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE4D51BFF5D5D48549074DD75F0DB1C99"><enum>(K)</enum><text>In the case of a contractor, a statement of whether the contractor has subcontracted for the cutting, sewing, dying, or assembling of textiles or apparel or sections or components of apparel.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA27F9762A3B3409E8CB004FCD6716875"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Registration fee</header><subparagraph id="HE2C7F7A3554440C99FEF4E558526A226"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The registration fee required under this subsection for each year shall be $200.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H156F1FDB85DD4EC395077B04F8DE3043"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prorated fees</header><text>The Secretary may prorate the registration fee under subparagraph (A) for any registration described in subsection (d)(2)(B)(i).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4BED43EAD105449DAEB15042301C0C79"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Use</header><text>The Secretary shall use the total amount of each registration fee required under this subsection for carrying out this section.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3474BD70377C4211B24AC32CA88CFB96"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Submission</header><paragraph id="H25082ED580A848E29EFC4B8933AE6346"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consolidation</header><text>Each division, subsidiary corporation, or related company of a garment manufacturer or garment contractor may, at the option of the manufacturer or contractor, be named and included under 1 registration under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H326A9C73B04841EFBDF2E7ABE509F441"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing</header><subparagraph id="H83A25DF569464F44A062EFAE37DD7ADC"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided under subparagraph (B), each registration submitted under this section shall be filed not later than the date that is 6 months after the date of enactment of this Act and annually thereafter on a date determined by the Secretary. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB3F0D342CB544504850D810712FEFCDA" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New manufacturers or contractors</header><text>In the case of a garment manufacturer or garment contractor that begins garment manufacturing operations or enters into a contract for such operations for the first time after the date of enactment of this Act, the registration required under this section shall be submitted—</text><clause id="H781F5F49BD6E4ED9A97EC749FF4547DA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not later than 6 months after the date on which the garment manufacturing operations begin or the contractor enters into the contract for such operations; and </text></clause><clause id="H389554A305C8479C9C2F5D4A1E5DF51A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>annually thereafter on a date determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H500135D5D7D5492BA22B5424ED41E00F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Certificates</header><paragraph id="HBC2CF23A2F8B4FB09D02D0854787FAA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary shall issue a certificate of registration to each garment manufacturer or garment contractor that submits a registration meeting the requirements under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBAAB2642210D4459A601C00A15D8D36F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Applicability</header><subparagraph id="H8DF4434E12F749F7A38C5946C0B22A8F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), each certificate issued under paragraph (1) shall be effective for a period of 12 months.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H100B1259924C4D10B53E309DF7CF8424"><enum>(B)</enum><header>New manufacturers or contractors</header><text>A certificate with respect to a registration submitted under subsection (d)(2)(B)(i) shall be effective until the following registration date as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA601D878818E4D5CAA9ABAE53CFE5595"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Posting</header><text>Each garment manufacturer or garment contractor receiving a certificate under paragraph (1) shall post such certificate in a place where it may be read by any employee of the manufacturer or contractor during the workday. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H504E77BD4BC7465CA6C209A5FA88177D" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Suspension or revocation</header><text>The Secretary may suspend or revoke a certificate of registration issued under paragraph (1) if the garment manufacturer or garment contractor that submitted the registration—</text><subparagraph id="HAA98320E2092424A9160CCD91E06A087" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has knowingly made any misrepresentation in the application for such certificate; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C88DCD00784818A489B5F3B95D9C40" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>has failed to comply with this Act or any regulation under this Act.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA0F8706DAE0488281E31D731BDD8562"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Recordkeeping</header><text>The Secretary shall, through regulations, establish requirements for recordkeeping for all garment manufacturers and garment contractors engaging in the garment industry in order to assist in enforcing the requirements of this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H683FEAABA1DD4D4CB1813754F72C718F"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Enforcement</header><paragraph id="H9ABC78F6C4004FB48D838E59C60F3D54"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may impose a civil money penalty of not more than $50,000,000 against any person who violates a requirement under this section. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CDCF2A06A8C4AAE855B2964C7231FFC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Considerations</header><text>In assessing the amount of a penalty under this subsection, the Secretary shall give consideration to—</text><subparagraph id="H4A63F2F9149D4D8EA5B37A49E3AEDA44"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the size of the business of the person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H65712CAEB4E14C97B6691B578EE06692"><enum>(B)</enum><text>whether the violation of the person was committed in good faith;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H884958BE651749B7AB8D0B5C5B5C895B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the gravity of the violation; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H50801B9D32C940D6A636A37BCCE03A69"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the history of any previous violations of the person under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H988C834C956A4E02A62F52D2A5F187E8"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the history of the person in complying with the recordkeeping requirements under subsection (f).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAE4E27C010904B1796AE5247400D36FC"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary may prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H488EED109FE0437D996B283F65295B45"><enum>4.</enum><header>Undersecretary of the Garment Industry</header><subsection id="HD9083ED2EB274389B626C87132D372CD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established in the Department of Labor the Office of the Garment Industry (referred to in this section as the <quote>Office</quote>).</text></subsection><subsection id="HA965BA8F52BC441AA1DD3971A37C75B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Undersecretary</header><paragraph id="H7D69C70A6147404888D8F6BC30E85303"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary of Labor shall appoint an Undersecretary of the Garment Industry (referred to in this section as the <quote>Undersecretary</quote>) to head the Office.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2F7E24337E98456A9E35658CE16AD6EA"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Functions</header><text>The Undersecretary shall—</text><subparagraph id="HBF59D3C0CF82436CA152D3AD0D577814"><enum>(A)</enum><text>carry out section 3 using sums appropriated under subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1BE06C827C43488E92BB4E8BB3A39953"><enum>(B)</enum><text>carry out the national domestic garment manufacturing support program under section 5; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4F584D256DAB490D8200E7690AB4D531"><enum>(C)</enum><text>provide assistance to the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division in enforcing section 8 of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/208">29 U.S.C. 208</external-xref>). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H535B757F89A8435BBE0ADE3FCC833EA9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><paragraph id="H0EE3EA6EE4C8425792CC16A19F4B62B2"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Labor—</text><subparagraph id="HE6C89142AD9245CDA69819686728F20F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>$10,000,000 for fiscal year 2022, to establish the Office and carry out the functions described in subparagraphs (A) and (C) of subsection (b)(2); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA1CD7AD655E14FFAA1FBBAAE9DE0BFDF"><enum>(B)</enum><text>$3,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, to carry out the functions described in subparagraphs (A) and (C) of subsection (b)(2).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H174305ECB4D24B03B78E0430B02A46B9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Availability</header><text>Any sums appropriated under the authorization contained in this subsection shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H77233B6BB689496E81E2360FE7734365"><enum>5.</enum><header>National domestic garment manufacturing support program</header><subsection id="H4A158F1A9039492AAE8F7AD4C1E0477D"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H371E94359DE54E34A5300A373FCC3C02"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means an entity that is—</text><subparagraph id="H3EC0EE5DF1E245C38BCF0F7FF066480A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a garment manufacturer that is incorporated in and performs garment manufacturing within the United States; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31794077DF5D4AE4B519C2BA1BBAA063"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a nonprofit organization that provides workforce development opportunities with respect to the garment industry.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F1F474F6F09459ABCD61FDE6963D035"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Garment industry; garment manufacturer; garment manufacturing</header><text>The terms <term>garment industry</term>, <term>garment manufacturer</term>, and <term>garment manufacturing</term> have the meanings given such terms in section 8(f) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/208">29 U.S.C. 208(f)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE3630E0D8A73474E9BB5145DE5DFDF8E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Labor, acting through the Undersecretary of the Garment Industry appointed under section 4(b). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2089119A639741CC84AFF90756453786"><enum>(b)</enum><header>In general</header><text>From amounts made available under subsection (g), the Secretary shall award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to support garment manufacturing in the United States.</text></subsection><subsection id="H38979E7071E14EA6B5330C1A47375229"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Application</header><text>An eligible entity seeking a grant under this section shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require, including—</text><paragraph id="H4C61350A5F9A4E7AAD11613AD25D068C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a description of the project that the eligible entity proposes to carry out using such grant; and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3B31B8BA66D2432D8B6C962D5D0D6C05"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an implementation plan of such project that reflects the expected participation of, and partnership with, applicable labor organizations and relevant community stakeholders.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDD6C24E0D2FC43B1A1152EF6912AD2D8"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Award</header><paragraph id="H3B0D0AFD68EA41E0A68E8BEE25A8A9B1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>In awarding grants under this section to eligible entities, the Secretary shall give priority to eligible entities—</text><subparagraph id="H42A8D811892446F59AFF380BF9D24B25"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with a workforce that is covered by a collective bargaining agreement;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF6591ED6204D44639E0EFF1AB19598A6" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(B)</enum><text>that are certified by a State in which such eligible entity operates as minority-owned businesses, women-owned businesses, or veteran-owned businesses; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H13D6FD4F09B54D6D865866F110F76635"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who have operated as a garment manufacturer within the United States for more than 5 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no" id="H10D7C1846E5F43E6A29CBA18C044AD4E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Amount</header><text>The amount of a grant awarded under this section may not be more than $5,000,000.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H773C9E0542A141AE84952E83B61DDAA2"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>An eligible entity receiving a grant under this section shall use the grant funds to support—</text><paragraph id="HA33D7DB79CEA4AA6ABB7A1ABA6B54964"><enum>(1)</enum><text>investments in training and workforce development for employees within the garment industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H720721B33191483292940BDBD43AD6D6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the acquisition of relevant tools and equipment for garment manufacturing in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H47317EA430CA4124932175B25F304CAF"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the acquisition of, and capital improvements to, facilities for garment manufacturing in the United States and to promote the health and safety of employees in such facilities; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HACAA2CA524014D4C8B046BF6D293C45B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>efforts to assist in educating employees about rights under this Act and other relevant Federal, State, or local laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H2D7B7AD8FE244A4589C91B2442799CF2"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 6 months after the date on which an eligible entity receives a grant under this section, the eligible entity shall submit to the Secretary a report that includes an account of the use of grant funds awarded under this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3D84AE86B94042F7BF3495014A6DA50B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is authorized to be appropriated $40,000,000 to carry out this section. </text></subsection></section><section id="HE9C719CE7AB04567845C87D723A451C0"><enum>6.</enum><header>Credit for insourcing expenses</header><subsection id="HD8B73D6B5BA74E6F9015941305831843"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/26/1">chapter 1</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 is amended by adding at the end the following new section:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB66D09D4202E48869655139B62E94B56"><section id="H8AC2ECB0578F401E8BB36A4A7BAED1ED"><enum>45U.</enum><header>Credit for insourcing expenses</header><subsection id="H4BDF5AF5E47D4C96A4B38ED662BED688"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of section 38, the insourcing expenses credit for any taxable year is an amount equal to 30 percent of the eligible insourcing expenses of the taxpayer which are taken into account in such taxable year under subsection (d).</text></subsection><subsection id="H2D8D98211713492BA2150A04E9257403"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible insourcing expenses</header><text>For purposes of this section—</text><paragraph id="HB5263C20ECAA4CCCB57DF393C2143982"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible insourcing expenses</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H9BB481CBF241456D920F66E6B9F3FA42"><enum>(A)</enum><text>eligible expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the elimination of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located outside the United States, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0C35E6E2BCD94C2BB6638BFAF2E205F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>eligible expenses paid or incurred by the taxpayer in connection with the establishment of any business unit of the taxpayer (or of any member of any expanded affiliated group in which the taxpayer is also a member) located within—</text><clause id="H313E68CEBC7A4CFD8DF489DE257338BC"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a HUBZone (as defined in section 31(b) of the Small Business Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/657a">15 U.S.C. 657a(b)</external-xref>)), or</text></clause><clause id="H3602EF7FEF2247ED892FC01CDE810FEA"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a low-income community (as described in section 45D(e)),</text></clause><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subparagraph">if such establishment constitutes the relocation of the business unit so eliminated. For purposes of the preceding sentence, a relocation shall not be treated as failing to occur merely because such elimination occurs in a different taxable year than such establishment.</continuation-text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H331AB7DF3A0C4E6D967BC9C57C7FEC2F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible expenses</header><text>The term <term>eligible expenses</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H85C850BD327A455A833B2E80CDD1AA8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any amount for which a deduction is allowed to the taxpayer under section 162, and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75C223D34BDA4D9CACA4BA9743BB6B56"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">permit and license fees, lease brokerage fees, equipment installation costs, and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, other similar expenses.</text></subparagraph><continuation-text continuation-text-level="paragraph">Such term does not include any compensation which is paid or incurred in connection with severance from employment and, to the extent provided by the Secretary, any similar amount.</continuation-text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DC45D55CC5E49B48B8411BA4D178CF0"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Business unit</header><text>The term <term>business unit</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H99999B1F201A42C589F19557F75C1BAD"><enum>(A)</enum><text>any trade or business within the garment industry (as defined in section 8(f) of the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938), and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H165016DBF3BA41ABABC1D95351F58287"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any line of business, or functional unit, which is part of any trade or business described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6748831CEF544A02879BFDD3E291B817"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Expanded affiliated group</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>expanded affiliated group</term> means an affiliated group as defined in section 1504(a), determined without regard to section 1504(b)(3) and by substituting <quote>more than 50 percent</quote> for <quote>at least 80 percent</quote> each place it appears in section 1504(a). A partnership or any other entity (other than a corporation) shall be treated as a member of an expanded affiliated group if such entity is controlled (within the meaning of section 954(d)(3)) by members of such group (including any entity treated as a member of such group by reason of this paragraph).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0BC8651664F4F65BD541E36C2014D38"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Expenses must be pursuant to insourcing plan</header><text>Amounts shall be taken into account under paragraph (1) only to the extent that such amounts are paid or incurred pursuant to a written plan to carry out the relocation described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9E6EC0A850BE49E48A0C8077282CAFEB"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Operating expenses not taken into account</header><text>Any amount paid or incurred in connection with the on-going operation of a business unit shall not be treated as an amount paid or incurred in connection with the establishment or elimination of such business unit.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCC2C253FEBF4403F9DE6D4B42D2D4C9E"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increased domestic employment requirement</header><text>No credit shall be allowed under this section unless the number of full-time equivalent employees of the taxpayer for the taxable year for which the credit is claimed exceeds the number of full-time equivalent employees of the taxpayer for the last taxable year ending before the first taxable year in which such eligible insourcing expenses were paid or incurred. For purposes of this subsection, full-time equivalent employees has the meaning given such term under section 45R(d) (and the applicable rules of section 45R(e)). All employers treated as a single employer under subsection (b), (c), (m), or (o) of section 414 shall be treated as a single employer for purposes of this subsection.</text></subsection><subsection id="H55879D0298954D46BADBFD31A178A049"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Credit allowed upon completion of insourcing plan</header><paragraph id="HE8AD5ADEF4D34574A75678E15A9688F0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in paragraph (2), eligible insourcing expenses shall be taken into account under subsection (a) in the taxable year during which the plan described in subsection (b)(5) has been completed and all eligible insourcing expenses pursuant to such plan have been paid or incurred.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H36CF7FC1A80F415783CE6ABD75AEEB40"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Election to apply employment test and claim credit in first full taxable year after completion of plan</header><text>If the taxpayer elects the application of this paragraph, eligible insourcing expenses shall be taken into account under subsection (a) in the first taxable year after the taxable year described in paragraph (1).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection commented="no" id="H8A0747A49A59491A90AF179BEBC527EF"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Possessions treated as part of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>United States</term> shall be treated as including each possession of the United States (including the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands).</text></subsection><subsection id="H0D5124E315E84C1FA6F563BADD23C2AE"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text>The Secretary shall prescribe such regulations or other guidance as may be necessary or appropriate to carry out the purposes of this section.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H9B90F99E352447DB90262BD3C60D951C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Credit To be part of general business credit</header><text>Subsection (b) of section 38 of such Code is amended by striking <quote>plus</quote> at the end of paragraph (32), by striking the period at the end of paragraph (33) and inserting <quote>, plus</quote>, and by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD8AB1079CF4C4B1EAA256B17936502BD"><paragraph id="HF81E7EF634FF4B9A83C796F12E8357E0"><enum>(34)</enum><text>the insourcing expenses credit determined under section 45U(a).</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H8DA9B0BA00EA46C6856B360514FE83A2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of sections for subpart D of part IV of subchapter A of chapter 1 of such Code is amended by adding at the end the following new item:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA373BEAB63DE416F85D16501874FF79A"><toc container-level="quoted-block-container" idref="HB66D09D4202E48869655139B62E94B56" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded" lowest-level="section" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" regeneration="yes-regeneration"><toc-entry idref="H8AC2ECB0578F401E8BB36A4A7BAED1ED" level="section">Sec. 45U. Credit for insourcing expenses.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H61978A1033C54474B1EF7A24115827AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by this section shall apply to amounts paid or incurred after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF017DBE2228F4712917E89E9BEDAF8F5"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Application to United States possessions</header><paragraph id="HA6E04E4F01D14626B509FEAC563D7F28"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Payments to possessions</header><subparagraph id="H974DDBE8676D4581AC36876237C38B7F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Mirror code possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make periodic payments to each possession of the United States with a mirror code tax system in an amount equal to the loss to that possession by reason of <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/45U">section 45U</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986. Such amount shall be determined by the Secretary of the Treasury based on information provided by the government of the respective possession.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFCD39F000AF24D3397A343F8EDD7B0FE"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other possessions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of the Treasury shall make annual payments to each possession of the United States which does not have a mirror code tax system in an amount estimated by the Secretary of the Treasury as being equal to the aggregate benefits that would have been provided to residents of such possession by reason of section 45U of such Code if a mirror code tax system had been in effect in such possession. The preceding sentence shall not apply with respect to any possession of the United States unless such possession has a plan, which has been approved by the Secretary of the Treasury, under which such possession will promptly distribute such payment to the residents of such possession.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC9FC97B921384AC99A6974E0C9A41491"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Coordination with credit allowed against United States income taxes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No credit shall be allowed against United States income taxes under section 45U of such Code to any person—</text><subparagraph id="H62C58A25FE5942DAA9B482941039E43E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>to whom a credit is allowed against taxes imposed by the possession by reason of such section, or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H84FCF616993A4D5E952CDD5671D06C57"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is eligible for a payment under a plan described in paragraph (1)(B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H38E41ED9728A46809A6D4D6A94DF77A6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Definitions and special rules</header><subparagraph id="HE193C77FA9F643AFA7711E3B33AB69AB"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Possessions of the United States</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this section, the term <term>possession of the United States</term> includes the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico and the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A5E8D00AD1C436A8E9E939BC074235F"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Mirror code tax system</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>mirror code tax system</term> means, with respect to any possession of the United States, the income tax system of such possession if the income tax liability of the residents of such possession under such system is determined by reference to the income tax laws of the United States as if such possession were the United States.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCA27B3B77FC4441863D3CF58F18F86D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Treatment of payments</header><text>For purposes of section 1324(b)(2) of title 31, United States Code, the payments under this section shall be treated in the same manner as a refund due from sections referred to in such section 1324(b)(2). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

