<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H181BAC2B50EE465989B4418CFBDE82D3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9343 IH: Tribal Connect Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9343</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221117">November 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000273">Ms. Leger Fernandez</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Communications Act of 1934 to improve access by Indian Tribes to support from universal service programs of the Federal Communications Commission, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H58E06C3877DA479BA71F7510B6BBC11D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="HA2BB0F5A30034A65B7CFEFB8F761A324"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Tribal Connect Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HC4616A939C884336A9CFB4FB425B137E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Tribal essential community-serving institutions and universal service support</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 254 of the Communications Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/47/254">47 U.S.C. 254</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H9B7E7950D3364FCF91CB51A832913AB6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (h)(4), by inserting <quote>, except as provided in subsection (m)(2)(C),</quote> before <quote>is a library or library consortium</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF5C1B42B84D54389B43FEA3B195849BA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HECBCB40742FA4928BBC0D861CC2EE639"><subsection id="H5006663405B4435086A5509F19F734E2"><enum>(m)</enum><header>Tribal essential community-Serving institutions and universal service support</header><paragraph id="H7B1EC201C70F4468924383A882CE69BB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this subsection—</text><subparagraph id="H5F54D4D9D5C648A681AF1691F8E2C901"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the term <term>broadband internet access service</term> has the meaning given the term in section 8.1(b) of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88C72B7488BF4004A7B49AE15B7EFCCE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the term <term>E-rate program</term> means the universal service support mechanism for schools and libraries authorized under subsection (h)(1)(B), the rules of which are set forth under subpart F of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), as authorized under subsection (h)(2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB49C3CEB9AA47409EC2D933D6F02DB3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the term <term>E-rate support</term> means universal service discounts on eligible services in accordance with subpart F of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), as authorized under subsection (h)(2)(A);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27C683CD838E46C2BBE0888847DBA1D7"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the term <term>essential community-serving institution</term> means a facility exclusively owned by an Indian Tribe, including— </text><clause id="HF4BE01E1161248DE8961ACFD4D9A066C"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a Tribal government building, chapter house, longhouse, community center, senior center, or after-school facility; or </text></clause><clause id="H94E53051820B46EB96E06878196E6BAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other public building similar to a building described in clause (i); </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCFA339CA23B242CA9438D48825A06B76"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the term <term>High-Cost Program</term> means the program under which universal service support is awarded in high-cost areas in accordance with subpart D of part 54 of title 47, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulations), as authorized under subsection (e); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H00D10527F396476894171EBDB8061F33"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the term <term>Indian Tribe</term> has the meaning given the term <quote>Indian tribe</quote> in section 20.100 of title 25, Code of Federal Regulations (or any successor regulation).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5750B3E3A496424EAFFCB9E3F97D9623"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tribal essential community-serving institution pilot program</header><subparagraph id="H2C4EB6D74BA74B59B1D6FD82AD025404"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Tribal Connect Act of 2022</short-title>, the Commission, in consultation with the Institute of Museum and Library Services and any other agency with relevant responsibilities, shall establish, as part of the universal service support programs carried out under this section, either as part of the High-Cost Program or as a standalone universal service pilot program, a pilot program to be known as the <quote>Tribal Essential Community-Serving Institution Program</quote>— </text><clause id="HBA84427AEFEA421DA9CC8647AA68E17B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>under which the Commission shall— </text><subclause id="HE291C9FBF2E54C8B8A959A161EE9BCC1"><enum>(I)</enum><text>provide an opportunity for Indian Tribes to request broadband internet access service at essential community-serving institutions located on Tribal land; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H815D0EC027D94A3CBFC73FF52E833E80"><enum>(II)</enum><text>authorize support for the development of infrastructure to provide the services requested under subclause (I) in a manner similar to the deployment supported under the High-Cost Program; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H77DAF64FDE424EFE98D0B9021753001D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>which shall remain in effect through the end of fiscal year 2025.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E22B0A2403B4D338D1FBD2422CA02FF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>Universal service support obtained under this paragraph shall only be available if the applicable essential community-serving institution intends to deliver publicly available broadband internet access service and telecommunications services to students, teachers, librarians, and members of the community.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAFC247DC7C4B436682D92D29101D4515"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Eligibility for support after the demonstration program</header><text>An essential community-serving institution that receives universal service support under this paragraph shall, after the conclusion of the pilot program described in subparagraph (A), be eligible for universal service support through existing (as of the date on which that pilot program concludes) and future universal service fund programs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9294E577A5194E57A3205CD7C39AA86C"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Use of contributions</header><text>Of amounts collected under subsection (d), not more than $300,000,000 shall be made available to carry out the pilot program described in subparagraph (A).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDE4A36AFD2894FFF98068CCEE785E5DD"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Training and technical assistance for Indian Tribes and essential community-serving institutions</header><subparagraph id="H51BAC01BD8264D2BAA51006158986BE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Technical assistance; annual reports</header><clause id="H3C2C69FE09DF463B83B0474FEF2BEE7A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><subclause id="HC09884D64EA84543AFBCEB61301B490D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>direct the administrator of the universal service support programs under this section to—</text><item id="HA330649E41CF4FE78A291D24D12C944C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>provide technical assistance to ensure that Indian Tribes can participate fully and effectively in the universal service programs, including the E-rate program, including by conducting—</text><subitem id="H61C6CF83F40E43E2BEE47A06E005800D"><enum>(AA)</enum><text>outreach efforts targeted to Tribal schools and libraries, essential community-serving institutions, and Indian Tribes that do not have schools and libraries to promote awareness of the E-rate program and the demonstration programs; and</text></subitem><subitem id="H64EFDE983C0440E392F2DB70A9841EFA"><enum>(BB)</enum><text>specific training programs for Tribal schools and libraries, essential community-serving institutions, and Indian Tribes; and</text></subitem></item><item id="H47D348BD11684F1A88FA01B86C281F23"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>submit to the Commission an annual report regarding the provision of the technical assistance required under item (aa) during the year covered by the report; and</text></item></subclause><subclause id="HB1B8477FD8F849D4A49F0FFDC8939E13"><enum>(II)</enum><text>submit each annual report received under subclause (I)(bb) to—</text><item id="H9EEFB7C9F625412FA61761469F934DF2"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate;</text></item><item id="HE4EE3D434C26463D8B4936CA7C7C5E91"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>the Committee on Indian Affairs of the Senate;</text></item><item id="HE3F3999312C748F783006C946002D2C8"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives; and</text></item><item id="H80901943F21540C69CC7107018D9DB91"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>the Committee on Natural Resources of the House of Representatives.</text></item></subclause></clause><clause id="H7686029313C94D6DA4A8FE9DE22BFC9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 to provide the technical assistance required under clause (i)(I)(aa) for fiscal years 2022 through 2025.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H94004F8477E64221A0480A51D8049404"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Review of annual reports</header><text>The Commission shall— </text><clause id="HE674696E22454CE3A030D47D33A2C014"><enum>(i)</enum><text>review each annual report received under subparagraph (A)(i)(I)(bb) to determine whether additional steps are necessary to ensure that Indian Tribes can participate fully and effectively in the universal service programs, including the E-rate program, so that all students who are members of Indian Tribes can have access to robust, high-speed broadband internet access service connections; and</text></clause><clause id="HDBD0E24EB348416FB1D2F99C0780BBF3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in conducting a review required under clause (i), consider the resources available to Tribal members through the entity responsible for administering the universal service programs established under this section.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDFB956EEF76748F787F9A5DCE76CD5BD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Grants</header><clause id="H012E1026379D4CDA8D73D3247A9A407A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Institute of Museum and Library Services, in coordination with the Commission and the entity responsible for administering the universal service programs established under this section, shall make direct grants to essential community-serving institutions and Indian Tribes for technical assistance initiatives regarding the application process for the E-rate program and the pilot program established under paragraph (2).</text></clause><clause id="H6BEF9CCF355745FBB5D26530188BE7F0"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated $25,000,000 to make the grants described in clause (i).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4F7375637FA4698A3F3DC231D36747D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Coordination and performance measurement</header><text>The Commission shall—</text><subparagraph id="H61E0A457B54B457389D9E5E340DFECC9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>improve the reliability of the data of the Commission relating to institutions that receive universal service support by defining the term <quote>Tribal</quote> on the application for any such support; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2F641373B6AB4BB3AA08B682182B37E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop performance goals and measures to track progress on achieving the strategic objective of the Commission of ensuring that all Indian Tribes have affordable access to broadband internet access service for educational purposes for students, teachers, librarians, and members of the community;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H898DDB0E3FF44AACBE10385326B3C8B0"><enum>(C)</enum><text>in coordination with the Institute of Museum and Library Services, identify, in the United States, all— </text><clause id="HADF64A01B17445A48807A2D51377D797"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Tribal libraries; </text></clause><clause id="H40A15E64A2E34268BAC7DDE89CDC2B6C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>developing Tribal libraries; and </text></clause><clause id="H02988694B2A649879C2341A536926CB7"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Indian Tribes without adequate library services; and </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72D6D0AB1E1248F89D3B32B118F98F02"><enum>(D)</enum><text>not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Tribal Connect Act of 2022</short-title>, submit to Congress and make public a report on the goals and measures developed under subparagraph (B) and the list of libraries and Indian Tribes identified under subparagraph (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3F8E2E82E83047818110877F42EE3B52"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Appointment of Tribal member; expansion of office</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of the <short-title>Tribal Connect Act of 2022</short-title>, the Commission shall require the entity responsible for administering the universal service programs established under this section to—</text><paragraph id="HF0AEFC7C82A14AFDA37DFAC18A7C9C6D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>appoint a member of an Indian Tribe, as defined in subsection (m)(1), to the board of directors of that entity; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C230EE8635F4D469B5994F306098A98"><enum>(2)</enum><text>create or expand the office of that entity dealing with matters affecting Indian Tribes, as defined in subsection (m)(1).</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

