<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HBB113D19FE77481C9A6D394ABA37CC6A" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6843 IH: Building Civic Bridges Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6843</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220225">February 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000381">Mr. Kilmer</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B001282">Mr. Barr</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001208">Mrs. McBath</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000480">Mr. Timmons</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000294">Mr. Jeffries</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000585">Mr. Reed</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000386">Mr. Katko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000624">Mrs. Dingell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="U000031">Mr. Upton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000610">Mr. Deutch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000582">Miss González-Colón</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001202">Mrs. Murphy of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000467">Mr. Thompson of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001298">Mr. Bacon</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the National and Community Service Act of 1990 to establish an Office of Civic Bridgebuilding within the Corporation for National and Community Service, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8035BA3BD2574274B642CDBCAC775A03" style="OLC"><section id="H4E85EA55CB944887B0A2F6E1E0AC0994" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Building Civic Bridges Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFF235A2EF730434888AF228ECA52B682"><enum>2.</enum><header>Civic Bridgebuilding</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subtitle H of title I of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12653">42 U.S.C. 12653 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H396C1BEDD4DD4CBBBB3ACB9DC782EAA3" display-inline="no-display-inline"><part id="H6608BC5C00864D8A8D446F9D2AD31165"><enum>VI</enum><header>Civic Bridgebuilding</header><section id="HE2CD6F5023314EB0BCC053BA80E51B73"><enum>198T.</enum><header>Office of Civic Bridgebuilding</header><subsection id="H7B60CF870DFE4939837CC0F571CBFE24"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment and duties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to the requirements of section 195(b), the Chief Executive Officer of the Corporation may designate an Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding within the Corporation to administer an Office of Civic Bridgebuilding (in this section referred to as the <quote>Office</quote>) to carry out the following:</text><paragraph id="H923BB7925BDE4DFC9FE5BA71ABC2265A"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Administer the grant program described in subsection (c) to support civic bridgebuilding across the Nation, including establishing standardized criteria to track the effectiveness of projects and activities funded under such program, which shall be based on principles of scientific research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0A2370713654D0FB54CA4D1F56D89F3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Support the Corporation in providing training in civic bridgebuilding skills and techniques (with the consideration and input of best practices collected by the Office)—</text><subparagraph id="HA480DD7343AC440CB5E9699197C0FA72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for participants (including individuals who have been selected to be participants) of a program receiving assistance under a national service law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBAC86B6648354E6FA634724EEA6EE7BE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>upon request, for an organization that receives assistance under a national service law or that is carrying out a program in which participants described in subparagraph (A) are participating.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C98B09ACCFC46E8A2EFAECF79DAC349"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Select the members of the Advisory Committee under subsection (b).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67073537F6A54439BBB3FF183EBBB61B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Support research and evaluations on civic bridgebuilding and the dissemination of that information, including through—</text><subparagraph id="HDCBEE8E8905744239FBBD4907C00D7A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>evaluation and oversight of the grant program described in subsection (c);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD7E6BCD6EBDC4C2DAD1EFF8788F449EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">collaboration (including through the evaluation of the activities of the Corporation relating to civic bridgebuilding and civic engagement) between the Office and other offices (such as the Office of Research and Evaluation), teams, or individuals within the Corporation as the Corporation determines necessary; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC10D2E12316A4053A79233A28F653FD3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the creation of a public research base that monitors national metrics for civic bridgebuilding and convenes research focused on evaluating the extent to which civic bridgebuilding and civic engagement activities strengthen or weaken such bridgebuilding and engagement in the United States.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FB0457234FC4B76BC2247CA2D4DECE1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Activate a public conversation about the importance of civic bridgebuilding by convening and coordinating civic bridgebuilding programs, providing resources, networking, and collaboration opportunities to the field, which may include—</text><subparagraph id="H1872395DE40C4ED7A77765C1F7BF8376"><enum>(A)</enum><text>network cultivation to strengthen the community of those involved, interested, or engaged in the civic bridgebuilding field, including through activities such as—</text><clause id="HA57B7612FB3D49218217BEF463221D2D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in-person and virtual events for the public to showcase impactful practices, bring civic bridgebuilding leaders together, present relevant research, and explore emerging civic bridgebuilding needs;</text></clause><clause id="HFF8C640FCB8541C3B218A07B7983A539"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>organizing peer-learning opportunities to facilitate conversations within the field of civic bridgebuilding; </text></clause><clause id="H81A1F5D0C8CA49EBB2D9D9F7DCF9DE5B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>organizing and distributing lists of civic bridgebuilding leaders, organizations, and groups in the civic bridgebuilding field; and</text></clause><clause id="H6F11B64056B04D92BEAA48F7F3B0C26D"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>coordinating national communications among civic bridgebuilding leaders, including through the promotion of civic bridgebuilding programs and sharing stories of local impact; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA48D0F82D8C04D3EBD2A6A1A45FDBCE7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>developing or distributing resources to expand best practices in the civic bridgebuilding field, including through—</text><clause id="HABEB84733848458F8805C7339351AC89"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the curation of a digital resource hub focused on sharing resources from entities that receive grants under subsection (c), other civic bridgebuilding leaders and programs, or the research base; and</text></clause><clause id="H33C0A272A4EA4FA8B454A143700CC9B8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the production of new resources, trainings, or best practices based on learnings from the civic bridgebuilding field.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H35FAC7EB4B3A4A0ABC9454E3C14F58D2" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Advisory Committee</header><paragraph id="H4FF57A4362424B7289528D99BF683691"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There is established within the Office of Civic Bridgebuilding an Advisory Committee (in this subsection referred to as the <quote>Committee</quote>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4842AC828F314A97948AC44E4672969E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Members</header><subparagraph id="HA721497F030F4C309682965264DDDBE1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Selection</header><text>The Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding shall select 9 members of an Advisory Committee, including a Chairperson of the Committee, and ensure that such Committee is comprised of civic bridgebuilding leaders who represent diverse ideological, religious, racial, regional, or ethnic communities, and with relevant experience and expertise from the civic bridgebuilding field.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H88A5825BBA7C4703BD462940255B9AB4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Terms of service</header><text>A member of the Committee shall serve for a term of 3 years.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H85F7B8CB6AB1413DB74D012CC156B499"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall carry out the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB803887EB3C0477F9106B11B10E3FE5A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Provide advice and consultation to the Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding on the priorities and administration of such Office.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B87B94CB1144768B8582E5B62CACC85"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Conduct an annual review of grants awarded under subsection (c), with a focus to diversity, equity, and inclusion, and identifying any gaps or needs that emerged from previous application cycles.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H214CB087CDAD43189337A621CB629BA6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Conduct an annual review of the process of awarding grants under subsection (c), including rubrics or metrics for grant selection used by the Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D3F97B43A444F728418118130FD116E" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Review the analysis provided under the peer review process under subsection (c)(5). </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2AE25722600404BAB443CC7BCFA4DB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding pilot grant program</header><paragraph id="H8106BBDA82484ED1AF6DDB2B7B54ED89"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">From the amounts appropriated to carry out this subsection, the Corporation (acting through the Officer of Civic Bridgebuilding and in consultation with the Advisory Committee established under subsection (b)) shall carry out a pilot program for a 3-year period (with the possibility of renewal for additional 3-year periods) to award grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities to support civic bridgebuilding programs across the Nation.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0DCFC04AAA6431CA76E3EEF74963882"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grant period</header><text>A grant awarded under this subsection shall be for a 1-year period. There shall be 3 grant cycles under the 3-year pilot program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4066A1CF7BC4EA691E5D8D611C3A411"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible to receive a grant under this subsection, an eligible entity shall submit an application to the Corporation at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Corporation may require, including—</text><subparagraph id="HE6AB0154FAA84C6AAA574A8D2BB0F5B8"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of the project that will be funded with the grant;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDEA6E5FE43F94EF6BCC0F9136768BDB7"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that such project will—</text><clause id="H7F4ABC660E4242E88D4BCE6CC9F7836B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>provide evidence of engaging diverse communities;</text></clause><clause id="H61415F6665DC44A39D919C4E56270E19"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilitate the creation or endurance of civic bridgebuilding or address the root causes of polarization as articulated in the research base;</text></clause><clause id="HD74B74C7BDA44144A0D26A062FC34B6E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">cite research supporting the efficacy and impact of the proposed approach for the project; and</text></clause><clause id="HEBEB87B64923443DA146539FFA5384D2"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure physical, social, and psychological safety for all participants involved in the project and provide a description of evidence-based best practices for how this goal will be achieved; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CA23A8A2CD34B91944A2834AFA3DB9B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an assurance that the eligible entity will report outcomes of such project to track effectiveness based on standardized criteria established by the Office of Civic Bridgebuilding under subsection (a)(1) or will evaluate the impact of such project based on principles of scientific research. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F84847AAD3C4D859B75D8AFEEFFA75B"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Uses of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity receiving a grant under this subsection shall use such grant to carry out a project to advance civic bridgebuilding in communities across the Nation or address the root causes of polarization as articulated in the research base.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H527057DD4D9745F6A3244F8B5399BA66" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Peer review process</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Corporation shall establish a peer review process which shall include consultation with research communities in the civic bridgebuilding field to analyze the process of awarding grants (and the grants that are awarded) under this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB7F185A0932D45DD83F2CC2EA51ACC68" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Comptroller General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Comptroller General of the United States shall, on an annual basis, submit to Congress a report, which summarizes and assesses the effectiveness and impact of the activities carried out under grants awarded under subsection (c).</text></subsection><subsection id="H760C791EDB044A7580BF84EA6CDA495E"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text><paragraph id="H04C3AE00B5C94127A098B28CCCDAE268"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding</header><text>The term <term>civic bridgebuilding</term>—</text><subparagraph id="H48E86A5A6D004770BD3C3DB79872A4CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>means activities that foster respect between diverse communities, strengthen relationships across lines of difference, and forge a sense of common civic purpose, and which seeks to solve community problems and diminish polarization; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF56B7BBBA214C01B22D7A05C6F2A645"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes—</text><clause id="H1ECDF3D0E04E4834A8D5FE3CE17B5607"><enum>(i)</enum><text>activities that take place in local communities, where individuals and institutions come together to build empathy, strengthen belonging, and address local issues; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B26EA68F1654B0CB9BC7E5061A3F36D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>activities at the field level, where civic bridgebuilding leaders work together to share research and best practices, learn from one another, and grow civic bridgebuilding efforts.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H12F8BE8CFAF347EC9C04ED7BC5634546"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding leader</header><text>The term <term>civic bridgebuilding leader</term> means an individual who leads civic bridgebuilding programs or efforts. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H468816773741409A91B02E150AD481DE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Civic bridgebuilding program</header><text>The term <term>civic bridgebuilding program</term> means a program, project, or activity which embodies or works to achieves the goals of civic bridgebuilding. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE7A26DF9594C66BA48C63BEB135797"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Civic engagement</header><text>The term <term>civic engagement</term> means an individual or collective action designed to address a public concern or an unmet human, educational, health care, environmental, or public safety need.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC6CBB041F934C4096363AC41604A246"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <term>eligible entity</term> means a nonprofit entity, public institution, elementary school, secondary school, institution of higher education, religious group, or consortium of any such entities. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3EA65187285C4EE38CA35DA268F957C4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Public institution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public institution</term> means a library, unit of local government, or other entity expending public funds or performing public functions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE4255626798741C298C777A3877F382E"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Research</header><text>The term <term>research</term> means research which embodies principles of scientific research.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6897479C33A4A27911D73AE9416D420"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Research base</header><text>The term <term>research base</term> means any publications that contain observations, analysis, and conclusions based on principles of scientific research with respect to the challenges of political and social polarization in the United States, and practical approaches to strengthen social cohesion, foster a sense of national connection, or improve intergroup relations in divided communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE8EA649AB49B4E29AE58DF7B4EB007C0"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $25,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025.</text></subsection></section></part><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H395E5107BBA54CCDB863AB36CD171ACF"><enum>3.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the National and Community Service Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12501">42 U.S.C. 12501</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting at the end of the item relating to subtitle H of title I, the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD752C0D8E9D0466E968E869320F0EF88" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="part">Part VI—Civic Bridgebuilding </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 198T. Office of Civic Bridgebuilding.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

