<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H17980949360240AB8ED6E0880582B824" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6393 IH: Responsible Budgeting Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6393</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220113">January 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="A000375">Mr. Arrington</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001312">Ms. Bourdeaux</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Committee on Rules</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Ways and Means</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HBU00">the Budget</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31 of the United States Code and title IV of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to automatically suspend the debt limit for the fiscal year of a budget resolution.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD5C19F5A0DE44DD1A26AFCC780FFA11D" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H34EA2DBB195E471DBE844E3F929EAE23"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Responsible Budgeting Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="H5FC7924511904D38B12C74D3B1AF81AD"><enum>2.</enum><header>Presidential request to suspend the debt limit</header><subsection id="H08901938C3BF425F86B9BDAB2AC0F05C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking section 3101A and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H0E14BFD3F78E4A188E888BC73FDA8BF4"><section id="HB3B226C3126E4A0BA8FD1AC1751523FD"><enum>3101A.</enum><header>Modification of statutory limit on the public debt</header><subsection id="H3A3E201B2107415881D15A2CCDC0A094"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon adoption by Congress of a concurrent resolution on the budget under section 301 or 304 of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/632">2 U.S.C. 632</external-xref>, 634) that satisfies the required ratio, as determined by the Congressional Budget Office, the Clerk of the House of Representatives shall prepare an engrossment of a joint resolution in the form prescribed in subsection (b) suspending the statutory limit on the public debt until the last day of the fiscal year of that concurrent resolution. Upon engrossment of the joint resolution, the vote by which the concurrent resolution on the budget was adopted by the House of Representatives shall also be considered as a vote on passage of the joint resolution in the House of Representatives, and the joint resolution shall be considered as passed by the House of Representatives and duly certified and examined. The engrossed copy shall be signed by the Clerk of the House of Representatives and transmitted to the Senate. Upon receipt of the House of Representatives joint resolution in the Senate, the vote by which the concurrent resolution on the budget was adopted in the Senate shall also be considered as a vote on passage of the joint resolution in the Senate, and the joint resolution shall be considered as passed by the Senate, duly certified and examined, and transmitted to the House of Representatives for enrollment. </text></subsection><subsection id="H2179A71F5FF544F19EFAD6249F3ABF3D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Form of joint resolution</header><text>The form of the joint resolution described in this subsection is a joint resolution—</text><paragraph id="H6D2B74506A234897854200BC820CCC4D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>which does not have a preamble; </text></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H78909583A7634828BD299996BEA5F4E4"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the title of which is only as follows: <quote>Joint resolution suspending the debt limit, as prepared under section 3101A of title 31, United States Code, on ______</quote> (with the blank containing the date on which the joint resolution is prepared); and </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H594B82C310DB491EB3054D3C0AC0CD7D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause which is only as follows: <quote>Section 3101(b) of title 31, United States Code, shall not apply for the period beginning on the date of enactment and ending on September 30, ____.</quote> (with the blank being filled with the fiscal year of the concurrent resolution on the budget).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEBB7DD5881244B9EA8EFC4AD3A49DB1F"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increase of debt limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date on which the authority of a joint resolution described in subsection (b) terminates, the limitation in effect under section 3101(b) shall be increased to the extent that—</text><paragraph id="H7A2CA82078F943F68C6D562536383E52"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the face amount of obligations issued under this chapter and the face amount of obligations whose principal and interest are guaranteed by the United States Government (except guaranteed obligations held by the Secretary of the Treasury) outstanding on such date, exceeds</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H64A9A40C99B143A08B42B7F683EB6F56"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the face amount of such obligations outstanding on the date the debt limit was last in effect.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5481607C1EE24167BDC90F0344B95F57"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Restoring Congressional Authority Over the National Debt</header><paragraph id="H108E391A62AB43A28DF838284199184C"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Extension limited to necessary obligations</header><text>An obligation shall not be taken into account under subsection (c)(1) unless the issuance of such obligation was necessary to fund a commitment incurred pursuant to law by the Federal Government that required payment before the date on which the authorization of the joint resolution described in subsection (b) terminates. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDDEEC617B8D74403B883CF02768CDF7C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on creation of cash reserve during extension period</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall not issue obligations during the period specified in the matter after the resolving clause of a joint resolution, as described in subsection (b)(3), for the purpose of increasing the cash balance above normal operating balances in anticipation of the expiration of such period.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6D2E95D809AC48CA92E4B240D11E9C8C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed as limiting or otherwise affecting—</text><paragraph id="H326FA0E383C84811BBD414A0B68217FF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the power of the House of Representatives or the Senate to consider and pass bills or joint resolutions, without regard to the procedures under subsection (a), that would change the statutory limit on the public debt; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H569AFAEBF1454C69AB5EBCB07DF522E9"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the rights of Members, Delegates, the Resident Commissioner, or committees with respect to the introduction, consideration, and reporting of such bills or joint resolutions.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H82F74D6BBC9A454BAA2F4DF978C27A75"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section and section 3101B—</text><paragraph id="HFF875DFCC3724883911675BA0228EB1B"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the term <term>required ratio</term> means the ratio that reduces by not less than 5 percentage points the projected ratio under current law of debt held by the public to Gross Domestic Product in the tenth fiscal year after the current fiscal year; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0A581BDD555C45CF934E7B5554FEFC9C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the term <term>statutory limit on the public debt</term> means the maximum face amount of obligations issued under authority of this chapter and obligations guaranteed as to principal and interest by the United States (except such guaranteed obligations as may be held by the Secretary of the Treasury), as determined under section 3101(b) after the application of section 3101(a), that may be outstanding at any one time.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H33C7E6BDCC2940719035E5A148D52597"><enum>3101B.</enum><header>Presidential modification of the debt ceiling</header><subsection id="HF49E166D226C40D99E15690E2FC3EFFB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="HA4E72586CA954C9DBAED2DCF4E0ECB1A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If, for a fiscal year, Congress does not adopt a concurrent resolution on the budget that satisfies the required ratio by the covered date, the President may submit a written notification to Congress, including a debt reduction proposal with legislative language that satisfies the required ratio, that the President is suspending the statutory limit on the public debt subject to limit in section 3101(b) and that further borrowing is required to meet existing commitments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DDCCC8B96F14B3C9935F46442085573"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of notification</header><subparagraph id="H76BA1B558C974A57BA73FD67191447AE"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Subject to subparagraph (C), upon the submission of a written notification by the President under paragraph (1), including a debt reduction proposal comprised of legislative text that the Director of the Office of Management and Budget has determined satisfies the required ratio, the statutory limit on the public debt shall be suspended until the end of the fiscal year beginning in the calendar year in which the President submits a request.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H405F5B6A470149AC8E2A9718E8CF25D4"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (C), a suspension of the statutory limit on the public debt under subparagraph (A) shall take effect on the date that is 30 calendar days after the date on which the written notification is submitted by the President under paragraph (1). </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H79A14C6646EA492CB9CDC5428509FB86"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Limitation on authority</header><text>The statutory limit on the public debt shall not be suspended under this paragraph if, during the 30-calendar-day period beginning on the date on which Congress receives a notification under this paragraph, Congress enacts into law a joint resolution of disapproval in accordance with subsection (b). </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H30507A15EC9B4DA6A6877C41EA514208"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered date defined</header><text>For purposes of paragraph (1), the term <term>covered date</term> means the earlier of—</text><subparagraph id="H94C8D8B711E7486295217AF2143E03F1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>April 15 of the calendar year in which the fiscal year of the applicable concurrent resolution on the budget begins; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H86962BC8D09B49C6AEA030D664361494"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">60 days before the date on which the statutory limit on the public debt will be reached, as described in the congressional notification submitted by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HD2126AA2CD9340FC800BA7F575778F24"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Increase of debt limit</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Effective on the date the debt limit extension pursuant to the written notification under paragraph (1) terminates, the limitation in effect under section 3101(b) shall be increased to the extent that—</text><subparagraph commented="no" id="HDBA1C7A776AE4D048BD43719E7094810"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the face amount of obligations issued under this chapter and the face amount of obligations whose principal and interest are guaranteed by the United States Government (except guaranteed obligations held by the Secretary of the Treasury) outstanding on such date, exceeds</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="HD6444622DD2E4C85B2504DF04EE7A336"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the face amount of such obligations outstanding on the date the debt limit was last in effect.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="H3C33A736DA06482ABA1C9068AC17AC3A"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Restoring Congressional Authority Over the National Debt</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="H297A887C2CB5485CB2F2ED00B41B0B96"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Extension limited to necessary obligations</header><text>An obligation shall not be taken into account under paragraph (4)(A) unless the issuance of such obligation was necessary to fund a commitment incurred pursuant to law by the Federal Government that required payment before the date on which the debt limit extension pursuant to the written notification under paragraph (1) terminates. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H56F87E078D634F50A822A7AD1F9CBEF3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Prohibition on creation of cash reserve during extension period</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall not issue obligations during the period beginning on the effective date described in paragraph (2)(B) and ending on the last day of the fiscal year described in paragraph (2)(A) for the purpose of increasing the cash balance above normal operating balances in anticipation of the expiration of such period.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H233CAC21C49440948D9D144A6FFB5D27"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF4D553C0EA164D229DCFD384AE629D45"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If a joint resolution of disapproval has not been enacted by the end of the 30-calendar-day period beginning on the date on which the presidential notification to which the joint resolution relates was received by Congress under subsection (a), the statutory limit on public debt shall be suspended as specified in the presidential notification.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H11AC492377DD4470ADD26F81FA7D2EC4"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Contents of joint resolution</header><text>For the purpose of this section, the term <term>joint resolution</term> means only a joint resolution—</text><subparagraph id="H5C2A3A6577B84BDAAD7012D168F12651"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that is introduced between the date the written notification is received and 3 calendar days after that date (or if the House of Representatives or Senate is not in session, the next calendar date in which it is in session);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H526162703E8745D1A47027C4A815E36E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>which does not have a preamble;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HECF9BB971B50445CBC550914644AF49B"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the title of which is only as follows: <quote>Joint resolution relating to the disapproval of the President’s exercise of authority to suspend the debt limit, as submitted under section 3101B(a) of title 31, United States Code, on ______</quote> (with the blank containing the date of such submission); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H64B9CF7EC2D94713886E36AC6CFC08A5"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is only as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves of the President’s exercise of authority to suspend the debt limit, as exercised pursuant to the written notification under section 3101B(a) of title 31, United States Code.</quote>.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFE6C0DA9835947569DB31177A0536110"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Expedited consideration in the House of Representatives</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H6B442FF396C146AB9CC6E3D02C7AD7EB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reconvening</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon receipt of a written notification described in subsection (a)(1), the Speaker of the House of Representatives, if the House of Representatives would otherwise be adjourned, shall notify the Members of the House of Representatives that, pursuant to this section, the House of Representatives shall convene not later than the second calendar day after receipt of such written notification. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5527248D1EA44730A4FB0F537BCD5212"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>A joint resolution introduced under paragraph (1) shall be referred to the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives and such committee shall report the joint resolution to the House of Representatives without amendment not later than 5 calendar days after the date on which the joint resolution is introduced. If the Committee on Ways and Means fails to report the joint resolution within the 5-day period, the Committee on Ways and Means shall be discharged from further consideration of the joint resolution and it shall be referred to the appropriate calendar.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C5CD7C7189442CCA475A134F1EEF30B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Upon report or discharge from the Committee on Ways and Means of the House of Representatives, and not later than 6 days after the date on which the joint resolution is introduced under paragraph (1), it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House of Representatives. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House of Representatives has disposed of a motion to proceed on a joint resolution addressing a particular submission. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H426A712A46764145B57CF0B02E8966E4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to its passage without intervening motion except two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE19584C3B3494827BE1F6644DDFCD5A5"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Expedited procedure in Senate</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HB3691040CFBD43EF908DA09ACD005C04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reconvening</header><text>Upon receipt of a written notification under subsection (a)(1), if the Senate has adjourned or recessed for more than 2 days, the majority leader of the Senate, after consultation with the minority leader of the Senate, shall notify the Members of the Senate that, pursuant to this section, the Senate shall convene not later than the second calendar day after receipt of such message.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H034FBAF123134D34851F3B31D7472B3C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Placement on calendar</header><text>Upon introduction in the Senate, the joint resolution shall be immediately placed on the calendar.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0549CCB437694CCAA4A75C8DE3463FCE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Floor consideration</header><subparagraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF46E6EFB8BF44978AD84639267D511C8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time during the period beginning on the day after the date on which Congress receives a written notification under subsection (a) and ending on the sixth day after the date on which Congress receives a written notification under subsection (a) (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) are waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the resolution is agreed to, the joint resolution shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H95AEB8357FC84874B7F5DBC416F50ADB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>Consideration of the joint resolution, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees. A motion further to limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution is not in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D5377CDABC4453E87EBD42ED0F8F0CC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>If the Senate has voted to proceed to a joint resolution, the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall occur immediately following the conclusion of consideration of the joint resolution, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2705FE5BBF3F4E9FA59E81A85F5FAAD4"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rulings of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to a joint resolution shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H052DA4C19AB74E7D954C58FEF25EEBF9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Amendment not in order</header><text>A joint resolution of disapproval considered pursuant to this section shall not be subject to amendment in either the House of Representatives or the Senate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C63C98F825A4848B2405137EA0EEC9E"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Coordination with action by other house</header><paragraph display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HF8E7CB22E2954860B085C437DB01BA8A"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If, before passing the joint resolution, one House receives from the other a joint resolution—</text><subparagraph id="H7A5269D535F0420DAB89CCDA3BBCF35E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the joint resolution of the other House shall not be referred to a committee; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H22B341B5934B451D98A355955055D5F0"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the procedure in the receiving house shall be the same as if no joint resolution had been received from the other house until the vote on passage, when the joint resolution received from the other house shall supplant the joint resolution of the receiving House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EBE277E0C5248948C390E114FB9E4AB"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Treatment of joint resolution of other House</header><text>If the Senate fails to introduce or consider a joint resolution under this section, the joint resolution of the House shall be entitled to expedited floor procedures under this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2645C713D4D942818C707ED935D5DCA9"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Treatment of companion measures</header><text>If, following passage of the joint resolution in the Senate, the Senate then receives the companion measure from the House of Representatives, the companion measure shall not be debatable.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF2F94064BEE54BF6B497936AEC01EEEC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Consideration after passage</header><subparagraph id="H80695EFD261B4323B2938A4EFFC43CE8"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>If Congress passes a joint resolution, the period beginning on the date the President is presented with the joint resolution and ending on the date the President signs, allows to become law without the signature of the President, or vetoes and returns the joint resolution (but excluding days when either House is not in session) shall be disregarded in computing the appropriate calendar day period described in subsection (b)(1).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE49DE800928443708607FCEF9AB8E733"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Debate on veto message</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Debate on a veto message in the Senate under this section shall be 1 hour equally divided between the majority and minority leaders or their designees.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4A605F0AE5364925B324C42EB2F87ADD"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Veto override</header><text>If, within the 30-calendar-day period described in subsection (b)(1), Congress overrides a veto of a joint resolution, the limitation in effect under section 3101(b) shall not be suspended. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HDA27288B5E5A4DB39053740E3A151DB1"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Rules of House of Representatives and Senate</header><text>This section and section 3101A are enacted by Congress—</text><paragraph id="HFEDBD9FE3C7F422681A81B9888B59CFA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and House of Representatives, respectively, and as such it is deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of a joint resolution, and it supersedes other rules only to the extent that it is inconsistent with such rules; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H151BAAFC74B042E1AEDA675A56D148ED"><enum>(2)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HB2E486AF443E441E9F6E780219E88EEF"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of sections of subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/31">chapter 31</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking the item relating to section 3101A and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA814C25C02A14475B74DFB4396442D37"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">3101A. Modification of statutory limit on the public debt. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section">3101B. Presidential modification of the debt ceiling.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HFBAD73417B8442589A6B5C95EA0459CA"><enum>3.</enum><header>Consideration of the debt reduction proposal submitted by the President</header><subsection id="H85C2838F59A7499996EF0018944D1207"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Part A of title IV of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/651">2 U.S.C. 651 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by inserting after section 406 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H229365125C8F4652BAD2D65C6071AE32"><section id="HED33C7907F4C42CE9CCE955B4D85A746"><enum>407.</enum><header>Consideration of the debt reduction proposal submitted by the President</header><subsection id="HFEE551E8712344569B222BED5D545F73"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any debt reduction proposal submitted by the President under section 3101B(a)(2)(A) of title 31, United States Code, is required to satisfy the required ratio as determined by the Office of Management and Budget.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEB2F1610AAB647FDBA2294D654945712"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consideration of the President’s proposal in the House of Representatives</header><paragraph id="HB286D7BD56E5471084EC9B80729525FD"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>Any debt reduction proposal submitted by the President under section 3101B of title 31, United States Code, shall be introduced by the majority or minority leader of the House of Representatives or their designees. Upon introduction, the Chair of the Committee on the Budget shall within 3 days submit the proposal to the Congressional Budget Office to be scored.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9F2492A832464425B6A1C37E03A7C811"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>Any proposal introduced under paragraph (1) shall be referred to the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7663D98034A6484CA013391EE4483221"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requests by budget committee</header><text>Not later than 3 days after the date on which a proposal is referred under paragraph (2), the Chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives shall submit to each appropriate committee of the House a request that, during the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the request is made, the appropriate committee submit to the Committee on the Budget of the House—</text><subparagraph id="H05DB8D96A2B84515B62109AE5CB34C03"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a general assessment of the proposal introduced under paragraph (1); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE229ED6A410B46D3AF94C11AAF9A9D7D"><enum>(B)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="HF01D32B680994AD8B4B80E0EEFF09C09"><enum>(i)</enum><text>any recommendations related to the proposal; or</text></clause><clause id="H19C3DADD6B5740D4BA3E61FF2F4EC117" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any alternative recommendation to reduce the deficit within the jurisdiction of the committee.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HF9BABEA9C872482EAA22BD7C0B0CFACC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reported legislation by budget committee</header><subparagraph id="H0370277ECDB54F78ADECF30E9B17B9C1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives shall report a bill that meets the required ratio not later than 60 days after the date on which the President submits a debt reduction proposal under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2977E0ADC11F4E06AAB569DEE8646BCA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of legislation</header><text>The bill reported under subparagraph (A) may include—</text><clause id="HCCA372094D2E4211AE28A83AC0C34E7B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the debt reduction proposal submitted by the President under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="H8F93A5CF59114D898840EB70B1B0CC8C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any recommendations submitted to the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives under paragraph (3), including any modifications to such proposals by the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF7D77C75A2D8433BAB16CFBC6D36A757"><enum>(C)</enum><header>CBO score</header><clause id="HDE732AF3BD7C4CEB9BF3464F9EFD46CF"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No bill may be reported under subparagraph (A) unless the Chair of the Committee on the Budget—</text><subclause id="H1FC1813359CC4FAB9A9EC9AF58C46B76"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submits to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office such bill for a cost estimate to be prepared under section 402; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HEFEB59702A4A42E3BB327C14A5A440C3"><enum>(II)</enum><text>receives from the Director a cost estimate described in subclause (I) that includes a statement that such bill meets the required ratio.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H6AEE72139F184EFFB75C4E37975C4F24"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Time period</header><text>The 60-day period described in subparagraph (A) shall not include the period beginning on the date on which the Chair of the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives submits to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office the bill under clause (i)(I) and ending on the date on which the Chair receives the cost estimate under clause (i)(II). </text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph commented="no" id="HC7196DA9B89B4EF28325A507F4C3461C"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Discharge</header><subparagraph commented="no" id="HB3A0618FEDB74D31BAAFF840F4249AB0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Committee on the Budget of the House of Representatives fails to report a bill within 60 days after the referral of the proposal submitted under section 3101B of title 31, United States Code, and such proposal has been determined by the Director to satisfy the required ratio, then the committee shall be discharged from further consideration of the bill that embodies the debt reduction proposal of the President and it shall be referred to the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph commented="no" id="H9C30AB3015CC49A59E1B1F09EFAF80CF"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>In the House of Representatives, if the Committee on Rules fails to report a rule within 7 legislative days of the bill being placed on the Calendar for the consideration of a bill reported by the Committee on the Budget under paragraph (4) or discharged under subparagraph (A) of this paragraph which has been determined by the Director to satisfy the required ratio, then any Member may offer a privilege resolution providing for the consideration of the bill. Such resolution shall provide that upon its adoption it shall be in order to consider in the House of Representatives the bill. The bill under the procedure set forth in section 408(c) shall be debatable for two hours equally divided and controlled by a proponent and opponent of thereof. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill of final passage without intervening motion except 1 motion to recommit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H38D37E15232843099B75BFC27F7AFFBB"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of the President's proposal in the Senate</header><paragraph id="H9BBC0AA80AEE4F35894A719CCB1396A4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text>Any debt reduction proposal submitted by the President under section 3101B of title 31, United States Code, shall be introduced by the majority or minority leader of the Senate or their designees. Upon introduction, the Chair of the Committee on the Budget shall within 3 days submit the proposal to the Congressional Budget Office to be scored. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H53606E9FD1944431819373FEC4030645"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Referral</header><text>Any proposal introduced under paragraph (1) shall be referred to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72C6F494EAF940B0B84BCEA61B6B9D57"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requests by budget committee</header><subparagraph id="H136A2F412570484A9D1AE30894DA5AA7"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Appropriate committees</header><text>Not later than 3 days after the date on which a proposal is referred under paragraph (2), the Chair of the Committee on the Budget of the Senate shall submit to each appropriate committee of the Senate a request that, during the 30-day period beginning on the date on which the request is made, the appropriate committee submit to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate—</text><clause id="H926D647F00C546269CF5BBEB07B58E0B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>a general assessment of the proposal introduced under paragraph (1); and </text></clause><clause id="HE2E071BA715F4C9384EA3B6A2B2009BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><subclause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H06B676EB201B4EC2A532CE1E14468861"><enum>(I)</enum><text>any recommendations related to the proposal; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HA111FA9D859A47D6AB03BD4A3E664339" indent="up1"><enum>(II)</enum><text>any alternative recommendation to reduce the deficit within the jurisdiction of the committee.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1085008519AA4D17A94BD594F9C146B9"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Other proposals</header><text>Any Member of the Senate may introduce a bill that meets the required ratio, as determined by the Congressional Budget Office, which shall be referred to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate if the proposal is sponsored by not less than one-fifth of the Members, duly chosen and sworn, including—</text><clause id="H204A847269604FC182A30FEEA0AFA450"><enum>(i)</enum><text>not fewer than 10 Members who are members of or caucus with the members of the political party of the majority leader of the Senate; and</text></clause><clause id="H085FF3B61E74402CBAFCC2586EF49D18"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>not fewer than 10 Members who are members of or caucus with any other political party that is not the political party of the majority leader of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H348FDD0E0CE94113B9D124102815491F"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Reported legislation by budget committee</header><subparagraph id="HC3007921CD9A4E4BB642CF071A063402"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Committee on the Budget of the Senate shall report a bill that meets the required ratio not later than 60 days after the date on which the President submits a debt reduction proposal under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H490EEA7E7EF44896BD27555A1E0FF368"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of legislation</header><text>The bill reported under subparagraph (A) may include—</text><clause id="HA93B8AD69EC44B6A8F1D5A1FECF264CA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the debt reduction proposal submitted by the President under this section; and</text></clause><clause id="HCD80EBABA2E74CEAB09BC752E267316C"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any proposal submitted to the Committee on the Budget of the Senate under paragraph (3), including any modifications to such proposals by the Committee on the Budget of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H451E8E171CFA4658BB730B6B5161CF79"><enum>(C)</enum><header>CBO score</header><clause id="HEBF9A34680EE4C6A8F6020A5E215A004"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>No bill may be reported under subparagraph (A) unless the Chair of the Committee on the Budget—</text><subclause id="HF7C48D4BFB3A4154ACDA55514F31185D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>submits to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office such bill for a cost estimate to be prepared under section 402; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HD99FCC724EE741D0B5E67C39633B1C73"><enum>(II)</enum><text>receives from the Director a cost estimate described in subclause (I) that includes a statement that such bill meets the required ratio.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HC1E633C10354484A8BC7D07DEA448A51"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Time period</header><text>The 60-day period described in subparagraph (A) shall not include the period beginning on the date on which the Chair of the Committee on the Budget of the Senate submits to the Director of the Congressional Budget Office the bill under clause (i)(I) and ending on the date on which the Chair receives the cost estimate under clause (i)(II).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H50749E9DF0AF4693AC368F26C9C88331"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Discharge</header><text>If the Committee on the Budget of the Senate has not reported a bill under paragraph (4) before the end of the 60-day period described in that paragraph, the Committee on the Budget of the Senate shall be automatically discharged from further consideration of—</text><subparagraph id="H36018CC6E19E4CA2BA31F5D88BBAA6D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the proposal introduced under paragraph (1), which shall be placed on the appropriate calendar; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0AF43659C24D4CC7A664E93969296A48"><enum>(B)</enum><text>any proposal submitted under paragraph (3)(B), which shall be placed on the appropriate calendar. </text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC6C802094244887B8348CB83086465E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>In this section and section 408, the term <term>required ratio</term> means the ratio that reduces by not less than 5 percentage points the projected ratio under current law of debt held by the public to Gross Domestic Product in the tenth fiscal year after the current fiscal year.</text></subsection></section><section id="H666E43E5687743A785842DE668CAD749"><enum>408.</enum><header>Consideration in the House of Representatives of alternative debt reduction proposals</header><subsection id="H73CF6F2CB1DF4B338B1D9CEAB2F5F350"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Introduction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the House of Representatives, any bill that satisfies the required ratio as determined by the Congressional Budget Office and does not contain any matter that is unrelated to debt reduction may be introduced by the majority leader, the minority leader, or by any other Member (if that Member’s proposed bill is cosponsored by at least 145 other Members or by at least 20 Members of the majority party and 20 Members of the minority party).</text></subsection><subsection id="H692F93DAC64C490B95075319E3038AF4"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Referral to Committee on Rules</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any bill introduced under subsection (a) shall be referred to the Committee on Rules. Each such bill shall be scored by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office to determine if such bill satisfies the required ratio. If such bill achieves the required ratio, it shall be reported without amendment to the House for its consideration within 30 calendar days of the date of introduction of the bill.</text></subsection><subsection id="HCFBDAD11A3C740BDA33AA0CD5C68DBAD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Queen-of-the-Hill rule for consideration</header><text>In the House of Representatives, any bill described in section 407 and any bill reported under subsection (b) shall be considered in the House of Representatives pursuant to a special order of business if the text of the bill provides that the text of all such bills reported under subsection (b) may be offered as amendments in the nature of a substitute and if more than one such amendment is adopted then the one receiving the greater number of affirmative recorded votes shall be considered as finally adopted.</text></subsection></section><section commented="no" id="H9278179C28354A73AFD7965E09C15DE1"><enum>409.</enum><header>Consideration on the floor of the Senate</header><subsection id="H636608A62896425FB338D1142F2EC2FC"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order, not later than 5 days of session after the date on which a bill meeting the requirements of section 407(c)(4) is reported from the Committee on the Budget of the Senate or the date on which any proposal is placed on the calendar after discharge under section 407(c)(5), as applicable, for the majority leader of the Senate or a Member of the Senate designated by the majority leader of the Senate to move to proceed to the consideration of the bill. It shall also be in order, notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, for any Member of the Senate to move to proceed to the consideration of the bill at any time after the conclusion of such 5-day period. A motion to proceed is in order even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to. All points of order against the motion to proceed to the bill are waived. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. Consideration of the motion to proceed shall be limited to not more than 10 hours equally divided between the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees. A motion to proceed shall require an affirmative vote of three-fifths of Senators duly chosen and sworn.</text></subsection><subsection id="HC34CD96C34CE49D9A640F9104951579F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Extraneous provisions</header><paragraph id="H1B0B4852AF7D443A99A756A90D391298"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>When the Senate is considering a bill under subsection (a), upon a point of order being made by any Senator against a extraneous material contained in the joint resolution, and the point of order is sustained by the Chair, the provision that contains the extraneous material shall be stricken from the joint resolution. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H98F908BAFE56487594DE6236A431DA61"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Extraneous material defined</header><text>In this subsection, the term <term>extraneous material</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H655A50C4893A49768C04BD3E664AABA7"><enum>(A)</enum><text> a provision that does not produce a change in outlays or revenue, including changes in outlays and revenues brought about by changes in the terms and conditions under which outlays are made or revenues are required to be collected (but a provision in which outlay decreases or revenue increases exactly offset outlay increases or revenue decreases shall not be considered extraneous by virtue of this subparagraph); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H905D3B870346434EB6176A8B6CB06BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a provision producing changes in outlays or revenues which are merely incidental to the non-budgetary components of the provision.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H18A2553BE2E34EA5929A650A156C5DC4"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Form of the point of order</header><text>A point of order under paragraph (1) may be raised by a Senator as provided in section 313(e) of the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/2/644">2 U.S.C. 644(e)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H76FECF9721EB4799A998F0E59F9263E4"><enum>410.</enum><header>Consideration by other house</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">If a House of Congress receives a bill passed by the other House under section 408 or 409 and has not yet passed a bill under section 408 or 409, the following procedures for consideration shall apply:</text><paragraph id="H1438535A6B744FCC97EE7512EEF34837"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Expedited consideration in the House of Representatives</header><subparagraph id="H3550D587DD3C48F8933C0B8D372D9E0D"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><clause id="H59B47D3109E14065AD60B7C83F045DF8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>It shall be in order, not later than 30 days after the date on which the House of Representatives receives a bill passed by the Senate under section 409, to move to proceed to consider the bill in the House of Representatives.</text></clause><clause id="HE164ED7B881A48FBAD2FC86C95E72F9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>For a motion to proceed to consider a bill under this subparagraph—</text><subclause id="HAC3BC122A80C4126B3AE745237996F3F"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all points of order against the motion are waived;</text></subclause><subclause id="H4783D625F88C4A45B99C996C612C09E4"><enum>(II)</enum><text>such a motion shall not be in order after the House of Representatives has disposed of a motion to proceed on the bill;</text></subclause><subclause id="HB18B5FB736B94D5D928EA93802BB2EB2"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3AD078C7429A46B7B0FD1AF1AF3D79C4"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>the motion shall not be debatable; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HA2C7E9E8BF464486A8EAFD16215F99B8"><enum>(V)</enum><text>a motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD87182024EC048F28DFBFC55C31205F3"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>If the House of Representatives proceeds to consideration of a bill under this paragraph—</text><clause id="HF252A3AAE071428E93F9A0F69EAB5F44"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the bill shall be considered as read;</text></clause><clause id="H551B1E67E3134FE18E9BFD40C5AD5FCD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>all points of order against the bill and against its consideration are waived;</text></clause><clause id="H0410CE29AB934E5680E8063B26230C06"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the previous question shall be considered as ordered on the bill to its passage without intervening motion except three hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the proponent and an opponent;</text></clause><clause id="H0FD911AFEE964294990F957670541602"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an amendment to the bill shall not be in order; and</text></clause><clause id="HCABFEC1C3BED4A839A479A9EB7E70CBC"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the bill shall not be in order.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DCA0D650CCC4A1198B76EF5BCC1DFBD"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Expedited consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph id="H30232FA96AD041D796D09B4D729AA393"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><clause id="H7953404182434D159AB79C6CB6116DC8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Notwithstanding rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order, not later than 30 days after the date on which the Senate receives a bill passed under section 408 by the House of Representatives, to move to proceed to consider the bill in the Senate.</text></clause><clause id="H7414856D1BBC40DF9501C7149C282D82"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Procedure</header><text>For a motion to proceed to the consideration of a bill under this paragraph—</text><subclause id="H893D1F18A4734D6788850AF1AA68449B"><enum>(I)</enum><text>all points of order against the motion are waived;</text></subclause><subclause id="H94DDCCEE388D4C5DA2ACE291657713CC"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the motion is not debatable;</text></subclause><subclause id="H68B7212DD72B4C5C89E51DF1AFD1B0C6"><enum>(III)</enum><text>the motion is not subject to a motion to postpone;</text></subclause><subclause id="H56CD199DC1D14FAEA6C48CD741FDBB62"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>a motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H6A67CCB2237B48608FFB0200592336D4"><enum>(V)</enum><text>if the motion is agreed to, the bill shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA5AA916FCCB4176AC61AF5E950D1B0B"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Floor consideration generally</header><text>If the Senate proceeds to consideration of a bill under this paragraph—</text><clause id="HDAD26C58125347F1AA584663BF9DC53F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>all points of order against the bill (and against consideration of the bill) are waived;</text></clause><clause id="HF7420A2C52C444B0BD7E9238C36D04A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>consideration of the bill, and all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 20 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees;</text></clause><clause id="H5F9CD58361DF464CA51B3B1DB5FC39B0"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>a motion further to limit debate is in order and not debatable;</text></clause><clause id="H24E3BA0F0D6B4D66A15B37C6C80DCB09"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>an amendment to, a motion to postpone, or a motion to recommit the bill is not in order; and</text></clause><clause id="H04607A72FE214C3096C0F718F4F7AAA1"><enum>(v)</enum><text>a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business is not in order.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H83EE077D994A4A3CAD4DBD8F06039225"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage of a bill under this paragraph shall occur immediately following the conclusion of the consideration of the bill, and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate, and shall require an affirmative vote of three-fifths of the Members of the Senate duly chosen and sworn.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H29081A4C9DC6451D8ACC7EEA0617E629"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Conferences</header><text>If the Senate and the House of Representatives have both passed the bill in different forms, then a conference committee on the bill shall be considered as ordered and the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the majority leader of the Senate shall immediately appoint Managers to such conference committee to resolve any disagreement between the Houses.</text></paragraph></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HBE33D0B6E8FF429F8C27ED432B3901BD"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974 is amended by inserting after the item relating to section 406 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1A9B85688AB446DDB9349D5D4809484E"><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="HED33C7907F4C42CE9CCE955B4D85A746">Sec. 407. Consideration of the debt reduction proposal submitted by the President. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H666E43E5687743A785842DE668CAD749">Sec. 408. Consideration in the House of Representatives of alternative debt reduction proposals. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H9278179C28354A73AFD7965E09C15DE1">Sec. 409. Consideration on the floor of the Senate. </toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H76FECF9721EB4799A998F0E59F9263E4">Sec. 410. Consideration by other house.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

