<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H64652309E80E465EAED4AC991FEFED17" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9576 IH: Leveraging Our Water and Energy data to Reduce Energy Bills Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9576</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221215">December 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001066">Ms. Castor of Florida</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and carry out a benchmarking and transparency initiative for commercial and multifamily properties to advance knowledge about building energy and water use and greenhouse gas emissions and inform efforts to reduce energy and water consumption and greenhouse gas emissions nationwide, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H8DBD4A943C464D02A6243AFE5F402CC7" style="OLC"><section id="H4F091FC74AC54730A9A851F7DB4FE0C2" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title; table of contents</header><subsection id="H893CAE31A22543D488572AD2F8C2D620"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Leveraging Our Water and Energy data to Reduce Energy Bills Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LOWER Energy Bills Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="HE4951688059E42299619DCF882CD7598"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc container-level="legis-body-container" quoted-block="no-quoted-block" lowest-level="section" regeneration="yes-regeneration" lowest-bolded-level="division-lowest-bolded"><toc-entry idref="H4F091FC74AC54730A9A851F7DB4FE0C2" level="section">Sec. 1. Short title; table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HEEEE22E90D9A45FB84F9CD88EBFB7B4B" level="section">Sec. 2. Findings.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HC20F7FD8D41641458F7781D1A49B68C3" level="section">Sec. 3. Covered property benchmarking and transparency initiative.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H133BC7A3B3C249B0819C7A1E563F67AA" level="section">Sec. 4. National benchmarking requirement.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="HF65CA4060FC04A69B2BB68FAE15A7695" level="section">Sec. 5. Exemptions and extensions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H4A5DF40F9F7947CFBD5FB62DE4E2152B" level="section">Sec. 6. Data transparency and sharing.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H12EA97EEE21C4931A39CC6CA91DE3E4C" level="section">Sec. 7. Federal assistance.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H3D6AF542C9624DB2A4CEAC923E56F65C" level="section">Sec. 8. Penalties.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0B641DFBE3BB4D3A8AC933945DEF0A1E" level="section">Sec. 9. Report.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H739BF3E82A12471AA7F99017FC4D318E" level="section">Sec. 10. Residential benchmarking study.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H9F05F34BC79248378143489FAC853699" level="section">Sec. 11. Regulations.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H0F56DED340D84FCB8C7D89C81CD3634D" level="section">Sec. 12. Definitions.</toc-entry><toc-entry idref="H2D82E048716845E6A182F674F9C75498" level="section">Sec. 13. Authorization of appropriations.</toc-entry></toc></subsection></section><section id="HEEEE22E90D9A45FB84F9CD88EBFB7B4B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="HBFFD1DB62DDD44DE8A23FCE3F855E844"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The climate crisis is raging and is already imposing significant costs on the economy of the United States.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE6EF98F0F7B64C37B919639275AC51AC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Biden-Harris Administration has committed to reducing harmful climate pollution by 50 to 52 percent below 2005 levels economy-wide by 2030.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H72F792933D8548C1A41CEF2090E34E39"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Increasing energy efficiency will improve energy security, save money on energy bills, create jobs, and reduce harmful climate pollution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AC8D3C5525E41ED88444C636653454B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Building energy benchmarking and disclosure helps provide transparency in building energy efficiency and has provided substantial benefits at affordable costs to State and local governments who have adopted benchmarking, including reducing energy use and emissions, helping tenants become informed about the utility costs associated with properties, helping tenants experience better health and comfort in properties, helping building owners experience lower vacancy and turnover rates, and allowing policymakers to make more informed decisions about future energy efficiency policies.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2AAC9726B9A94100A7C798D653042D86"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal benchmarking requirement will reduce harmful climate pollution that crosses State boundaries, provide information for people relocating to other States, and harmonize building energy efficiency and disclosure requirements in metropolitan areas that cross State lines.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC20F7FD8D41641458F7781D1A49B68C3" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Covered property benchmarking and transparency initiative</header><subsection id="H1228A5CE01D44E159EFB55B52EB75318" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Purpose</header><text>The Administrator shall develop and carry out a benchmarking and transparency initiative for covered properties the purpose of which is to—</text><paragraph id="H388CF2CCE892400EAA5F713604526008" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>advance the knowledge of owners and occupants regarding building energy and water use and greenhouse gas emissions; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8484FA069F774EB796F4A9ED59EAF028" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>inform efforts to reduce energy and water use and greenhouse gas emissions nationwide.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE37EEBBDB7594EE78B8DC6F45E7E46FA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation and coordination</header><text>In developing the initiative, the Administrator shall consult with and coordinate with the Secretary, other relevant agencies, and relevant stakeholders, including State and local governments with relevant benchmarking programs and experts from academia, nonprofits, and industry.</text></subsection><subsection id="H63A8B71013DB4F0A994AE6B0DEC1B1EB" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Existing programs</header><text>In developing the initiative, the Administrator shall make appropriate use of existing Federal programs.</text></subsection></section><section id="H133BC7A3B3C249B0819C7A1E563F67AA" commented="no"><enum>4.</enum><header>National benchmarking requirement</header><subsection id="H6670DB88CEA140C6BD4ACD4763ABB61B" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the initiative, the Administrator shall require each owner of a covered property to, as applicable, submit data annually to the Administrator (in this Act referred to as a <quote>benchmarking submission</quote>) in accordance with this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA1762A84EBD042788FB8CC984C0FA933" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Benchmarking schedule</header><paragraph id="HA5B6587BCA6B43ABA9FEB1DE8311EE75" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The owner of a covered property shall, as applicable, make a benchmarking submission for the covered property with respect to the previous calendar year not later than—</text><subparagraph id="H306469C2ED214CDDBA5B1221D29D0EDA" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a covered property that is greater than 200,000 square feet in gross floor area—</text><clause id="H00DA3EA0C3C54C4FAC515353103E6600"><enum>(i)</enum><text>May 1, 2025; and</text></clause><clause id="HF7E21004946C45D4BF1DBB717F4804D4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>May 1 of each calendar year thereafter;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEEF60EEF86C64386B0AA36FAF9C0F79E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a covered property that is greater than 100,000 square feet in gross floor area, but equal to or less than 200,000 square feet in gross floor area—</text><clause id="H66146FF174264DC29A03AAE45852CDA8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>May 1, 2026; and</text></clause><clause id="HB34E8BAA4C04476FA0F211332ECB430F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>May 1 of each calendar year thereafter; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H236199A67F2B4E0A8BD9C51697AD7473" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">for a covered property that is greater than 50,000 square feet in gross floor area, but equal to or less than 100,000 square feet in gross floor area—</text><clause id="H205DFC636E9D428795868CE85532ADD7"><enum>(i)</enum><text>May 1, 2027; and</text></clause><clause id="H935B37C7934943E5ADAAEC246E5731D7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>May 1 of each calendar year thereafter.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HE87E610065794723B166004EBF84DD3B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Smaller covered properties</header><text>The Administrator may, as the Administrator determines appropriate, require an owner of a covered property that is equal to or less than 50,000 square feet in gross floor area to make a benchmarking submission for the covered property with respect to the previous calendar year.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC6AB6CC729954588BF93274055D5AE2A" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Notification</header><paragraph id="H3A5A2DDEC58C4979A1436B34B2327880" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>First submissions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Between January 1 and March 1 of each year, for at least the first 3 years during which an owner of a covered property is required to make a benchmarking submission, the Administrator shall attempt to notify such owner of such requirement via direct mail, electronically via email, or through a public posting on a website.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H63417EACD448489E8E7DCDE4F0123848" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Failure to notify</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Failure of the Administrator to notify an owner of a covered property under this subsection shall not affect the obligation of such owner to make a benchmarking submission.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44AEF06D114B451D8416A251C97BCD7A" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Benchmarking data collection and reporting</header><paragraph id="HCAD27AE4ABFC4367867FEDDDC6B8E9BD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="HDDBC230CB61C4C928D98D56138E3F321" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Administrator shall develop requirements for benchmarking submissions. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1D65D37161E242DFABC2BEFBD6640478" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Failure to develop requirements</header><text>If the Administrator fails to develop requirements pursuant to subparagraph (A), the owner of a covered property shall make a benchmarking submission in accordance with paragraphs (2) and (3).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC1C9CE7EA10744ACA5BAA550B17A7F4E" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Updating requirements</header><text>The Administrator may periodically update the requirements developed under this paragraph to increase data transparency for the purposes of reducing energy and water use and greenhouse gas emissions of covered properties. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H7320F361C5FE4C269D9785E182227B7F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Data requirements</header><text>The requirements developed under paragraph (1) shall include a requirement that each benchmarking submission for a covered property include—</text><subparagraph id="H69E588536D5A4239A37995923B1638C9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>descriptive information about the covered property; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C769A1FC5C14E6C9F3B10AA28689C8D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information about the operational characteristics of the covered property, including—</text><clause id="H91CAD71DCA004CB9823D054875CC2C39"><enum>(i)</enum><text>aggregated whole-building data regarding energy and water use for the covered property compiled or submitted in accordance with subsection (e); and</text></clause><clause id="H50C61C15E1994E7A85D896257B43DA56"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>any other information that is required by the Administrator for purposes of the Energy Star Portfolio Manager.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H440A0F4D80DE4833884F30DB20687BE3" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Verification requirement</header><subparagraph id="H24C096BCF7ED4F31A9BD456959099C51" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The requirements developed under paragraph (1) shall include a requirement that each owner of a covered property verify, not less than once every 3 years, as applicable, that data submitted in each benchmarking submission for the covered property, including data regarding energy and water use for the covered property, is accurate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H25EA6DFBE566433DB1E104FB6871C0A0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text>The Administrator shall develop requirements for verification of data required under subparagraph (A), including requirements related to third-party data verification, the use of licensed professionals for such verification, and any appropriate waivers for such verification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H7EA5E01FA4494F9281722E5312E494A2" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Aggregated whole-Building data</header><paragraph id="HB811306AD4034D76B8AB072DCBBBD743" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Compilation of data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of meeting the requirements of the initiative, an owner of a covered property may obtain aggregated whole-building data on the energy and water use of the covered property—</text><subparagraph id="HD0CC66827F7842EC838FB24869A218AF" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by obtaining such data from an electric utility, gas utility, or public water system pursuant to paragraph (2);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DBA6A0354D646F7A3EBCF91B62444C6" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by collecting such data from all tenants pursuant to paragraph (3); or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H91CB0469E06B4EECB79FD32BE326F465" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by reading a master meter or reading all meters serving the covered property.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H73AB0BBEDF304CAFB481DF88FF0C0A2D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Energy and water data</header><subparagraph id="H4EE6C1D3E28E45A1B3C63E643049C106" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Request</header><text>An owner of a covered property may request, for purposes of meeting the requirements of the initiative, that an electric utility, gas utility, or public water system—</text><clause id="H3E91B58486C24CBAA4A7438FA76ADC7F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide the owner aggregated whole-building data on the energy or water use of the covered property; and</text></clause><clause id="HF52FCB82737347CAA8B88BED27F290C5" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>directly submit to the Administrator aggregated whole-building data on the energy or water use of the covered property.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC0B54C9C095E4204A9ADC64E338A8981"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Fulfillment of request</header><clause id="HADBA90F1951A415485B1454E6E2FDC17"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>An electric utility, gas utility, or public water system shall, not later than 10 days after receiving a request from an owner of a covered property under subparagraph (A), provide the owner aggregated whole-building data on the energy or water use of the covered property and submit to the Administrator aggregated whole-building data on the energy or water use of the covered property, provided that—</text><subclause id="H864FCC8E852B4AE28A05894C9BDDA9CC" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>the number of individually metered accounts associated with the covered property is at least 4; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H0016FDAC52A44D9D81DA67CBA97B1718" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>the electric utility, gas utility, or public water system receives consent from tenants, or in the case of a condominium, receives consent from an individual unit owner, for the electric utility, gas utility, or public water system to provide and submit the data.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H065C07E74F884BEFB48D8AF13E5640C9"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Exception</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Clause (i) shall not apply to a public water system, with respect to a covered property, if such public water system does not measure and record water usage of such covered property. </text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H209E5C58A61C4B0BB47126DA2B1EEE09" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Specifications</header><text>Data provided or submitted under subparagraph (B) shall—</text><clause id="HA0DAB66C7D704CFBA961F34B23A12C2B" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">be provided in an electronic, automated, machine readable form, without additional charge; </text></clause><clause id="H923BA0A701084C28A119BD9DAF454D7D" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include information on at least 24 months of energy or water use; and</text></clause><clause id="H58104F3B1716466F828DF0A2576063DF" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>be provided in a manner that provides adequate protections for the security of the information and consumer privacy.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD3514B690C74E30AB3A32EA35E6C34A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Tenant data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an electric utility, gas utility, or public water system does not provide aggregated whole-building data pursuant to this subsection, the owner of a covered property shall request any information that cannot otherwise be acquired by the owner and that is needed by the owner to comply with the requirements of this section from each tenant or, in the case of a condominium, an individual unit owner, located on the covered property. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H17D4BB0AFA7444359E7139C797673ED2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Use of data</header><text>Nothing in this section shall be construed to relieve covered property owners from compliance with State or local laws governing direct access to utility data by a tenant or, in the case of a condominium, an individual unit owner, from the responsible electric utility, gas utility, or public water system.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8C6A839137A8414EA69779758918079F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Unmetered water use</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making a benchmarking submission, the owner of a covered property shall not be required to include aggregated whole-building data regarding water use if the covered property does not have a meter that measures and records water usage data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HF65CA4060FC04A69B2BB68FAE15A7695" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Exemptions and extensions</header><subsection id="H08321E64FF264FF3A8FF36DE0DD8468A" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>State or local benchmarking</header><paragraph id="H062A401D4FFE4225A962DA39D2E60D1F" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Exemption</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The owner of a covered property shall not be required to make a benchmarking submission to comply with the initiative with respect to the covered property for a calendar year if the owner is required for such calendar year to comply with a benchmarking requirement of a State or local government that the Administrator has determined meets or exceeds the benchmarking submission requirements under section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA4A17E028D84B8A971F321EA6D34D5C" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Listing</header><subparagraph id="HBE67CF97EA2644D9ABB79DD0EDB8B965"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>For purposes of this section, the Administrator shall list, and update the list periodically, the States and local governments that have benchmarking requirements that meet or exceed the benchmarking submission requirements under section 4.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9FCF50F2C7A4649B3B0F76812714F58"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Removal</header><text>The Administrator may remove a State or local government from the list under subparagraph (A) if the Administrator determines that the benchmarking requirements of such State or local government no longer meet or exceed the benchmarking submission requirements under section 4, including due to low compliance with the benchmarking requirements of such State or local government.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H400B91F9F155428E8FA39448AF88C41D" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Exemptions for certain conditions</header><paragraph id="H23D6465EDB0F4578AC1A8422A5223972" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Conditions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may grant an exemption from making a benchmarking submission or a time extension for making a benchmarking submission if the request for such exemption or a time extension establishes that due to special circumstances not based on a condition caused by actions of the applicant, compliance with requirements of the initiative would cause undue hardship or would not be in the public interest.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37681B266CD3403F9D8A4BCA73D98DDF" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall determine and describe the circumstances in which the owner of a covered property may be exempt from making a benchmarking submission or may be granted a time extension for making a benchmarking submission in accordance with this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H4A5DF40F9F7947CFBD5FB62DE4E2152B" commented="no"><enum>6.</enum><header>Data transparency and sharing</header><subsection id="H093A7919BA894E50AE88669B9B9EAAE3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Data transparency</header><paragraph id="HC7A76481C66D4D84A96623C5398A3AF1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the initiative, the Administrator shall, to help inform owners, managers, tenants, and the market at large about a covered property’s energy and water use, annually make available, on a publicly accessible website, the subset of data, determined in accordance with paragraph (3), that is submitted to the Administrator as part of a benchmarking submission for the previous calendar year for such covered property. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5689B02DD9E34E678660984057F39B70" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Mapping and automated data access</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall seek to make data made available under this subsection easily accessible and interpretable, including—</text><subparagraph id="HD61E0303DB68456DB15C953B0A532928" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>through interactive web-based maps, including by city or region;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2E77EB887F0E403A9AE5C7635B20CF2D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">by making the data available for download in 1 or more forms to enable analysis and use of the data;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7A32A4914B4F4714B9D08AF8EF7B2BFD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by encouraging real estate listing services to include the data for all listed properties; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE156C6D5CCFA4F3CA687F2F6A06DB47B" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>if the Administrator determines appropriate, by assigning covered properties letter grades or other categorical ratings based on such data to improve understanding of the data.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD51A108115F4A559B711FD7B9B37E33" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Shared benchmarking information</header><text>The Administrator shall determine the subset of data submitted to the Administrator as part of a benchmarking submission to be made publicly available under paragraph (1), which shall include gross floor area and the information described in section 4(d)(2)(B), as the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1F7D6538AB6A45049C96F889B6C4AC00" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The Administrator may determine that data be excluded from publication under this subsection because publication of such data is not in the public interest. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H095F19D7A82D49E8959BAAAC1D5EA9E0" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sharing of data</header><paragraph id="HE051F8AEFF94489C83C2C87215B7108E" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Sharing of nonanonymized data</header><text>The Administrator may provide data regarding a covered property that is not anonymized data from benchmarking submissions to any electric utility, gas utility, or public water system serving the covered property or to any Federal, State, county or city-managed energy efficiency or management program, provided that the data will be used only for purposes of offering government regulated programs, services, and incentives related to energy and water efficiency and management. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDAE343BCC9554725A8D2A0ABDE60F040" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Disclosure of anonymized data</header><text>The Administrator may disclose any data from benchmarking submissions to a third party for academic or other non-commercial research purposes provided that such data is anonymized data.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H12EA97EEE21C4931A39CC6CA91DE3E4C" commented="no"><enum>7.</enum><header>Federal assistance</header><subsection id="H015CB70EE5FC4CE781EEAA97DA0B6D0F" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Energy star portfolio manager support</header><text>In carrying out the initiative, the Administrator shall improve the Energy Star Portfolio Manager and enhance implementation of the initiative, including by—</text><paragraph id="H40940405DC7B43149A9844C6702E4186" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>expanding the types of buildings eligible for Energy Star scores;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7B4BF144E8584C9B92B22FD0ACEF4647" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>considering the most effective use of data gathered from the initiative and the Commercial Buildings Energy Consumption Survey in determining timely and accurate Energy Star scores for covered properties;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBF46B5E9BF6B4A5E96C9503C23301530" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">considering greenhouse gas emissions in determining eligibility for Energy Star recognition; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB5B47F56A2474133B83FFB02E690F5B4" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>making any other improvements the Administrator determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H0DF26B73DFBF480096705DF3ACC20248" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical and financial assistance</header><paragraph id="H22ECA6EFF193413991726DEC2BD76960" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the initiative, the Administrator may provide technical assistance to any State or local government that has or intends to establish a building energy and water benchmarking requirement. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H83BBFCB475C24769A4D1876B77D66D65" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>New benchmarking programs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator may provide financial assistance to States and local governments to help such State and local governments establish building energy and water benchmarking programs. Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall develop application materials for State and local governments to apply for such assistance and funding award limits for such assistance.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3D6AF542C9624DB2A4CEAC923E56F65C" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Penalties</header><subsection id="H49D6C631CF484BDBB15F34B36A9E1CA3" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Penalties assessed on owners of covered properties</header><paragraph id="HC302CF78DE7E405DBB59F38C500FEE96"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written warning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall issue a written warning to an owner of a covered property if the Administrator determines that the owner of the covered property has—</text><subparagraph id="H083C5115CF744751BEE93E5F8E41644D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>failed to submit a benchmarking submission for the covered property by the applicable deadline under section 4(b);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H74B243431889427BB51D560C2D1BE410"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">misrepresented any material fact in a benchmarking submission;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA9234CF9F1554470A6721F7F74FA486A"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">submitted incomplete or inaccurate information in a benchmarking submission; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7AE2E1B1F9E640E4B14E4A4F3C2F5729"><enum>(D)</enum><text>failed to verify that data submitted in a benchmarking submission for the covered property is accurate in accordance with section 4(d).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H52BDE7CAD5184BAD94222762DCC2AA1A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of violation and initial penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an owner of a covered property does not make or appropriately update a benchmarking submission, or verify data, as applicable, within 30 days of the date on which a written warning is issued to such owner under paragraph (1), the Administrator may issue such owner a notice of violation assessing a penalty of not more than 1 cent per square foot of the applicable covered property per month of noncompliance.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC2406619342B48BC8B6594ADF8C6F5D4" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an owner of a covered property does not make or appropriately update a benchmarking submission, or verify data, as applicable, within 90 days of the date on which a notice of violation is issued to such owner under paragraph (2), the Administrator may, at that time, and every three months thereafter, assess an additional penalty against such owner of not more than 2 cents per square foot of the applicable covered property per month of noncompliance.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE7760893E5994156B5F54FBBA971C967" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Penalties assessed on utilities</header><paragraph id="H55B1339887F14E12B498829146982E29" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Written warning</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall issue a written warning to an electric utility, gas utility, or public water system that is, with respect to a covered property, required under section 4(e)(2) to provide the owner of such covered property aggregated whole-building data on the energy or water use of the covered property and to submit to the Administrator such aggregated whole-building data, if the Administrator determines that the electric utility, gas utility, or public water system has failed to provide or submit such aggregated whole-building data in accordance with section 4(e)(2). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF8A1D33B115741AAAF22691E19F9FE25" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Notice of violation and initial penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an electric utility, gas utility, or public water system that is described in paragraph (1) and issued a written warning under such paragraph does not provide or submit aggregated whole-building data to the applicable owner or to the Administrator within 30 days of the date on which such written warning is issued, the Administrator may issue such electric utility, gas utility, or public water system a notice of violation assessing a penalty of not more than $5,000 per violation. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H722627DC4AF44372A5058EAFA40D288C" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Subsequent penalties</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If an electric utility, gas utility, or public water system that is described in paragraph (1) and issued a notice of violation under paragraph (2) does not provide or submit aggregated whole-building data to the applicable owner or the Administrator within 90 days of the date on which such notice of violation is issued, the Administrator may, at that time, and every three months thereafter, assess an additional penalty against such electric utility, gas utility, or public water system, of not more than $10,000 per violation. </text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H0B641DFBE3BB4D3A8AC933945DEF0A1E" commented="no"><enum>9.</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than December 1, 2027, the Administrator shall conduct an assessment of the initiative, including an assessment of compliance rates for the initiative, and submit to Congress a report—</text><paragraph id="HA7818672F2C2417B9C3A7D386A42C886"><enum>(1)</enum><text>on the findings of the assessment, including—</text><subparagraph id="HBE9BB90D76A149389FA67F2ACE22F483"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a summary of energy and water use data submitted under the initiative;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9A2B3777D9D5476F9BECDDC3D5468DAD" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an evaluation of the accuracy, and issues affecting the accuracy, of such data; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H060AC720FCDE48678A743D8445015710"><enum>(C)</enum><text>changes in the energy and water use and greenhouse gas emissions of covered properties over time; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H734A81FC38234AD3A012CE915749D24E" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>that includes any recommendations for modifications to improve the impact of the assistance provided under section 7(b) to help achieve the purpose of the initiative. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H739BF3E82A12471AA7F99017FC4D318E"><enum>10.</enum><header>Residential benchmarking study</header><subsection id="H2E28330205C843F4AAF5D43F7F2989BB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the initiative, the Administrator, in consultation and coordination with the Secretary, shall—</text><paragraph id="HFFD0A78E641D4CD68AFB1B7B16D8D015"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a study on energy rating and assessment programs for residential buildings, including—</text><subparagraph id="H9247FAD67B284446B946C9E68D774686" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an evaluation of the impacts of State and local energy benchmarking, energy audit, home energy rating, and other related energy benchmarking and transparency policies for residential buildings, including multifamily units and single-family homes, on energy use and emissions of greenhouse gases and other air pollutants;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E3F996AD16C4190ACA81F5A41562EF0" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>identification of best practice policy approaches studied under subparagraph (A), including approaches for rating systems, that have resulted in the greatest reductions in residential building energy use and emissions of greenhouse gases and other air pollutants; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7C349FFE951449148D9D8C6AA1E6D053" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>consideration of the impacts of a Federal residential benchmarking and transparency requirement modeled after best practice policy approaches identified under subparagraph (B), including on—</text><clause id="H80BC84DB0EA34776AA354D757BB5D8DA" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the benefits and costs to homeowners, tenants, landlords, enforcement agencies, and other parties;</text></clause><clause id="H5C3143EB2E424E768336249986F3412A" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>residential energy use;</text></clause><clause id="HD4639B387F674890A4B54B3AF6CB2533" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>residential emissions of greenhouse gases and other air pollutants;</text></clause><clause id="HC7A1356057EC47CB8B9E450EB43D6CA0" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>distributional effects, especially for low-income communities and communities of color;</text></clause><clause id="H644F1242722046A6BDC7671F33502472" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>housing affordability; and</text></clause><clause id="H7B069D9BCDF1402184A5601CD9AF499F" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>energy insecurity; and</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H920103C46AC64D94A6988669A38E7C50" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">based on the study conducted under paragraph (1), develop recommendations on changes to existing Federal programs or new Federal policies, programs, or incentives to better provide information on home energy use and emissions of greenhouse gases and other air pollutants to homeowners and tenants for the purposes of reducing residential energy use and emissions of greenhouse gases and other air pollutants and alleviating household energy burdens. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H637DDF2B38F74FDE9D83CD29AAEC90FB" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Submission to Congress</header><text>Not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Administrator shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and Committees on Environment and Public Works and Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted, and the recommendations developed under subsection (a).</text></subsection></section><section id="H9F05F34BC79248378143489FAC853699" commented="no"><enum>11.</enum><header>Regulations</header><subsection id="H5C719D8E14404A01AC5643991A3C3BCD"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall promulgate and revise such regulations as are necessary to carry out the initiative. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEB529830A686478D9DABE5978D31E28A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Initial regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Administrator shall promulgate initial regulations under this section not later than 12 months after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section><section id="H0F56DED340D84FCB8C7D89C81CD3634D"><enum>12.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">For purposes of this Act:</text><paragraph id="H880E9EA9E7714EF3815E0CB0436C0B18"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Administrator</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Administrator</term> means the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC29318F2C68B4EABB2F9AD078F2E4D3A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Anonymized data</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>anonymized data</term> means data that does not reveal names, addresses, or any other information that would identify an individual or business.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H67EDD1A65B63469F808F2EE1B61F230A" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Condominium</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>condominium</term> means a property that combines separate ownership of individual units with common ownership of other elements, such as common areas.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H021C900E55EA4E37A71D5033595DBDE2" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered Property</header><subparagraph id="H366CAE662FD84787B172A6759AAB81F1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>covered property</term> means any of the following properties:</text><clause id="H1372CD114E0E4CA0B27556AC190A3E74" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A single building.</text></clause><clause id="H8ACAE863F18A41AE9532569D08554D9C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>One or more buildings held in the condominium form of ownership.</text></clause><clause id="H72F97388AA1F4F07832891358A974FA4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>A campus of two or more buildings which are owned and operated by the same party and are—</text><subclause id="H7DBD1C1EA3604833B66B741934835AC9" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>behind a common utility meter, or served by a common mechanical or electrical system (such as a chilled water loop), which would prevent the owner from being able to easily determine the energy use attributable to each of the individual buildings; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HE56DC9BB2CA9418883E227520787BB28" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>used primarily as—</text><item id="HC1270502E33E4491812AF32B92B1E9ED" commented="no"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>an elementary or secondary school;</text></item><item id="H770F8A7B4E754A5C9A681472EDE1FE94" commented="no"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>a hospital;</text></item><item id="H10B4F0BBF5DC4A8599963B9A38A4B4A6" commented="no"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>a hotel;</text></item><item id="H5EE8B4BDBD9B42099D231C2E399FE170" commented="no"><enum>(dd)</enum><text>multifamily housing; or</text></item><item id="H63B08C41F57945F9A99473CDD61BA3F0" commented="no"><enum>(ee)</enum><text>a senior care community.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA4C8362A35B74AA88DC2B801DC2963FB" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusions</header><text>The term <term>covered property</term> does not include any of the following:</text><clause id="H50318555F1234D6B9C2A56A4BE91EDC0" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Single family, duplex, triplex, and fourplex residential homes and related accessory structures, or any other residential building with less than 5 units.</text></clause><clause id="H9C0071EA91C044628FF55895D4A3B01C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Properties classified as manufacturing per designated Standard Industrial Classification (SIC) codes 20 through 39.</text></clause><clause id="HE65E179CCE46411E8DD09026DE95E33B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Other building types not meeting the purpose of the initiative, as determined by the Administrator.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0148BF1025A243659646733887416373" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Electric utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>electric utility</term> has the meaning given such term in section 3 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/16/2602">16 U.S.C. 2602</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H30098122DD68405FB54D6F421EE23490" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Energy Star Portfolio Manager</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Energy Star Portfolio Manager</term> means the tool developed and maintained by the Administrator to track and assess the relative energy performance of buildings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1245CBA261A146B09A3B9F0AE5FB6B61" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Energy Star score</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Energy Star score</term> means the 1–100 numeric rating generated by the Energy Star Portfolio Manager as a measurement of a building’s energy efficiency.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H44490971C1614B17ABA4C919ACA3E995" commented="no"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Gas utility</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gas utility</term> has the meaning given such term in section 302 of the Public Utility Regulatory Policies Act of 1978 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/3202">15 U.S.C. 3202</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE5EFA942D34CBDB5EC5255966A8AA9" commented="no"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Greenhouse gas</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>greenhouse gas</term> means the air pollutants carbon dioxide, hydrofluorocarbons, methane, nitrous oxide, perfluorocarbons, and sulfur hexafluoride.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7E009224E394DAFBDE08B9C61929CF0" commented="no"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Gross floor area</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>gross floor area</term> has the meaning given such term in the glossary for the Energy Star Portfolio Manager. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC0EBDFCD9D9A44529B36399A88CD1A6C" commented="no"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Initiative</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>initiative</term> means the benchmarking and transparency initiative for commercial and multifamily properties developed and carried out pursuant to section 3.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9617EEDDEA441B591EE398FD9679892" commented="no"><enum>(12)</enum><header>Owner</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>owner</term> means any of the following:</text><subparagraph id="H49B00E02F12D4513B87BAAB82E2A1A70" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An individual or entity possessing title to a property.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H46186BCBBC5F4B16BBD7BA4FF71478E2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a condominium, the board of the owners’ association or the master association, as applicable.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC71FBBD82C2348A59DFBFED37C8CCDD9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The board of directors, in the case of a cooperative apartment corporation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0F4D8C630ECD4B898C48F5577805692D" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>An agent authorized to act on behalf of any individual or entity described in subparagraph (A), (B), or (C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H98BD0B38B697450EAA1A233708CA198D" commented="no"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Public water system</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>public water system</term> has the meaning given such term in section 1401(4) of the Safe Drinking Water Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/300f">42 U.S.C. 300f(4)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA011C4B16FFD4B839AC23F2DC65FE046" commented="no"><enum>(14)</enum><header>State</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>State</term> means each of the several States, the District of Columbia, each territory or possession of the United States, and the governing body of each federally recognized Indian Tribe, band, nation, pueblo, or other organized group or community which is recognized as eligible for the special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians because of their status as Indians.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB046C8DEFF1341F69ACDD17EA5AC7151"><enum>(15)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H2D82E048716845E6A182F674F9C75498"><enum>13.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><subsection id="HC9D7091B295B431597BA1C0C01B921F2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Initial development and regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027, there is authorized to be appropriated to develop and carry out the initiative, including to promulgate initial regulations under section 11, $10,000,000, to remain available until expended. </text></subsection><subsection id="HDD8F7BDCD3294BF29A46AB23AC49190B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Implementation of initiative</header><text>In addition to amounts authorized to be appropriated under subsection (a), for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2032, there is authorized to be appropriated—</text><paragraph id="H45798262ED944CD2B62DCC6C303C3259"><enum>(1)</enum><text>$5,000,000 to carry out section 7(a), to remain available until expended;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB6F4BDC1258B45E1BF51CF102593097F"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$50,000,000 to provide technical and financial assistance under section 7(b), to remain available until expended; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA8FC96763044620918C7BE79F926564"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">$5,000,000 to carry out section 8, to remain available until expended.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

