<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HAB221A2D0DEC4BF68475263B95879140" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8208 IH: Children’s Literacy Initiative on Military Bases Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-23</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8208</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220623">June 23, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001085">Ms. Houlahan</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001186">Mr. Meijer</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001072">Mr. Hill</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Committee on Armed Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title 10, United States Code, to authorize a program of the Department of Defense to promote early literacy among certain young children as part of pediatric primary care, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HAC50253AD2DC453E968127CE1E1407C3" style="OLC"><section id="H21810B829017482BA817F5939F0C9A32" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Children’s Literacy Initiative on Military Bases Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>CLIMB Act of 2022</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HE5EFF77CA275495EBDE204164DC44297"><enum>2.</enum><header>Authority for Department of Defense program to promote early literacy among certain young children as part of pediatric primary care</header><subsection id="H4082EAD3EF6B442C97234AD2A458491E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline"><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/10/55">Chapter 55</external-xref> of title 10, United States Code, is amended by inserting after <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/10/1109">section 1109</external-xref> the following new section (and conforming the table of sections at the beginning of such chapter accordingly):</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H73CEB53BE6BE4F0CA900D0F891FE780D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><section id="HDCAFB7D5D5064029B6ADBB9AC399B56C"><enum>1109A.</enum><header>Authority for program to promote early literacy among certain young children as part of pediatric primary care</header><subsection id="H9355BD7237524FF48D406AB91C350CEB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense may carry out a program to promote early literacy among young children the caregivers of whom are members of the armed forces as part of the pediatric primary care of such children.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDACC1E02B4BA4FB0ABFDA045378A603C"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities under the program under subsection (a) shall be evidence-informed and include the following:</text><paragraph id="H036573DAEB874709A1F857F5AB99C529"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The provision to pediatric primary care providers and other appropriate personnel of the Department of training on early literacy promotion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H74522CEDCD9C4437A2691288F9DDCE2D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purchase and distribution of age-appropriate books to covered caregivers.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2FDF6A64F5A9448DBFCFE917F446D255"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The modification of waiting rooms in military medical treatment facilities, including in specific clinics within such facilities, to ensure such waiting rooms include materials that reinforce language-rich interactions between young children and their covered caregivers, including a full selection of literature for young children.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H25062D3125FE40F4BFA7C42EC43795A0"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The dissemination to covered caregivers of education materials on pediatric early literacy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1D1365BBD4434FBB95E1D00E40A07C00"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Such other activities as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD9B2398D023F4E2F8E7D6AC2C4AC3932"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Locations</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary may conduct the activities under subsection (b) at any military medical treatment facility.</text></subsection><subsection id="HBF4F03390CC4494EBE8527BA4E8A6A62" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="HE3A47A50C8BE48DE95A7F6247DE82268"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The term <quote>covered caregiver</quote> means a member of the armed forces who is a caregiver of a young child.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6540CBDD2AF74E36AF39320078ACA38C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The term <quote>young child</quote> means any child from birth to the age of five years old, inclusive.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HA9D7FF3FA6A945E2B87CA521AF02AD70"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense shall submit to the Committees on Armed Services of the House of Representatives and the Senate a report on the extent to which the authority under section 1109A(a) of title 10, United States Code, (as added by subsection (a)) is used, including a description of any activities carried out under the program so authorized.</text></subsection><subsection id="H60973A101A914C788FDC377928332F89"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this section, or the amendments made by this section, shall be construed as requiring that a child have more than one caregiver as a condition of receiving services under, or otherwise participating in, the program authorized under such section 1109A.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

