<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="HF38C0E5D9ECA467F89A8F183A14652AC" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7946 RH: Veteran Service Recognition Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-15</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 400</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7946</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–558, Part I]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220603">June 3, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="L000397">Ms. Lofgren</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000130">Mr. Vargas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000599">Mr. Ruiz</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221115">November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsors: <cosponsor name-id="S001177">Mr. Sablan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000579">Mr. Lowenthal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000468">Ms. Titus</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000574">Mr. Gallego</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000613">Mr. Panetta</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001200">Mr. Soto</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001205">Ms. Scanlon</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000371">Mr. Aguilar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001059">Mr. Costa</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221115">November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221115">November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on June 3, 2022</action-instruction></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide benefits for noncitizen members of the Armed Forces, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HJU00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H41FC880134BB4D8BB2F783EEA89EDAE7"><section id="H32944AEB18BE4B7EA4CDA49CDF9DF9A7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Veteran Service Recognition Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H23B99DFB19CF43A7A96A351E3A4CD717"><enum>2.</enum><header>Study and report on noncitizen veterans removed from the United States</header><subsection id="HD9E5D2456B074B59894CD0E624744649"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly carry out a study on noncitizen veterans and noncitizen former members of the Armed Forces who were removed from the United States during the period beginning on January 1, 1990, and ending on the date of the enactment of this Act, which shall include the following:</text><paragraph id="H4B90605D9A7E4031B4B335223D006785"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The number of noncitizens removed by U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement or the Immigration and Naturalization Service during the period covered by the report who served in the Armed Forces for an aggregate period of more than 180 days.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFAB5EAA05C954D619F0D6C2098C5871C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For each noncitizen described in paragraph (1)—</text><subparagraph id="H38670D063D8E40E89680C81FD032C2CA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the country of nationality or last habitual residence of the noncitizen;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H47DF8F1D0615448CAEE27A976BD8A74B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the total length of time the noncitizen served as a member of the Armed Forces;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H536685D4590B4D97977D17066AD7EB06"><enum>(C)</enum><text>each ground on which the noncitizen was ordered removed under section 237(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1227">8 U.S.C. 1227(a)</external-xref>) or section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>), as applicable; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAA35E0DFF3BE4D5F8A046FD82144636C"><enum>(D)</enum><text>whether the noncitizen appealed the removal order to the Board of Immigration Appeals.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFB2EEA9BA124CD6B9D47F8D60DF4185"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each of the following enumerations:</text><subparagraph id="H7277BAC0D9664EC08243A5D673345831"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who were discharged or released from service under honorable conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE1B7DD505994F57832E4D6C6A0D8EFF"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who were discharged or released from service under other than honorable conditions.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFBCA02C756D34E9E92541055D9417668"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who were deployed overseas.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HED8A18E03AE34CC79AB59103CE37D083"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who served on active duty in the Armed Forces in an overseas contingency operation.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H081BFCB25F114903B9E573AE4353497A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who were awarded decorations or medals.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC5BB40EE54A44F26B9048E7A6C55AEE9"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who applied for benefits under laws administered by the Secretary of Veterans Affairs.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0B6E6ABB53CD4A6DBF233C82C62C90B5"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The number of noncitizens described in paragraph (1) who receive benefits described in subparagraph (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB7A67372C2254AC7AD5A529664B6421C"><enum>(4)</enum><text>A description of the reasons preventing any of the noncitizens who applied for benefits described in paragraph (3)(F) from receiving such benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF6A935F766454AA6A455044ECDC3DAF8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the completion of the study required under subsection (a), the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Homeland Security, and the Secretary of Veterans Affairs shall jointly submit a report containing the results of such study to the appropriate congressional committees.</text></subsection></section><section id="H2C91C5DF9FAC4601B79EDFAE827759E6"><enum>3.</enum><header>Information system on veterans subject to removal</header><subsection id="H5A4069BAB33F4F7EB6DD0C7E88F0E71A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall create—</text><paragraph id="H759C624FD82B4E508CDE4D565946B9F5"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a protocol for identifying noncitizens who are or may be veterans; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC915DC2A9ABF43ADB5F2631DC47ED8CE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a system for maintaining information about noncitizen veterans identified pursuant to the protocol created under paragraph (1) and information provided by the Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness under section 4(d). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06C60042875B443FA79A191629811B7D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information sharing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The system shall be shared across all components of the Department of Homeland Security, including Enforcement and Removal Operations, the Office of the Principal Legal Advisor, Homeland Security Investigations, and the Military Family Immigration Advisory Committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2992EC07B1794B488FDF38FE9448D0F8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Consideration of veteran status</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security shall ensure that, in the case of any noncitizen veteran who is potentially removable, and in any removal proceeding against such a noncitizen veteran, information available under this system is taken into consideration, including for purposes of any adjudication on the immigration status of such veteran. </text></subsection><subsection id="HEDC14288C0B544F6B4C5008AFF14734E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of system required</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security may not initiate removal proceedings against an individual prior to using the system established under subsection (a) to attempt to determine whether the individual is a veteran. If the Secretary of Homeland Security determines that such an individual is or may be a veteran, the Secretary shall notify the Military Family Immigration Advisory Committee concurrently upon initiating removal proceedings against such individual.</text></subsection><subsection id="H03992478F7264F7392D15E16137BD7E1"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Training</header><text>Beginning in the first fiscal year that begins after the Secretary of Homeland Security completes the requirements under subsection (a), personnel of U.S. Immigration and Customs Enforcement shall participate, on an annual basis, in a training on the protocol developed under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H42951C4774DE4F3293EED24E2AF9EDCA"><enum>4.</enum><header>Military family immigration advisory committee</header><subsection id="HF1B4E9A8312D4C9F81359E71662123D5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall establish an advisory committee, to be known as the <quote>Military Family Immigration Advisory Committee</quote>, to provide recommendations to the Secretary of Homeland Security on the exercise of discretion in any case involving removal proceedings for—</text><paragraph id="HF6B0AA8EA13C40E891A2F232FDFB4DD6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF17C1D44E82F4CE2BA921731F46D67AF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>a veteran; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB39A61FAE4564141B626839AA10EF185"><enum>(3)</enum><text>a covered family member.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H06F2E6A8FE2047BAB4576D0EE324920E"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The Advisory Committee shall be composed of 9 members, appointed by the Secretary of Homeland Security. </text></subsection><subsection id="H816F26C223B64445A1D272FA3CA4D7D2"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Case reviews</header><paragraph id="HC72D86782C24415AA031CE5670F19AD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 30 days after the Advisory Committee identifies or is notified about the case of an individual described in subsection (a), the Advisory Committee shall meet to review the case and to provide a written recommendation to the Secretary of Homeland Security on whether—</text><subparagraph id="HCADF4F7A15664531884815F7C6F9E12B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an exercise of discretion is warranted, including—</text><clause id="H7372311E9D32490B9D75D6BB3519E4A2"><enum>(i)</enum><text>termination of removal proceedings; </text></clause><clause id="HC0CCDD728672452591D3E9E22D3B6F2D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>parole;</text></clause><clause id="H08053B0C13E7459A955C32061A1F6398"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>deferred action;</text></clause><clause id="HE98B8939F038402CAA16C5FAE9DFDA40"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>a stay of removal;</text></clause><clause id="H493AADB235B5405BBB30741D6E63A4B9"><enum>(v)</enum><text>administrative closure; or </text></clause><clause id="H02998F4EEA1748D195F295073C24CEB8"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>authorization to apply for any other form of relief; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE780A272EFB74F099AE56D91BEA34489"><enum>(B)</enum><text>to continue seeking the removal of such individual.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1C40443B451A4A59BDBB27F80C0CF2F5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Submission of information</header><text>An individual who is the subject of a case review under paragraph (1) may submit information to the Advisory Committee, and the Advisory Committee shall consider such information.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H43B0FF1A416A42B0A77874E471B6487E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In conducting each case review under paragraph (1), the Advisory Committee shall consider, as factors weighing in favor of a recommendation under paragraph (1)(A)— </text><subparagraph id="H6B865E046B004E28A9BE8D116E556885"><enum>(A)</enum><text>with respect to a member of the Armed Forces, whether the individual—</text><clause id="H620B8C55B769439D90DA911F86B01049" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>was an enlisted member or officer of the Armed Forces;</text></clause><clause id="HFC2F57D135E544B385E9F5A4F04B9569"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>received a medal or decoration, was deployed, or was otherwise evaluated for merit in service during his or her service in the Armed Forces;</text></clause><clause id="H7299F947098E41E6A2BCFC888B44F59C"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is a national of a country that prohibits repatriation of an individual after any service in the Armed Forces; or</text></clause><clause id="H11DEA855563C477F9000B5E0357F5213"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>contributed to his or her local community during his or her service in the Armed Forces;</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D124790DBF843CDB5942F4B8E9FAAC4"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with respect to a veteran, whether the individual—</text><clause id="HE54170236D8F4498B41C7682AAFB2814" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">was an enlisted member or officer of the Armed Forces;</text></clause><clause id="HF152E825EEA04229A3080BA5B05CDD42"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>completed a period of service in the Armed Forces and was discharged under conditions other than dishonorable;</text></clause><clause id="H9415089B7B64412EB2788D8E1A75E58B"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">received a medal or decoration, was deployed, or was otherwise evaluated for merit in service during his or her service in the Armed Forces;</text></clause><clause id="H7F75AE3434D34F01B339ADE6749E5B35"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>is a national of a country that prohibits repatriation of an individual after any service in the Armed Forces of another country; or</text></clause><clause id="H926D8226006F4B39B661D74676E1AD97"><enum>(v)</enum><text>contributed to his or her local community during or after his or her service in the Armed Forces; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48F23D2BBFF54427BDC33D23621EA7F6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>with respect to a covered family member, whether the individual—</text><clause id="HB322F3A634A04AEEBD5B6281FF514104"><enum>(i)</enum><text>supported a member of the Armed Forces serving on active duty or a veteran, including through financial support, emotional support, or caregiving; or</text></clause><clause id="H877FB3A3BDC441079C8DE3E6C34877E4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contributed to his or her local community during or after the military service of the member or of the veteran.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H74A553003784403C90D31A3C4FB8024D"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Precluding factor</header><text>In conducting each case review under paragraph (1), the Advisory Committee shall consider, as a factor requiring a recommendation under paragraph (1)(B), whether the member of the Armed Forces, veteran, or covered family member has been convicted of 5 offenses for driving while intoxicated (including a conviction under the influence of or impaired by alcohol or drugs), unless the conviction is older than 25 years. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB0BF832B00434985821998F08401D186"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Briefings on noncitizen veterans</header><text>The Under Secretary of Defense for Personnel and Readiness shall provide detailed briefings to the Advisory Committee regarding the service of a noncitizen veteran when that individual’s case is being considered by the Advisory Committee.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED97E55A21734B339913D7FEEFC17B7A"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Briefings on actions in response to recommendations</header><text>Not less frequently than quarterly, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide detailed briefings to the Advisory Committee regarding actions taken in response to the recommendations of the Advisory Committee, including detailed explanations for any cases in which a recommendation of the Advisory Committee was not followed.</text></subsection><subsection id="H1F16ABCDD7D74AD0A62837146A9345B8"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Transfer of case files</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For any individual with respect to whom the Advisory Committee is conducting a case review under this section, the Secretary of Defense and Secretary of Homeland Security shall provide to the Advisory Committee a copy of any available record pertaining to that individual, including such individual’s alien file, that is relevant to the case review.</text></subsection><subsection id="H84211A09226A49A19DBB68F349DBF470"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Limitation on removal</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, an individual described in subsection (a) may not be ordered removed until the Advisory Committee has provided a recommendation with respect to that individual to the Secretary of Homeland Security.</text></subsection><subsection id="H0B07DF4139FA43C8A0A1A71BA7DC7C5E"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Limitation on eligibility for case review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An individual who is inadmissible based on a conviction of an aggravated felony described in subparagraph (A) of section 101(a)(43) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(43)</external-xref>) shall be ineligible for a case review under this section.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9250BC4DBC1649FC8B3DB4077DD56ABE"><enum>5.</enum><header>Program of citizenship through military service</header><subsection id="H60E3707D6DC74C399C907EB8CA2538AE"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H97134DB000AE4DB5B4DB3663525C34FA"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Program established</header><text>The Secretary of Homeland Security, acting through the Director of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services, and in coordination with the Secretary of Defense, shall jointly implement a program to ensure that—</text><subparagraph id="H894146E782A24463B9720FD2B41EC1BE" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">each eligible noncitizen is afforded the opportunity to file an application for naturalization at any point on or after the first day of service on active duty or first day of service as a member of the Selected Reserve pursuant to section 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1440">8 U.S.C. 1440</external-xref>); and </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H62343AD476C248C79BD1AC2B163DDF6E"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the duly authenticated certification (or any other successor form) required under section 329(b)(3) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1140">8 U.S.C. 1140(b)(3)</external-xref>) is issued to each noncitizen not later than 30 days after the individual makes a request for such certification.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E40D38F94B047C5B525840774158AC9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Eligible noncitizen</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subsection, the term <quote>eligible noncitizen</quote> means a noncitizen who serves or has served in the Armed Forces of the United States during any period that the President by Executive order designates as a period during which the Armed Forces of the United States are or were engaged in military operations involving armed conflict with a hostile foreign force.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCD2CC35E150848F0BE541F5E03AD10F0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>JAG training</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that appropriate members of the Judge Advocate General Corps of each Armed Force receive training to function as liaisons with U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services with respect to applications for citizenship of noncitizen members of the Armed Forces.</text></subsection><subsection id="H34DCBD489EFD49E2A01D79C6E44FCB27"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Training for recruiters</header><text>The Secretary of Defense shall ensure that all recruiters in the Armed Forces receive training regarding—</text><paragraph id="HAB23A6A17E1A452FB29B36EE17696AAC"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the steps required for a noncitizen member of the Armed Forces to receive citizenship;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF0438AE1284E4FE09D823ED4426ADFB7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>limitations on the path to citizenship for family members of such individuals; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8D71E6D2CF3449BCA86DD01ADB327CF3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>points of contact at the Department of Homeland Security to resolve emergency immigration-related situations with respect to such individuals and their family members.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H160EC5BCC4A442E49EF4801078C80C8E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Annual reports</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of each military department shall annually submit to the appropriate congressional committees a report on the number of all noncitizens who enlisted or were appointed in the military department concerned, all members of the Armed Forces in their department who naturalized, and all members of the Armed Forces in their department who were discharged or released without United States citizenship under the jurisdiction of such Secretary during the preceding year.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEBA723AD45A6422096A4A825C3B640DC" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Further facilitation naturalization for military personnel in contingency operations</header><text>Any person who has served honorably as a member of the Armed Forces of the United States in support of a contingency operation (as defined in section 101(a)(13) of title 10, United States Code), and who, if separated from the Armed Forces, was separated under honorable conditions, may be naturalized as provided in section 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1440">8 U.S.C. 1440</external-xref>) as though the person had served during a period designated by the President under such section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFE5DEED506664BFBB36F34C34858C968"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Naturalization through service in the Armed Forces of the United States</header><text>Section 328 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1439">8 U.S.C. 1439</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3D5C4A9AA0E540DC9DFB91BEFA5366C6"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a), by striking <quote>six months</quote> and inserting <quote>one year</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D506C10CAF846C39550EA2BF2FDE3E6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in subsection (d), by striking <quote>six months</quote> and inserting <quote>one year</quote>.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H3B0D09329C2445DCAA155EC895EFC99D"><enum>6.</enum><header>Information for military recruits regarding naturalization through service in the Armed Forces</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary of Defense, in coordination with the Secretary of Homeland Security, shall ensure that there is stationed or employed at each Military Entrance Processing Station—</text><paragraph id="H859DE2EBA76D41B6892B85D6B6A617FD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>an employee of U.S. Citizenship and Immigration Services; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC2B73093682402485311281EC4ED38F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in the case that the Secretary determines that it is impracticable to station or employ a person described in paragraph (1) at a Military Entrance Processing Station, a member of the Armed Forces or an employee of the Department of Defense—</text><subparagraph id="HCF7F28FA8E934D7CBDA2C6B06F07D0C9"><enum>(A)</enum><text>whom the Secretary determines is trained in the immigration laws; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9B32F914931C4973A720FC957EF504AA"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who shall inform each military recruit who is not a citizen of the United States processed at such Military Entrance Processing Station regarding naturalization through service in the Armed Forces under sections 328 and 329 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1439">8 U.S.C. 1439–1440</external-xref>).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="HA7BDDA7F032E4177BE79AE566EFC7723"><enum>7.</enum><header>Return of eligible veterans removed from the United States; adjustment of status</header><subsection id="H5A771215EB98402E9373C32C378373BF"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Eligible veterans</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a noncitizen who has been issued a final order of removal, the Secretary of Homeland Security, may, notwithstanding such order of removal, adjust that noncitizen’s status to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or admit such noncitizen for lawful permanent residence if the Secretary determines that such noncitizen is a veteran and, consistent with subsection (b), is not inadmissible. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7885DB570C9E419BAEF39BF61D3844D8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Waiver</header><paragraph id="H59BBA468C3504808A76B202ACCFAC232"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Authority</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a noncitizen veteran described in subsection (a), the Secretary of Homeland Security may waive any applicable ground of inadmissibility under section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>) (other than paragraphs (3) and (2)(H) of such section 212(a), a finding of inadmissibility under paragraph (2)(A) based on a conviction of an aggravated felony described in subparagraph (A), (I), or (K) of section 101(a)(43) (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)(43)</external-xref>), or 5 convictions for driving while intoxicated (including a conviction for driving while under the influence of or imparied by alcohol or drugs) unless the conviction is older than 25 years, if the Secretary determines that it is in the public interest. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1BE178A1D8B40E5BBB8F1CE574EBBB9"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Public interest considerations</header><text>In determining whether a waiver described in paragraph (1) is in the public interest, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall consider factors including the noncitizen’s service in the Armed Forces, and the recency and severity of any offense or conduct that forms the basis of a finding of inadmissibility under section 212(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8C04B471F6E04BDA94A5AB737E0DFF0A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Procedures</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security shall, by rule, establish procedures to carry out this section. </text></subsection><subsection id="HB2BDDD7AE2334F5CAB13021D55D2A51F"><enum>(d)</enum><header>No numerical limitations</header><text>Individuals who are granted lawful permanent residence under this section shall not be subject to the numerical limitations under section 201, 202, or 203 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151</external-xref>, 1152, or 1153).</text></subsection><subsection id="H948CD42B561D4155A0D3CD2DDAB4E6A9"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Clarification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a noncitizen veteran’s status is adjusted under this section to that of an alien lawfully admitted for permanent residence, or if such noncitizen is lawfully admitted for permanent residence, such adjustment or admission shall create a presumption that the noncitizen has established good moral character under paragraphs (1) through (8) of section 101(f) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(f)</external-xref>).</text></subsection><subsection id="H4B2B309212474A79A4C768620AA82C88"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Limitation on removal</header><paragraph id="H90B8892CB5344013BBA6893576FC76E3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A noncitizen who appears to be prima facie eligible for lawful permanent resident status under this section shall be given a reasonable opportunity to apply for such status. Such noncitizen shall not be removed from the United States until a final administrative decision establishing ineligibility for such status is rendered. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6D9659B814484B05AF9D56CC3A18DF7A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Effect of final order</header><text>A noncitizen present in the United States who has been ordered removed or has been permitted to depart voluntarily from the United States may, notwithstanding such order or permission to depart, apply for lawful permanent resident status under this section. Such noncitizen shall not be required to file a separate motion to reopen, reconsider, or vacate the order of removal. If the Secretary of Homeland Security approves the application, the Secretary shall notify the Attorney General of such approval, and the Attorney General shall cancel the order of removal. If the Secretary renders a final administrative decision to deny the application, the order of removal or permission to depart shall be effective and enforceable to the same extent as if the application had not been made, only after all available administrative and judicial remedies have been exhausted.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H8D05EE6CE735473585E5DEAC374854F6" commented="no"><enum>8.</enum><header>Adjustment of status for certain immediate relatives of United States citizen service members or veterans</header><subsection id="HDD74724DCC2D45B7B09671D50D6E7B24" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of an application for adjustment of status pursuant to an approved petition for classification under section 204(a)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>), an alien described in subsection (b)—</text><paragraph id="H283A4A9DE3884D9CAFB7C9B4230CF797" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is be deemed to have been inspected and admitted into the United States; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13E683857CE04C7C8033A06B047C239A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not be subject to paragraphs (6)(A), (6)(C), (7)(A), and (9) of section 212(a) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1182">8 U.S.C. 1182(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC066B614D0EB4311BF1ED8525C65409F" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Alien described</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An alien is described in subsection (a) if the alien is the beneficiary of an approved petition for classification under section 204(a)(1)(A) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1154">8 U.S.C. 1154(a)(1)(A)</external-xref>) as an immediate relative (as defined in section 201(b)(2)(A)(i) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1151">8 U.S.C. 1151(b)(2)(A)(i)</external-xref>)) of a citizen of the United States who—</text><paragraph id="H2A34904AA4924B49894696B409847CC3" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">served, for a minimum of 2 years, on active duty in the Armed Forces or in a reserve component of the United States Armed Forces; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H00A1A0F993A6483CB476E2CFAFE11965" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if discharged or released from service in the Armed Forces, was discharged or released under honorable conditions.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H340DE4763018403392BE81DC7C2D8CA9"><enum>9.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H3EFC4C9201904087836CFCC1158B45D9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Advisory committee</header><text>The term <term>Advisory Committee</term> means the Military Family Immigration Advisory Committee established pursuant to section 4.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6C508ACA9115455C8160693E9CFF6DF2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text><subparagraph id="H4BC2DEBABA22444ABFC9EF283470AF58"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDA065BADA6E84C7C9FB40072CA9BF7D3"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DCE01A23AA94BF4BC2D99E17B1CB46D"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE589184880BD4C259325F2BCAF1DBC74"><enum>(D)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the Senate;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC87561F214524EC4B92967273E96EB58"><enum>(E)</enum><text>the Committee on Armed Services of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAEA49CE4E609489DAEA7676FC2882E7F"><enum>(F)</enum><text>the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H4C525E6B593644559C6D332EC6AEA0C6"><enum>(G)</enum><text>the Committee on the Judiciary of the House of Representatives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2A5414CA6341450F8E8B8BA770498C90"><enum>(H)</enum><text>the Committee on Veterans’ Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD361034F6BB1444798F767CA6F9E04FF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Armed Forces</header><text>The term <term>Armed Forces</term> has the meaning given the term <term>armed forces</term> in section 101 of title 10, United States Code.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7E1950A120034EEB9F124CBD098BA60A"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered family member</header><text>The term <term>covered family member</term> means the noncitizen spouse or noncitizen child of—</text><subparagraph id="H36005CE43E2A4854B73970DB459B077A"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a member of the Armed Forces; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HB7AAAA7426E54AD1845F46263CBE5734"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a veteran.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H1823A7DD73974B108EEABA578146D950"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Immigration laws</header><text>The term <term>immigration laws</term> has the meaning given that term in section 101 of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101</external-xref>).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBFD63ADAFDE4C999780A1EF75077C0D"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Noncitizen</header><text>The term <term>noncitizen</term> means an individual who is not a citizen or national of the United States (as defined in section 101(a) of the Immigration and Nationality Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/8/1101">8 U.S.C. 1101(a)</external-xref>)).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7821323D929D463B8716B335AC3BF39F" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Veteran</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>veteran</term> has the meaning given such term in section 101 of title 38, United States Code.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221115">November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported from the <committee-name added-display-style="italic" committee-id="HJU00" deleted-display-style="strikethrough">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name> with an amendment</action-desc><action-date date="20221115">November 15, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HVR00">Veterans' Affairs</committee-name> and <committee-name committee-id="HAS00">Armed Services </committee-name> discharged; committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

