<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H2D86F244EB1646BD86EE05E8A1735988" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc">
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9446 IH: Department of Energy Clean Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-06</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code>
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session>
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9446</legis-num>
<current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber>
<action display="yes">
<action-date date="20221206">December 6, 2022</action-date>
<action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="B000740">Mrs. Bice of Oklahoma</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HSY00">Committee on Science, Space, and Technology</committee-name></action-desc>
</action>
<legis-type>A BILL</legis-type>
<official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to conduct a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application with respect to clean hydrogen and fuel cell energy, low-emission fuels, and coproducts, and for other purposes.</official-title>
</form>
<legis-body id="H77B2DA9A59CD422A84C59A6573BE3690" style="OLC">
<section id="HC4BAD8B0C7954F799B2D5D6039435819" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Department of Energy Clean Hydrogen and Fuel Cell Research, Development, and Demonstration Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H9E728E4F59864ADDB89940599C98F575"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text>
<paragraph id="H5866B60DB45247299D8E03EFCE42AFA4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Clean hydrogen</header><text>The term <quote>clean hydrogen</quote> means hydrogen produced from any source that results in a significant reduction in lifecycle greenhouse gas and criteria air pollutant emissions compared to conventional fuel options.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8C7D4ED2272E49D9AD027E6AA126B9E1"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Department</header><text>The term <quote>Department</quote> means the Department of Energy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H40654C18213948C58D00CA54BEEA66EF"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible entity</quote> means—</text> <subparagraph id="H98AB1A7EBA48471B8FF409158DE55980" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an institution of higher education, including historically Black colleges and universities, minority-serving institutions, Hispanic-serving institutions, Tribal colleges or universities, emerging research institutions, and community colleges;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H33CC7D8FFFEA469E881F2DAED6E0DB73" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a National Laboratory (as such term is defined in section 2 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/15801">42 U.S.C. 15801</external-xref>));</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB430FA5803A044BBAAC332B8D39392C5"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a Federal research agency;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE1640FFEB8564B07922D4C3D39ACDB82"><enum>(D)</enum><text>a State research agency;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HD0828C95B5F24EE38DEC2B4F54E49311" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>a research agency associated with a territory or Freely Associated State;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA5294BDCE9B84FBFA7A215960D5492B8"><enum>(F)</enum><text>a nonprofit research organization;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H35B07A8DFDAB4667B001B210E81574A2"><enum>(G)</enum><text>a private sector entity;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H61987D4E7BCF4EA68226ED043FFB65BD"><enum>(H)</enum><text>any other entity, as determined by the Secretary; or</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8FAD586176EE42F18251BA240DFE1BB0"><enum>(I)</enum><text>a consortium of two or more entities described in subparagraphs (A) through (F).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H720B2F492D434A1692BB6085DC765B4E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Hispanic-serving institution</header><text>The term <quote>Hispanic-serving institution</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 502(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1101a">20 U.S.C. 1101a(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HD55882AAA2E444E79A2382F521E69495"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Historically Black college or university</header><text>The term <quote>historically Black college or university</quote> has the meaning given the term <quote>part B institution</quote> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HA4EED52AA51E4A40A62704127BB5B297"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Hydrogen carrier</header><text>The term <quote>hydrogen carrier</quote> means a substance that meets one or both of the following descriptions:</text> <subparagraph id="HC15B8129983542F2B8D6992B08D3F4D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Molecules that have been synthesized from hydrogen.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H705C8B9862EC47EF9C6F8959EBB18687"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Reversible liquid, solid, or gas chemical states that store hydrogen in a state other than as free hydrogen molecules.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB40D04A02EFB4B588589D42A414F7D05"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Hydrogen-related technologies</header><text>The term <quote>hydrogen-related technologies</quote> means technologies relating to the production, purification, distribution, storage, and use of hydrogen for heat, stationary power, transportation, industrial chemical feedstocks, or energy storage, including fuel cell technologies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H02554FC6C98C423789BA833DD689D25A"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <quote>institution of higher education</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 101(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1001">20 U.S.C. 1001(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C43A52DAF714E81BC0EA912C328F7ED"><enum>(9)</enum><header>Minority-serving institution</header><text>The term <quote>minority-serving institution</quote> includes the entities described in any of paragraphs (1) through (7) of section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDE3665D6CDE944A1B78DFB78FC0A9654"><enum>(10)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H50B855AF992C46E7A05B4B23429466BF"><enum>(11)</enum><header>Tribal college or university</header><text>The term <quote>Tribal college or university</quote> has the meaning given such term in section 316(b) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1059c">20 U.S.C. 1059c(b)</external-xref>).</text></paragraph></section>
<section id="H28483B9EFE3F4B49AF5FCB8E91BDAE6C"><enum>3.</enum><header>Clean hydrogen and fuel cell technology research and development program</header>
<subsection id="H5462C5F6421C4B97B999C00F91188594" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, in consultation with the heads of relevant Federal agencies, shall conduct a program of research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of clean hydrogen and fuel cell technologies to enable production, distribution, and use of clean hydrogen, including in energy storage, industrial applications, building, power, and transportation sector applications, and to advance the development of related hydrogen infrastructure. In carrying out such program, the Secretary shall award financial assistance through a competitive, merit-reviewed process and consider applications from eligible entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HA7273B67DE724CAB9EA1FB80AF714605"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Program components</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall coordinate with the heads of relevant Federal agencies to determine a comprehensive set of technical milestones for the activities and focus on research and development challenges across the hydrogen supply chain for various applications, including clean hydrogen production, the supply of hydrogen, storage of hydrogen, transportation of hydrogen, and end uses of hydrogen that advance the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H2C92ABA1461848BCB8D4BD2EEDB706FB"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Clean hydrogen production from diverse energy sources.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10E89BE03F664DF8B568023905338387"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Clean hydrogen transportation, distribution, and end use efficiency.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H343FDF0758A04019B4DD9066748E39AC"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Clean hydrogen and hydrogen-related technologies for the production of the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HB70F6445171341418B29D3B62FC0EBE7"><enum>(A)</enum><text>High- and low-temperature heat in industry and the built environment, including low-emission production of cement, iron, steel, and other metals.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H711DF3AFB7C341C3A2839471EF9F2C46"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Improved environmental performance of petroleum-based transportation fuels with clean hydrogen.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H03427DBEC1B54EDEAB9FA18582BE1F90"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Sustainable chemical products and materials.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE5BDB47D0ECF46A5B6901363A325D3A2"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Sustainable synthetic fuels.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB9E9FA23BB954D56BB2E9FCD4896B897"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Energy storage for electric grid flexibility and long duration energy storage.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE6CBA9D90F524959A3C1203C56E6BE8B"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Hydrogen blending for power generation, industrial use, and other end use applications relating to fuel cell performance, reliability, durability, and cost.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3B552E6BAF9946ADB891F47198FDFEDF"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Fuel cell technologies for transportation and stationary applications.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H41CD429073C64393BBEE0F3F2EA233B5"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Domestic fuel cell manufacturing capabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H125F4ECC50FE49EFB296FCF235689C64"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Hydrogen and hydrogen carrier technologies as a fuel for electric transportation and stationary applications powered by fuel cells.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4452D6D5EA3B40EAA011346EBE278EBD"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Dynamic control systems needed to integrate clean hydrogen production and end users with sources of reliable and affordable low-emission power.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFA0DCD5FDF91484FB71A68B45CB4576F"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Computational tools for lifecycle assessments and economic analysis of the entire supply chain of clean hydrogen production and utilization.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H8B335DE933E84AA09AF844B947F2E318"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Hydrogen fueling of various vehicle classes and vocations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H663AC27189794AFA8230E2049FDDB1FE"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Safe, durable, and affordable materials for hydrogen-related technologies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HF81E3238AF0E41ACBD4F3C3A4238CCBA"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Methods for integrating carbon capture and storage and waste by-product treatment technologies, including considerations for produced water, into clean hydrogen system processes.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H1CE7240570964121933A8A89BA9C96B1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall carry out research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities to advance the following:</text>
<paragraph id="HF35705F399204BF9B0A3A648303D301F"><enum>(1)</enum><text> Clean hydrogen production, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="H45661D408B4F448B9EEFE5C24C32D551"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Production from water splitting, including the following:</text>
<clause id="H3725529F377B49CCAE32E87F3B550925"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Fresh, salt, and, wastewater and steam electrolysis using low-emission electricity sources.</text></clause> <clause id="H26C75FD820C348909F393E31F6EFBCF1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Development of catalysts using alternatives to rare earth metals.</text></clause>
<clause id="HBCF6A85D867443A883966A0F154F01B2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Thermochemical water splitting using low-emission power sources.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5F7E37E3CA144E71AC5BD2EF8AFBEBF9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Production from biomass and organic carbon waste conversion, which may include biomass-derived liquid reformation and biomass gasification with a focus on the following:</text>
<clause id="H9EAFE341ACED434B82FE9AC9F1D78702"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Optimizing processes and addressing challenges related to different biomass feedstock characteristics, including biomass and waste blends.</text></clause> <clause id="H930441F28A1D4E529272A9A6C734BB7B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Improvement of energy conversion efficiency.</text></clause>
<clause id="HD93A4D7E27CE4DC3B8DF4E3F6A6A2671"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Development and optimization of catalysts for given feedstocks.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HAF33086F5D8B4ACE9F38B445C047E6CE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Production from a direct hydrogen carrier, such as ammonia or methanol with carbon capture and sequestration, and liquid organic hydrogen carriers.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H49C032A9C5554AFE8112BB0B790C95C8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Biological hydrogen production, which may include the following:</text> <clause id="H2BD7899E047A4CBFAB96EFEFA46891E4"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Dark or photo-assisted fermentation.</text></clause>
<clause id="H6DB6B6E7910B49588A89B134390565BD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Microbial electrolysis.</text></clause> <clause id="H95A5495E5C4B4EF5813A07D96D346416"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Bio- or bio-inspired photolysis.</text></clause>
<clause id="HE04FCF2275374A6B8D750EDAD76D9B04"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Hybrid systems combining multiple bio- or bio-inspired processes.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA648B6D109094EE98933B9893B276F17"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Production from hydrocarbons to carbon-free hydrogen or to hydrogen with carbon capture and sequestration, which may include the following:</text>
<clause id="HCD262F34194443E7B09A221FB7745023"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Development of nonprecious and nontoxic metal catalysts and electrodes.</text></clause> <clause id="HFBF7F58782C84B4085542258175B6CC6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Development of effective reactor design.</text></clause>
<clause id="H3478B89F8423431D8E9744E2CD6CAF2E"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Use of heat from noncombustion source.</text></clause> <clause id="H1B8409EDE5AA419480FE435C03A108D9"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Development of advanced materials of construction for improved reactor performance and lifetimes and reduced capital costs.</text></clause>
<clause id="H16CEA5A66EB940A080FBC0AFE4090007"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Reduction of water usage.</text></clause> <clause id="HE497D6A2F6FF4C9F9CAD7BF11A15E2B7"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Development of catalytic processes to convert natural gas to carbon-free hydrogen and solid carbon materials.</text></clause>
<clause id="H9A31000002FB4F3998989782379C72A3"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Development of suitable treatment of waste by-products.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H316CDC01726148699F729280CAFC7FAA"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Production of clean hydrogen at a place of consumption where demand from many use cases can be satisfied, including airports supplying air-side aircraft, support vehicles, and ground-side services for hydrogen electric buses, trucks, and cars.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H2730F5E8F049482D814CA70274B2FBF8"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Production from nuclear power and heat, including from advanced nuclear reactors.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HEAE60901DD4147AD9375C2B26EFB9E59"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Production from renewable energy sources.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA701BA015B8F4424B0B05A98D8EC1189"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Production of hydrogen carriers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H08D7A49B7A27484B85228BE14450A38C"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Production from integrated energy systems (as such term is defined in section 1310 of the Energy Independence and Security Act of 2007 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/17387">42 U.S.C. 17387</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HDCA5B5766DBC4D22A9B4DE3F0CF49AFB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Hydrogen storage, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HF35A757ADE204CD1832A4556E88A3F4F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Gas compression and liquefaction, including improving liquefaction efficiency.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1A9EC9C5811D47789E9228DBEC56BF1B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Chemical storage, including the following:</text> <clause id="H76B96B4E9E684FB2AED27043CFEFA71F"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Porous materials.</text></clause>
<clause id="H19855152CC2E4E4885842C4E5C89080F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Liquid hydrogen carriers, which may include the following:</text> <subclause id="HC3CDCB33D9D44AAF8D01A4EB710C76C1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Liquid organic hydrogen carriers with needed improvement of the chemistry of dehydrogenation through catalyst development.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HE28D87300EA1473299E58E658B56F708"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Liquid ammonia with needed improvement of the fundamental chemistry of dehydrogenation and hydrogen purity after dehydrogenation.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H2BD08E56333C41C8A8A57160C54A37DD"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Diverse physical storage methodologies for hydrogen, including liquid hydrogen, hydrogen carriers, and hydrogen blends in the form of a solid, liquid, or gas, including distribution tanks, on site storage, storage onboard vehicles, and geologic storage.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8A2B8A755D4F456E8381FA0C9B8D4BB6"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Development of advanced storage materials and systems for large-scale hydrogen storage, including long-duration storage, with a focus on low-cost, ambient-temperature, and high-energy density materials and systems.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HCBEA6E7F33024B8CB50682AE3A4EA1CD"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Assessment of regional geology, including seismic assessments, infrastructure requirements, and materials of construction for the storage of hydrogen in geologic formations, including salt domes, caverns, depleted oil gas reservoirs, aquifers, surface porous media, and natural gas storage sites.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H13C65891A17949008D77E8B8233A63AF" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Assessment of hydrogen and hydrogen blend storage processes, including physical, chemical, and biological processes within geological formations, that could impact the longevity and reversibility of geologic storage.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC55054628D354164A33D616CB2EA3D11"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Development of advanced tools and technologies to convert or transform natural gas geologic storage sites into hydrogen storage sites.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAF3EB5E78A1443A6AC77068E74C5DC7C"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Metal hydride materials, such as magnesium-containing systems with a focus on the following:</text> <clause id="H4F60771834F94AE496213061B2686672"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Improvement of kinetics of hydrogen uptake and release.</text></clause>
<clause id="H71A099D66DAD43919F86EA6B072B37A1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Decreasing working temperatures, to ambient or near ambient conditions.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB2FD305237046058E768C120961F8A3"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Hydrogen transportation, delivery, and fueling infrastructure, including the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="HF70EB57DC899436C8D1650103D777439"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Improvement in energy efficiency, maintenance of hydrogen purity, and minimization of potential hydrogen leakage, including from hydrogen carriers.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB5994AE22F014017A8D387EE47101E94"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Advancing a diverse range of distribution methods, including transmission by pipeline, transmission of liquid hydrogen carriers, and transmission of hydrogen blends.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1E64FF5DD83B432BBC791E823A007759"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Advancing the feasibility of retrofitting or the modification of existing energy infrastructure, including existing natural gas transportation infrastructure, for the purpose of transportation and storage of significant quantities of hydrogen and hydrogen blends.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7331489F0F3C40EDA80B48AB6E0C3B5E"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Development and improvement of hydrogen and hydrogen fuel specific sensor technologies to detect and mitigate potential risks.</text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6907DB88F33C4917A79871B21BC2C0FE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Clean hydrogen utilization, including the following:</text> <subparagraph id="HFF72C08B362E4100B2B4F0856F1C539E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Power generation utilization, including the retrofit or development of hydrogen fueled turbines, reversible fuel cells or hybrid cycle fuel cells, and hydrogen blends for power applications.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBB4342ADAD0041A8A61D6A52B3F02849"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Energy storage, including the development of long-term energy storage systems for grid, back-up power, microgrid and other applications.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H07E77F9615CB41B69D3497605D2D23F3"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Transportation fuel utilization.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE7F8A8A4079F496DBB90D1D1132E71B6"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Industrial utilization, including the utilization of hydrogen and hydrogen blends for diverse applications.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H331DC6B6D14D43498EFBB60E7D9E64D3"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Agricultural utilization.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9EB26E04D244439E83DAECB0AFCE0E40"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Other applications, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H749FCD769E894A369FFB878A4F927B7A"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Advanced manufacturing technologies and methods for clean hydrogen and hydrogen-related technologies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA4BF465D8654E55B0C5DC81D0F55C3F"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Hydrogen carrier recycling and reuse.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA326F7D8C944849938CE61A1825C1D3"><enum>(7)</enum><text>Safe, durable, and affordable materials for clean hydrogen, hydrogen carrier, and hydrogen-related technologies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAC16691A33B048CFBE28DD6E9FDD283A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Advanced technologies and methods for safe hydrogen transportation, distribution, and utilization, such as hydrogen infrastructure monitoring and controls and combustion characterization technologies.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H183C056813BD4DF487FA2AF28F086863"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Other research areas that advance the purposes of the program, as determined by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H00A6332076C04705BB7FDAD4D644B546" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Fuel cell research, development, and demonstration</header>
<paragraph id="HA3E6E4953F3D4FE795224EB4E4BD4DC1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out with the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall support research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities to advance fuel cell technologies for transportation and stationary applications with a focus on reducing fuel cell system cost and improving overall system efficiency and durability over a wide range of operating conditions.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6C18412DD03F4D9CB63194BEAB63DA38"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Tools, technologies, and methods</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (1), the Secretary shall develop tools, technologies, and methods for the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H9E7B1D0C0E3D46A680A94447D987B45E" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Fuel cell durability, which may include the following:</text> <clause id="H80182BDF6A2E40AEA412AC116BC26461" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Improving understanding of catalyst and membrane degradation and mitigating performance degradation, including at high and low power conditions.</text></clause>
<clause id="H3D0AE0ACD0A64F2CA81C86A9BFF6CA15" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Improving fuel cell tolerance to air, fuel, and system-derived impurities.</text></clause> <clause id="HD3F9134364404C3B8ADD80219E301B61" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Improving stationary fuel cells to achieve greater than 80,000 hours of durability, including improving durability under start-up and transient operation for high-temperature fuel cells.</text></clause>
<clause id="HE4E3D788C68B4A9D997084B08659A68F" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Improving fundamental understanding of failure mechanisms to develop mitigation strategies.</text></clause> <clause id="H6CF48CBCC5F341BF9880D3D6359158E7" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Activities to update and accelerate testing protocols to enable projection of durability.</text></clause>
<clause id="HDA13540B4E674563BFE4004F55281612" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Improving system balance-of-plant component efficiency, responsiveness, adaptation to fuel cell aging conditions, reactant’s impurity, environmental variability, and durability.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H7EE9278E8E7A4A6D8EC82B47D390053A" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>Development of lower cost fuel cell materials, components, and assemblies.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H19384DE154C2480FB9AC5C21EAA09D92" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>Fuel cell performance, which may include research to improve the performance and efficiency of the following:</text> <clause id="HE30B57AC49334FC0855396232E12CBB8" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Cathodes.</text></clause>
<clause id="HA8568792FDA14B4E8EEABE648B43CB28" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Water quality controls.</text></clause> <clause id="HCE6212D403184610BAA211E2AE6E6BAD" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Stack water management, including membranes in fuel cells to enable effective water management and operation in low humidity and subfreezing environments.</text></clause>
<clause id="H2597458ACB0E4E8FB832A630DB5FCF8C" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>System thermal and water management, including research to improve the following:</text> <subclause id="H26450937D4294EA7A0DAD244FBCB5F88" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Heat utilization, cooling, and humidification techniques.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="HB9C709C0E0084FD99F561EB303CDE399" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text>Efficiency of heat recovery systems, system designs, advanced heat exchangers, and higher temperature operation of current systems.</text></subclause> <subclause id="H6216B39D838B417C9F8ED427569D7671" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><text>Techniques to manage water during start-up and shutdown at subfreezing temperatures.</text></subclause>
<subclause id="H88C9A3C3C7014A05A779593F95CDD664" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>Management of nonuniform conditions caused by variable thermal and current density gradients.</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H773D8C87E1294A59AA802E97E2661AFC" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>System air management.</text></clause>
<clause id="H86C18C2B5AA3479285A5613766D93677" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>System start-up and shutdown time and transient operation.</text></clause> <clause id="HF3B0E5D6C7B04549AC02BF44CB622350" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Utilizing direct hydrogen carriers, such as ammonia, methane, and methanol.</text></clause>
<clause id="HCE24CF3169BF45C4889C9DD6C4584DAC" commented="no"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>Reversible fuel cells.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H28588483E2074DFA8C0FCDB01D6E24C6" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>Catalyst and electrode design, which may include the following:</text>
<clause id="HFAA8FED8102A4F96978BB1BB0CA12D65" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Developing catalysts that reduce or eliminate platinum-group metal loading while maintaining or improving upon performance and durability.</text></clause> <clause id="H99B3399B31F8438C84B126AD1E51967C" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Increasing durability and stability of catalysts during potential cycling.</text></clause>
<clause id="HDF0AB1A23CBC4BC78E8EE8CF6D20BF65" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Increasing tolerance of catalysts to air, fuel, and other system derived impurities.</text></clause> <clause id="H4E1942F9B67441EBB3FB9FC2C1BFECA6" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Increasing catalyst utilization.</text></clause>
<clause id="H36609277B7CA4676B7BDD2FBC12C083F" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Developing catalysts and catalyst support with high durability at high voltages.</text></clause> <clause id="HB117DF9DC43B4E09B594E7301A706F81" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Design and demonstration of scalable production of novel catalysts.</text></clause>
<clause id="HBBD66C4067074709BF90FB015E4F0C92" commented="no"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>Optimization of electrode design and assembly for efficient water and thermal management.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H481A5545A9204F3B9B889FBA1C3F472D" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>Electrolyte synthesis and development.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HA84E555A8B0D4FDBBE0807370E298E92" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Fuel cell membrane development, including polymer electrolyte member and alkaline electrolyte member development.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H069D4322601D436282144FB8C74A2C87" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>Membrane electrode materials, assemblies, cells, and other stack components, including demonstration of small-scale production of novel membrane electrode assemblies.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HBBE2F8797C9E4F2AB219E3E8E8CFBE15" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Solid oxide fuel cell development, including the following:</text> <clause id="H09442431857240AEB144263DB1128421" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Cell development on individual cell components that increases power density, reduces degradation, and reduces costs.</text></clause>
<clause id="H7D37D5663A374CC499E93D1282A23F85" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Balance-of-plant and stack components that improve reliability and robustness and reduce degradation and costs.</text></clause> <clause id="H01D3BA9ABA014779B16B4CE4023636A4" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Systems development.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H9972B00627EB4FA593BDE03395549026" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>Protonic ceramic fuel cell development.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B63E517289E43309EFB2CF5EB645B7B" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>Other research areas that advance the purposes of the program, as determined by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HCF27DBDBC0BA412C94D1584421630C83" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Testing and validation</header><text>In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary, in consultation with the Director of the National Institute of Standards and Technology, shall support the development of standardized testing and technical validation of hydrogen and hydrogen-related technologies, including fuel cell technologies, through collaboration with one or more National Laboratories, and one or more eligible entities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HF7AA889DDB8546E18D4D182E42E1020C" commented="no"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Leveraging</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall leverage resources and expertise from across the Department, including the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H303622BE6B674F8E9479CFEE5D8E1EB2" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The Office of Energy Efficiency and Renewable Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEA79BC4E65024657996B18594480B117" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>The Basic Energy Sciences Program, Advanced Scientific Computing Research Program, and the Biological and Environmental Research Program of the Office of Science.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H0029C14844014C3085FD5DA74DD16FDB" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The Office of Fossil Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7C8CD958727B40EFBFC3433C663C2D77" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>The Office of Nuclear Energy.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H699BF8D3A9C2407590DC47D54C59AD9F" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The Advanced Research Projects Agency—Energy.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4B1F4EEEEF074EFC97FFF405C360490D" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text>The Office of Clean Energy Demonstrations.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H78455FE71E004A53B1F970C34FDDC431" commented="no"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Standard of review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under subsection (a), the Secretary shall periodically determine the status of achievement of the comprehensive set of technical milestones referred to in subsection (b).</text></subsection></section> <section id="H980EB7EE15E54C909D04BDEB186A50C8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Clean hydrogen demonstration projects</header> <subsection id="HF803382A38524A67B8DD0CF1961355D4" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In carrying out the program under section 3, the Secretary shall establish a demonstration program under which the Secretary, through a competitive merit review process, shall select eligible entities to carry out not more than six demonstration projects that involve clean hydrogen and hydrogen-related technologies.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HA8F0F5EF087D4BAFA675A86BEB9FA8DB"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Project criteria</header><text>Of the demonstration programs carried out pursuant to subsection (a), two shall be designed as clean hydrogen hybrid use demonstration projects that—</text> <paragraph id="HDB4BF8D5688046A587691A5DE4800D24" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>demonstrate configurations of different commercial and preproduction hydrogen with wind, solar, nuclear, fossil, or other energy technologies for combined use, including evaluation and modeling of performance under load demands relevant to urban and rural communities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H02088AAD8053445F84722A0D22BEBAB2"><enum>(2)</enum><text>serve as an incubator for novel energy technologies and the combined use of such technologies.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H5708A5F52B614A369A91FDABAABC72A4"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Selection requirements</header><text>In selecting eligible entities for the demonstration programs carried out pursuant to subsection (a), the Secretary shall, to the maximum extent practicable—</text>
<paragraph id="HAB6771BB952D4C1A9EE5E7674D5C8058"><enum>(1)</enum><text>encourage regional diversity among eligible entities, including participation by such entities located in rural States;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3A000017E87A4C798D0613DA38456A39"><enum>(2)</enum><text>encourage technological diversity among eligible entities;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE6A3452DEACF488B89BD467E8F7F9E71"><enum>(3)</enum><text>ensure that selected demonstration programs are coordinated with and expand on existing technology demonstration programs of the Department;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4880F5957C9A4EBE8A0B3A07BA72AB88"><enum>(4)</enum><text>prioritize demonstration programs that leverage and are complementary to existing energy infrastructure, such as existing power plants and power installations, fleet vehicle centers, microgrids, or industrial facilities; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H4B8F10EED032444B943DAC082D02168E"><enum>(5)</enum><text>prioritize demonstration programs that leverage matching funds from non-Federal sources.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H821EB381B15047299AE547878AD88966"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>From amounts authorized to be appropriated pursuant to section 9, $30,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 shall be made available to the Secretary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="HD49BB34E429047659648FA5BB2C31A6C"><enum>5.</enum><header>Hydrogen Innovation Center</header>
<subsection id="HA1A4455F18164A7B94272A5C6FDB4D71" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Operation</header>
<paragraph id="H1121F8FCE4324757B762B2FBA238B878"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program under section 3, the Secretary, in accordance with paragraph (2), shall operate through the Office of Science of the Department a national Hydrogen Innovation Center (referred to in this section as the <quote>Center</quote>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H761264718F494D5C80DCAA733851A998" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Selection; administration</header> <subparagraph id="H16D0D21E60DA43CBBF7B3BC491CA27E0"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall select on a competitive, merit-reviewed basis, an entity to administer the Center. In making such selection, the Secretary shall solicit and consider applications from such entities.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEB523677A0124E19821D7A8D35846933"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Entity defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>entity</quote> means a National Laboratory, an institution of higher education, a Federal research agency, a multi-institutional collaboration, or other appropriate entity (as determined by the Secretary).</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H06F657448D904E1C873EB38AD27E9EB1"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Focus</header><text>The Center shall focus on fundamental research and development activities, including the following:</text>
<subparagraph id="H73AE7A0A606149839CD64EE6431E3351" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Theory, modeling, and simulation of the following:</text> <clause id="H8F5513C6EC32468D984DC12B8AD9A59A" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The physics and chemistry of multi-scale hydrogen interactions.</text></clause>
<clause id="HA2292BFD50A54D4685A54E91A60E883E" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The behavior of hydrogen fuel cell membranes.</text></clause> <clause id="H2374D5E68EB34EE39DF661F9ED951E02" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>Catalytic pathways for hydrogen production.</text></clause>
<clause id="HCA96F6A0A5E6499883543935577AEB3E" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Photochemical processes and complex photoredox systems.</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H208A70462E5A41D0882CDFB0C10C320E" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The development of analytical tools to characterize and predict hydrogen-materials interactions.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HD87B1C5585864A2AABE90672BCE6F5C9" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The potential physical, chemical, and biological effects of geologic hydrogen storage.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1B83839F21C04042B2555004BFC5C142" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The development of advanced computer modeling to design different configurations of energy systems and optimize systems operations for clean hydrogen production in different electricity markets.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H25CEE19B6E2C434C9830EFDBC6D799F7" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><text>The development of novel fuel cell membranes and integrated nanoscale architectures for hydrogen fuel cell technologies.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H562972D2BAFE4DE2A729B5322DDF6823" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><text>Advanced catalytic research and design, with considerations given to nanoscale catalysts, enzyme catalysts, biocatalysts, catalyst-solid carbon separation, and innovative synthetic techniques.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H90D000ADEF7C4554A54C04E48CA7D8FE" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><text>The advancement of organic semiconductors for photovoltaic and photocatalytic applications.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HF0170CB425E344EBABBD8F59B7425A91" commented="no"><enum>(H)</enum><text>Examination of the molecular mechanisms of biological hydrogen production.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H8475BC6A1D3F4CAA8689F387C34A4EF8" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The development of bio-hybrid systems scalable to hydrogen production facilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0FE1D2FB5C3E4F9DB9592DDDB51740E5" commented="no"><enum>(J)</enum><text>The development of novel materials for hydrogen storage, including chemical storage with complex hydrides and nanostructured materials, with a focus on the following:</text>
<clause id="HCB56B43301524E40AB42EEF547EC18F5" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Improvement of kinetics of hydrogen absorption and desorption.</text></clause> <clause id="HF11F24BEF0EA4A0C88723E9DFBB92C8B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Decreasing working temperatures.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HE3067D525B9A4362BF1EF939AE0CDB49" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Duration</header><text>The Center shall receive support for a period of not more than five years, subject to the availability of appropriations.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H8A0DA227F4474261AB175B074FA0C8E1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Renewal</header><text>Upon the expiration of any period of support of the Center, the Secretary may renew such support, on a merit-reviewed basis, for a period of not more than five years.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="HF3BF7C495116491F8BFB87F06DE900A1" commented="no"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Termination</header><text>Consistent with existing authorities of the Department, the Secretary may terminate the Center for cause during any period of support.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HE683B086E9D8416F87D196DA1851211C"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>Of amounts authorized to be appropriated to the Office of Science, $15,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027 shall be made available to the Secretary to carry out this section.</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H6792971EE0B444BFA6A4CC26CBD59E36"><enum>6.</enum><header>Study to examine research pathways for hydrogen production with net-zero greenhouse gas emissions</header>
<subsection id="HC8B2B89B839347168BD05E850CF4F4ED"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary shall enter into an agreement with the National Academies of Sciences, Engineering, and Medicine (referred to in this section as the <quote>National Academies</quote>) under which the National Academies shall conduct a study to examine research pathways for hydrogen production processes with net-zero direct and indirect greenhouse gas emissions as a part of a low-carbon energy future. Such study shall—</text> <paragraph id="HAE9A2CDA80B34362B7D8F4243CEF2E56"><enum>(1)</enum><text>analyze and assess research needed to leverage potential contributions of hydrogen production processes with net-zero direct and indirect greenhouse gas emissions;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H278801EBC82B4E458DADFF325842473C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>examine lifecycle impacts of such processes on energy consumption and emissions; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBF5D6906660446558CA4724DC90F8C9B"><enum>(3)</enum><text>identify additional research activities and provide recommendations to support net direct and indirect greenhouse gas emission reductions across hydrogen production processes, including research to address—</text>
<subparagraph id="HD65B0BD62E3E451D8CACB48BB09E2526"><enum>(A)</enum><text>potential environmental impacts associated with hydrogen production using new and existing evaluation metrics, including lifecycle impacts on local and regional air and water quality and estimates of hazardous air pollutants impacts on and benefits to United States communities, including urban, small, rural, Tribal, and disadvantaged communities;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8825519FF20341E992EB34FE87CF9AE6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>infrastructure challenges;</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H436ACA5D9C064A36A74DCC100D3A8DE9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>scientific and technical barriers to achieve greater net greenhouse gas emission reductions in present and future production processes; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H3CBB61A42F9843D5894E30C4BA085C31"><enum>(D)</enum><text>socioeconomic costs and benefits of zero-carbon liquid fuel production and use systems, including fiscal, monetized health, and job impacts.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HF0A053C716F44C7C95B88C97A436ACF1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report</header><text>The agreement entered into under subsection (a) shall include a requirement that the National Academies, not later than 24 months after the date of the enactment of this Act, submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report on the results of the study conducted pursuant to such agreement.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HC16151DD30AF4D24AE203127EFCE3734"><enum>7.</enum><header>Reporting</header> <subsection id="H3EE6766062DB412188B713AB5D4EDFCC" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Technologies developed</header><text>Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and every two years thereafter through 2027, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report regarding the technologies and knowledge developed and demonstrated as a result of the program carried out under section 3 with a particular emphasis on whether such technologies were successfully adopted for commercial applications, and if so, whether the supply chains of such technologies are domestic.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2F02A8C2F37E4105B585F8153AB0F160"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Additional matters</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than two years after the date of the enactment of this Act and every two years thereafter through 2027, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Science, Space, and Technology of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate a report describing activities undertaken pursuant to this Act, including relating to the following:</text> <paragraph id="H15553A32671C4CEBB03B75D68A96465A"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The status of public-private partnerships.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H58B944A75C6741E4B99D8B78535AE389" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Progress of such activities in meeting goals and timelines.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7EE176D07BE14518A48D6A40A3CAE03A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>The status of demonstration projects.</text></paragraph></subsection></section>
<section id="H647D176D25214D9C916EA62D39BCFC18"><enum>8.</enum><header>Additional provisions</header>
<subsection id="H2F7AF3F27D52489E891DB08FFB5665D2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Education and outreach</header><text>In carrying out the program under section 3, the Secretary shall support and expand education and outreach activities to disseminate information relating to hydrogen and fuel cell energy technologies and the hydrogen and fuel cell energy workforce.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H28503067963346918134063B7F68DCBF" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Technical assistance</header><text>In carrying out the program under section 3, the Secretary shall provide technical assistance and analyze activities for eligible entities to support the commercial application of advances in hydrogen and fuel cell energy systems development and operations, which may include activities that support expanding access to advanced clean hydrogen and fuel cell energy technologies for rural, Tribal, and disadvantaged communities.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H927E67F80EF44D0B93EED97DDBBE180E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Public-Private partnerships</header><text>In carrying out the activities described in this Act, the Secretary shall pursue partnerships with private industry, private foundations, and other appropriate private entities to—</text> <paragraph id="H29723D1C304348B1A33FDEB27F8BB96B" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>ensure the United States maintains technological competitiveness in developing advanced clean hydrogen and fuel cell technologies;</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCB4F19D2F478475F9ABC15779392215D" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>enhance the impact and advancement of the hydrogen economy investments and contributions to United States economic competitiveness and security; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9BD6FB2DF3AB47B5BC2189CE351708A6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make available infrastructure, expertise, and financial resources to the United States hydrogen and fuel cell technologies scientific and engineering research and education enterprise.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7F85B6AE543944CBA65D4B95FF1E9242"><enum>(d)</enum><header>International hydrogen energy development</header><text>In carrying out the program under section 3, the Secretary, in coordination with the heads of other appropriate Federal and multilateral agencies (including the United States Agency for International Development) shall support collaborative efforts with international partners to facilitate and accelerate the transition to clean and efficient energy and mobility systems using fuel cells and hydrogen technologies through research, development, demonstration, and commercial application activities.</text></subsection> <subsection id="HD51DBE7238EC4D2A8775FF26356FDE91"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the maximum extent practicable, the Secretary shall carry out the program under section 3 in coordination with other relevant programs and capabilities of the Department and other Federal research programs, including activities authorized in sections 803, 805, and 808 of the Energy Policy Act of 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/16152">42 U.S.C. 16152</external-xref>, 16154, and 16157) and in subtitle B of title III of division D of the Infrastructure Investment and Jobs Act (PL 117–58).</text></subsection></section>
<section id="H7B00C29FD469458E8CDB64C8C8178782"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary for research, development, demonstration, and commercial application of hydrogen and fuel cell energy systems, and other related technologies in the United States, including to carry out this Act, the following:</text> <paragraph id="H7C137F8DEAC842CBA657AA5513AF9C12"><enum>(1)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2023, $161,160,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HCDB14C292EA043468CAF2BEC085248FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2024, $164,383,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DB5E904F4E2461487EEAF91ACD64E65"><enum>(3)</enum><text>For fiscal year 2025, $167,670,000.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H52565D10CA8A4C89BCCA5E9239B0353E"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2026, $171,024,000.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H270164AD58F24FC3B751EC001178EBB4"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For fiscal year 2027, $174,444,480.</text></paragraph></section>
</legis-body>
</bill> 


