<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4417219D60A64CBEAB0705580CE928B4" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6896 IH: Reduce Exposure and the Threat of Unused Residual Narcotics Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6896</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220302">March 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="F000450">Ms. Foxx</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Controlled Substances Act to improve consumer take-back programs by allowing persons who are authorized to collect controlled substances from ultimate users and other non-registrants for destruction through an authorized consumer return program to open and inspect packages, to provide a secure method of transporting substances to another location of destruction, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H134F60677576419389A1DDCD017F8B50" style="OLC"><section id="H6934CF8D6383434EAD7E7B59292C3547" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Reduce Exposure and the Threat of Unused Residual Narcotics Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>RETURN Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H789E9FDEF8334C52954F73640ED570A1"><enum>2.</enum><header>Inspection of packages of controlled substances received through mail-back disposal program</header><subsection id="H1F52B31CED774E3B94B8887388F7F13E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(g)(2) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/822">21 U.S.C. 822(g)(2)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HF3EF0A78F30A4C53979D555CF78B94D1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>by striking <quote>(2) In developing</quote> and inserting <quote>(2)(A) In developing</quote>;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H609A5DD639214712987FE6C5CB15E504"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by striking <quote>Such regulations may not</quote> and inserting the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HCA39B4833FD74D6DB055683EE1F46B91" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="HB43907A404D549DBA46F8C5D95D1A3F1" indent="up2"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such regulations may not</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="HED2C41D00DEE41DAAF2C9589E58F9A37"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HD1D3721EB9BE48EBAF92F82FDCF1B9FD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H5AF9F7856FDE466EB0EC32AB3BC44701" indent="up2"><enum>(C)</enum><clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5E1D09232F4A4ADD96B2CF20D3ABC51D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Such regulations shall allow persons who are authorized to collect controlled substances from ultimate users and other non-registrants for destruction through an authorized mail-back program under this subsection to open a package for identification of the contents of the package for purposes of a consumer incentive program.</text></clause><clause id="H013F37031ED741B68A5B8C061333F3A9" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this subparagraph, the term <term>consumer incentive program</term> means a program providing ultimate users who return unused controlled substances through a person described in clause (i) a financial or other incentive that is determined based on the contents of the returned materials.</text></clause></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H62D1DB1BE95C422E82A40057DFCAA679"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General of the United States shall finalize such revisions to regulations as may be necessary to carry out section 302(g)(2)(C) of the Controlled Substances Act, as added by subsection (a), including by revising section 1317.70(f) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="HED9A11681855423292244C5AA0FAB171"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 302(g)(2)(C) of the Controlled Substances Act, as added by subsection (a), applies beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="HD4D221A2F28E4204B7065ECC5AA1B69E"><enum>3.</enum><header>Option of transporting controlled substances received through mail-back disposal program to another location for destruction</header><subsection id="H3E113B63A9D34926BBE7EDEC645EBC99"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302(g)(2) of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/822">21 U.S.C. 822(g)(2)</external-xref>), as amended by section 2, is further amended by adding at the end the following subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H9FD609FEDC0C41F8A0B70517A06927C6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subparagraph id="H71EDDFCCFE1B4475A32A89F4C61847B2" indent="up2"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Such regulations shall give persons who are authorized to collect controlled substances from ultimate users and other non-registrants for destruction through an authorized mail-back program under this subsection, in lieu of having and utilizing at their registered location an authorized method of destruction, the option of providing a secure method of transporting such substances to a location of destruction consistent with applicable regulations.</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="HC2D3C8F8367A41E6BF527C6D1B3F6AD5"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Regulations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Attorney General of the United States shall finalize such revisions to regulations as may be necessary to carry out section 302(g)(2)(D) of the Controlled Substances Act, as added by subsection (a), including by revising section 1317.70(a) of title 21, Code of Federal Regulations.</text></subsection><subsection id="H396D714946534C54845EB5AF98EAA6B5"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applicability</header><text>Section 302(g)(2)(D) of the Controlled Substances Act, as added by subsection (a), applies beginning on the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

