<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA397E186800C4786AF81FA76164BE082" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9511 IH: Black Sea Security Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-13</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9511</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221213">December 13, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="T000463">Mr. Turner</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001165">Mr. Sires</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001193">Mr. Swalwell</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To provide for security in the Black Sea region, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H9126B310BB1E4E94B9362BEF8718FCCE" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H8FFCD53C79DA4D08B5F165D85314D504" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Black Sea Security Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="HF1123F7408BB4EE9906C3D7AC54EBEBA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress makes the following findings:</text> 
<paragraph id="H3DD15983309B4CC2831E2A0A2457C365"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Black Sea region is of critical importance to the national security of six nations: Ukraine, Georgia, Moldova, Romania, Bulgaria, and Turkey.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3DBF04C3B78C42EE9D18B2B44749A864"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Black Sea region has been a zone of increasing tension and conflict on the eastern border of the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) following President Vladimir Putin’s 2014 and 2022 invasions of Ukraine and 2008 invasion of Georgia, which still has territories illegally occupied by the Russian Federation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H0E2BEB94E54F4B819959DB52969412EE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since the illegal attempted annexation of Ukraine’s Crimea region in 2014, the Russian Federation has enhanced the Black Sea Fleet to increase its presence in the region, enhanced its air and coastal defenses, disregarded international law regarding freedom of navigation to interrupt in regular shipping routes, and threatened freedom of navigation exercises in the Black Sea.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H10EE346D9F81488C91AB8562B2E94E86"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since its military interventions in the Black Sea region starting in 2008, the Russian Federation has undertaken persistent hybrid measures to further destabilize the region through malign influence campaigns.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H40C58B4ED49B452B91C623D02E77DE04"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Since the 2022 invasion of Ukraine by the Russian Federation, the unity among Black Sea countries has strengthened, particularly among NATO member countries Romania, Bulgaria, and Turkey.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF5997A852D674A72B0A81146D6835ED4"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation is leveraging its illegal claim over Black Sea waters and the territories of Black Sea region states to execute military exercises to threaten the territorial sovereignty of Ukraine and kill innocent civilians.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H7BA8934DE707421DBD4923BD88CFB4EC"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russia has a long history of using its position in the Black Sea and Crimea to threaten NATO allies, including the HMS Defender incident of June 2021, when a British ship was harassed by Russian ships while undertaking a freedom of navigation patrol in waters near the Crimean Peninsula.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24F7FCD978E443F68439EA6561C3E427"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While NATO has conducted routine exercises in the region, the United States presence in the Black Sea has decreased since Russia’s annexation of Crimea due to competing security priorities among allies, a lack of available ships and resources, and a lack of a clearly defined regional strategy.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H4E37C2A14551442BBF08360E0199747B"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While, in February 2022, Turkey blocked the entry of Russian warships into the Black Sea pursuant to the Convention regarding the Regime of the Straits, signed at Montreux, Switzerland July 20, 1936 (commonly known as the <quote>Montreux Convention</quote>), the Montreux Convention does not account for the increase in size, weight, and capabilities of modern warships, and Russia does not have the same limits on tonnage as non-littoral states.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBC0A42A780A94C669C485C79D09D456B"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Turkey has resisted attempts to change its interpretation of the Montreux Convention to avoid weakening their position in the region.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H9B87006AD59B49A59204758B1CDBCD31"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">While NATO has long recognized the strategic importance of the Black Sea, Russia has sought to capitalize on at times divergent priorities among NATO members in the region to advance expansionist claims.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H949D583EE8BC4E8F880C1A798776E586"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On February 24, 2022, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin instigated an unprovoked, unjustified, and unlawful war violating the territorial integrity of the sovereign country of Ukraine and is using the Russian Federation’s military presence on the Black Sea to kill innocent Ukrainian civilians.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H8D1B6574C0054AC69C253DF05BFF57EE"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation’s unprovoked war on Ukraine has underscored the importance of the Black Sea region to United States national security interests.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H277CCA7053124B4C967393E77597A625"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation’s unprovoked war has caused a food security crisis as 20,000,000–30,000,000 tons of Ukrainian grain remain unable to leave Ukraine in an efficient and secure manner. The war has also impeded Ukraine’s ability to produce and transport next year’s harvest.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF2D72755BE6B470CBAB7074B3F0DB7C6"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Russian Federation’s actions in and around the Black Sea have also disrupted secure, reliable access to energy resources throughout Europe. Notably, Gazprom suspended natural gas supplies to Poland and Bulgaria on April 27, 2022, after the two countries refused to abide by a March 31, 2022, Russian decree that all payments be made in rubles, in violation of the terms of their contracts with Gazprom.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5BE3550B143A44E5AA0262E4D3C9BFE4"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The People’s Republic of China (PRC)’s coercive economic policies also threaten the economic stability of the Black Sea region.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="HFDBBB79E6D5140659388B75E7AFCA665"><enum>3.</enum><header>Sense of Congress on Black Sea security</header> 
<subsection id="HFA6720742200479F8F71F2CCFC174E40"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that—</text> <paragraph id="H6E6B9D3290994AA0A89957B678B80F76"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is in the interest of the United States to prevent the spread of further armed conflict in Europe by recognizing the Black Sea region as an arena of Russian aggression;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H97FE4DFDFF484569ADD529D08CEE9DA3"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the littoral members of the Black Sea are critical in countering aggression by the Government of the Russian Federation and maintaining the collective security of the NATO alliance;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5912D82D87024F6785D51F88236FA8AE"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the repeated, illegal, unprovoked, and violent attempts of the Russian Federation to expand its territory and control access to the Mediterranean through the Black Sea constitutes a threat to the national security of the United States and the NATO alliance;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H6DFA23A059784F8ABC3F4A4D35484CB8"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States condemns attempts by the Russian Federation to change or alter boundaries in the Black Sea region by any means contrary to international law;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2590F8B88E9B476D881262AFC0DDBEAB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States and its allies should robustly counter Russia’s illegal territorial claims on the Crimean Peninsula, along Ukraine’s territorial waters in the Black Sea and the Sea of Azov, in the Black Sea’s international waters, and in the territories it is illegally occupying in Ukraine;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H91F8370AA78948799D710505E3FD961E"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should continue to work within NATO and with NATO allies to develop a long-term strategy to enhance security, establish a permanent, sustainable presence in the eastern flank, and bolster the democratic resilience of its allies and partners in the region;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H0BDD565D0739429E83ACC5578ADBCCB2"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should also work with the European Union in coordinating a strategy to support democratic initiatives and economic prosperity in the region, which includes two European Union members and four aspirant nations;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB3E4A52098DA4894927EB8955F95BDCB"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should explore efforts to rebuild trust and bilateral relations with Turkey, a key ally in the Black Sea region and a bulwark against Iran;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HB5AF0B1F033C41C8AE8A080809C6B63B"><enum>(9)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is in the interest of the United States that NATO adopt a robust strategy toward the Black Sea, including by working with interested partner countries in the region to advance common security objectives;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H72B14C129D3943258AA973294EBBE101"><enum>(10)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should work to foster dialogue among countries within the Black Sea region to improve communication and intelligence sharing and increase cyber defense capabilities;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HF7BE65BDAD244810A691AFC1733F8F99"><enum>(11)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">countries with historic and economic ties to Russia are looking to the United States and Europe to provide a positive economic presence in the broader region as a counterbalance to the Russian Federation’s malign influence in the region;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HF0BD2AEAC69F47599B285A538A30BDB6"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">it is in the interest of the United States to support and bolster the economic ties between the United States and Black Sea partners;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC400571944484AB1B0B9A40367E843ED"><enum>(13)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States should support the initiative undertaken by central and eastern European states to advance the Three Seas Initiative Fund to strengthen transport, energy, and digital infrastructure connectivity in the region between the Adriatic Sea, Baltic Sea, and Black Sea;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H190687BF6FAD4282B7086DF87CEE7784"><enum>(14)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">there are mutually beneficial opportunities for increased investment and economic expansion, particularly on energy, climate, and transport infrastructure initiatives, between the United States and Black Sea states and the broader region;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7D90894CC55744558C05951810677C2C"><enum>(15)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">improved economic ties between the United States and the Black Sea states and the broader region can lead to a strengthened strategic partnership;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HA67D907A93BF422B8189E2C99ED3E2CB"><enum>(16)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States must address the food security challenges arising from closure of Ukraine’s Black Sea ports, as this global challenge will have critical national security implications for the United States, our partners, and allies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA6C6C881324F4A41AC71AEE726817DAB"><enum>(17)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Russia has a brutal history of using hunger as a weapon and must be stopped; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H5EFE348135D544BBA4BFCF5BBD1D6F67"><enum>(18)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">countering the PRC’s coercive economic pursuits remains an important policy imperative in order to further integrate the Black Sea countries into western economies and improve regional stability.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="HA16C1AD88D924C22A494E31CB81159F1"><enum>4.</enum><header>Report on United States policy toward the Black Sea region</header> <subsection id="H97B370692DC84FC7830EC4EED20DC379"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the National Security Council, in coordination with the Department of State, Department of Defense, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Commerce, the Department of Energy, the United States Agency for International Development, the Trade and Development Agency, the United States Export-Import Bank, the Department of Agriculture, and the United States International Development Finance Corporation, shall deliver to the appropriate congressional committees an interagency report that outlines current United States efforts and policy options toward Black Sea countries and the broader region and addresses the matters addressed in section 3, including NATO engagement in the region.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="H59A2F41070444CE18BBAA3BAED31151A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Elements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The report required under subsection (a) shall include the following elements:</text> <paragraph id="H8BBB6D4AC13A42988B893B616A1B1D6E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An overview of ongoing efforts by relevant United States Government agencies toward the Black Sea region, both through bilateral initiatives with Black Sea countries and any regional initiatives toward the region, to provide military and security assistance, economic support, and good governance initiatives.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H362EF254F9E44ACCB5B12EE79D0CC3AB"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A description of current efforts and policy options that can be undertaken by the Department of State, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the United States Export-Import Bank, the Trade and Development Agency, the Department of Energy, the Department of the Treasury, the Department of Commerce, and the Department of Agriculture to promote economic growth, integration, and quality infrastructure (including for energy integration and independence) in the Black Sea littoral states and the broader region.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBDCB2C0003084D9581C50559A7D2DE4E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A breakdown of initiatives to provide the following types of support, together with a breakdown of funding to support these efforts:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H97BF34F741344C45933CAFA2A7BB5632"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Military assistance, including infrastructure in support of enhanced deployments and supply logistics in the region.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0E1D2BA44EFC4EAE8363D85F29C90612"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Economic assistance, including support for the food security crisis.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H5A5B734584794E9DB578FBD2DD937213"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Countering Russian disinformation and propaganda in the Black Sea region.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9BCF421677DF4364A8D0440FF24EFD2A"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Energy diversification and regional market integration and supply to reduce dependence on energy from the Russian Federation and promote clean energy initiatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H8298FEAF2F43496DA4F4452374A397D2"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Using economic statecraft tools, such as trade and monetary policy, equity investments and debt financing and political risk insurance, to increase the United States bilateral trade and investment in the region and opportunities for near-shoring production in the broader region for the European market.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H889A84FFD7234E1DAEACBBEA16111868"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Fostering greater regional cooperation.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB2BCE44F45C54E80871E36ABAB711FAB"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing access to global capital markets and enhancement of local and regional sources of capital for critical infrastructure and other investments.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H87CEDC2CE1BA42688688B96826D79F56"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for helping United States allies in the region to accelerate their transitions from legacy Russian military equipment and promote NATO interoperability.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HFC15439146C941BF98AE7A50C5BED5F3"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Strengthening rule-of-law and anti-corruption efforts.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H20FA67233F2F4BFCA859035C0E357211"><enum>(J)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Addressing the PRC’s coercive economic actions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HAD91BD50D0774F789ED65F6A3E3A2E8A"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of NATO engagement in the region and policy options to address the changed regional security environment, including NATO’s presence in the region and an outline of NATO’s planned and recent military exercises in the region, in particular those under Headquarters Multinational Division Southeast (in Romania) and the four new battle groups in Romania, Bulgaria, Hungary, and Slovakia.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H838067338B0C48F98626DC760F0E0B84"><enum>5.</enum><header>United States policy</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the policy of the United States to—</text> 
<paragraph id="H2EC7181446EA47549556E0B5E405733D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">actively deter the threat of further Russian escalation in the Black Sea region and defend freedom of navigation in the Black Sea to prevent the spread of further armed conflict in Europe;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1AC3929F85044377A6F43C75E06FE036"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">advocate within NATO, among NATO allies, and within the European Union to develop a long-term coordinated strategy to enhance security, establish a permanent, sustainable presence in the eastern flank, and bolster the democratic resilience of United States allies and partners in the region;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H3B1B3B5353A84BCF98672055D27657BA"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">support and bolster the economic ties between the United States and Black Sea partners, and mobilize the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the Export-Import Bank, the Trade and Development Agency, the Department of State, the United States Agency for International Development, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of Commerce to increase United States presence and investment in Black Sea countries;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HECD7C0A956B54D70B824DDA3FCC02581"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide economic alternatives to the PRC’s coercive economic options that destabilize and further erode economic integration of the Black Sea littoral states;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H274A89277CF6498BBF3AC346BE935FDB"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure that the United States continues to support Black Sea countries to strengthen their democratic institutions to prevent corruption and accelerate their advancement into the Euroatlantic community; and</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H3BDFF6144A10429C90559DE9A394791F"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage the initiative undertaken by central and eastern European states to advance the Three Seas Initiative to strengthen transport, energy, and digital infrastructure connectivity in the region between the Adriatic Sea, Baltic Sea, and Black Sea.</text></paragraph></section> 
<section id="H89C49C66105746B4BE6C9C85E9BC45F9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Black Sea security and development strategy</header> 
<subsection id="HF3952EEC73354363B6E5DCF0673829EB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Black Sea development and security strategy</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than 360 days after the enactment of this Act, drawing from the policy options developed in the report in section 4, the National Security Council, in coordination with the Department of State, the Department of Defense, the United States International Development Finance Corporation, the United States Agency for International Development, the United States Export-Import Bank, the Trade and Development Agency the Department of Commerce, the Department of Energy, the Department of Agriculture, and the Department of the Treasury, shall direct an interagency strategy, based on the findings of the report under section 4, to increase military assistance and coordination with NATO and the European Union, deepen economic ties, strengthen economic and energy security and enhance security assistance with Black Sea countries, and support efforts to bolster their democratic resilience.</text></subsection> <subsection id="H2733D493CF384D20BE2BB3856393CC49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purpose and objectives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The initiative established under subsection (a) shall have the following goals and objectives:</text> 
<paragraph id="H24B2AFBA04834F0491B2947F4E24B659"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Ensuring the efficient and effective delivery of security assistance to the Black Sea states, prioritizing assistance that will bolster defenses against hybrid warfare and improve interoperability with NATO forces.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HFCE1282E7C934B5E80D49AD4427E2ED0"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Bolstering United States support for the region’s energy security and integration with Europe and reducing their dependence on Russia while supporting energy diversification.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H2082BDB5FBDC48A3B4BFC5E816A97D99"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Mitigating the impact of economic coercion by the Russian Federation and the PRC on Black Sea states and identifying new opportunities for foreign direct investment from the United States and cooperating countries and the enhancement of United States business ties.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HC801A99E7A3C4DB9A1F061A575D1A54B"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing high-level engagement between the United States and the Black Sea states, and reinforcing economic growth, financing quality infrastructure, and reinforcing trade with a focus on improving high-level economic cooperation.</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H15278D1D184A4A98AE576EB8521F02B6"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Increasing coordination with the European Union and the North Atlantic Treaty Organization to maximize effectiveness and minimize duplication.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H166E5C662A6844CF9A7EB5EC0DB1A851"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Activities</header> <paragraph id="H6B5D8058B49D435EA49109394B1BED48"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy established under subsection (a) shall include the following elements related to security:</text> 
<subparagraph id="H37223041F2224F4DAE4665FBA8C51CCD"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to increase interagency coordination toward the Black Sea region.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA9B20038A88D4183B03726117BDEFF9A"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strategy for—</text> 
<clause id="H296139FE2EB547BDB917F95748088A3B"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the United States to increase NATO’s presence and capabilities in the Black Sea region, including land and air forces; or</text></clause> <clause id="H848FC63CA56D47B88C060EA8942CC9CC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a United States-led initiative with NATO member countries to increase coordination, presence, and regional engagement among Black Sea countries.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H7206DFE3937A493EBDB85CE076C8912B"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strategy to increase military assistance toward Black Sea countries, particularly Ukraine, Romania, Bulgaria, and Georgia.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC17BFE91B9E7441EA4F59C11AC853603"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Prioritization of intelligence, surveillance, and reconnaissance systems to monitor Russian operations in the Black Sea region, as well as upgrading from air policing to air defense missions.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H65C3B11550FA4A55811D000F230FF939"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An assessment of the value of establishing a joint, multinational three-star headquarters on the Black Sea, responsible for planning, readiness, exercises, and coordination of all military activity in the greater Black Sea region.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HB871FAB871C04B069B4E0CA6121076A2"><enum>(F)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An overview of Foreign Military Financing, International Military Education and Training, and other United States security assistance to the region.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H6CCF430526C142DCBEAA813DED2098AC"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for communicating the changes to NATO posture to the public in allied and partner countries, as well as in the Russian Federation and Belarus.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H36D46BBFDB6A4D1A828A8B3785304D3E"><enum>(H)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan for combating Russian disinformation and propaganda in the Black Sea region, utilizing the resources of the United States Government, including the Global Engagement Center.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HDDA6C85FCC6546DAAE4FC1D8858B6242"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A plan to promote greater freedom of navigation, working primarily with Turkey, Ukraine, Romania, and Bulgaria to allow for greater security and economic Black Sea access.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H7F3F351454654C36A147689516CC4481"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Economic prosperity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy established under subsection (a) shall include the following elements related to economic prosperity:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HD1B60D82A9EC48E899C41DDC1A9F51CB"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strategy to foster dialogue between experts from the United States and from the Black Sea states on economic expansion, foreign direct investment, strengthening rule of law initiatives, and mitigating economic coercion by Russia and the PRC.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5DD20F16987B48B992640326EA3B1B1D"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strategy for the United States International Development Finance Corporation and all Federal departments and agencies that contribute to United States economic statecraft to identify new opportunities for private investment in Black Sea states.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HCFDCAE2E52E143BE9F66800441D8B3A1"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An evaluation undertaken by United States International Development Finance Corporation to establish regional offices in Georgia, Ukraine, or Romania.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H261834CF28844C1E8A20EF4740E4A1B4"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessments on energy diversification. The assessment should focus on the immediate need to replace energy supplies from Russia, and recognize the long-term importance of broader energy diversification, including clean energy initiatives.</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H83B07D6AA64A4C079396C80ED00F8E9A"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Assessments of potential food security solutions.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA03016E543CE40649F4D9AA9023FCA7A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Democratic resilience</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy established under subsection (a) shall include the following elements related to democratic resilience:</text> 
<subparagraph id="HCA0D7BF21CBC45CBBE18B840D338E3F3"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A strategy to increase independent media and United States-supported media initiatives to combat foreign malign influence in the Black Sea region.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6AC26409913647C09DD60F8A36FEFA3B"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Greater mobilization of initiatives spearheaded by the Global Engagement Center and the United States Agency for International Development to counter Russian propaganda and disinformation in the Black Sea region.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB72BD9ABA73C4905891322D5F45D23DC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Regional connectivity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The strategy established under subsection (a) shall promote regional connectivity by sending high-level representatives of the Department of State or other agency partners to—</text> <subparagraph id="H8179FC530F114158A6F1C8874C42FD5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Black Sea region not less frequently than twice a year; and</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H350243FC2AF14A688ECF709A0BA02F50"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">major regional fora on infrastructure and energy security, including the Three Seas Initiative Summit.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="HE82B442C6BE843C7B5BC18AFC4A6E47C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Identification of necessary programs and resources</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No later than 360 days after the date of the enactment of this Act, the interagency shall identify any necessary program, policy, or budgetary resources required, by agency, to support implementation of the Black Sea Security Strategy for fiscal years 2024, 2025, and 2026.</text></subsection></section> 
<section id="HB18BE5BA58D74ABF86AB3926C42A64BB"><enum>7.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H0B47779A0BF44BF2952E780438F46BD3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text>The term <term>appropriate congressional committees</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H942F1651E1E6430086D09485D669A183"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Relations, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the Senate; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA858113A3DB94097B7A2F48B91C20508"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Committee on Armed Services, and the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HFA794FDC1C5F485BB01B72FAD439C715"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Black Sea states</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Black Sea states</term> means Turkey, Romania, Bulgaria, Moldova, Ukraine, and Georgia.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9176CD4BECBC461B98811D3CCCEA6D1C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Three Seas Initiative Investment Fund countries</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Three Seas Initiative Investment Fund countries</term> means Estonia, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia, Hungary, Slovenia, Austria, Croatia, Romania, and Bulgaria.</text> </paragraph></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

