<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H9A60A350DE274B17A11267A5EC1EB08B" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 935 RH: Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2021</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-10</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 233</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 935</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–313]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210208">February 8, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001058">Mr. Huizenga</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000599">Mr. Posey</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on February 8, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to exempt from registration brokers performing services in connection with the transfer of ownership of smaller privately held companies.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HBA00" reported-display-style="italic" id="H0E7A20B06F3342AEA2DDF97CD3D06662"><section id="H8F153A424BDF463E8959AAE0DC4B868E" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Small Business Mergers, Acquisitions, Sales, and Brokerage Simplification Act of 2021</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HFCC256868F8C4CABB4150C8F00B0FF61"><enum>2.</enum><header>Registration exemption for merger and acquisition brokers</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 15(b) of the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/78o">15 U.S.C. 78o(b)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HDF50FA81B79A451E92A57A23AE331F9A" style="OLC" changed="added" reported-display-style="italic" committee-id="HBA00"><paragraph id="H0B91A4431A5148DB9CC6B7D65D6E8C26"><enum>(13)</enum><header>Registration exemption for merger and acquisition brokers</header><subparagraph id="H066BA6CE89E94A5E9261D7B9DF6F001B"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Except as provided in subparagraph (B), an M&amp;A broker shall be exempt from registration under this section.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD64AA227647043CAAEF6DE64CD421E62"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Excluded activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An M&amp;A broker is not exempt from registration under this paragraph if such broker does any of the following:</text><clause id="H8B6C9EE871E444A798CD910EB3F02001"><enum>(i)</enum><text>Directly or indirectly, in connection with the transfer of ownership of an eligible privately held company, receives, holds, transmits, or has custody of the funds or securities to be exchanged by the parties to the transaction.</text></clause><clause id="H48435B6C7BC54137A7B39215609EC74D"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>Engages on behalf of an issuer in a public offering of any class of securities that is registered, or is required to be registered, with the Commission under section 12 or with respect to which the issuer files, or is required to file, period information, documents, and reports under subsection (d).</text></clause><clause id="H040CF704054440C990930A74885D66F2"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engages on behalf of any party in a transaction involving a shell company, other than a business combination related shell company.</text></clause><clause id="H437FDA819FE54094B9116ADCF9B941E8"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Directly, or indirectly through any of its affiliates, provides financing related to the transfer of ownership of an eligible privately held company.</text></clause><clause id="H152AF64EC8254031A9B8649ECB7A45EA"><enum>(v)</enum><text>Assists any party to obtain financing from an unaffiliated third party without—</text><subclause id="H5516A35938BE468EA4414D881BD99A73"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">complying with all other applicable laws in connection with such assistance, including, if applicable, Regulation T (12 C.F.R. 220 et seq.); and</text></subclause><subclause id="H44FA17ADAE6B45BC9E3EFEE56DAF0532"><enum>(II)</enum><text>disclosing any compensation in writing to the party.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H09C4DB89BA014DC8A02A7CCDBF9EEAF9"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>Represents both the buyer and the seller in the same transaction without providing clear written disclosure as to the parties the broker represents and obtaining written consent from both parties to the joint representation.</text></clause><clause id="H007ACC783A9B49DE929FD032258A7412"><enum>(vii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Facilitates a transaction with a group of buyers formed with the assistance of the M&amp;A broker to acquire the eligible privately held company.</text></clause><clause id="HD03CC7FBB80341ED8075B25CCBCABB83"><enum>(viii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Engages in a transaction involving the transfer of ownership of an eligible privately held company to a passive buyer or group of passive buyers.</text></clause><clause id="H24575AA9A578492385559B64B7000BB3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Binds a party to a transfer of ownership of an eligible privately held company.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7CA23643CD24C43A9596A2E526D569C"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Disqualification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An M&amp;A broker is not exempt from registration under this paragraph if such broker (and if and as applicable, including any officer, director, member, manager, partner, or employee of such broker)—</text><clause id="HF5E79C96E1B7488795E0F81E4623A2E1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>has been barred from association with a broker or dealer by the Commission, any State, or any self-regulatory organization; or</text></clause><clause id="HCF4C0CE2B4794A10B947484B490AA0BC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>is suspended from association with a broker or dealer.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H288B11064ED8456E8083F4C01BE5471B"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this paragraph shall be construed to limit any other authority of the Commission to exempt any person, or any class of persons, from any provision of this title, or from any provision of any rule or regulation thereunder.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA3D60817DAD74EC7BE3128678A89108F"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="HCE2017710F2C43348337C913F2748FA8"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Business combination related shell company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>business combination related shell company</term> means a shell company that is formed by an entity that is not a shell company—</text><subclause id="H0C3663F5743E421580DB810D4780C623"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">solely for the purpose of changing the corporate domicile of that entity solely within the United States; or</text></subclause><subclause id="H87FDB3F22C934DC39289B2E061586A36"><enum>(II)</enum><text>solely for the purpose of completing a business combination transaction (as defined under section 230.165(f) of title 17, Code of Federal Regulations) among one or more entities other than the company itself, none of which is a shell company.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HD9F2112AF0F64E9B9F9919B840B73D40"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Control</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>control</term> means the power, directly or indirectly, to direct the management or policies of a company, whether through ownership of securities, by contract, or otherwise. There is a presumption of control if, upon completion of a transaction, the buyer or group of buyers—</text><subclause id="H342DA6D31EFD49CFBB9CF17692EC41C2"><enum>(I)</enum><text>has the right to vote 25 percent or more of a class of voting securities or the power to sell or direct the sale of 25 percent or more of a class of voting securities; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB933FECE9C384BD19D3618A6734D8716"><enum>(II)</enum><text>in the case of a partnership or limited liability company, has the right to receive upon dissolution, or has contributed, 25 percent or more of the capital.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H12DFCC9FA4AC48B3B5ECC1005D7019E8"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Eligible privately held company</header><text>The term <term>eligible privately held company</term> means a privately held company that meets both of the following conditions:</text><subclause id="H25DABFF7370E490882EC106E58831230"><enum>(I)</enum><text>The company does not have any class of securities registered, or required to be registered, with the Commission under section 12 or with respect to which the company files, or is required to file, periodic information, documents, and reports under subsection (d).</text></subclause><subclause id="H4EF88D35D620436B96B7E74DFD90EA87"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the fiscal year ending immediately before the fiscal year in which the services of the M&amp;A broker are initially engaged with respect to the securities transaction, the company meets either or both of the following conditions (determined in accordance with the historical financial accounting records of the company):</text><item id="HC1321AE5B26846538C302D40EA10834C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>The earnings of the company before interest, taxes, depreciation, and amortization are less than $25,000,000.</text></item><item id="HCD3009F9E37645D895B74130C2233182"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>The gross revenues of the company are less than $250,000,000.</text></item><continuation-text continuation-text-level="subclause">For purposes of this subclause, the Commission may by rule modify the dollar figures if the Commission determines that such a modification is necessary or appropriate in the public interest or for the protection of investors. </continuation-text></subclause></clause><clause commented="no" id="H954CD2B8A3AA42009E898B2E1FE89CA5"><enum>(iv)</enum><header>M&amp;A broker</header><text>The term <term>M&amp;A broker</term> means a broker, and any person associated with a broker, engaged in the business of effecting securities transactions solely in connection with the transfer of ownership of an eligible privately held company, regardless of whether the broker acts on behalf of a seller or buyer, through the purchase, sale, exchange, issuance, repurchase, or redemption of, or a business combination involving, securities or assets of the eligible privately held company, if the broker reasonably believes that—</text><subclause commented="no" id="HE8A1286CC7B54E4194FD2C9DF16A6FAB"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">upon consummation of the transaction, any person acquiring securities or assets of the eligible privately held company, acting alone or in concert—</text><item id="H8976B96F3A1147909B30C8AC0BE592FC"><enum>(aa)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">will control the eligible privately held company or the business conducted with the assets of the eligible privately held company; and</text></item><item id="HA1D37509F8A94D94BCC48C6F0B1839B6"><enum>(bb)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">directly or indirectly, will be active in the management of the eligible privately held company or the business conducted with the assets of the eligible privately held company, including without limitation, for example, by—</text><subitem id="H44B38B16143B4C7481135F1ADC69A556"><enum>(AA)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">electing executive officers;</text></subitem><subitem id="H686786B304DB4A05AACF980CF8025481"><enum>(BB)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">approving the annual budget;</text></subitem><subitem id="H5B95E28FD9FD46E384EFDA02D7DF5EF8"><enum>(CC)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">serving as an executive or other executive manager; or</text></subitem><subitem id="H923E8802545345BDBCA680AD0999F192"><enum>(DD)</enum><text>carrying out such other activities as the Commission may, by rule, determine to be in the public interest; and</text></subitem></item></subclause><subclause commented="no" id="H4498DBC9635E4B8FBC62930A3EA9A51D"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if any person is offered securities in exchange for securities or assets of the eligible privately held company, such person will, prior to becoming legally bound to consummate the transaction, receive or have reasonable access to the most recent fiscal year-end financial statements of the issuer of the securities as customarily prepared by the management of the issuer in the normal course of operations and, if the financial statements of the issuer are audited, reviewed, or compiled, any related statement by the independent accountant, a balance sheet dated not more than 120 days before the date of the offer, and information pertaining to the management, business, results of operations for the period covered by the foregoing financial statements, and material loss contingencies of the issuer.</text></subclause></clause><clause id="HDABA412BF0F74014A7F2D455C4E52492"><enum>(v)</enum><header>Shell company</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>shell company</term> means a company that at the time of a transaction with an eligible privately held company—</text><subclause id="H09918A8E7F2D4AAF8CBA26A3B29BA6C5"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">has no or nominal operations; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H34717405318440769AC5622BD2834F5C"><enum>(II)</enum><text>has—</text><item id="H1F4367623FE345CAA00F4FF412695C0C"><enum>(aa)</enum><text>no or nominal assets;</text></item><item id="H7387683EA99F4606810073351474B1C4"><enum>(bb)</enum><text>assets consisting solely of cash and cash equivalents; or</text></item><item id="HE3FE09A45812484FA6F85DE1826022B5"><enum>(cc)</enum><text>assets consisting of any amount of cash and cash equivalents and nominal other assets.</text></item></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H062B0DDC9ECB46439BB3EC190F5419A7"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Inflation adjustment</header><clause id="H63CBCEB5D394415F94D6DE6BE25C5A5A"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On the date that is 5 years after the date of the enactment of this paragraph, and every 5 years thereafter, each dollar amount in subparagraph (E)(iii)(II) shall be adjusted by—</text><subclause id="H4C80060B60644223B035DCB2CFA6563A"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">dividing the annual value of the Employment Cost Index For Wages and Salaries, Private Industry Workers (or any successor index), as published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics, for the calendar year preceding the calendar year in which the adjustment is being made by the annual value of such index (or successor) for the calendar year ending December 31, 2020; and</text></subclause><subclause id="HE3F7470593584CA594124548CD9917F6"><enum>(II)</enum><text>multiplying such dollar amount by the quotient obtained under subclause (I).</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7DA26119C26644528094057E8C00C33E"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Rounding</header><text>Each dollar amount determined under clause (i) shall be rounded to the nearest multiple of $100,000.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H2FD3DB80A580478E9DA5EB5FBC646E51"><enum>3.</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act and any amendment made by this Act shall take effect on the date that is 90 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20220510">May 10, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

