<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H31F4BDB0F9574C168A65DFE02209DE61" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6567 IH: Licensing Individual Commercial Exam-takers Now Safely and Efficiently Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-02-02</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6567</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220202">February 2, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="L000585">Mr. LaHood</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="C001063">Mr. Cuellar</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001306">Mr. Balderson</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="H001090">Mr. Harder of California</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Transportation to modify certain regulations relating to the requirements for commercial driver’s license testing and commercial learner’s permit holders, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HB427DF5F13D842CF96B4A4B35FB82AB8" style="OLC"><section id="HD3F5FEF0C2F849AA87138C87F490F4DC" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Licensing Individual Commercial Exam-takers Now Safely and Efficiently Act of 2022</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>LICENSE Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB58307D05CB14B67925FB5E50BBDCB33" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Modifications to certain commercial driver’s license regulations</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Motor Carrier Safety Administration, shall—</text><paragraph id="HA9CF5C1674414E70BD271DB44B9848AD"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise section 384.228 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), to allow a State or third-party examiner to administer the commercial driver’s license knowledge test only if the examiner—</text><subparagraph id="H4B17F905C71A48008189B19F664A4792"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">maintains a valid commercial driver’s license test examiner certification;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7850FC0C9BC9434687B2DC7D3F579FE3"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completes a commercial driver’s license skills test examiner training course that meets the requirements of subsection (d) of such section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8935B9644DEB44F6B3F7D96C93AFCA48"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">completes 1 unit of instruction described in subsection (c)(3) of such section;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H9A20786604D64CBEB4EAA17F79FFF8FE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise section 383.25(a)(1) of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), to allow a commercial driver’s license holder accompanying a commercial learner’s permit holder to be present anywhere in the cab of the vehicle being operated by the commercial learner’s permit holder; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2D95BCB1F81143EBB590604B87D9879E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">revise section 383.79 of title 49, Code of Federal Regulations (or a successor regulation), to allow a State to administer a driving skills tests to any commercial driver’s license applicant, regardless of the State of domicile of the applicant or where the applicant received driver training.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

