<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H4CA6F05778FB4D11AE7959BB50B39421" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8681 IH: John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-08-05</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8681</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220805">August 5, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M000194">Ms. Mace</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001112">Mr. Carbajal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B000490">Mr. Bishop of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Committee on Foreign Affairs</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish the John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship to fund international internships and research placements for early- to mid-career professionals to study nonviolent movements to establish and protect civil rights around the world.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD0CB0399BC8945BE86CB04AD5B99FA5A" style="OLC"><section id="H1B77CD58DEE3412698FA81CA3FAC1B71" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF7DC371F0EAA4114AD10F146F0051977"><enum>2.</enum><header>John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship Program</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2451">22 U.S.C. 2451 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC55BBF5C621346E093752D64A6909432"><section id="H9835019FD3AE4DB7883F29BE2E154CF7"><enum>115.</enum><header>John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship Program</header><subsection id="H5702A2E36DE94FFEA50BC787FA0747A8"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established the John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship Program (referred to in this section as the <quote>Fellowship Program</quote>) within the J. William Fulbright Educational Exchange Program.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB5D62E0C291145E88D398FCF7BCEE848"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The purposes of the Fellowship Program are—</text><paragraph id="H0A9E12F7D3DF466C9EC4E47955895503"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to honor the legacy of Representative John Lewis by promoting a greater understanding of the history and tenets of nonviolent civil rights movements; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0DDA2B9362E5491AAD3D709046725BE7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>to promote studies, research, and international exchange in the subject of nonviolent movements that established and protected civil rights around the world.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HBC44E0F8E23C498D98D7B167F444F593"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Bureau of Educational and Cultural Affairs (referred to in this section as the <quote>Bureau</quote>) shall administer the Fellowship Program in accordance with policy guidelines established by the Fulbright Foreign Scholarship Board, in consultation with the binational Fulbright Commissions and United States Embassies.</text></subsection><subsection id="H3702E9E26F7F4013ACE274CCD1AC0C9A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Selection of fellows</header><paragraph id="HAEC084879BC3429585CF35F04B57501F"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Board shall annually select qualified individuals to participate in the Fellowship Program. The Board may determine the number of fellows selected each year, which shall be not fewer than 25 whenever feasible. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49651BC7908840D39544FF51A5A2256D"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Outreach</header><subparagraph id="HDC8A56FB16A84214A93C48F191B3AC3C"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Bureau should conduct outreach at organizations described in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="H15CFDD60D32C432DBFB8B4567D105CB3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>to broaden the pool of qualified applicants; and</text></clause><clause id="H3A11DDE765904EFBAF4B58F598AD69E3"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>to facilitate, to the extent practicable, diversity within each cohort of fellows.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDCD72203CCCB4AA59A58C2587A5AEE5A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Organizations described</header><text>The organizations described in this subparagraph are—</text><clause id="H364EA706E5FA49CD86C37B94843B523D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minority serving institutions, including historically Black colleges and universities; and</text></clause><clause id="HE44542AD3AB0454AABB8E8AFE435A196"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>other appropriate institutions, as determined by the Board.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H31C54705F75147B0970C39E01419019E"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this paragraph:</text><clause id="H92DA19C936BA42918CA8D26E106C07FB"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Diversity</header><text>The term <term>diversity</term> means diversity of individuals based on factors including race, color, religion, sex, pregnancy, gender identity, national origin, political affiliation, sexual orientation, marital status, disability, genetic information, age, parental status, or military service.</text></clause><clause id="HD0E78A8EC4A84A58B42852CB04355975"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Historically Black college and university</header><text>The term <term>historically Black college and university</term> has the meaning given the term <term>part B institution</term> in section 322 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1061">20 U.S.C. 1061</external-xref>). </text></clause><clause id="H2BF4826D8CE94430A564049C4C413D63"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Minority serving institution</header><text>The term <term>minority-serving institution</term> means an eligible institution under section 371(a) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1067q">20 U.S.C. 1067q(a)</external-xref>).</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HED8A591E7ED844B49586514EB74AE9AD"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Fellowship orientation</header><text>The Bureau shall organize and administer a fellowship orientation that shall—</text><paragraph id="HEB1BDC638E7F40D58D53D6491E51F641"><enum>(1)</enum><text>be held in Washington, DC, or at another location selected by the Bureau; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H99C9AA9D42A24328AAF24F2CB867A23E"><enum>(2)</enum><text>include programming to honor the legacy of Representative John Lewis; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA3E8D9D6081E48C08A65A65CFE5AB321" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>be held on an annual basis not later than 30 days before the commencement of the fellowship program.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D4A4FE1FAB84C3092BF1B500F14D238"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Structure</header><paragraph id="H3475AAF864D14B8F82B64907A03CCF55"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Work plan</header><text>To carry out the purposes described in subsection (b)(2)—</text><subparagraph id="H692ECBBEC00D4EBCB8B8FAA130BF5F95"><enum>(A)</enum><text>each fellow selected pursuant to subsection (d) shall arrange an internship or research placement— </text><clause id="HF03E295D103E48039A5034BA3ECF0A4E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>with a nongovernmental organization, academic institution, or other organization approved by the Bureau; and</text></clause><clause id="H53469728A8394D4799C8A851E625036E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in a country with an operational Fulbright U.S. Student Program; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HEACD6EB8469F4E97BA123F552D62A8F8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the Bureau shall, for each fellow, approve a work plan that identifies the target objectives for the fellow, including specific duties and responsibilities relating to those objectives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDD49E4510C0E44DDA93A8D239008B371"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Conferences; presentations</header><text>Each fellow shall—</text><subparagraph id="H8D702C9F011B40DA95ABE76F7F3DFAE3"><enum>(A)</enum><text>attend the fellowship orientation described in subsection (e);</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13B91D0D1DC54BCA9770A43F1031441F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>not later than the date that is one year after the end of the fellowship period, attend a fellowship summit organized and administered by the Bureau, which shall be held in Atlanta, Georgia, or at another location of importance to the civil rights movement in the United States and selected by the Bureau; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85E27349784647778DC00DF4439AA54E"><enum>(C)</enum><text>at such summit, give a presentation on lessons learned during the period of fellowship.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6E5AF7730D794007A79C3012136F072B"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Fellowship period</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each fellowship under this section shall continue for a period determined by the Bureau, which shall be not shorter than 10 months whenever feasible. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HCBF0B61C26224852BC37B4FB55ED7E49"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Fellowship award</header><text>The Bureau shall provide each fellow under this section with an allowance that is equal to the amount needed for—</text><paragraph id="HAFC530E01CB64BB4B1E36F80CD39C497"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the fellow's reasonable costs during the fellowship period; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A4F4DBA2DE541B8947A826236C3DEBC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>travel and lodging expenses related to attending the orientation and summit required under subsection (e)(2).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H3DF8AA4F35EB4410B82844394703694F"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Briefing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of the selection of the initial cohort of fellows under subsection (d), and on an annual basis thereafter, the Secretary of State shall brief Congress on the state of the Fellowship Program, including—</text><paragraph id="HC561C256056042C3A3F95D09BC5DED82"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the demographics of the cohort of fellows who completed a fellowship during the preceding 1-year period;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA15FA32C578346D7AA98B3BDFA9D4240"><enum>(2)</enum><text>an analysis of the diversity of the Fellowship Program based on the demographics of each cohort of fellows who completed a fellowship by the date of the briefing; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71688984A60B4B56BCA5CD538C146590"><enum>(3)</enum><text>an analysis of trends relating to the diversity of the cohorts of fellows over the course of the Fellowship Program.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H181E0B78B2F34732B4E91B3F7E0F7944"><enum>3.</enum><header>Technical and conforming amendments to the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 112(a) of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2460">22 U.S.C. 2460(a)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCB5447D33A0645BF9E0604497FEC520D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (8), by striking <quote>; and </quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H01748DDD159148B68D4BD747D2F65183"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (9), by striking the period and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D2375A6DA13438BB9AF7B2E4BCA142C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H8D8DA9AA54C64E98BAD1E9C06DDE074A"><paragraph id="H1FA705F7164C4CC78A315FD72A253E4E"><enum>(10)</enum><text>the John Lewis Civil Rights Fellowship Program established under section 115, which provides funding for international internships and research placements for early- to mid-career individuals from the United States to study nonviolent civil rights movements in self-arranged placements with universities or nongovernmental organizations in foreign countries. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

