<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H08D7D28E1CB9458288F01DA2E39F3411" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7859 IH: Promoting Responsible Emergency Protocols for All Students Act </dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-05-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7859</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220519">May 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="W000826">Ms. Wild</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To create a Council on Emergency Response Protocols to ensure the establishment of accessible, developmentally appropriate, culturally aware, and trauma-informed emergency response protocols in public schools, early child care and education settings, and institutions of higher education, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94C1A65E5EA34B0CA5AF1B6D44267EA3" style="OLC"> 
<section section-type="section-one" id="H12BE8141D0AC4584979CC5D61AEFDE12"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Promoting Responsible Emergency Protocols for All Students Act </short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>PREP for All Students Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H36A9E758818F4F0185CDE4F1CB28F2C3"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text>
<paragraph id="H82BD228AA426409A97E19882545C2DE3"><enum>(1)</enum><text>The lack of accessible, developmentally appropriate, culturally aware, and trauma-informed emergency response protocols for children and youth in public schools, early child care and education settings, and institutions of higher education is not a trivial issue:</text> <subparagraph id="HBAE6AD7AE7E941679C22EAD84643329D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>In 2016, there were 12,032,000 children from ages 3 to 5 enrolled in preprimary education programs, and almost one-quarter of children under the age of 5 are in some form of child care arrangement, including nurseries, child care centers, and preschools.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HEDBC53AB5BBB4B35BA8366ACCE392418"><enum>(B)</enum><text>In the 2017–2018 school year—</text> <clause id="H8BA07F82FEF746EF98551F1AEDBE06A3"><enum>(i)</enum><text>14 percent of students in grades kindergarten through grade 12 had a disability; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H237F606DBDDA47AA99CA293C81C68D1E"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>11 percent of students in postbaccalaureate programs self-identified as having a disability.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H38C54425829E4D7C92A0C91C0E235217"><enum>(2)</enum><text>As of the date of enactment of this Act, little has been done to integrate specific populations, such as children and youth at various developmental stages or children and youth with disabilities, into emergency preparedness planning.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB9FC8DB14FCC4252B611299C80BE7BDE"><enum>(3)</enum><text>In 2018 alone, there were 108 natural disasters in the United States, including severe thunderstorms, floods, wildfires, droughts, earthquakes, and other extreme weather.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA51246F7746F4590AB5508462FF39C38"><enum>(4)</enum><text>During the 16 academic years from 2000 through 2015, there were 85 fatal fires in dormitories, fraternities, sororities, and off-campus housing, resulting in 118 fatalities—an average of approximately 7 per school year.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9A2EB045A6FA44F1B55D1673AFA66FBD"><enum>(5)</enum><text>The risks associated with natural and manmade disasters have a disproportionate impact on individuals with disabilities. People with disabilities are 2 to 4 times more likely to die or sustain critical injuries during a disaster than people without disabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5C81A45A74C04BB6A4C210BDCD291293"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Technology plays an increasingly vital role in emergency communications but remains largely inaccessible for many individuals with disabilities. </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H9DFEAADF530D4F3DAEBD11F2811BFAD4"><enum>(7)</enum><text>The rise of gun violence and gun violence-related deaths has contributed to the expansion of school security technologies and devices. While such technologies and devices have the potential to save lives, they have largely been developed without consideration of the needs of students at various developmental stages or students with disabilities. Thus, there may be inherent biases within these technologies and devices that disadvantage or create bias toward specific populations.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HE63607B2A9CB4790AFEAC3797D8086E2"><enum>(8)</enum><text>As of the date of enactment of this Act, 92 percent of schools nationwide have an active shooter lockdown protocol. More than 1,000,000 elementary-age children experienced a lockdown in the 2017–2018 school year, and among that group, at least 220,000 were in kindergarten or prekindergarten.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE59C5EC4160540F9AB810B85FC71B072"><enum>(9)</enum><text>While the Department of Homeland Security active shooter emergency guidelines recommend that students and personnel in school and early child care and education settings <quote>Run, Hide, and Fight</quote>, these strategies can exacerbate danger for young children in prekindergarten and child care centers, and can exclude and put at risk students with a wide range of disabilities.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H24376D42E0EC4C8BB88500DAB33B9833"><enum>(10)</enum><text>At the height of the 2019 novel coronavirus (COVID–19) pandemic, emergency closures of early education centers, elementary schools, secondary schools, and institutions of higher education created great disruptions in learning and cast a light on educational institutions’ lack of preparedness protocols for public health emergencies.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H25897465C11F44F4A43B7D11068DED3C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>During the pandemic, early care and education remains indispensable for the development of children and for millions of health care workers, first responders, educators, and essential personnel, and it is imperative that early care and education centers and schools have emergency preparedness plans to ensure the safety of students and educators. </text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H2D6821B315D9457ABFBC9EC42DEFB5BD"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Emergency preparation drills and real-life lockdowns where danger may be external can create undue stress, fear, and trauma in children, youth, employees, and other specific populations in schools, early child care and education settings, and institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H553B644855794F3992CE0C067226EB45"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Traumatic events have a long-lasting and profound sensory impact on young children, as birth to age 5 is a critical developmental age. Frightening visual stimuli, loud noises, violent movements, and other sensations associated with an unpredictable frightening event, such as in an emergency preparation drill or lockdown, can cause substantial stress. Unlike older children, young children cannot express in words whether they feel afraid, overwhelmed, or helpless, and may have difficulty regulating their behavior and emotions after experiencing trauma.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HBD7745BCC55E4BA794BA972D91A909FB"><enum>(14)</enum><text>There is an increasing need to ensure the establishment of accessible, developmentally appropriate, culturally aware, and trauma-informed emergency response protocols, including gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, fire drills, and other emergency preparation drills or lockdown procedures, in public schools, early child care and education settings, and institutions of higher education. </text></paragraph></section>
<section id="HD7AA08A33CE94D3EB684EFFDF6FB1AFC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text> <paragraph id="H1C96423F749D4B4D8AC44BC472158EA0"><enum>(1)</enum><header>ESEA definitions</header><text>The terms <term>elementary school</term>, <term>local educational agency</term>, <term>paraprofessional</term>, <term>school leader</term>, <term>secondary school</term>, and <term>specialized instructional support personnel</term> have the meanings given the terms in section 8101 of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/7801">20 U.S.C. 7801</external-xref>).</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HB6243EC93AA54A1881A4B8B04E556950"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Accessible</header><text>The term <term>accessible</term>, when used with respect to an emergency response protocol, means a protocol that—</text> <subparagraph id="HE277984669384E0B84CE4187B6655B8C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>is developed in full compliance with title II of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12131">42 U.S.C. 12131 et seq.</external-xref>) and the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/29/701">29 U.S.C. 701 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H1E95979E5A35437BBEB80A9F780B4815"><enum>(B)</enum><text>accounts for a comprehensive range of disabilities, including children and youth who use non-speech modes of communication. </text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H31CC3E91EE344A979F6E75B7E5AD513A"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Council</header><text>The term <term>Council</term> means the Council on Emergency Response Protocols established under section 4.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H77981F371C3C4B28A9F8D0C11B245622"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Culturally aware</header><text>The term <term>culturally aware</term>, when used with respect to an emergency response protocol, means a protocol that—</text> <subparagraph id="H87199A4C81FF4F8AB9A0CDC199B807D2"><enum>(A)</enum> <clause commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H658050AB806246CA9EBBE629240B078B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>incorporates the roles of first responder personnel, law enforcement personnel, school resource officers, and other authorities in the communities where the students live and attend school; </text></clause>
<clause id="HBDBA4D1812E14D939E9F88A083739485" indent="up1"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>takes into account the use and prevalence of firearms in such communities; and</text></clause> <clause id="HD7CF239C5FA1420895F8D03FB0A4B582" indent="up1"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>is cognizant of the ways in which African-American students and students of other racial or ethnic minority groups are more likely to face disciplinary action in schools; </text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H048660E309C14CC585ECC9171E0F58B9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>is designed to be sensitive to and respect cultural differences and differences in customs and worldview; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H5B68DD0E40384B2D9A54D03B992C233A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>considers the ways in which certain emergency events have disparate impact on African Americans, Native peoples, and other racial and ethnic minorities. </text></subparagraph></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H22A7C94839174B5680099DD9E358DA19"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Developmentally appropriate</header><text>The term <term>developmentally appropriate</term>, when used with respect to an emergency response protocol, means a protocol that is appropriate for children’s ages and physical, social, sensory, and emotional developmental statuses.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HA2DBF69C413B4A33B52F03128BC0AAC4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Disability</header><text>The term <term>disability</term> has the meaning given the term in section 3 of the Americans with Disabilities Act of 1990 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/12102">42 U.S.C. 12102</external-xref>). </text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HAA561D63543442FCA528AD518C8DC47B"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Institution of higher education</header><text>The term <term>institution of higher education</term> has the meaning given the term in section 102 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1002">20 U.S.C. 1002</external-xref>).</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H8E5987816781449EBD3B732383C6F356"><enum>(8)</enum><header>Trauma-informed</header><text>The term <term>trauma-informed</term>, when used with respect to an emergency response protocol, means a protocol that—</text>
<subparagraph id="H53103E1022BF4CD1B2CF5288F4D81F55"><enum>(A)</enum><text>recognizes the prevalence of trauma and the role that trauma plays in the lives of children, youth, and survivors of trauma; </text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H1A99B3309F0540AC8AC659ED7E85EED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>considers the physical, psychological, and emotional well-being of individuals during and after an emergency event; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H416C85B06DDD4F5186B585C06D1AFAF9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>takes an approach that actively combats the traumatization or retraumatization of children, youth, and survivors of trauma.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section> <section id="H132DBB3D6F694A7ABA50CEB24F00862B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Establishment of Council on Emergency Response Protocols</header> <subsection id="HA8EFABDD02C1494496606C6499D86745"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text>There is established a Council on Emergency Response Protocols.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H04CBC150FD5C4FFBB7CF4ECC5A284961"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Composition</header>
<paragraph id="H2A68469533194E1FB3C954B4A384EA04"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Chairperson</header><text>The Secretary of Education, in an expeditious manner, shall appoint an individual who represents one of the categories described in paragraph (2) to serve as a member and chairperson of the Council.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDBA85464C3FF48DF81CBE6A4342A6F6C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Appointed members</header><text>By not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the chairperson of the Council shall appoint a member to the Council for each of the following categories (except for the category represented by the chairperson):</text>
<subparagraph id="HF14ECC8F73BF44F1AE790532D8EE6D72"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An executive director or a representative from a national organization representing individuals with disabilities.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HBFF3FCF30978418CB0862FAF283D950C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>An executive director or a representative from a national organization representing early child care educators.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HB082F146EC2A4B2D87E1EBD7C68231C1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The executive director or a representative from a national organization representing law enforcement officials.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H851AC7E000FA4E53B6CCFE3AEDF6C7A4"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The executive director or a representative from an organization focused on emergency preparedness training in early child care. </text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HE2300C5CB4934B71B7BDD1424ECA983A"><enum>(E)</enum><text>A member of an organization representing teachers, school leaders, specialized instructional support personnel, and paraprofessionals.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HA4FB78E08081499694ABADF802F88EED"><enum>(F)</enum><text>A member of an organization representing school-based child welfare and mental health professionals.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HAC33403A853F4FBB91A5E0B2D516D559"><enum>(G)</enum><text>An individual with a physical, sensory, intellectual, developmental, mental health, or other disability who has demonstrated disability advocacy experience in kindergarten through grade 12 education.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HE981DF2B74044253B6F6E01406CA7AE8"><enum>(H)</enum><text>An individual with a physical, sensory, intellectual, developmental, mental health, or other disability who has been enrolled in an institution of higher education for at least a year during the 5 years prior to the date of the individual's appointment to the Council.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H08FFAC886CBB4FA484CC9DCBFEC6FDCB"><enum>(I)</enum><text>An individual with a physical, sensory, intellectual, developmental, mental health, or other disability who has been enrolled in an institution of higher education for a year prior to the date of the individual's appointment to the Council.</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H149CCB7670244203A69502B07C6D9F2F"><enum>(J)</enum><text>A parent or guardian of a child in an early child care and education program.</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H4071F85C71B0442CAE27FAF9614F034A"><enum>(K)</enum><text>A parent or guardian of a child with a physical, sensory, intellectual, or developmental disability in—</text> <clause id="H6CCF6B79E2554A2A89B44C855193B7AF"><enum>(i)</enum><text>an early child care and education program; or</text></clause>
<clause id="HB958D4AE0884451D82BE84C64EDD5992"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>a public elementary school or secondary school.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HDEC97470DEDC4C6D8A080F74247255B6"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Federal members</header> <subparagraph id="H8FEB7D07683F4C52B8435AB69A9B36F1"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Department of Education members</header><text>The following officers of the Department of Education shall serve as members of the Council:</text>
<clause id="HAB2664A620974FF9B0373555A4785CCA"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary of the Office of Planning, Evaluation and Policy Development.</text></clause> <clause id="H221D1B18FC7A4C4E9F962D84091424B4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary of the Office of Special Education and Rehabilitative Services.</text></clause>
<clause id="HFF2E10BA99CC44C388BE89B5C3F76A85"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>The Assistant Secretary for Civil Rights.</text></clause> <clause id="H78766B68BD4848F2A752E3E8C973FC94"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Innovation and Early Learning.</text></clause>
<clause commented="no" id="H094348B6A982467EB36F80FE2003BB0B"><enum>(v)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Special Education Programs. </text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph commented="no" id="HF922716E46884F2F97B87D06788790EA"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Health and Human Services members</header><text>The following officers of the Administration for Children and Families of the Department of Health and Human Services shall serve as members of the Council:</text>
<clause id="H8D29F05AC29D49AAA37C5C039C207A6D"><enum>(i)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Child Care.</text></clause> <clause id="HA1F18B62302749DCB1B058605944F1DE"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>The Director of the Office of Head Start.</text></clause></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="H3098A9E04E274B469834A756297901CC"><enum>(C)</enum><header>FEMA member</header><text>The Administrator of the Federal Emergency Management Agency shall serve as a member of the Council.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="HEB33645F9B6449DCB56BB375EB08980E"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Additional requirements for representation</header><text>The chairperson shall, to the best of the chairperson's ability, promote representation among the membership of the Council, including—</text>
<subparagraph id="H97072B3421D0492B85B061784FD3162D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensuring that not less than one of the members appointed under paragraph (2) has directly experienced, as a student, gun violence or another emergency event in which a lockdown protocol was enforced in an educational setting that was the primary target of the emergency event; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HDE328E68190848D8B5C3F8D2BEA76A81"><enum>(B)</enum><text>ensuring diversity among members appointed under such paragraph with regard to race, ethnicity, disability, gender identity and expression, age, sexual orientation, primary language, and other demographic characteristics.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="H7712184137D44BB59087397DC3B81806"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Meetings</header>
<paragraph id="H5F5530BDDE064B878BB2DC5F092761D4"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Initial meeting</header><text>The Council shall hold its first meeting not later than 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" id="H0D6A288AD468437DB5D2B7EE87FCE7D5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Frequency</header><text>The Council shall meet at the call of the chairperson.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HC670769C21074F61AECD72332665C120"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Quorum</header><text>A majority of the members of the Council shall constitute a quorum, but a lesser number of members may hold hearings.</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section id="H1AD205F418C94AB68A20F402C1153A2F"><enum>5.</enum><header>Duties</header> <subsection id="H958B0188CBFA41E3B337C1688EB58CD4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall hold a hearing with relevant stakeholders, including students and educators, principals and other school leaders, child care experts, disability advocates, civil rights advocates, law enforcement, security experts, and others, not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection id="H2C47AA6178B34A7CBCD18057EF475980"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Study and review</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Council shall—</text> <paragraph id="H40209835EB094C269E4D225BEC38C271"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">study emergency response protocols, including gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, fire drills, and other emergency preparation drills or lockdown procedures, for educational settings including early child care and education settings, elementary schools and secondary schools, and institutions of higher education; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="H6B1FC8249A034B8D9D31E597C14756DE"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conduct a complete and thorough review of the relevant literature and research surrounding emergency response protocols in such educational settings and the impact that emergency response protocols can have on specific populations of children, youth, and employees, including the effects on children living in poverty and children of color. </text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H9D296DBC566848C7A524843BA84AB5DE"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Recommendations and guidelines</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">After completing the study and review described in subsection (b), the Council shall provide— </text>
<paragraph id="HAC32C68A2463407582A8CE372135E10C"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">recommendations that ensure that States, early child care and education settings, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education are provided with accurate information about the needs of specific populations of children, youth, and employees during emergencies;</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H4E8A19B4C9C04F1CB4E898AC92853ACC"><enum>(2)</enum><text>guidelines for States, early child care and education settings, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education to use in developing and implementing emergency response protocols, including gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, fire drills, and other emergency preparation drills or lockdown procedures, that are inclusive and accessible; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph id="HE24946947FEB4987BA904CD7C7FD223A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>guidelines—</text> <subparagraph id="HD0A94B1921764BEABB1873DC9825D2A5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>for the development and implementation of accessible, developmentally appropriate, culturally aware, and trauma-informed emergency response protocols, including gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, fire drills, and other emergency preparation drills or lockdown procedures, that include information about—</text>
<clause id="H7D0ECBAC67D74CBAB1C4DA5C2EA0733A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>preparedness drills, including discussions and seminars on emergency preparedness, workshops, and full-scale emergency simulations;</text></clause> <clause id="H2F4B9EE57330495FB7B1DAB3D2556C55"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>emergency communications;</text></clause>
<clause id="H97F470111E8F466BB904F7BB92A92598"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>training for educators, early child care and education staff, administrators, and support personnel, including—</text> <subclause id="H7F8BFFEEA5194F52B81936D71BBD3590"><enum>(I)</enum><text>training addressing implicit biases on the basis of race, national origin, socioeconomic status, religion, disability, and sex (including sexual orientation and gender identity); and </text></subclause>
<subclause id="H814BFE517A6447E7865D6EE717FF0281"><enum>(II)</enum><text>other training to ensure the nondiscriminatory application of protocols and treatment of students;</text></subclause></clause> <clause id="H1A1F92E975C642E988A5F060C3C0824A"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>the use of technology; and</text></clause>
<clause id="H4482EBB15F0E4C94BBB77A9370B1F791"><enum>(v)</enum><text>other issues determined appropriate by the Council;</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6C61D42277DE4FC4815402E8258A9440"><enum>(B)</enum><text>for the use of Federal funds by States, early child care and education programs, local educational agencies, and institutions of higher education to develop and implement emergency response protocols, including gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, fire drills, and other emergency preparation drills or lockdown procedures, that are inclusive and accessible; and</text></subparagraph>
<subparagraph id="HF684D73925614B139F93E96A59EB0A77"><enum>(C)</enum><text>for States to create and develop recommendations for oversight for public elementary schools and secondary schools, early child care and education settings, and institutions of higher education to ensure any emergency response protocols—</text> <clause id="HC26CF93C3604427B9B6652E3ABD935F1"><enum>(i)</enum><text>are inclusive and accessible;</text></clause>
<clause id="H45C473BDAC844EBD82415A8CF04C0C46"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>protect student privacy; and </text></clause> <clause id="H3C9723F4CDAA4243B5D8BC3780D32052"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>avoid exacerbating risk for children and youth with disabilities, young children, employees, and other specific populations.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection id="HBEE0B20DB5204EC5AEDADCF32D274CB3"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text>By not later than 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act, the Council shall prepare and submit to Congress a detailed report that contains—</text> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H4D0F7FBF49E74D1D80A0785F1ECA1EC3"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">findings from stakeholders related to the challenges faced by children and youth with disabilities, young children, and other specific populations with regard to emergency response protocols, including gun violence response and prevention protocols, natural disaster preparedness procedures, fire drills, and other emergency preparation drills or lockdown procedures; and</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA67C8C0FA6234467B43D7B1AC7C8BB76"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the recommendations and guidelines described in subsection (c).</text></paragraph></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H39AB6577ACB94B728A0434737B222245"><enum>6.</enum><header>Powers of Council</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H54D187D9E98649AB84C0DA103C63BA8F"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Hearings</header><text>The Council may hold such hearings, sit and act at such times and places, take such testimony, and receive such evidence as the Council considers advisable to carry out this Act.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H5AD438BCB5814426B2006EEACD7D7D41"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Information from Federal agencies</header>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H60B12C3C57644DFB8DC4E3EF9DD6B1E9"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Council may secure directly from a Federal department or agency such information as the Council considers necessary to carry out this Act.</text></paragraph> <paragraph commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H751D10323D1D43998750F4A8714B1CD5"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Furnishing information</header><text>On request of the chairperson of the Council, the head of the department or agency shall furnish the information to the Council.</text></paragraph></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HAFD9B13BFE6F4DDB8FAA2BF7D4D85A77"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Postal services</header><text>The Council may use the United States mails in the same manner and under the same conditions as other departments and agencies of the Federal Government.</text></subsection></section> <section commented="no" id="H4BB6F9C0AE2A4F8680E17D64A7510CB9"><enum>7.</enum><header>Council personnel matters</header> <subsection commented="no" id="H733DD083E0FE4149B3865F254C36095A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Compensation of members</header><text>Only members of the Council representing categories described in subparagraphs (G) through (K) of section 4(b)(2) shall be compensated for their work for the Council. Such members may receive compensation at a rate equal to the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5, United States Code, for each day (including travel time) during which the members are engaged in the performance of the duties of the Council.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="HDA036FB94EDC44FBB38FFB29DA79B5E2"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Travel expenses</header><text>A member of the Council shall be allowed travel expenses, including per diem in lieu of subsistence, at rates authorized for employees of agencies under subchapter I of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/57">chapter 57</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, while away from their homes or regular places of business in the performance of services for the Council.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H258A778A3484405EB1CA43FB77235C35"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Staff</header> <paragraph commented="no" id="HBFE605EFE4AE4EF9AE63694CA2908DC6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The chairperson of the Council may, without regard to the civil service laws (including regulations), appoint and terminate an executive director and such other additional personnel as may be necessary to enable the Council to perform its duties, except that the employment of an executive director shall be subject to confirmation by the Council.</text></paragraph>
<paragraph commented="no" id="H9530037DF5C3498BA4C2E92134F046DC"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Compensation</header><text>The chairperson of the Council may fix the compensation of the executive director and other personnel without regard to chapter 51 and subchapter III of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/5/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 5, United States Code, relating to classification of positions and General Schedule pay rates, except that the rate of pay for the executive director and other personnel may not exceed the rate payable for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="HB46B05639817434E8565EED57C4E72C2"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Detail of government employees</header><text>A Federal Government employee may be detailed to the Council without reimbursement, and such detail shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subsection>
<subsection commented="no" id="H4E128B4DFA054C31823F9791C414DBDC"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Procurement of temporary and intermittent services</header><text>The chairperson of the Council may procure temporary and intermittent services under section 3109(b) of title 5, United States Code, at rates for individuals that do not exceed the daily equivalent of the annual rate of basic pay prescribed for level V of the Executive Schedule under section 5316 of that title.</text></subsection></section> <section id="HEA51D21D15C6472EBDC93815EA39D253"><enum>8.</enum><header>Termination of Council</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Council shall terminate 60 days after the date on which the Council submits the report required under section 5(d).</text></section>
<section commented="no" id="H6CE08FE1A440440782D0207EB870711D"><enum>9.</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header>
<subsection commented="no" id="HC5C7B5DC62294ED98A3E79CEB3C147B7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Council to carry out this Act a total of $500,000 for fiscal years 2023 and 2024.</text></subsection> <subsection commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H3F77AA9511F2415FB3B0B58FDE757776"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Availability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any sums appropriated under subsection (a) shall remain available, without fiscal year limitation, until expended.</text></subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

