<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F3B6BF4AA334139BB3A95DA3749CA10" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9648 IH: Bus Rapid Transit Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-21</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9648</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221221">December 21, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="B001224">Ms. Bush</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000087">Mrs. Carolyn B. Maloney of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001068">Mr. Huffman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000582">Mr. Lieu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000306">Mr. Jones</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000389">Mr. Khanna</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000482">Mr. Michael F. Doyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000623">Mr. DeSaulnier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000148">Mr. Auchincloss</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000800">Mr. Welch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000560">Mr. Larsen of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001143">Ms. McCollum</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001061">Mr. Cleaver</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001296">Mr. Brendan F. Boyle of Pennsylvania</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000597">Ms. Pingree</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000002">Mr. Nadler</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001300">Ms. Barragán</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000808">Ms. Wilson of Florida</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000032">Ms. Jackson Lee</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000631">Ms. Dean</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="A000370">Ms. Adams</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000197">Ms. DeGette</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000296">Mr. Evans</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001150">Mr. Schiff</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001218">Ms. Stansbury</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000562">Mr. Lynch</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001251">Mr. Butterfield</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001304">Mr. Brown of Maryland</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HPW00">Committee on Transportation and Infrastructure</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish, maintain, and expand frequent, reliable, interconnected electric bus rapid transit service to expand racial, economic, and environmental justice.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA6785B65871448A9A77DEC3C7F88FA67" style="OLC"><section id="H0DFAF8CC278B46F6A786E9C4FF4D6C36" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Bus Rapid Transit Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HB4FB9FFA7CE842CEAB2971AF9B2B1944" section-type="subsequent-section"><enum>2.</enum><header>Bus rapid transit program</header><subsection id="H7ADEF21DC4804EC28D7707D2274BE2D4"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Transportation, acting through the Administrator of the Federal Transit Administration, shall establish a program to provide grants to eligible public entities for the design and implementation of covered bus rapid transit systems. </text></subsection><subsection id="H7AA5EABF9242470D9236EEB577750C00"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Application</header><text>To be eligible for a grant under this section, an eligible public entity shall submit to the Secretary an application at such time, in such manner, and containing such information as the Secretary may require.</text></subsection><subsection id="H71379ED699CB435AB2147A58BBC41F3B"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible public entity receiving a grant under this section may use such grant for—</text><paragraph id="H92224D9E26024FA883A2ECA23B82377E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the design and implementation of a covered bus rapid transit system, including the design, acquisition, operations, maintenance, construction, and leasing of required supporting facilities, and integration and improvement of other connected or nearby bus corridors, bicycle infrastructure, and pedestrian infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAF258F93BC8F42AC9144E32229D04295"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">procuring and installing charging infrastructure and renewable energy to power charging infrastructure; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4469D628A8124F3CA828E6DF0CC9EC1C"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the redesign, retrofit, renovation, update, and repair of existing bus systems to bring such systems up to the standard of covered bus rapid transit systems;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD000B63F92C045D8B3CCF950B79A75A5"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">training current employees to effectively operate, maintain, or otherwise adapt to new technologies relating to a covered bus rapid transit system and associated charging equipment; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9913098B20FF48848041A0D90C637819"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">operating costs to increase service frequencies on bus rapid transit routes that otherwise conform with this Act; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4A0AA816F9C74FEAB81DE13DD35A8F68"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">reducing or eliminating fares as part of eligible projects; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H60CB610CD8F74DAE8CB1966F5B21E265"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">public engagement and participatory planning processes that meaningfully incorporate input from community members impacted by the covered bus rapid transit systems, including representatives from local labor organizations and other community groups, including those described subsection (d)(4). </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HE74E6D85A8364B4D94CF1E1F44733AE0"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As a condition of accepting a grant under this section, an eligible public entity (other than a Tribal authority) shall—</text><paragraph id="HF55734D3CBE84B7C895520F10C128CF4"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">agree to take steps, in consultation with community groups and tenant advocates, to secure existing housing in neighborhoods receiving benefits from such grant, including through the use of rent control, rent stabilization, or other methods to stabilize existing residents and prevent gentrification residential displacement;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4934A2C5676049819096EBD038017298"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">ensure safety for covered bus rapid transit systems funded by such a grant by employing Electric Vehicle Infrastructure Training Program (EVITP)-certified electricians for the installation and maintenance of the electric components of the charging infrastructure;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14F1F129934E4701B0629529787E1EDA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>provide to the Secretary in the application for such a grant information on what such steps the entity will take and how the entity will carry out the activities described in paragraph (1); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDBBA0579124541AC9989286BFE7354BD"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develop transit-oriented development plans for the area located around station stops that include new affordable housing or public housing;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9D17768803F145379BA2FD776E765616"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">provide to the Secretary a public engagement, outreach, and education plan that illustrates the grantee’s commitment to meeting the mobility needs of the entire community that will be served by the covered bus rapid transit system, including strategies to incorporate input from local labor organizations and other community groups, including environmental advocates, racial justice advocates, tenant advocates, youth advocates, transit advocates, and disability rights advocates; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28E6BEE062874B43BFC92A669F57C814"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">certify that the covered bus rapid transit system funded by such grant shall operate on an either flat-fare or fare-free basis. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD038EBFD07AB45B69A3442E40976C861"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Prohibition in impact on fares</header><text>As a condition on receipt of a grant under this section, an eligible public entity shall certify to the Secretary that the fares for riding the covered bus rapid transit system—</text><paragraph id="H9AB39C71DB8445E1BEF58F3115292722"><enum>(1)</enum><text>shall not increase solely due to the improvements carried out with funds provided under this section; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFB1E48795BDA4B438328199DB38BDA96"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">shall not increase for any reason for at least 1 year after the completion of the project funded under this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1A276832037B40BEA61E0E9A9EE49C54"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Priority for economically disadvantaged communities</header><text>In carrying out the program under this section, the Secretary shall prioritize projects located in economically disadvantaged communities.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE8AAC9C32E854013947DACF77761CEF1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Special rules for Tribes</header><subsection id="H1EB7E3CD0C1C48B989A1E82702C81385"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Set-Aside</header><text>Contingent on sufficient qualifying applicants for grants under this Act that are Tribal authorities, the Secretary shall ensure that 5 percent of such grants are awarded to such applicants.</text></subsection><subsection id="H517FCBB468A941B69D14F596C3791042"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Criteria for consideration as covered bus rapid transit system</header><text>With respect to a grants provided to a Tribal authority, notwithstanding section 5(2)(A), a transit system for which funds are provided under this Act shall be considered a covered bus rapid transit system by meeting 4 of the criteria listed in section 5(2)(A)(x) and 7 of the criteria listed in section 5(2)(A)(xi).</text></subsection></section><section id="HB38B16D06B6342AB97E4D8436B9FF67A"><enum>4.</enum><header>Funding requirements</header><subsection id="HBE3EAF928F4D4042AB201FB8C61BD57A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Federal share</header><paragraph id="HE185A42EEF204936970F880585C716C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Federal share of a grant under this Act shall not exceed 85 percent.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBD890DB05F3B4F3CA3F64866E4C2128E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Projects in economically disadvantaged communities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the Federal share for a project located in and benefitting an economically disadvantaged community may be up to 100 percent if the Secretary determines that—</text><subparagraph id="H32EDB216C2404D8EBDA10BFB3EA5CDE0"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the project is part of an approved transportation plan required under sections 5303 and 5304 of title 49, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD4319B023D4A43D69EC84615FC261DBE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the applicant has, or will have—</text><clause id="H534C6EE79798497C8AF32EEA3DA618F0"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the legal, financial, and technical capacity to carry out the project, including the safety and security aspects of the project;</text></clause><clause id="H5CDF2C22265949228FB342407873D9D6"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>satisfactory continuing control over the use of the equipment or facilities; and</text></clause><clause id="HF79EEEDF94F94C76BF64536EC9295401"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>the technical and financial capacity to maintain new and existing equipment and facilities.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF2481503E1F4499389D58FA791CD851F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">None of the funds made available by this Act may be used to employ or otherwise enter into a contract for local, State, or Federal law enforcement officers or fare collectors who are armed.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF1252684E2EA4F5BAF9890D4BF62AE62" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Special rule</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">No financial assistance under <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/49/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 49, United States Code, may be used for an automated vehicle providing public transportation unless the recipient of such assistance that proposes to deploy an automated vehicle providing public transportation certifies to the Secretary that the deployment does not eliminate or reduce the frequency of existing public transportation service.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9E42B66305AF4E59890D72303E21E93A"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated $60,000,000,000 total for fiscal years 2024 through 2028 to carry out this Act.</text></subsection></section><section id="H9EAC1511CA1A4599BB0C8B519D98AC56"><enum>5.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H55AD5E776BB04A319A8307DFC71D61DF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible public entity</header><text>The term <quote>eligible public entity</quote> means a local, Tribal, or State governmental authority, including metropolitan planning organizations, transit agencies, port authorities, and regional entities, or multiple adjacent authorities submitting a joint application.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7A6DDD9FA93647DD848AD4F23AC3665C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Covered bus rapid transit system</header><text>The term <quote>covered bus rapid transit system</quote> means a publicly owned bus rapid transit system that—</text><subparagraph id="H3CC904EB835D495F9003FDF6A0B97869"><enum>(A)</enum><text>has—</text><clause id="H1054CCCA299E42FE8767BC0B1A5C3F0E"><enum>(i)</enum><text>dedicated, physically separated right of ways that run at least 2 miles;</text></clause><clause id="H34785A3CD49945A995C18C9760E2568B" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">all buses added to operation are battery powered electric vehicles and any existing operational buses meet applicable 2010 emissions standards;</text></clause><clause id="H759149DC78AE428089593550237A28BB"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>accessibility for all customers, including those who are physically, visually, or hearing-impaired, as well as those with temporary disabilities, the elderly, children, parents with strollers, and other load-carrying passengers;</text></clause><clause id="HCC57C5FB49C745949E2CC7E937636E78"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">buses aligned in the central verge of the roadway for at least 75 percent of the route;</text></clause><clause id="HD95CD3018E35491E8017DFB6B589EFDD"><enum>(v)</enum><text>all buses, routes, and stations in corridor follow single unifying brand of entire bus rapid transit system;</text></clause><clause id="H479AE41ECD784EC1A6AD89735421E1EB"><enum>(vi)</enum><text>functioning real-time and up-to-date static passenger information corridor-wide that is available during all hours of operation;</text></clause><clause id="HBF7BA1DCCC1C4597841F3B14A4917592"><enum>(vii)</enum><text>physical transfer points integrated with other public transit;</text></clause><clause id="H03E034495A65423DA36463BF81DBA73B"><enum>(viii)</enum><text>safe and accessible pedestrian design at each station, with a continuous walking path network along the entire corridor;</text></clause><clause id="HEAF47A50D44048218223F0435A875FF3"><enum>(ix)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">service frequency no less than 6 buses per hour on all routes;</text></clause><clause id="HFB2AA070AA2F46E98B2F418C81E752D6"><enum>(x)</enum><text>at least 5 elements out of—</text><subclause id="H44007C09559A4094850EE44B67752DC3"><enum>(I)</enum><text>off board fare collection;</text></subclause><subclause id="HFF6E62B225CD49B0BD3E1D49DFCB6151"><enum>(II)</enum><text>traffic signal priority;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCD7B67CEC90A4958B1601A271F8BC467"><enum>(III)</enum><text>turns prohibited across the busway;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC378D9C95A0B404098288DFF2C6EC4E0"><enum>(IV)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a system that includes multiple routes or is connected to an existing route;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA66CFA3D3E3749A0851C87C00C00E8DE"><enum>(V)</enum><text>stations separated by between 0.2 and 0.5 miles;</text></subclause><subclause id="H7D904F16B8A446879AD401AEA4A410C5"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>a fare system that can be integrated with other modes of transport; or</text></subclause><subclause id="HB1ADFE6C6FFD424F8B277656FDC623E7"><enum>(VII)</enum><text>platform level boarding; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H7851587AE4F34462B0AD6F7CA55BB3DD"><enum>(xi)</enum><text>at least 10 elements out of—</text><subclause id="H853F77AC15D242BDB714B935DBCC9AC1"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">multiple routes sharing corridors;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCA016565CF294C0EB8D7998971AD7E0E"><enum>(II)</enum><text>limited and express services;</text></subclause><subclause id="H74B435E531D745B390D064B287A7F392"><enum>(III)</enum><text>a full service control center;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCE9DB748B6214CBA8A43BF45A4A75DAE"><enum>(IV)</enum><text>location in 1 of the locality’s top 10 demand corridors;</text></subclause><subclause id="HC40A9A191DD24827942133F05C647FE2"><enum>(V)</enum><text>late night and weekend service;</text></subclause><subclause id="HA8E484051AAB447F8F5E5EEC3AC18629"><enum>(VI)</enum><text>passing lanes at not less than 60 percent of station stops;</text></subclause><subclause id="H3013A329BC47409FBD6431CAE2F5FD46"><enum>(VII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">at least 80 percent of stations are located at least 100 feet from intersections;</text></subclause><subclause id="HBD61AC0379FE401EBC22D2665A70E2E2"><enum>(VIII)</enum><text>physically connected center stations serving both directions of the bus rapid transit system;</text></subclause><subclause id="H6162BB35A27B478FB51B9E8F196038D3"><enum>(IX)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">90 percent of stations offer seating, are weather-protected, well-lit, and at least 8 feet wide;</text></subclause><subclause id="H95D009C224594BBE806103CEF6A4A318"><enum>(X)</enum><text>buses have at least 3 doors (for articulated buses) or 2 wide doors (for non-articulated buses) on the station side, including the system allowing for boarding at all doors;</text></subclause><subclause id="H0F44EBAE030549E69CF3B8B2910B0989"><enum>(XI)</enum><text>at least 2 substops or docking bays at the highest demand stations;</text></subclause><subclause id="HCFF1E7DE37B34B9995771D3FE9BBB934"><enum>(XII)</enum><text>all stations have sliding doors;</text></subclause><subclause id="H8C11C99F55074244B1FEF540BCDB8341"><enum>(XIII)</enum><text>secure bicycle parking at least in higher-demand stations and standard bicycle racks elsewhere;</text></subclause><subclause id="H2D489BD2372B409B97F7BC998132CD21"><enum>(XIV)</enum><text>bicycle lanes on or parallel to 75 percent of the corridor;</text></subclause><subclause id="HAC9EC95E9C9F4B3CAAFEEE10880452B6"><enum>(XV)</enum><text>bicycle sharing available at 50 percent or more of stations;</text></subclause><subclause id="H49E053D83C3E4A80995413652F20F157"><enum>(XVI)</enum><text>elimination or prohibition on parking minimums in the area of the system; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H751DE29B31FE442A91D1D34517AB5B12"><enum>(XVII)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">service frequency of no less than 7 buses per hour on all routes;</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE06EB31672CF46B384A8DC8A7771A88D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>powers charging infrastructure with renewable energy; </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9609652165094BA7B7CDF6D07BD394A2"><enum>(C)</enum><text>uses labor standards at least as protective as the labor standards described in section 5333 of title 49, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF2D62099EFCB48A0B73B7238182E7A66"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">meets domestic assembly qualifications for its buses and charging equipment.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H35F9E2051EAB46E29C125D567A8FA202"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Domestic assembly qualifications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>domestic assembly qualifications</quote> means, with respect to any qualifying electric bus or charging equipment, that the final assembly of such a bus or charger occurs at a plant, factory, or other place which is located in the United States and operating under a collective bargaining agreement negotiated by an employee organization (as defined in <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/26/412">section 412(c)(4)(B)(ii)(II)</external-xref> of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986), determined in a manner consistent with section 7701(a)(46) of such Code. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6CB3D757CE9D4F11BBE327D56C312938"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Economically disadvantaged community</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>economically disadvantaged community</quote> means an economically disadvantaged community, including an environmental justice community, an underserved community, or a community located in an area of persistent poverty (as such term is defined in section 101 of title 23, United States Code). </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFEAE86853B084877A18B5537C5101C29"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Platform level boarding</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>platform level boarding</quote> means a platform for boarding a bus that contains no more than 0.5 inch vertical gap between the bus floor and the station platform.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4D12130664414D209E9AD19F2BCD575A"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Renewable energy</header><text>The term <quote>renewable energy</quote> means solar, wind, geothermal, and tidal energy. </text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

