<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Reported-in-House" dms-id="H7823ED9B89BD4C728867D48E225DB5FB" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 2626 RH: Pullman National Historical Park Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-11-17</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">IB</distribution-code><calendar display="yes">Union Calendar No. 423</calendar><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 2626</legis-num><associated-doc role="report" display="yes">[Report No. 117–582]</associated-doc><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20210416">April 16, 2021</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="K000385">Ms. Kelly of Illinois</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="Q000023">Mr. Quigley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001286">Mrs. Bustos</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HII00">Committee on Natural Resources</committee-name></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221117">November 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Additional sponsor: <cosponsor name-id="D000619">Mr. Rodney Davis of Illinois</cosponsor></action-desc></action><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221117">November 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc><action-instruction>Strike out all after the enacting clause and insert the part printed in italic</action-instruction><action-instruction>For text of introduced bill, see copy of bill as introduced on April 16, 2021</action-instruction></action><action><action-desc><pagebreak></pagebreak></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To redesignate the Pullman National Monument in the State of Illinois as the Pullman National Historical Park, and for other purposes.<pagebreak></pagebreak></official-title></form><legis-body display-enacting-clause="yes-display-enacting-clause" changed="added" style="OLC" committee-id="HII00" reported-display-style="italic" id="HA3138E516FDF4CA8BA042F0EDDFB805D"><section id="H1FA1A70BC9274F59BBC0BD3BA041D7FB" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pullman National Historical Park Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H93E651EAEBA646BEBCF50C142A62A07B"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H0A49FFDE3EBC4F34915AFEFFF2B09850"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Historical park</header><text>The term <quote>historical park</quote> means the Pullman National Historical Park established in section 3(a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H09D9EEC64BDE48D199B916271BCB9BA7"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <quote>Secretary</quote> means the Secretary of the Interior.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H147CFC167FB946D4B5D8C9A38ADD4CFC"><enum>3.</enum><header>Redesignation of Pullman National Monument</header><subsection id="HA9A1339DCD2349CF89A8A536EFBE9676"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>There is established the Pullman National Historical Park for the purposes set forth in this Act.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2A831D6687E84016972FE06475C132F1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Abolishment of monument, incorporation of lands, and availability of funds</header><text>The Pullman National Monument, established by Proclamation Number 9233, dated February 19, 2015, is abolished as such, and all lands or interests in land that constitute the Monument (as in existence on the day before the date of enactment of this Act) are incorporated in, and shall be considered to be part of, the historical park. Any funds available for purposes of the Pullman National Monument shall be available for purposes of the historical park.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5C64E08C203A46DEA85AE57F886B207A"><enum>(c)</enum><header>References</header><text>Any references in a law, regulation, document, record, map, or other paper of the United States to the Pullman National Monument shall be considered to be a reference to the historical park.</text></subsection></section><section id="H93A288A848D84A9F8836C00CB350472B"><enum>4.</enum><header>Purposes</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The purposes of the historical park are to preserve, protect, and interpret Pullman’s nationally significant cultural and historical resources associated with—</text><paragraph id="H0C1439B6CF0740E38BF9BF801F7C0E1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Nation’s labor history and creation of a national Labor Day holiday;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB429C67385AA43679CDE81878288DFE5"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the first planned model industrial community in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEFC4F53164EC4265B642C984E4919D0A"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the architecture and landscape design of the planned community;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H90C59A4E8370428B939A522046073594"><enum>(4)</enum><text>the pivotal role of the Pullman porter in the rise of the African-American middle class; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9CC848AB08840CE939AB9DA2101AE26"><enum>(5)</enum><text>the entirety of the history, and historic figures discussed in Presidential Proclamation Number 9233.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H92EC3F1AF2E54A01A7B45DBBDB667614"><enum>5.</enum><header>Boundaries</header><subsection id="H162293D577834ECCB17ED983740C5609"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The boundaries of the historical park are as generally depicted on the map entitled <quote>Pullman National Historical Park</quote>, numbered 590-125,485, and dated November 2021.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAB15A4C7E1624BFDA2AD18479374A42A"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Acquisition of land</header><text>The Secretary may acquire land, including interests in land, within the boundaries of the historical park by donation, transfer, exchange, or purchase from a willing seller using donated or appropriated funds.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2AE00D69899E4312B8DE45D88394BF09"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Availability of map</header><text>The map shall be on file and available for public inspection in the appropriate offices of the National Park Service and the Department of the Interior.</text></subsection></section><section id="H852BE7879A4141F9B36F7D62265797D3"><enum>6.</enum><header>Administration</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Secretary shall administer the land within the boundary of the historical park in accordance with—</text><paragraph id="H6AF401A852E444C3A6BC9D9B38D6FB90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>this Act; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14DEF03427C54BF1B89A2927FEBA9F3F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the laws generally applicable to units of the National Park System, including—</text><subparagraph id="H07D17579A7BF4E61B924D6B932CC17D2"><enum>(A)</enum><text>section 100101(a), chapter 1003, and sections 100751(a), 100752, 100753 and 102101 of title 54, United States Code; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H75E11573821544C8ACDA75D9E942A0CF"><enum>(B)</enum><text><external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/54/3201">chapter 3201</external-xref> of title 54, United States Code.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></section><section id="H3D5BA0FB314747B9922B783CB47597A1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Cooperative agreements</header><subsection id="HB50675604B854C4FBC5E71817741C8AA"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the State, other public and non-profit entities, and other interested parties to identify, interpret, and provide technical assistance, including collaborative interpretive and educational programs, at—</text><paragraph id="H924E84661AFC42908D23866FA8DFF48D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>non-Federal historic properties within the boundaries of the historical park; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB52F93019784D9795827CD69364B2B1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>sites in close proximity to the historical park, but located outside the boundaries of the historical park, including providing for placement of directional and interpretive signage, exhibits, and technology-based interpretive devices.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEEA899042A734D94A97B28B43F09CF31"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Preservation</header><text>The Secretary may enter into cooperative agreements with the State, other public and non-profit entities, and other interested parties to provide financial assistance to mark, interpret, and restore non-Federal nationally significant historic or cultural properties and resources within the historical park as the Secretary determines appropriate to carry out the purposes of this Act. These cooperative agreements will be subject to such terms and conditions that the Secretary determines necessary, and shall provide that—</text><paragraph id="HF879BCF8CE914A80B80349F8E88A2BE5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>reasonable public access to the property covered by such agreement for the purpose of interpreting them to the public;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBB95C589C8054C90A9D68629AA357A0F"><enum>(2)</enum><text>no changes or alterations shall be made to the exterior of the properties except by mutual agreement of the other parties to the agreements; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3D8EC7602AE64F4E81F73D47EF475B00"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the Federal share of the total cost of any activity carried out under the agreement shall be not more than 50 percent, with in-kind contributions or goods or services fairly valued authorized, as appropriate, for the non-Federal share; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE3433A7FFA47EF9317C990959FB180"><enum>(4)</enum><text>any conversion, use, or disposal of the restored property for purposes that are inconsistent with the purposes of this subsection, as determined by the Secretary, shall result in a right of the United States to reimbursement of the greater of—</text><subparagraph id="HE749FE23968A4C3CA6682EDF76F8A6EE"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the amount provided by the Secretary to the project; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC678FC1B1CEA4282889E9A5891A28566"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an amount equal to the increase in the value of the project that is attributable to the funds, as determined by the Secretary at the time of the conversion, use, or disposal.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HC4B2923F76A5451B967CB9E7F0E36367"><enum>8.</enum><header>Management plan</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Not later than 3 years after the date on which funds are first made available to carry out this Act, the Secretary shall complete a general management plan for the historical park in accordance with section 100502 of title 54.</text></section></legis-body><endorsement display="yes"><action-date date="20221117">November 17, 2022</action-date><action-desc>Reported with an amendment, committed to the Committee of the Whole House on the State of the Union, and ordered to be printed</action-desc></endorsement></bill> 

