<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HA5F1B20CB1C04B9A9FB745E09F2C085E" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6494 IH: Stopping Corrupt Actors from Making Political Action Committees Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-01-25</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6494</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220125">January 25, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001203">Mr. Malinowski</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="P000618">Ms. Porter</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000606">Mr. Raskin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000616">Mr. Phillips</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M000312">Mr. McGovern</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000472">Mr. Takano</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000147">Ms. Norton</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="T000481">Ms. Tlaib</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHA00">Committee on House Administration</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the disbursement of funds to entities owned or controlled by individuals with executive or managerial authority over the operations of political committees, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HDEC517C1183C4F11B0C2328A172AEA5D" style="OLC"><section id="H0BF928F1809544AE96126E6FEBFBEFDA" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Stopping Corrupt Actors from Making Political Action Committees Act</short-title></quote> or the <quote><short-title>SCAM PAC Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HCD03F96BD14F459A91BA1203C2C64B86"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on disbursement of funds to entities owned or controlled by individuals with authority over operations of political committees</header><subsection id="HF28DBED877DA4CACA305BF88AA3CBD77"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 302 of the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/52/30102">52 U.S.C. 30102</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H23290E38E78345F9B157DD468257C56D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H2A89A8793D1E4D83A04052011F1CF43B"><enum>(j)</enum><paragraph commented="no" display-inline="yes-display-inline" id="H5B3925A223F7414D96551B74BF85B4E1"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Except as provided in paragraphs (3) and (4), during a reporting period covered by a report filed by a political committee under section 304, the committee may not make disbursements to an entity owned or controlled in whole or in part by an individual, or by an immediate family member of an individual—</text><subparagraph id="HBFEE908B16BD4B74ACDD4DB369AE1518" indent="up1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>who is authorized to carry out executive or managerial authority over the operation of the committee;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDAB6E05A5E894722B1D84382833ED527" indent="up1"><enum>(B)</enum><text>who is authorized to solicit or disburse funds for or on behalf of the committee; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9E7A4B09C7C64C2089B0C6A78DD5590D" indent="up1"><enum>(C)</enum><text>who is an employee of the committee (whether paid or unpaid) and who provides the committee with professional services (other than accounting or legal services) relating to the committee’s campaign or fundraising strategy.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H70DC9055A27248A2B463ED5DAEB5B41D" indent="up1"><enum>(2)</enum><text>A political committee may not employ or allow to volunteer on behalf of the committee an individual who owns or controls an entity that has accepted disbursements made from any political committee in violation of paragraph (1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D991706F6FE47059BB2C6E8F6A7F90C" indent="up1"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to disbursements made by a political committee during the reporting period covered by a report filed by the committee under section 304 if the committee includes in the report a true and accurate certification, under penalty of perjury, that a majority of the funds disbursed by the committee during the period were for expenses other than administrative costs, fundraising costs, and salaries of employees of the committee.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4EFC13D808C14194803764F8CD0466DC" indent="up1"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Paragraph (1) does not apply with respect to the following:</text><subparagraph id="H63066660971E4F17827F52D82C7C91D1"><enum>(A)</enum><text>An authorized committee of a candidate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H73FB0B5DF5E84646B8937241947D9D3F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>A committee of a political party.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3DB2D853FC3543088481F886061E5707"><enum>(C)</enum><text>A separate segregated fund of a corporation or labor organization under section 316(b)(2)(C).</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0FCF9114880843C98927A0009F0F6B0E" indent="up1"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this subsection, the term <term>immediate family member</term> means, with respect to an individual, a parent, parent-in law, grandparent, child, child-in law, grandchild, spouse, or sibling. </text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection><subsection id="H26CE4A3E71E741318AFE2D93BE39CC50"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendment made by subsection (a) shall apply with respect to disbursements made on or after the date that is 90 days after the date of enactment of this Act. </text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

