<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE30631E15A3D47ECB19D133D326D7BFE" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8316 IH: Securing America’s Borders Against Fentanyl Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-07-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8316</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220707">July 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="S001209">Ms. Spanberger</sponsor> (for herself and <cosponsor name-id="G000597">Mr. Garbarino</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HHM00">Committee on Homeland Security</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HGO00">Oversight and Reform</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require reports, evaluations, and research by the Department of Homeland Security regarding drug interdiction along the border, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H94BF86F96045426F86719063EBE9C92B" style="OLC"><section id="HACEF135FCC414E55842EC16A5DA05961" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Securing America’s Borders Against Fentanyl Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H4BEADFED699D40AEA71E9744700054E4"><enum>2.</enum><header>Reports, evaluations, and research regarding drug interdiction at and between ports of entry</header><subsection id="H4CF3B7661C0242B2B1BCE59A2C739A98"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Research on additional technologies To detect fentanyl</header><paragraph id="H5A34714BB5D54D939A148F48857AB2C1"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Federal Drug Administration, and the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency, shall research additional technological solutions to—</text><subparagraph id="HAAA0BD5C969B452C9F4188D80FB73BFB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">target and detect illicit fentanyl and its precursors, including low-purity fentanyl, especially in counterfeit pressed tablets, and illicit pill press molds;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H01B3D5193EA24D0C894436E558B0157D"><enum>(B)</enum><text>enhance targeting of counterfeit pills through nonintrusive, noninvasive, and other visual screening technologies; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCD4A55B6F4564629A044FD62F394C984"><enum>(C)</enum><text>enhance data-driven targeting to increase seizure rates of fentanyl and its precursors.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC9EEA83472B4602B6AE25FCB167A707"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There is authorized to be appropriated to the Secretary of Homeland Security to carry out this subsection $20,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H8FB959608EAB4FB3BF086C6A49DC7A53"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Evaluation of current technologies and strategies in illicit drug interdiction and procurement decisions</header><paragraph id="H3F6B7D1EA1E947E4AFE60F1C8F43E0D6"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Homeland Security, in consultation with the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, shall establish a program to collect available data and develop metrics to measure how technologies and strategies used by the Department, U.S. Customs and Border Protection, and other relevant Federal agencies have helped detect, deter, or address illicit fentanyl and its precursors being trafficking into the United States at and between land, air, and sea ports of entry. Such data and metrics program may consider the rate of detection at random secondary inspections at such ports of entry, investigations and intelligence sharing into the origins of illicit fentanyl later detected within the United States, and other data or metrics considered appropriate by the Secretary. The Secretary, as appropriate and in the coordination with the officials specified in this paragraph, may update such data and metrics program.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H80CCB088519F45CAAEE8B7270037F8F6"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports</header><subparagraph id="H3AA6471DF7D74417B0DD6B8AFE804CE3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Secretary of Homeland Security</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after the date of the enactment of this Act and biennially thereafter, the Secretary of Homeland Security, the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration, the Director of the Federal Bureau of Investigation, the Director of the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, the Commissioner of Food and Drugs, and the Postmaster General shall, based on the data collected and metrics developed pursuant to the program established under paragraph (1), submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs a report that—</text><clause id="HA9CDC79D66E44957A19882CDB371DAB6"><enum>(i)</enum><text>examines and analyzes current technologies deployed at land, air, and sea ports of entry, including pilot technologies, to assess how well such technologies detect, deter, and address fentanyl and its precursors;</text></clause><clause id="HFF80B98FA14749209C7D8383DC34CAD5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>contains a cost-benefit analysis of technologies used in drug interdiction; and</text></clause><clause id="H1C29B9BFC2F64C0196ECEEDC28FD98BA"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>describes how such analysis may be used when making procurement decisions relating to such technologies.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2C4E13992AF426BB6BF742E4B7D8AA1"><enum>(B)</enum><header>GAO</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than one year after each report submitted pursuant to subparagraph (A), the Comptroller General of the United States shall submit to the Committee on Homeland Security of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Homeland Security and Governmental Affairs of the Senate a report that evaluates and, as appropriate, makes recommendations to improve, the data collected and metrics used in each such report.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H51B13D29FB4B4E8FA1DE647AB8FEC110"><enum>3.</enum><header>ONDCP supplemental strategies</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 706(h) of the Office of National Drug Control Policy Reauthorization Act of 1998 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/1705">21 U.S.C. 1705(h)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HB85347ACD3DC47D798BE0D6024B77104"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5D1877652D1D4DBBA6DA931EC92C97DA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting <quote>; and</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H48A5ACA8AB784B5980C2D1E5549DE86D"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new paragraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H5DCE903602B446D1B3D0D6A457B38F2D" display-inline="no-display-inline"><paragraph id="H939B58C4E2574396A01A1FEA08B29CB6"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">develops performance measures and targets for the National Drug Control Strategy for supplemental strategies (the Southwest Border, Northern Border, and Caribbean Border Counternarcotics Strategies) to effectively evaluate region-specific goals, to the extent the performance measurement system does not adequately measure the effectiveness of the strategies, as determined by the Director, such strategies may evaluate interdiction efforts at and between ports of entry, interdiction technology, intelligence sharing, diplomacy, and other appropriate metrics, specific to each supplemental strategies region, as determined by the Director. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

