<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEF34CC89FD94467586F3740718C11B24" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 9542 IH: Higher Education Access for Military Dependents Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-12-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 9542</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20221214">December 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="M001215">Mrs. Miller-Meeks</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend the Higher Education Act of 1965 to ensure fairness in the award of in-State tuition at public institutions of higher education for members of qualifying Federal services changing duty locations and their spouses and dependent children, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4DE6F38BCBAF415D88F5FE2C9E6D2D8B" style="OLC"><section id="HA7E1E2997CFC4A1991846AAEA518A380" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Higher Education Access for Military Dependents Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H568B7448573D42C3AFDC788A05C0DA0A"><enum>2.</enum><header>In-State tuition rates for members of qualifying Federal services, spouses, and dependent children</header><subsection id="H4A0F8A138A734523891C874D5CA6E344"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 135 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1015d">20 U.S.C. 1015d</external-xref>), as amended by section 6206 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>), is amended—</text><paragraph id="H3B3BC64C99CD4967AEC0AE822037CBDE" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (b)—</text><subparagraph id="H5E23206EB1694D3A930BD7FA72FAD38D"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>while continuously enrolled at that institution</quote> inserting <quote>while continuously enrolled at that institution in the same course of study for which such rate was determined</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7699E37F79A54F619C4F9FC8B513D5E8"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following: <quote>Each institution of higher education subject to this section shall ensure that the terms and conditions of continuation under this subsection are made available on a publicly accessible website of the institution in a clear and conspicuous format.</quote>;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H90F7BAF08AB54111985E62867A1D9D9A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by redesignating subsections (c) and (d) as subsections (d) and (e), respectively; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5F9556D89FD64CD2A0B1B9229FE36651"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by inserting after subsection (b) the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HA7A16144EC3D4E0395F796A2EC558A71" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H7C747EFD3CCB477F83445185CD164B32"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Effect of transfer prior to attendance</header><paragraph id="H6AA7418F2F784C709222ECE3D7F5B270"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In the case of a member of a qualifying Federal service (or the spouse or dependent child of such a member) who is accepted for enrollment at a public institution of higher education in a State and who meets the requirements of paragraph (2), the provisions of subsections (a) and (b) shall apply to such member, spouse, or dependent (as the case may be) notwithstanding a change in the permanent duty station of the member to a location outside such State prior to the member’s, spouse’s, or dependent’s initial date of attendance at such institution.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE58C54074DB94D35BA8470F9121FFE12"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><subparagraph id="HB9D16AF8022A470B9519F4EFB511D047"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Member requirements</header><text>A member of a qualifying Federal service meets the requirements of this subsection if—</text><clause id="H754FB1279B8B40E9B9DE1FE08EB0DA13"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the member is accepted for enrollment at a public institution of higher education in a State (regardless of the location at which such member is domiciled or stationed at the time of application to such institution); and</text></clause><clause id="H207C4C7AF9BD4B7CB9E1A969BA5F12D5"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the domicile or permanent duty station of such member was in such State for a period of more than 30 days at any time during the period of one year preceding that member’s initial date of attendance at such institution.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6FAA5489E93E43058894C4DCE6F22248"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Spouse and dependent requirements</header><text>A spouse or dependent child of a member of a qualifying Federal service meets the requirements of this subsection if—</text><clause id="HC9D8A1795CDB4AF2AD9922A153850E1A"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the spouse or dependent child is accepted for enrollment at a public institution of higher education in a State (regardless of the location at which such member is domiciled or stationed at the time of the spouse’s or dependent child’s application to such institution); and</text></clause><clause id="H168C94D087FE4EB7896A8B9E94ED7820"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the domicile or permanent duty station of the member of a qualifying Federal service who is the spouse or parent of the individual described in clause (i) was in such State for a period of more than 30 days at any time during the period of one year preceding that individual’s initial date of attendance at such institution.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6FCD8E51B3C341B5B40A606EE84E95AE"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Rule of construction</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Nothing in this subsection shall be construed to limit the authority of a State or public institution of higher education to a provide a tuition benefit to a member of a qualifying Federal service (or the spouse or dependent child of such a member) on terms that are less restrictive than the terms specified in this subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4C3DEE4255094FF5B3EB439ECBE22938"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Effective date and applicability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amendments made by subsection (a) shall take effect immediately after the coming into effect of the amendments made by section 6206 of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2022 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/117/81">Public Law 117–81</external-xref>) and shall apply as provided by subsection (b) of that section.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

