<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Engrossed-in-House" dms-id="H4E0B7C0A3CE54E3192E1EE0ABABF8855" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc" stage-count="1"> 
<metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 5914 EH: Empowering States to Protect Seniors from Bad Actors Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date></dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="no">I</distribution-code> 
<congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session> 
<legis-num display="yes">H. R. 5914</legis-num> 
<current-chamber display="no">IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber> 
<legis-type>AN ACT</legis-type> 
<official-title display="yes">To amend the Investor Protection and Securities Reform Act of 2010 to provide grants to States for enhanced protection of senior investors and senior policyholders, and for other purposes.</official-title> 
</form> 
<legis-body id="HF1200499376745029EA8D134E4A7BE31" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H5FECECD349934F31B243FE71344C4218" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Empowering States to Protect Seniors from Bad Actors Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section> <section id="H2DA9B575C9844E42A4E95A19DBDFE1B0"><enum>2.</enum><header>Grants to eligible entities for enhanced protection of senior investors and senior policyholders</header> <subsection id="HC385E8F9CDF24F5AA3A417B6B7BB7AE1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 989A of the Investor Protection and Securities Reform Act of 2010 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/15/5537">15 U.S.C. 5537</external-xref>) is amended to read as follows:</text> 
<quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H23D145DC23F24BA58C5097E4E8AAD49E"> 
<section id="HA863277ACD404DAFA0EC8930686BE4D6"><enum>989A.</enum><header>Grants to eligible entities for enhanced protection of senior investors and senior policyholders</header> 
<subsection id="H026CC00F4C8742D193EE25FEBFC13244"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section:</text> <paragraph id="HA3AD535D46C34CBC921086DC2D6EC6A3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible entity</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible entity</term> means—</text> 
<subparagraph id="HB88009F1A3A142EE9F20DCA356B4AC5E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the securities commission (or any agency or office performing like functions) of any State; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8B78A1D897AF48D18A581EAEFD2F5C29"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the insurance department (or any agency or office performing like functions) of any State.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H12E65198760D4DBB952700BBCA5AEB46"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Senior</header><text>The term <term>senior</term> means any individual who has attained the age of 62 years or older.</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H9DD4A67F410A4798A4D88D4D4D11508C"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Senior financial fraud</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>senior financial fraud</term> means a fraudulent or otherwise illegal, unauthorized, or improper act or process of an individual, including a caregiver or a fiduciary, that—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H60AA6B798D0245908C544DF28B55FC30"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">uses the resources of a senior for monetary or personal benefit, profit, or gain;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H32DDE1CEBCB144F28AA4C7BDD00C5566"><enum>(B)</enum><text>results in depriving a senior of rightful access to or use of benefits, resources, belongings, or assets; or</text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HF8F842F2D90047E7A47A22C2C405B872"><enum>(C)</enum><text>is an action described in section 1348 of title 18, United States Code, that is taken against a senior.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H1153C8C33EC34DE18F8FEC510C3E9CA4"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Task force</header><text>The term <term>task force</term> means the task force established under subsection (b)(1). </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="HE7D7EE59919948108CB3FF284FC5B87F"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Grant program</header> 
<paragraph id="HB99912C548E94502ABF729887D354FE8"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Task force</header> 
<subparagraph id="HDFF1E4EC275F476DB2806BF7AE88F1B4"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Commission shall establish a task force to carry out the grant program under paragraph (2).</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H230855AEC9164182AE30814A408FBC1A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Membership</header><text>The task force shall consist of the following members:</text> 
<clause id="HC698BCA6364B453DA2EC3166DA855487"><enum>(i)</enum><text>A Chair of the task force, who—</text> <subclause id="H04ED5CF7A31D4C65967100A685A3E32D"><enum>(I)</enum><text>shall be appointed by the Chairman of the Commission, in consultation with the Commissioners of the Commission; and</text></subclause> 
<subclause id="H1482EA7619FB4F92BEA826DDB6E70D2F"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may be a representative of the Office of the Investor Advocate of the Commission, the Division of Enforcement of the Commission, or such other representative as the Commission determines appropriate. </text></subclause></clause> <clause id="HFE0DF8ACADAF4FEA8BACDA9972B9B9E0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If the Chair is not a representative of the Office of the Investor Advocate of the Commission, a representative of such Office. </text></clause> 
<clause id="H1678326002204D5BB9F609A0623F9806"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>If the Chair is not a representative of the Division of Enforcement of the Commission, a representative of such Division.</text></clause> <clause id="H34D2E6AAC5DC45F29C46CA11AD221C44"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>Such other representatives as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H0485A9665E2C4CFDB88F826425627251" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Detail of executive agency employees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Upon the request of the Commission, the head of any Federal agency may detail, on a reimbursable basis, any of the personnel of that Federal agency to the Commission to assist it in carrying out its functions under this section. The detail of any such personnel shall be without interruption or loss of civil service status or privilege.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H6108D05E7E264C5D8E3F434C8C233AA8"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Grants</header><text>The task force shall carry out a program under which the task force shall make grants, on a competitive basis, to eligible entities, which—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H22A8F99099CA4D359E17904A80C6747B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may use the grant funds—</text> <clause id="H7A95062395B145AAA86215806F8308F2"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to hire staff to identify, investigate, and prosecute (through civil, administrative, or criminal enforcement actions) cases involving senior financial fraud;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H5ECBAD98D44B4302BB16FBC515028F44"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to fund technology, equipment, and training for regulators, prosecutors, and law enforcement officers, in order to identify, investigate, and prosecute cases involving senior financial fraud;</text></clause> <clause id="H1B1A3F929A1D4BA19C86959AD82C0829"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to provide educational materials and training to seniors to increase awareness and understanding of senior financial fraud;</text></clause> 
<clause id="H090E0EB201164A9E9642A37B93D7377B"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to develop comprehensive plans to combat senior financial fraud; and</text></clause> <clause id="HB43F276DEDF24AD0AF299C4F1C3B1732"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to enhance provisions of State law to provide protection from senior financial fraud; and</text></clause></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="H507C60995E7941C0930E95247CADE668"><enum>(B)</enum><text>may not use the grant funds for any indirect expense, such as rent, utilities, or any other general administrative cost that is not directly related to the purpose of the grant program.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> <paragraph id="H5F0D6EA190EC49A993F464F6CDB2A514"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Authority of task force</header><text>In carrying out paragraph (2), the task force—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H0C537695DFC74375B4921F37CE526A52"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may consult with staff of the Commission; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H0C48AFC3C3654922ADC2DB124DFB4656" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall make public all actions of the task force relating to carrying out that paragraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H47B0200B415B4BE88D35A6211C55C6CF"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Applications</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity desiring a grant under this section shall submit an application to the task force, in such form and in such a manner as the task force may determine, that includes—</text> <paragraph id="H3C063996A43043149701BB1A768F2077"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a proposal for activities to protect seniors from senior financial fraud that are proposed to be funded using a grant under this section, including—</text> 
<subparagraph id="H829A8686D4624762BFBD188EAC008629"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an identification of the scope of the problem of senior financial fraud in the applicable State;</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H6981C4FF898F42F9A30177B6896C9E06"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a description of how the proposed activities would—</text> 
<clause id="HB0B66591816346AD9445AAD8977E5DBB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">protect seniors from senior financial fraud, including by proactively identifying victims of senior financial fraud;</text></clause> <clause commented="no" id="H8FFA05A1D05246F8999EA8119D1113FC"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">assist in the investigation and prosecution of those committing senior financial fraud; and</text></clause> 
<clause id="H2B3256261CD7418687B5FCD8D5620512"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">discourage and reduce cases of senior financial fraud; and</text></clause></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H8D4757EC4CA847D29AA6BE7F204074C9"><enum>(C)</enum><text>a description of how the proposed activities would be coordinated with other State efforts; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H54D75CC1C22F486990C70FCBA0C4AD7C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any other information that the task force determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H399A75CDBB48492AA74E2E7EF24AE1AE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Performance objectives; reporting requirements; audits</header> <paragraph id="HF6A060DCB1A640EA83A4753ABDBF3DEC"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The task force— </text> 
<subparagraph id="H9EC10050F1784775B35676E405A98150"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may establish such performance objectives and reporting requirements for eligible entities receiving a grant under this section as the task force determines are necessary to carry out and assess the effectiveness of the program under this section; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="HC2A7805641FF4155A6DDFD9F88F62F58"><enum>(B)</enum><text>shall require each eligible entity that receives a grant under this section to submit to the task force a detailed accounting of the use of grant funds, which shall be submitted at such time, in such form, and containing such information as the task force may require.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H1C285CD4313346B596F47FF13EAF12B3"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 2 years, and again not later than 5 years, after the date of the enactment of the <short-title>Empowering States to Protect Seniors from Bad Actors Act, </short-title>the task force shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report that—</text> <subparagraph id="H92B2A05A217D43FA91F9A2B7820A5ACB"><enum>(A)</enum><text>specifies each recipient of a grant under this section; </text></subparagraph> 
<subparagraph id="HB509AFB7D066486C90E79C00D8C7D22E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>includes a description of the programs that are supported by each such grant; and</text></subparagraph> <subparagraph id="H9DB0EC822CD1453F8E0CEBCBB2E6F78A"><enum>(C)</enum><text>includes an evaluation by the task force of the effectiveness of such grants.</text></subparagraph></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HB7856EDF5939432FA8FC89D6B372E063"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Audits</header><text>The task force shall annually conduct an audit of the program under this section to ensure that eligible entities to which grants are made under that program are, for the year covered by the audit, using grant funds for the intended purposes of those funds.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection commented="no" id="H986A5E8F1D85496B901C1194EFE6A796"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Maximum amount</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The amount of a grant to an eligible entity under this section may not exceed $500,000, which the task force shall adjust annually to reflect the percentage change in the Consumer Price Index for All Urban Consumers published by the Bureau of Labor Statistics of the Department of Labor.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HA210A351A95E4A57948C3050E7A60B47"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Subgrants</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An eligible entity that receives a grant under this section may, in consultation with the task force, make a subgrant, as the eligible entity determines is necessary or appropriate— </text> <paragraph id="H7F6F920F8B8D4D31A4820F42032BB653"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">to carry out the activities described in subsection (b)(2)(A); and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HBB2C917135A248A89AF4B6D21FF788EA"><enum>(2)</enum><text>which may not be used for any activity described in subsection (b)(2)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H72D830671F934F309A8DA7D519613DEC"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">There are authorized to be appropriated to carry out this section $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2028.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDC8458341BB14B96863FE893D7E1BFE0"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Conforming amendment</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The table of contents in section 1(b) of the Dodd-Frank Wall Street Reform and Consumer Protection Act is amended by striking the item relating to section 989A and inserting the following:</text> <quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="H13701C00FEA34BCBAD6FC732B39E0A24"> <toc regeneration="no-regeneration"> <toc-entry level="section">Sec.989A. Grants to eligible entities for enhanced protection of senior investors and senior policyholders.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section> </legis-body> <attestation><attestation-group><attestation-date date="20220510" chamber="House">Passed the House of Representatives May 11, 2022.</attestation-date><attestor display="no">Cheryl L. Johnson,</attestor><role>Clerk.</role></attestation-group></attestation> <endorsement display="yes"></endorsement> </bill> 

