<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HEE0A6AD0AAE84FD9811092C328DD69F2" public-private="public" key="G" bill-type="olc" star-print="first-star-print"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>114 HR 6968 IH: Suspending Energy Imports from Russia Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-08</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6968</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220308">March 8, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000399">Mr. Doggett</sponsor> (for himself, <cosponsor name-id="B000574">Mr. Blumenauer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000460">Mr. Thompson of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000096">Mr. Pascrell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001156">Ms. Sánchez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001038">Mr. Higgins of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001185">Ms. Sewell</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000617">Ms. DelBene</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001080">Ms. Chu</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001292">Mr. Beyer</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001190">Mr. Schneider</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000188">Mr. Kind</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000375">Mr. Keating</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001163">Ms. Matsui</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000216">Ms. DeLauro</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000034">Mr. Pallone</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="K000009">Ms. Kaptur</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000131">Mr. Veasey</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000587">Ms. Garcia of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001175">Ms. Speier</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001206">Mr. Morelle</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000305">Ms. Ross</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001117">Mr. Casten</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001069">Mr. Courtney</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001121">Mr. Crow</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001068">Mr. Cohen</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000585">Mr. Gomez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000557">Mr. Larson of Connecticut</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="C001110">Mr. Correa</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HWM00">Committee on Ways and Means</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committees on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">the Judiciary</committee-name>, and <committee-name committee-id="HRU00">Rules</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To prohibit the importation of energy products of the Russian Federation, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA8D739EED98A4DCB934A1B058D608E09" style="OLC"><section id="HD83394EDE4334D0CA824B74CAA52D068" section-type="section-one" commented="no"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Suspending Energy Imports from Russia Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H511A6A304E664CDD9D4137C59DFA54EA"><enum>2.</enum><header>Prohibition on importation of energy products of the Russian Federation</header><subsection id="H2718870894DB467F8586A1B521A75091"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><paragraph id="H11153C49179F4253B0E3B8FB4EA69551"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Prohibition of energy products</header><text>Notwithstanding any other provision of law, all products of the Russian Federation classified under chapter 27 of the Harmonized Tariff Schedule of the United States shall be banned from importation into the United States, other than products imported on or before 11:59 p.m. eastern daylight time on the date that is 45 days after the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7897585598E44A2EAA7288FE563D10EE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Authority to allow importation under contract</header><text>Notwithstanding the prohibition under paragraph (1), the President may allow certain products described in such paragraph to be imported into the United States if the importation of such products is pursuant to a written contract or agreement that was entered into before the date of the enactment of this Act.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD34AEFF5ABBA4A298B66D8B7AAD42AB8"><enum>(b)</enum><header>National interest waiver</header><paragraph id="H6442B0596B674853B575C46A35412A73"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President is authorized to waive the prohibition under subsection (a) with respect to one or more of the products of the Russian Federation described in the matter preceding paragraph (1) of subsection (a) if the President certifies that such waiver is in the national interest of the United States and includes in such certification a description of the product or products to which the waiver is proposed to apply. Such waiver shall take effect beginning on the date that is 90 calendar days after the date of submission of such certification, unless there is enacted into law during such 90-day period a joint resolution of disapproval.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCC8A27AEEDDC490787F4F49535E3427C"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Congressional consultation</header><subparagraph id="HE6783B3AB2E94778B91B350398A7813F"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Prior justification</header><text>The President shall, not later than 15 calendar days before submitting a certification described in paragraph (1), submit to the appropriate congressional committees a justification for the waiver proposed under such paragraph.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H72E49A1A4ADC40399F2CE706D7D12C15"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Appropriate congressional committees</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of this paragraph, the term <quote>appropriate congressional committees</quote> means—</text><clause id="HC39F14CC8D164DE7977F869DF062DB86"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the Committee on Ways and Means, the Committee on Financial Services, and the Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives; and</text></clause><clause id="H62A007EE9CC54966B06CB202A7F26BC0"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the Committee on Finance, the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, and the Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HFC1FEB783CC44C4A87163FAA9B665D3E" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Joint resolution of disapproval</header><paragraph id="H87986BF52FD24BD7980648B58BB4D976" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Definition</header><text>For purposes of this section, the term <term>joint resolution of disapproval</term> means only a joint resolution—</text><subparagraph id="H52A69F5CB8F74A679BD284D059E76F77" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>which does not have a preamble;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6E003CCE132043E0A89E17BB67CB6F73" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the title of which is as follows: <quote>Joint resolution disapproving the President’s proposed waiver under section 2(b)(1) of the Suspending Energy Imports from Russia Act.</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H19BAEC83040E478DBD0E7ED36E000411" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>the matter after the resolving clause of which is as follows: <quote>That Congress disapproves the proposed waiver of the President under section 2(b)(1) of the Suspending Energy Imports from Russia Act, submitted to Congress on ___ </quote>, the blank space being filled in with the appropriate date.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC87455004E0E426A86BD4F88FC953589" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Introduction in the House of Representatives</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of 5 legislative days beginning on the date that a certification under subsection (b)(1) is submitted to Congress, a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the House of Representatives by the majority leader or the minority leader.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE52CC5986FAF40568F0A1F896CFA4C70" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Introduction in the Senate</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">During a period of 5 days on which the Senate is in session beginning on the date that a certification under subsection (b)(1) is submitted to Congress, a joint resolution of disapproval may be introduced in the Senate by the majority leader (or the majority leader’s designee) or the minority leader (or the minority leader’s designee).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0D469039995A4D1CB97B9D2BD889DBE1" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Floor consideration in the House of Representatives</header><subparagraph id="HDC2C4D1B94F9458595CAB3F6F973AF20" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">If a committee of the House to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred has not reported such joint resolution within 10 legislative days after the date of referral, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration thereof. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H510E1994FA1D4D05A00C8D429898810D" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Proceeding to consideration</header><text>Beginning on the third legislative day after each committee to which a joint resolution of disapproval has been referred reports it to the House or has been discharged from further consideration thereof, it shall be in order to move to proceed to consider the joint resolution in the House. All points of order against the motion are waived. Such a motion shall not be in order after the House has disposed of a motion to proceed on a joint resolution with regard to the same certification. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the motion to its adoption without intervening motion. The motion shall not be debatable. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is disposed of shall not be in order. </text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCA73C67913C74E19A819515E2421A257" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Consideration</header><text>The joint resolution shall be considered as read. All points of order against the joint resolution and against its consideration are waived. The previous question shall be considered as ordered on the joint resolution to final passage without intervening motion except two hours of debate equally divided and controlled by the sponsor of the joint resolution (or a designee) and an opponent. A motion to reconsider the vote on passage of the joint resolution shall not be in order. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HDC64815630FC40A9A74F4B685057DD23" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Consideration in the Senate</header><subparagraph id="H8DB9305FFBDB4424A3F64C395BDD6D13" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Committee referral</header><text>A joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate shall be referred to the Committee on Finance.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC8A0F6816A4C47A08D26C1718E29B696" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Reporting and discharge</header><text>If the Committee on Finance has not reported such joint resolution of disapproval within 10 days on which the Senate is in session after the date of referral of such joint resolution, that committee shall be discharged from further consideration of such joint resolution and the joint resolution shall be placed on the appropriate calendar.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H48DE6386AA424D1FAA1CEB8754D33936" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Motion to proceed</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding Rule XXII of the Standing Rules of the Senate, it is in order at any time after the Committee on Finance reports the joint resolution of disapproval to the Senate or has been discharged from its consideration (even though a previous motion to the same effect has been disagreed to) to move to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution, and all points of order against the joint resolution (and against consideration of the joint resolution) shall be waived. The motion to proceed is not debatable. The motion is not subject to a motion to postpone. A motion to reconsider the vote by which the motion is agreed to or disagreed to shall not be in order. If a motion to proceed to the consideration of the joint resolution of disapproval is agreed to, the joint resolution shall remain the unfinished business until disposed of.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H27B203BB074542CCAF50C1C805D04979" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><header>Debate</header><text>Debate on the joint resolution of disapproval, and on all debatable motions and appeals in connection therewith, shall be limited to not more than 10 hours, which shall be divided equally between the majority and minority leaders or their designees. A motion to further limit debate is in order and not debatable. An amendment to, or a motion to postpone, or a motion to proceed to the consideration of other business, or a motion to recommit the joint resolution of disapproval is not in order.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8C90661DDE98440B8D93E542EB87C677" commented="no"><enum>(E)</enum><header>Vote on passage</header><text>The vote on passage shall occur immediately following the conclusion of the debate on the joint resolution of disapproval and a single quorum call at the conclusion of the debate, if requested in accordance with the rules of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA0CE28A9232C4CD5B232A07A3C634F57" commented="no"><enum>(F)</enum><header>Rules of the chair on procedure</header><text>Appeals from the decisions of the Chair relating to the application of the rules of the Senate, as the case may be, to the procedure relating to the joint resolution of disapproval shall be decided without debate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD3E9764173674803B1587FA47C3FAE09" commented="no"><enum>(G)</enum><header>Consideration of veto messages</header><text>Debate in the Senate of any veto message with respect to the joint resolution of disapproval, including all debatable motions and appeals in connection with such joint resolution, shall be limited to 10 hours, to be equally divided between, and controlled by, the majority leader and the minority leader or their designees.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B4EAA8F2A114156A7423CDC5B610F38" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Procedures in the Senate</header><text>Except as otherwise provided in this subsection, the following procedures shall apply in the Senate to a joint resolution of disapproval to which this subsection applies:</text><subparagraph id="H82D59F148F3241A1A61DE85497F176B1" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a joint resolution of disapproval that has passed the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be referred to the Committee on Finance for consideration in accordance with this subsection.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6EA2F68303E1444CA79A64C5ABB3AE34" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>If a joint resolution of disapproval to which this section applies was introduced in the Senate before receipt of a joint resolution of disapproval that has passed the House of Representatives, the joint resolution from the House of Representatives shall, when received in the Senate, be placed on the calendar. If this subparagraph applies, the procedures in the Senate with respect to a joint resolution of disapproval introduced in the Senate that contains the identical matter as the joint resolution of disapproval that passed the House of Representatives shall be the same as if no joint resolution of disapproval had been received from the House of Representatives, except that the vote on passage in the Senate shall be on the joint resolution of disapproval that passed the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD468E4A41408404E9B8B47761B350E56" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Rules of the House of Representatives and Senate</header><text>This subsection is enacted by Congress—</text><subparagraph id="HCFB4C016625842D8B7A408627E213CA3" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>as an exercise of the rulemaking power of the Senate and the House of Representatives, respectively, and as such are deemed a part of the rules of each House, respectively, but applicable only with respect to the procedure to be followed in that House in the case of legislation described in those sections, and supersede other rules only to the extent that they are inconsistent with such rules; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CD54E32B24D4724ACCE5C866C0D9AF2" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>with full recognition of the constitutional right of either House to change the rules (so far as relating to the procedure of that House) at any time, in the same manner, and to the same extent as in the case of any other rule of that House.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H6EBF9876DC9340EFB2EA167D9E713A90" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>3.</enum><header>Cooperation and accountability at the World Trade Organization</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The United States Trade Representative shall use the voice and influence of the United States at the WTO to—</text><paragraph id="H47F1B426566848DEBF4CBD7949F8C8F6" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>condemn the recent aggression in Ukraine; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF04756E5AF454CE3AF6EFA801CB1BB4B" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">encourage other WTO members to suspend trade concessions to the Russian Federation; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4598A9D4A5354CA08156474488D663F6" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">consider further steps with the view to suspend the Russian Federation’s participation in the WTO.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HC6A54552A6D7427B805AFF574D978ABC"><enum>4.</enum><header>Modifications to and reauthorization of sanctions under the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act with respect to human rights violations</header><subsection id="H94B90FACA48A4A09922AE2EF6852376C"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>Section 1262 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended by striking paragraph (2).</text></subsection><subsection id="H974F7CA577CA49958E53CCE7D934A858"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Sense of congress</header><paragraph id="HEFC6966E203B495F9F4B860751D624D2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended by inserting after section 1262 (as amended by subsection (a)) the following new section:</text><quoted-block id="HE4921C7873E548518BCAB49D1144EF1A" style="OLC"><section id="H8B1D9DDBD0364D16B8B61C8CE18F410A"><enum>1262A.</enum><header>Sense of Congress</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">It is the sense of Congress that the President should establish and regularize information sharing and sanctions-related decisionmaking with like-minded governments possessing human rights and anti-corruption sanctions programs similar in nature to those authorized under this subtitle.</text></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H2B84B7B104B045039D5635A68FF758DD" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2(b) and in title XII of division A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>) are each amended by inserting after the items relating to section 1262 the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H22569469E78349EA8BB13669B90BA69F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><toc regeneration="no-regeneration"><toc-entry level="section">Sec. 1262A. Sense of Congress.</toc-entry></toc><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4B43D5001FAD4751905A19DFA1930ACD"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Imposition of sanctions</header><paragraph id="HC09B669FB6134E4CBA42F1238E77C7AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subsection (a) of section 1263 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (Subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended to read as follows:</text><quoted-block id="H02BCE091580D453EBF4FB93081DE083A" style="OLC"><subsection id="HAEDCEC08AF984C518E88D26038F137F1"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The President may impose the sanctions described in subsection (b) with respect to any foreign person that the President determines, based on credible information—</text><paragraph id="H56935F22A9484783B6830CE95FC86140"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in, serious human rights abuse;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H134608F2D42E4838BCB244C41E9DEB8A"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is a current or former government official, or a person acting for or on behalf of such an official, who is responsible for or complicit in, or has directly or indirectly engaged in—</text><subparagraph id="H1F28F623B5264D86ADEA9ADC9A038808"><enum>(A)</enum><text>corruption, including—</text><clause id="H3A13CD3855944F11987ECB511BD27001"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the misappropriation of state assets;</text></clause><clause id="H316A896EB8644358854E4DAC2AE0AE75"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the expropriation of private assets for personal gain;</text></clause><clause id="HA70519F7A0D84267BE8AF891C1C8D3CF"><enum>(iii)</enum><text>corruption related to government contracts or the extraction of natural resources; or</text></clause><clause id="H7A3EC890322F47148648EC78AA33D4BB"><enum>(iv)</enum><text>bribery; or</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA046E5EF421E43F085A412FB9E7F8574"><enum>(B)</enum><text>the transfer or facilitation of the transfer of the proceeds of corruption;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HED3E395E9E484109871528D876F80314"><enum>(3)</enum><text>is or has been a leader or official of—</text><subparagraph id="HF86A14A8C2D548618B776573D0EFB9DA"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an entity, including a government entity, that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, any of the activities described in paragraph (1) or (2) during the tenure of the leader or official; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0CFF8771B02948E09F13326519DA6DC0"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an entity whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section as a result of activities during the tenure of the leader or official;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HFFF585751A4C4C498B165FBE06E0417A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>has materially assisted, sponsored, or provided financial, material, or technological support for, or goods or services to or in support of—</text><subparagraph id="HE063001B0B734E079280F1A19D314F5C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>an activity described in paragraph (1) or (2) that is conducted by a foreign person;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF4A7671A45F94F3695181CA1489AD925"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HDE5D8724FB7C43A39B5C6D8A1E1BC087"><enum>(C)</enum><text>an entity, including a government entity, that has engaged in, or whose members have engaged in, an activity described in paragraph (1) or (2) conducted by a foreign person; or</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HC6083657A58E42E7A0DA9931CA061118"><enum>(5)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by, or has acted or been purported to act for or on behalf of, directly or indirectly, a person whose property and interests in property are blocked pursuant to this section.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H8B423E7196AD4EFCA28915987BEBF06E"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Consideration of certain information</header><text>Subsection (c)(2) of such section is amended by striking <quote>violations of human rights</quote> and inserting <quote>corruption and human rights abuses</quote>.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H89DAF5B8DA37475783164787E5B77207"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Requests by congress</header><text>Subsection (d)(2) of such section is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H75045F208C29419BA1F6E8E682380DB8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (A)—</text><clause id="H931733ECE47D4865A0DC514F4B0527E8"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the subparagraph heading, by striking <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Human rights violations</header-in-text></quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subparagraph" style="OLC">Serious human rights abuse</header-in-text></quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H1184171AB03544B7822CA5BCAC883485"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>described in paragraph (1) or (2) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in subsection (a) relating to serious human rights abuse </quote>; and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE80D28DED110430BA4CC7173FB8CB15F"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B)—</text><clause id="H8B4A17B7F2B748AC97F657CECF36C73B"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in the matter preceding clause (i), by striking <quote>described in paragraph (3) or (4) of subsection (a)</quote> and inserting <quote>described in subsection (a) relating to corruption or the transfer or facilitation of the transfer of the proceeds of corruption</quote>; and</text></clause><clause id="H2FC9E3B544684301BC99D2B306167BAD"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>by striking <quote>ranking member of—</quote> and all that follows through the period at the end and inserting <quote>ranking member of one of the appropriate congressional committees.</quote>.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HF67BA9A11AB748D9AE99F99526461621"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Section 1264(a) of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H594B30DB6DFD4739AA4C76477B5D2D67"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in paragraph (5), by striking <quote>; and</quote> and inserting a semicolon;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CA0164F8AF948809C17EF7239049C10"><enum>(2)</enum><text>in paragraph (6), by striking the period at the end and inserting a semicolon; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H71947B86DC264E2D96539F590696BD49"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block id="H454A9738724341B0B574084DBFE551BD" style="OLC"><paragraph id="HEAF2D7263B5F4566B9A44B91CDBB69A5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>a description of additional steps taken by the President through diplomacy, international engagement, and assistance to foreign or security sectors to address persistent underlying causes of serious human rights abuse and corruption in each country in which foreign persons with respect to which sanctions have been imposed under section 1263 are located; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1763E9137F414F2DB348C253685B4288"><enum>(8)</enum><text>a description of additional steps taken by the President to ensure the pursuit of judicial accountability in appropriate jurisdictions with respect to those foreign persons subject to sanctions under section 1263 for serious human rights abuse and corruption.</text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H37F1B43604CB4C7E9B7DCFE7AEEBE161"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Repeal of sunset</header><paragraph id="HE31F867F4267492F822969B529728C04" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Section 1265 of the Global Magnitsky Human Rights Accountability Act (subtitle F of title XII of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>; <external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/22/2656">22 U.S.C. 2656</external-xref> note) is repealed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF944555FB7F9431FA1189959C2BD67E1" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Clerical amendment</header><text>The table of contents in section 2(b) and in title XII of division A of the National Defense Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 2017 (<external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/114/328">Public Law 114–328</external-xref>) are each amended by striking the items relating to section 1265.</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

