<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE488460CB2074083B91B9C6E38B35568" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8052 IH: Global Nuclear Energy Assessment and Cooperation Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-06-14</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8052</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220614">June 14, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="C001103">Mr. Carter of Georgia</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name>, and in addition to the Committee on <committee-name committee-id="HFA00">Foreign Affairs</committee-name>, for a period to be subsequently determined by the Speaker, in each case for consideration of such provisions as fall within the jurisdiction of the committee concerned</action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the Secretary of Energy to conduct a study on the global status of the civilian nuclear energy industry, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HA63E420EEB1E495E89671083E2F87D04" style="OLC"><section id="HCB2CE487C4D54F329BB6CC386F768E82" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Global Nuclear Energy Assessment and Cooperation Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HF463F562104A47048D859AF97DA76C5E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Global nuclear energy assessment study</header><subsection id="HAFFED0CCE56E4AC5A301CA6C9EDA7937" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Study required</header><text>Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Commerce, the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, and the Commission, shall conduct a study on the global status of—</text><paragraph id="HD98392B5C92942D0B31F6590F113CCCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the civilian nuclear energy industry; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEDA456B03E1D4391B74763B4D5AEF59B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the supply chains of the civilian nuclear energy industry.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91A93D365BAF4B878A045B75D7FAC3B1"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Contents</header><text>The study conducted under subsection (a) shall include—</text><paragraph id="H19D8134F8BC048D1BCF279CC3AD3A927"><enum>(1)</enum><text>information on the status of the civilian nuclear energy industry, the long-term risks to such industry, and the basis for such risks;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2A43F6ABAFDA4C27A178ECC229C98898"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on how the use of the civilian nuclear energy industry, relative to other types of energy industries, can reduce the emission of criteria pollutants and carbon dioxide;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF20AFE84E91A4E27A301DAC5CECD2587"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the role the United States civilian nuclear energy industry plays in United States foreign policy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H119F2C2EDF7B4327A0E871BE690C68AE"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on the importance of the United States civilian nuclear energy industry to countries that are allied to the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H68B8897000A240018542E759997A07D4" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on how the United States may collaborate with such countries in developing, deploying, and investing in nuclear technology;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFCD85EE97055438682984AFD7A7ECE78"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on how foreign countries use nuclear energy when crafting and implementing their own foreign policy, including such use by foreign countries that are strategic competitors;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0B28729773E44C17A644B0B1854A95C5"><enum>(7)</enum><text>an evaluation of how nuclear nonproliferation efforts and nuclear energy safety are affected by the involvement of the United States in—</text><subparagraph id="HB916920ABDE042B9A02A1BFE6D5E179B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>international markets; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBF6528AC90DD49E48AB8BDC7CE67AE17"><enum>(B)</enum><text>setting civilian nuclear energy industry standards;</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2995B1352B87448B8984425DDB2F6D5F"><enum>(8)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an evaluation of how industries in the United States, other than the civilian nuclear energy industry, benefit from the generation of electricity by nuclear power plants;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H49836F84078E447AB47C4B95EA73E2F4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>information on utilities and companies in the United States that are involved in the civilian nuclear energy supply chain, including, with respect to such utilities and companies—</text><subparagraph id="H0352CB174D414B6AAE0DA34EA03CBB8B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>financial challenges;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21C18DC4438548AFACB50BB5AFFD88DB"><enum>(B)</enum><text>foreign strategic competition; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H833B77AFC8FF478B9A6E33604C65DABA"><enum>(C)</enum><text>risks to continued operation; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HBFFECB353D914D579197A950CCA2200C"><enum>(10)</enum><text>recommendations for how the United States may—</text><subparagraph id="HEC88C2F29BA040428429DF2DAF6CFEC5"><enum>(A)</enum><text>develop a national strategy to increase the role nuclear energy plays in diplomacy and strategic energy policy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD50138437CFC4562BADADB19C20C69E1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>develop a strategy to mitigate foreign competitor’s utilization of their civilian nuclear energy industries in diplomacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E6AE04509BE49BA83627C99AD412152"><enum>(C)</enum><text>align its nuclear energy policy with national security objectives; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2173C22CAFC24017AA3FD241B05E38E8"><enum>(D)</enum><text>remove regulatory barriers to the development of the United States civilian nuclear energy supply chain.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H44A1F24AE3204D6C853CEF2928D9941C"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Report to Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 6 months after the study is conducted under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy shall submit to the appropriate committees of Congress a report on the results of such study.</text></subsection></section><section id="H502D9928F2B74D0AACE1BDF13C078CF6" commented="no"><enum>3.</enum><header>Program to train and share expertise</header><subsection id="H6CC08BB415D946F6BF3B05BD82D1D6C5"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Energy, in consultation with the Secretary of State and the Commission, shall develop and carry out a program under which the Secretary of Energy shall train foreign nuclear energy experts and standardize practices.</text></subsection><subsection id="H171A6163E89445398CD984F5CF9AABA3"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In carrying out the program developed under subsection (a), the Secretary of Energy shall—</text><paragraph id="HB8517E420FC043D7BB0967B9F4008ACD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>issue guidance for best safety practices in the global civilian nuclear energy industry based on practices established in the United States;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3536F52AB3B24FDAB3AB508EE969544B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">train foreign nuclear energy experts on the operation and safety practices used by the United States civilian nuclear energy industry;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H96937BBA22DB4CDDB3C1B16F0917A0F2"><enum>(3)</enum><text>review global supply chain issues for foreign civilian nuclear energy industries;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H03E56F2EF216447681499449650A709A"><enum>(4)</enum><text>identify weaknesses and concerns found in foreign civilian nuclear energy industries; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3DBB922304F44A9F81993AB8EC610FFC"><enum>(5)</enum><text>establish partnerships with foreign countries that have developed or are developing civilian nuclear energy industries.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HA80E5C5B849048D5B5547F7F39369912" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Foreign nuclear energy expert</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In this section, the term <term>foreign nuclear energy expert</term> does not include a person who is from a country—</text><paragraph id="H07B53B6C778D4B02BEB449A6F929C724" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in which intellectual property theft is legal;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFA37390808DE45FEAFB17FFB1E76DF96" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">that takes actions to undermine the civilian nuclear energy industry or other critical industries of the United States; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70A077ACD74E49009C1D57332CA852F4"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">which the Secretary of Energy determines is inimical to the interest of the United States.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H2D652A44425940A98613F9C763DFD77C"><enum>4.</enum><header>International nuclear reactor export and innovation activities</header><subsection id="H192508E4CCF04C2D969B7D1F7B7BA31E" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall—</text><paragraph id="HF00DFD2F1A954F258241905657B7D9CB" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(1)</enum><text>coordinate all work of the Commission relating to—</text><subparagraph id="H8CB8E64B519E406F95FAC9478CD4E0E9"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">issuing a license for the import or export of a nuclear reactor under section 103 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2133">42 U.S.C. 2133</external-xref>); and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCF131518E63D495D80A92C641F2DD3A6"><enum>(B)</enum><text>international regulatory cooperation and assistance relating to nuclear reactors; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA9663A22D6164DBEA529B88995355AAE"><enum>(2)</enum><text>support—</text><subparagraph id="H49043857D1244B6DA21E05FB000B27A4"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the consideration of international technical standards to assist the design, licensing, and construction of advanced nuclear systems;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H798848819CA14675B8E3EA287B8D6096"><enum>(B)</enum><text>efforts to help build competent nuclear regulatory organizations and legal frameworks in foreign countries that are seeking to develop civilian nuclear energy industries; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HCCAF4C86278A4CCABB23DB2C62542B2E"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">exchange programs and training provided to foreign countries relating to civilian nuclear energy industry regulation and oversight to improve nuclear technology licensing.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HEB67ABB66E67409DB3D0B6CDCD5758FA" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Consultation</header><text>In supporting exchange programs and training under subsection (a)(2)(C), the Commission shall consult with—</text><paragraph id="H99F9DA84D8E047E1B8177E0D22C33275" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the Secretary of Energy;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H59C5142F93C04F23A35C8F03D105200F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the National Laboratories;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H499EABAFBA194BB4A017353E3C553163" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the private sector; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H211DA695C05D483EAC71E9AADAE69251" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text>institutions of higher education.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H77F62CF9011B483E84304A035C02E1AC"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Nuclear Reactor Export and Innovation Branch</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall establish within the Office of International Programs of the Commission a branch, to be known as the <quote>International Nuclear Reactor Export and Innovation Branch</quote>, to carry out the nuclear reactor export and innovation activities described in subsection (a) as the Commission determines appropriate.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5D124B3425E6443CAB596ADEFC81E3A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusion of international activities from the fee base</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 102 of the Nuclear Energy Innovation and Modernization Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2215">42 U.S.C. 2215</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HCA0D4B50034C48499D61B7387918A57D"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (a), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HD5DFD1BA02E9471196ACC4EC4566F10A"><paragraph id="HA49A049241054A038311FF47F22D47E8"><enum>(4)</enum><header>International nuclear reactor export and innovation activities</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Commission shall identify in the annual budget justification international nuclear reactor export and innovation activities described in section 4(a) of the <short-title>Global Nuclear Energy Assessment and Cooperation Act</short-title>. </text></paragraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph><paragraph id="H82BD8441E0984F419117E9DE9B9AEA01"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in subsection (b)(1)(B), by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" display-inline="no-display-inline" id="HA3726147609A456A9DB06E913356CEE2"><clause id="HD603ECA69D194E0EBA72E906AA7BA5FC"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Costs for international nuclear reactor export and innovation activities described in section 4(a) of the <short-title>Global Nuclear Energy Assessment and Cooperation Act</short-title>.</text></clause><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1348E504C0DA41FBBE9D0B87AEFB74B6" commented="no"><enum>5.</enum><header>Denial of certain domestic licenses for national security purposes</header><subsection id="H0751D57E65F049C7BFA81AB9B313F3E2" commented="no"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of covered fuel</header><text>In this section, the term <term>covered fuel</term> means enriched uranium that is fabricated into fuel assemblies for nuclear reactors by an entity that—</text><paragraph id="H224A91F818B2413EA4C57B916E75BABD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>is owned or controlled by the Government of the Russian Federation or the Government of the People’s Republic of China; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H76AA6A58889A452C8F6628A5D93B5A42" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text>is organized under the laws of, or otherwise subject to the jurisdiction of, the Russian Federation or the People’s Republic of China.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H5FC4536A2C184EDE9968C6F25F83E3AC" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Prohibition on unlicensed possession or ownership of covered fuel</header><text>Unless specifically authorized by the Commission in a license issued under section 53 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2073">42 U.S.C. 2073</external-xref>), no person subject to the jurisdiction of the Commission may possess or own covered fuel.</text></subsection><subsection id="H30D150408167464BA1D7881DA748F776" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>License To possess or own covered fuel</header><paragraph id="H08757EC5B5ED402CA3FE3B7ED99FD092" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Consultation required prior to issuance</header><text>The Commission shall not issue a license to possess or own covered fuel under section 53 of the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2073">42 U.S.C. 2073</external-xref>), unless the Commission has first consulted with the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State before issuing the license.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H06638927C89D4AF7B6DA43F4F32EBE8A" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Prohibition on issuance of license</header><subparagraph id="HF2C244AEC4294B2B835214827D234EB7" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Subject to subparagraph (C), a license to possess or own covered fuel shall not be issued if the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State make the determination described in subparagraph (B).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H85B00DD72DFE46B09E85606EF1EC3DA1" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Determination</header><clause id="HDDDFF6EE8B3147108137886E948FC93D" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The determination referred to in subparagraph (A) is a determination that possession or ownership, as applicable, of covered fuel poses a threat to the national security of the United States that adversely impacts the physical and economic security of the United States.</text></clause><clause id="H08C2867A3464407DBDF83C6D340A2671" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><header>Joint determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A determination described in clause (i) shall be jointly made by the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State.</text></clause><clause id="H9C5C542DF3CC49E1AEC0D2F5F753E641" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><header>Timeline</header><subclause id="HE540D1539C7A4B879B1A17060DA93831" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><header>Notice of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Commission receives an application for a license to possess or own covered fuel, the Commission shall notify the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State of the application. </text></subclause><subclause id="HE678CD13C9A24327A57627015AB54630" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><header>Determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State shall have a period of 180 days, beginning on the date on which the Commission notifies the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State under subclause (I) of an application for a license to possess or own covered fuel, in which to make the determination described in clause (i).</text></subclause><subclause id="H2FC631E195874257B54F0AA9639D4707" commented="no"><enum>(III)</enum><header>Commission notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">On making the determination described in clause (i), the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State shall immediately notify the Commission. </text></subclause><subclause id="H126C56F52AE9438C8001C8EE3C444DE7" commented="no"><enum>(IV)</enum><header>Congressional notification</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 30 days after the date on which the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State notify the Commission under subclause (III), the Commission shall notify the appropriate committees of Congress of the determination.</text></subclause><subclause id="H9E044B3F243B426A8D9DF7E76705AE51" commented="no" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(V)</enum><header>Public notice</header><text>Not later than 15 days after the date on which the Commission notifies Congress under subclause (IV) of a determination made under clause (i), the Commission shall make that determination publicly available. </text></subclause></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBA97B022DED94F77BA1CD0EFF676618F" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Effect of no determination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The prohibition described in subparagraph (A) shall not apply if the Secretary of Energy and the Secretary of State do not make the determination described in subparagraph (B) by the date described in clause (iii)(II) of that subparagraph.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="HFDDD7EC117E5425C881D5ECECBAD9064"><enum>6.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H4F3A49097EFD46C586A34A58FD6565FA" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Appropriate committees of Congress</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>appropriate committees of Congress</term> means each of the following:</text><subparagraph id="HB941354AEC6941F59B32570779485389" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7640812FB31C413993020D06F07E3CED" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Affairs of the House of Representatives.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE934DFE582D443489C585E680CA54A89" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><text>The Committee on Energy and Natural Resources of the Senate.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H460FE389FEE84C0BB1C024DF836D5FDA" commented="no"><enum>(D)</enum><text>The Committee on Foreign Relations of the Senate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2883C98C4626463CA539EA5596B09C64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Commission</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>Commission</term> means the Nuclear Regulatory Commission.</text></paragraph></section></legis-body></bill> 

