<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H6F3052A09BED465BABE5473E2DC8EA59" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 8887 IH: To direct the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health to establish an occupational research program on mental health.</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-09-19</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 8887</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220919">September 19, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="M001214">Mr. Mrvan</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To direct the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health to establish an occupational research program on mental health.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H339B5346A55344459C5E61118B391307" style="OLC"> 
<section id="H6366310A0D4D4286A4AC73648405ABD4" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Occupational research program on mental health</header> 
<subsection id="H3990413D0492448DB37508E8A300CFBB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director of the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (in this section referred to as the <quote>Institute</quote>) shall establish a research program to identify and apply comprehensive approaches to support frontline, essential, and other affected workers across all industries and occupations exposed to and affected by workplace stressors that contribute to adverse mental health outcomes, including traumatic stress, anxiety, depression, suicide, and related mental health conditions. In designing such research program, the Director shall, in consultation with the heads of other Federal departments and agencies, as appropriate, address workplace stressors such as—</text> <paragraph id="H5BE14113AF794978863D1EB72B543D3D"><enum>(1)</enum><text>traumatic grief resulting from COVID–19-related death or injury in the workplace;</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="H59F4598483DA4C2F80B6CCBCC507888D"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">conditions of employment or places of employment, including consecutive shifts, increases in shift duration, changes in workplace protocols, or increases in workloads and demands due to insufficient resources, which can result in fatal, near-fatal, or other serious occupational injuries or illnesses; or</text></paragraph> <paragraph id="H28009FFDD26A4878868D4831B15032B7"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">workplace violence or other physical and psychological hazards that contribute to worker injury or illness on the job, including poor mental health outcomes among workers. </text></paragraph></subsection> 
<subsection id="H112B12AECACB4380AD2F607A62AD8575"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Best practices and recommendations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of the research program established under this section, the Director shall develop best practices or recommendations for organizational-level workplace interventions and support services that would both prevent worker injury or illness and reduce the risk of such adverse mental health outcomes among frontline, essential, and other affected workers across all industries and occupations, including wraparound services, mental health awareness initiatives, workplace stress prevention programs, and training programs to promote work-related stress prevention and reduction and organizational resilience, to include specific strategies for preventing burnout among workers. </text></subsection> <subsection id="H7D9F98E3C87A4EA6AF145608E4F3EC75"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Additional support</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">As part of such research program, the Director shall also coordinate and support efforts through other research programs carried out by the Institute, including the Institute’s Total Worker Health program, to develop comprehensive, evidence-informed approaches to support mental and behavioral health as a part of worker wellbeing and related occupational safety and health programs.</text></subsection> 
<subsection id="HDB12A76D85F44A508539ECBA029375A9"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, the Director shall—</text> <paragraph id="HA7D8FBBED2A54D8C9A957F0276FC2590"><enum>(1)</enum><text>report to the Committee on Education and Labor of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate on the extent to which best practices or recommendations developed pursuant to subsection (b) have been adopted by relevant stakeholders; and</text></paragraph> 
<paragraph id="HEF789CBDF57245DC9E96F4A9A023957B"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">engage in education and outreach activities with employers, health care providers, nonprofit organizations, workers, labor organizations, and related stakeholders to support such adoption.</text></paragraph></subsection> <subsection id="H65DBD70593744270982069863929BC4F"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $10,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2025.</text> </subsection></section> 
</legis-body></bill>

