<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H36CA1978AAD9442CA15E5C909C34C3A8" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 6877 IH: Amir Locke End Deadly No-Knock Warrants Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-01</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 6877</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220301">March 1, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="O000173">Ms. Omar</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="M001160">Ms. Moore of Wisconsin</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000586">Mr. García of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000617">Ms. Pressley</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000193">Mr. Thompson of Mississippi</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001067">Ms. Clarke of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001072">Mr. Carson</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000822">Mrs. Watson Coleman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="N000192">Ms. Newman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="O000172">Ms. Ocasio-Cortez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="D000096">Mr. Danny K. Davis of Illinois</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="B001223">Mr. Bowman</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000551">Ms. Lee of California</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="T000486">Mr. Torres of New York</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="V000081">Ms. Velázquez</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="P000604">Mr. Payne</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S000510">Mr. Smith of Washington</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="E000297">Mr. Espaillat</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="M001188">Ms. Meng</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="H001081">Mrs. Hayes</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="W000788">Ms. Williams of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000288">Mr. Johnson of Georgia</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="R000515">Mr. Rush</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="G000553">Mr. Green of Texas</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="L000592">Mr. Levin of Michigan</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="S001145">Ms. Schakowsky</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="C001125">Mr. Carter of Louisiana</cosponsor>, <cosponsor name-id="J000298">Ms. Jayapal</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="G000551">Mr. Grijalva</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HJU00">Committee on the Judiciary</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To establish limitations on the use of no-knock warrants, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H4338457CA60B47AD879458ABA012DADB" style="OLC"><section id="H645CD7E9021B42E892A06ECFF985DDA7" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Amir Locke End Deadly No-Knock Warrants Act</short-title></quote>. </text></section><section id="HF43971DB7B5247558DEF1460453C8318"><enum>2.</enum><header>Definitions</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act:</text><paragraph id="H33C80B97F80D407FA9EF265717F96249"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Byrne grant program</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <quote>Byrne grant program</quote> means any grant program under subpart 1 of part E of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/10151">34 U.S.C. 10151 et seq.</external-xref>), without regard to whether the funds are characterized as being made available under the Edward Byrne Memorial State and Local Law Enforcement Assistance Programs, the Local Government Law Enforcement Block Grants Program, the Edward Byrne Memorial Justice Assistance Grant Program, or otherwise.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EBAA59E01C144198A4AF3452BEF8130"><enum>(2)</enum><header>COPS grant program</header><text>The term <quote>COPS grant program</quote> means the grant program authorized under section 1701 of title I of the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H13E20F5EAF174273A6FA7DDD37DBF1BB"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Covered law enforcement task force</header><text>The term <quote>covered law enforcement task force</quote> means a law enforcement task force that has not less than 1 Federal law enforcement agency or Federal law enforcement officer as a member.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6F327D5189214A7E84DCAACBB1F571BC"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Covered Federal warrant</header><text>The term <quote>covered Federal warrant</quote> means a warrant authorizing a search by a Federal law enforcement officer or covered law enforcement task force.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B62E0DC9F3C4607BAFC93716A8AF5E2"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Daylight hours</header><text>The term <quote>daylight hours</quote> means any time beginning at 9:00 a.m. and ending at 6:00 p.m. in the time zone in which a warrant is to be executed.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4956A5304F3946B580D83B15E93E3BB4"><enum>(6)</enum><header>No-knock entry</header><text>The term <quote>no-knock entry</quote> means entry into a property by a law enforcement officer without the law enforcement officer knocking and announcing their presence, authority, and intention to enter the property.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5588FF57F68A4931B676B9B8A31A2639"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Nighttime</header><text>The term <quote>nighttime</quote> means any time other than daylight hours in the time zone in which a warrant is to be executed.</text></paragraph></section><section id="HA919E8E5FC7548988A6ACDEB76006099"><enum>3.</enum><header>Federal search warrants</header><subsection id="HD9BF420990E4411C893BE7DC98BB5603"><enum>(a)</enum><header>No-Knock entry requirements</header><paragraph id="HA066BA51C735499681F68CE39D4A68FC" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Bar in drug cases</header><text>A covered Federal warrant may not authorize a no-knock entry for the investigation of any offense related to drugs.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21F3FF718C5748C58262039F8591814F"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements for court authorization</header><text>A court—</text><subparagraph id="HEABBAF37C25D4E68B9182A0E1662594C"><enum>(A)</enum><text>may only issue a covered Federal warrant authorizing a no-knock entry if the court determines there is clear and convincing evidence, supported by particularized facts, that law enforcement officers entering the property without announcing their presence and intention to enter is necessary because notice prior to entry would substantially endanger the life or safety of the law enforcement officer or other persons; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE9502B58303A4E6189F0BFF7078D92EC"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">may not issue a covered Federal warrant authorizing a no-knock entry for the investigation of any offense related to drugs.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H3ED8531F5C1842E38E84FBF3EE0BCAED"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Avoiding destruction of property and injury of persons</header><subparagraph id="H190122D461DF4BCB861AF72917B85F78"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>In executing a covered Federal warrant, law enforcement officers shall seek to avoid the destruction of property and injury of persons occasioned by forcible entry and execution of a search.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA94B5ECE401343128CDB4D9036D32BDB"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Restitution</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any person who is injured by, or the owner of property damaged by, law enforcement officers during the execution of a covered Federal warrant may bring an action against the United States in the appropriate Federal district court for appropriate relief, including restitution, unless the person is convicted of an offense related to the covered Federal warrant.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H0E13ED8B843D438187720A9607CB0E84"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Conforming amendment for drug investigations</header><text>Section 509 of the Controlled Substances Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/21/879">21 U.S.C. 879</external-xref>) is amended—</text><subparagraph id="H72F6D71E25874B99A05758BACD9FFBFC"><enum>(A)</enum><text>by striking <quote>A search warrant</quote> and inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC"><enum-in-header>(a)</enum-in-header></header-in-text> A search warrant</quote>; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H644F9D9FF3D14405933380994CC48C8E"><enum>(B)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H15C4A2356DE24D6A9DD2A157D26247B2" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HF6362106A51240D0B615E52925637E56"><enum>(b)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A Federal law enforcement officer (as defined in section 2 of the Law Enforcement Congressional Badge of Bravery Act of 2008 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/34/50301">34 U.S.C. 50301</external-xref>)) may not make a no-knock entry (as defined in section 2 of the <short-title>Amir Locke End Deadly No-Knock Warrants Act</short-title>).</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6CE2C2CB9B6147AEA16DFA23BDAB5554"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Planning and execution of all covered Federal warrants</header><paragraph id="H03F32AF317854C40A5E59EC3A6B613B3"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Execution during daylight hours</header><subparagraph id="H41FD74B5A7B84AE086A414AB5841CB83"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Except as provided in subparagraph (B), a covered Federal warrant shall only authorize execution of the covered Federal warrant during daylight hours not later than 7 days after such warrant is issued, and such a warrant shall only be executed by a Federal law enforcement officer or covered law enforcement task force during such hours.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H8BCF0B9667CC4451862956C524B03328"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Court authorization for nighttime service</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A court may authorize a covered Federal warrant to be executed outside of daylight hours if the court determines that the application for such warrant contains particularized facts indicating that nighttime execution is necessary because execution of the warrant during daylight hours would substantially endanger the life or safety of law enforcement officers or other persons.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HCEEE40B2B1EE41BCAA9F335AE7353C64"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Application for a warrant</header><subparagraph id="HA164344E87B8456AA3074F156DE9E011"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Approval</header><text>An application for a covered Federal warrant may not be submitted for consideration by a court unless the head of the law enforcement agency approves such an application. The authority for approval described in this subparagraph may not be delegated.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAD07384E1A804F8EA3187F5E49A46A91"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Contents of application</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An application for a covered Federal warrant shall include—</text><clause id="H63D25312BF3F42C3895645370BD5CECB"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of what investigative activities have been undertaken to support the request for such a warrant, or why no such investigative activity is needed; and</text></clause><clause id="H3EF8ABD7907148F98B41E2530C21F977"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>in the case of an application for a no-knock warrant, an explanation for why the applicant is unable to detain the suspect or search the premises without knocking or announcing law enforcement presence or using other less invasive methods.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H725E9D08CE234529AA7102C61F67BA2E"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Potential presence of vulnerable individuals</header><subparagraph id="HD39A0141CC2B4D1B9CD149A03C468324"><enum>(A)</enum><header>Evaluation</header><text>An application for a covered Federal warrant shall assess, and a court issuing a covered Federal warrant shall evaluate and include information with respect to the primary language of the individuals on the premises, whether there will be children, individuals with a disability, individuals who are elderly, or other vulnerable individuals present at the location where the covered Federal warrant is to be executed.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13A82149FBA5445CB383578D953D5E13"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Requirements for issuance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A covered Federal warrant may only authorize the search of a location where a child, individual with a disability, individual who is elderly, or other vulnerable individual will be present if the court determines, based on particularized facts, that there is a clear necessity for such search to avoid endangering the life or safety of law enforcement officers or other persons and that a safety plan is in place to ensure the safety of the vulnerable individuals. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D5C246D46D417EAA4369F470044932"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Knock and announce requirement</header><text>Except in any case in which a covered Federal warrant authorizes no-knock entry, during execution of a covered Federal warrant—</text><subparagraph id="H3A04C380596F400EB204EB462152E8D6"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement officer shall be easily recognizable and identifiable as a uniformed law enforcement officer;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H5E31699E3FF0417FBE041DB386AA54AD"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a law enforcement officer shall knock and audibly, or in a manner sufficient to provide notice to any person with a disability, and with consideration to the native language of the occupants, announce the officer’s identity as a law enforcement officer, authority pursuant to the warrant, and purpose;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H99C5DDD6E4EB45339B3468DB4AAD90CE"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an audible knock and announcement shall be provided in a manner reasonably expected to be received and understood by occupants of the premises to be searched based on the size and nature of the location;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0080AFCE20B748B1B77B63642B0F827F"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a body worn camera or any other government issued recording device shall be recording at least 5 minutes prior to the start of a covered Federal warrant execution, during any subsequent entry and the entirety of the search of the premises, and 5 minutes following the exit of the premises; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA190101828340BA8E18E5AE9836E1D6"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">law enforcement officers shall delay entry for at least 30 seconds, or a sufficient amount of time after the announcement, whichever is greater, based on the size and nature of the premises and occupants, to allow the occupant a reasonable opportunity to respond.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HB132971C9E794A328D292E83866EF731"><enum>(5)</enum><header>Exception to delayed entry requirement</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (4)(E), law enforcement officers may forcibly enter into the premises in less than 30 seconds if—</text><subparagraph id="H9752748F11CB42C88ED14577F11A5219"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a covered Federal warrant authorizes a no-knock entry; or</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFA850CF1D97F4D3886F334247EFF0ED7"><enum>(B)</enum><text>a verifiable exigent circumstance exists, there is an imminent threat to the life of law enforcement officers or others, and law enforcement officers provide information about such exigency in the warrant execution report. </text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H4F243857BB154C92A336CD7E81D2038E"><enum>(6)</enum><header>Verification of place to be searched</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Before executing a covered Federal warrant, law enforcement officers shall verify that the address or location about to be searched is the correct address or location authorized to be searched under the covered Federal warrant. Such verification shall occur within the 24 hours prior to execution of the covered Federal warrant.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H152847A328284DDBBB590361B6FA2AB0"><enum>(7)</enum><header>Use of explosive devices</header><text>Law enforcement officers executing a covered Federal warrant shall not use or possess flash-bang stun grenades, other explosive devices, chemical weapons, or any military-grade firearm, unless expressly authorized under the covered Federal warrant based on clearly articulated reasons, supported by particularized facts, that the use of any such device is necessary under the particularized circumstances to protect the life or safety of law enforcement officers or other persons.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H9E73FC753F10428ABB0A33B4595AD2DA"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Data collection</header><paragraph id="H2B37CEDFA6834618935DD362F40CE322"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>A Federal law enforcement agency shall—</text><subparagraph id="HF93747BFA4A54A7AAC6251A7BEFB32F9" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>collect data about—</text><clause id="H80942CF0771A4BBEA8447218C9860AA7" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text>the items to be seized under a covered Federal warrant, as described in the application; </text></clause><clause id="HB45F5407D63140BFA1B1DF97739F0CB0" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the items seized in the execution of that covered Federal warrant;</text></clause><clause id="H2A3B1F70EA564382AAF8C728B46C0A08" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of covered Federal warrant applications and the number of no-knock warrant applications;</text></clause><clause id="HD2B7EF91BE7D4B198B9600A5763895DE" commented="no"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total number of covered Federal warrant applications granted and the number of no-knock warrant applications granted;</text></clause><clause id="HE404BB5567C5489A94ADA346A85AF7E3" commented="no"><enum>(v)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the number of forcible entries made while executing warrants (both where no-knock entry is explicitly authorized by the warrant and when not explicitly authorized), including a description of the circumstances under which forcible entry occurred and why warrant requirements were modified; and</text></clause><clause id="H168B16A37351431C936B5122C9AD1B6F" commented="no"><enum>(vi)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">injuries that occur during the execution of warrants (sustained by both law enforcement and others); and</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE207570598534D2B85D1A787CD3E7D5C"><enum>(B)</enum><text>submit the data collected under paragraph (1) to the Attorney General.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H444B12CFC156427F8B93DB344C097A94"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Attorney General report</header><text>Not later than 2 years after the date of enactment of this Act, and every 2 years thereafter, the Attorney General shall make available to the public on the Department of Justice website a review and analysis of the data submitted to the Attorney General pursuant to paragraph (1)(B).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H36D7CFFE255C4F2CB196DBE46ADCBB76"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Exclusion of evidence</header><text>Evidence obtained in violation of this section may not be admissible in any trial, hearing, or proceeding in or before any court, department, officer, agency, regulatory body, or other authority of the United States, a State, or a political subdivision thereof.</text></subsection><subsection id="HAE7F1675DC464E65A13D8389DEA365F8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Officer accountability</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Any law enforcement officer who executes a covered Federal warrant in violation of the requirements of this section shall be subject to such consequence as the Attorney General determines appropriate, including rendering all evidence collected pursuant to the violation inadmissible, suspension of duty, civil penalties, or termination.</text></subsection></section><section id="H25EB8F6210394B5987C57DB34BA4B32C"><enum>4.</enum><header>Limitation on State and local law enforcement eligibility for funds</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Beginning in the first fiscal year that begins after the date that is 1 year after the date of enactment of this Act, a law enforcement agency of a State or unit of local government may not receive funds made available to the State or local government under the Byrne grant program or the COPS grant program for a fiscal year if, on the day before the first day of the fiscal year, the State or local law enforcement agency of the State or unit of local government does not have in effect policies that are substantially similar to the policies described in section 3.</text></section></legis-body></bill> 

