<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H7BD322DDA3024CB8B84AA6FAE05D33E3" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7236 IH: Strengthen Kids’ Mental Health Now Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7236</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220328">March 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="E000215">Ms. Eshoo</sponsor> (for herself, <cosponsor name-id="F000466">Mr. Fitzpatrick</cosponsor>, and <cosponsor name-id="B001303">Ms. Blunt Rochester</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to expand the availability of mental, emotional, and behavioral health services under the Medicaid program, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H740E8FF126C44F7297E708719DF5FC03" style="OLC"><section section-type="section-one" id="H8409DBCAE5B845B090CF1B25DD98D650"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Strengthen Kids’ Mental Health Now Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HDFAF56C8C40E413EBB05FFACDD23B2BE"><enum>2.</enum><header>Table of contents</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The table of contents for this Act is as follows:</text><toc><toc-entry level="section" idref="H8409DBCAE5B845B090CF1B25DD98D650">Sec. 1. Short title.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HDFAF56C8C40E413EBB05FFACDD23B2BE">Sec. 2. Table of contents.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H70CAD7CF0C494B8EB6F928EF9A5FAF87">Sec. 3. Payment parity for pediatric behavioral health services.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HD19289A0320F4EB4A1FCDDA067C5090D">Sec. 4. Guidance to States on supporting mental, emotional, and behavioral health services, and on the availability of telehealth under Medicaid.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H4411CC566E954D8CA4AB3E20DEB5D25B">Sec. 5. Ensuring children receive timely access to care.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="HC684D5F1E89A49F1BC1CC3930F266E8C">Sec. 6. Programs to support pediatric behavioral health care.</toc-entry><toc-entry level="section" idref="H128345599E8248BDBC3F63915BF96CB1">Sec. 7. Increasing Federal investment in pediatric behavioral health services.</toc-entry></toc></section><section id="H70CAD7CF0C494B8EB6F928EF9A5FAF87"><enum>3.</enum><header>Payment parity for pediatric behavioral health services</header><subsection id="H9DDDA5C0623649DC89F69D18E72C7C00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Payment parity for pediatric behavioral health services</header><text>Section 1902 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396a">42 U.S.C. 1396a</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="HEF51FBC18DCA49A68BBC8FD51F559213"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in subsection (a)(13)—</text><subparagraph id="H0C63FE0BC7304AA9A830BA3C5047881E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>in subparagraph (B), by striking <quote>and</quote> at the end;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC499C88AA6E9456A83DDE569E49974CC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>in subparagraph (C), by adding <quote>and</quote> at the end; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H1CC96241521440E0ADFCA08FB6090BC6"><enum>(C)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subparagraph:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H2D35F88DB6E540B8B45C2D41A4BBF403"><subparagraph id="H949659238FA84D399AE3C89B7C1F9512"><enum>(D)</enum><text>for payment for pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services (as defined in subsection (tt)) furnished on or after the date that is 180 days after the date of enactment of this subparagraph and before October 1, 2027, at a rate not less than 100 percent of the payment rate that applies to such providers under part A or B (as applicable) of title XVIII;</text></subparagraph><after-quoted-block>; and</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H2DFEADE24AF445E39DCACE95A075179C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0534EB55FE3F4CB4A79F8505F0FAB5C3"><subsection id="H0840B9998C80447A8C4E21774A5AF07A"><enum>(tt)</enum><header>Pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services defined</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">For purposes of subsection (a)(13)(D), the term <term>pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services</term> means the following services furnished by a health care provider, including hospitals, physicians, and other providers determined by the Secretary, for the purposes of screening for, diagnosing, or treating a mental, emotional, or behavioral health condition, whether furnished in-person or via telehealth:</text><paragraph id="HA839F8494BB5419384B5759F7EDA3CB5"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Mental health and substance use disorder screenings.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB3410C4BCC044FECB6CC6026B5761741"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Mental health development assessments.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF1B5B6CA00FC4B30BB8B55A6BA3AB2CA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Mental health behavior assessments and interventions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H26C578BD10D84C4E990E317AB6613F22"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Psychological and neuropsychological testing and assessment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC3FBE6A4E8A046DBA9D96FE7F7EAF612"><enum>(5)</enum><text>Mental health primary prevention services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBADAF793BF164547926BFEB0F068DC84"><enum>(6)</enum><text>Mental health and substance use disorder case management services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD9D6FDD77A254F93A9DDFF9FF4C5B94E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>School-based mental health and substance use disorder prevention, identification, and treatment services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3BDA24ACA2C2434BA3F9E2BD8868B183"><enum>(8)</enum><text>Child and adolescent psychiatry and psychology services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5B8845525FD44400A75E720F20C3FFD4"><enum>(9)</enum><text>Partial hospitalization services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H93C85FC6007B4B9DB127A6EBE09915B1"><enum>(10)</enum><text>Day program services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBC282FC0D8754BC08D5BC465D859F7C2"><enum>(11)</enum><text>Intensive outpatient services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1EF98E2F0F214CF6AA711F66090F596B"><enum>(12)</enum><text>Eating disorder treatment services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCB26255A00854E9993F0CA0BEE82E5AD"><enum>(13)</enum><text>Outpatient services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA0D1CFB66B934A358C482CC1E89CE62F"><enum>(14)</enum><text>Crisis residential services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8696A61BAE394F2FB8787F85D4CD318A"><enum>(15)</enum><text>Crisis intervention and stabilization.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB83EC1CF270A4FC5AFF32BF4ABD99997"><enum>(16)</enum><text>Inpatient psychiatric and psychological services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDA1C89B0D738439FBA62378E80C107CD"><enum>(17)</enum><text>Individual therapy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0CC690C7AA0F41F683E5998657CA2486"><enum>(18)</enum><text>Family therapy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC34A411DCFE04DC6932D196D49869738"><enum>(19)</enum><text>Group therapy services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEC44CEDD42AF41BBAD5222D66894EF46"><enum>(20)</enum><text>Intensive in-home services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H432FCF299D64474BBA54B0F702869FFE"><enum>(21)</enum><text>Peer support services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5071203654474FAFB688FC76C8A1D3C2"><enum>(22)</enum><text>Provider-to-provider consultation services involving primary care practitioners sand mental health care specialists, including child and adolescent specialists.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HAD3C39CDC973459396A87D6115CF5D1E"><enum>(23)</enum><text>Substance use disorder screening, including SBIRT, and treatment.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H533F18B549AD42E794A8A3B4DE9B6C0B"><enum>(24)</enum><text>Medication management.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0059C06C7BAC463A9CB3D6BAE0C9CEE1"><enum>(25)</enum><text>Any other pediatric mental, emotional, or behavioral health service determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H95A4F58F8D8C4FD4831A096B09FA253D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Under medicaid managed care plans</header><text>Section 1932(f) of such Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396u-2">42 U.S.C. 1396u–2(f)</external-xref>) is amended—</text><paragraph id="H2A49D21E8D4143299D2C3813CEBCB0CF"><enum>(1)</enum><text>in the header, by inserting <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">and pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health</header-in-text></quote> before <quote><header-in-text level="subsection" style="OLC">Services</header-in-text></quote>; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE9456A2FCFD249E6842374B723C505C7"><enum>(2)</enum><text>by inserting <quote>and pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services described in section 1902(a)(13)(D)</quote> after <quote>section 1902(a)(13)(C)</quote>; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23FADF99528A4217846E8CF6A8FFCDE7"><enum>(3)</enum><text>by striking <quote>such section</quote> and inserting <quote>section 1902(a)(13)</quote>. </text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H91CC2F57C8984FC18359AFD866C2BAB1"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Increase in payment using increased FMAP</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Section 1905 of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H1DFFB31214D644418C357CE1E9B5AF9F"><subsection id="HBF7495A912234E46868A50EF365994ED"><enum>(jj)</enum><header>Increased FMAP for additional expenditures for pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services</header><text>Notwithstanding subsection (b), with respect to the portion of the amounts expended for medical assistance for services described in section 1902(a)(13)(D) furnished on or after the date that is 180 days after date of enactment of this subsection and before October 1, 2027, and that is attributable to the amount by which the minimum payment rate required under such section (or, by application, section 1932(f)) exceeds the payment rate applicable to such services under the State plan as of the day before the date of the enactment of this subsection, the Federal medical assistance percentage for a State that is one of the 50 States or the District of Columbia shall be equal to 100 percent. The preceding sentence does not prohibit the payment of Federal financial participation based on the Federal medical assistance percentage for amounts in excess of those specified in such sentence.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="HD19289A0320F4EB4A1FCDDA067C5090D"><enum>4.</enum><header>Guidance to States on supporting mental, emotional, and behavioral health services, and on the availability of telehealth under Medicaid</header><subsection id="HF019076DFC77469C99E0E8C22254A2F9"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Mental, emotional, and behavioral health services</header><text>Not later than 180 days after date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue guidance to States on how to expand the provision of mental, emotional, and behavioral health services covered by State plans (or waivers of such plans) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>), including a description of best practices for effective programs, service provision for underserved communities, and recruitment and retention of providers.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9CE7E342F27D4B2AB4097E04596B2416"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Telehealth services</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than 1 year after date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall issue guidance to States on best practices to sustain and enhance the availability of telehealth services covered by State plans (or waivers of such plans) under title XIX of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396">42 U.S.C. 1396 et seq.</external-xref>).</text></subsection></section><section id="H4411CC566E954D8CA4AB3E20DEB5D25B"><enum>5.</enum><header>Ensuring children receive timely access to care</header><subsection id="H54F2C3C0772545E68F69CDF3F40B8936"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Guidance to States on flexibilities To ensure provider capacity To provide pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral crisis care</header><text>Not later than 60 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall provide guidance to States on existing flexibilities for hospitals and other providers under applicable laws, regulations, and guidance to support children in crisis or in need of intensive mental, emotional or behavioral health services.</text></subsection><subsection id="H5E1A2224BE3C406F8D6CC6897785682D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Mandated report to Congress regarding barriers to repurposing of beds, space, and staff To address pediatric behavioral health needs</header><paragraph id="HBFAD0B362B1D42BC86DB0680C508E868"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>Not later than 120 days after the date of enactment of this Act, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall submit to the Congress a report with respect to regulatory and legal barriers to care across the crisis continuum that identifies solutions to facilitate flexibility for children's hospitals and other providers of mental, emotional, or behavioral health services.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H854572438A044C6ABEB09F59DBAE427A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Requirements</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In preparing a report under this subsection, the Secretary of Health and Human Services shall include in such report—</text><subparagraph id="HDDB1041D4DCC495C8B31216626809D0F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>a comprehensive list of laws, regulations, and guidance impacting children’s hospitals’ and other providers' ability to repurpose immediately beds, space, and staff for children in need of mental, emotional, or behavioral health services, including a description of the rationale for each policy and corresponding actions required to repurpose such beds, space, and staff; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H08CCF0A6E9764E4EB555214E04B025EE"><enum>(B)</enum><text>recommendations on how children’s hospitals and other providers can immediately expand access to mental, emotional, and behavioral health services while also ensuring high quality and safety.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H4D7BA135C7F8408E911855E6F79BFAD9"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Ensuring consistent review and State implementation of early and periodic screening, diagnostic, and treatment services</header><text>Section 1905(r) of the Social Security Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/1396d">42 U.S.C. 1396d(r)</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Secretary shall, not later than July 1, 2022, and not later than January 1 each year thereafter, review implementation of the requirements of this subsection by States as they pertain to behavioral health services for children, including services provided by a managed care entity, identify and disseminate best practices for ensuring comprehensive coverage of services, identify gaps and deficiencies in meeting Federal requirements, and provide guidance to States on addressing identified gaps and disparities and meeting Federal coverage requirements in order to ensure children, including children without a mental health diagnosis, have access to behavioral health services.</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC684D5F1E89A49F1BC1CC3930F266E8C"><enum>6.</enum><header>Programs to support pediatric behavioral health care</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Subpart V of part D of title III of the Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/256">42 U.S.C. 256 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H0B64F408E3D74DDBA9D3B8C65F6B7C50"><section id="H8B1E852785E84B70A1F0085D8725CD11"><enum>340A–1.</enum><header>Program to support pediatric behavioral health care integration and coordination</header><subsection id="H2015D4A3248F4398B452D2CE7C504F00"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities for the purpose of supporting pediatric behavioral health care integration and coordination within communities to meet local community needs.</text></subsection><subsection id="HB292EE99B37944E89C20DC80C7BFD524"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Entities eligible for grants under subsection (a) include—</text><paragraph id="HB6E419487A1940D8A5EBA10CA7E81045"><enum>(1)</enum><text>health care providers, including family physicians, pediatric medical sub-specialists, and surgical specialists; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD055CE76192C45D3AAA880F4B442BC2C"><enum>(2)</enum><text>children’s hospitals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H82E52EEACF0440009B8879F1EE7B87A1"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilities that are eligible to receive funds under section 340E or 340H;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45FC83F89FBC4B2F8701F4EA7FCD62D8"><enum>(4)</enum><text>nonprofit medical facilities that predominantly treat individuals under the age of 21;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDC080D573B142CB9AFAA6ABF2E968B1"><enum>(5)</enum><text>rural health clinics and Federally qualified health centers (as such terms are defined in section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB1CEDCA7078147DE8F1085FBE5E22A32"><enum>(6)</enum><text>pediatric mental health and substance use disorder providers, such as child and adolescent psychiatrists, psychologists, developmental and behavioral pediatricians, general pediatricians, advanced practice nurses, social workers, licensed professional counselors, and other licensed professionals that provide mental health and substance use disorder services to patients under 21 years of age;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0502B6522C644E13B2A2045091A60210"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">child advocacy centers described in section 214(c)(2)(B) of the Victims of Child Abuse Act of 1990; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6D28C63EF7948D9A38CCB468D807D0A"><enum>(8)</enum><text>school-based health centers; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0ED7D58B22BD4787A329DC121F33D9B9"><enum>(9)</enum><text>other entities as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HAF305AC2DD454B73A09A7A287F089A79"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Prioritization</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In making awards under subsection (a), the Secretary shall prioritize—</text><paragraph id="HB3D607C765B548ECBD0F8DC3473FF171"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicants that provide children and adolescents from high need, rural, or under-resourced communities with services across the continuum of children's mental health and substance use disorder care; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEEEABE4A973B47E980DB307E7968EF45"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">applicants that predominantly provide care to children and adolescents that demonstrate plans to utilize funds to expand provision of care to children, adolescents, and youth under age 21.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H94532F2FD2E3492BA73F2238E4DC4CBE"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text>Activities that may be funded through an award under subsection (a) include—</text><paragraph id="HDFD4640A05F441699C3A5AF350008A80"><enum>(1)</enum><text>increasing the capacity of pediatric practices, family medicine practices, and school-based health centers to integrate pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services into their practices including through co-location of mental, emotional, and behavioral health providers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H14676EFCF62B4AA78B2BBCC9C827B3A6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>training for non-clinical pediatric health care workers, including care coordinators and navigators, on child and adolescent mental health and substance use disorder, trauma-informed care, and local resources to support children and caregivers;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9508BDBCFEF5472E9B696F64996B1EBA"><enum>(3)</enum><text>expanding evidence-based, integrated models of care for pediatric mental health and substance use disorder services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9EDECFF4D9D54550824CA48E219E1B56"><enum>(4)</enum><text>pediatric practice integration for the provision of pediatric mental health and substance use disorder services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H0C2C9ADDA9984BCD97AC2F95D2CC6454"><enum>(5)</enum><text>addressing surge capacity for pediatric mental health and substance use disorder needs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H51713AEAA18248778CA0F390D02420E9"><enum>(6)</enum><text>providing pediatric mental, emotional, and behavioral health services to children as delivered by mental health and substance use disorder professionals utilizing telehealth services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HD5173837F38D4B6AB35CF872C88BC11E"><enum>(7)</enum><text>establishing or maintaining initiatives to allow more children to access care outside of emergency departments, including partial hospitalization, step down residency programs, and intensive outpatient programs;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H5DE684FCF00349C6B6F033BCE039F2AA"><enum>(8)</enum><text>supporting, enhancing, or expanding pediatric mental health and substance use disorder preventive and crisis intervention services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HFDB2AE24368749AABC798E946DF33602"><enum>(9)</enum><text>establishing or maintaining pediatric mental health and substance use disorder urgent care or walk-in clinics;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HCBE3FDEDD2D44C479737EE49B3CE9FC9"><enum>(10)</enum><text>establishing or maintaining community-based pediatric mental health and substance use disorder initiatives, such as partnerships with schools and early childhood education programs; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H475C515CF9F6494FAE690342A29BBE0C"><enum>(11)</enum><text>addressing other access and coordination gaps to pediatric mental health and substance use disorder services in the community for children; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEA9F3B07802A4705AEA2D1AE7F59D47F"><enum>(12)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supporting the collection of data on children and adolescents’ mental health needs, service utilization and availability, and demographic data, to capture community needs and identify gaps and barriers in children's access to care, in a manner that protects personal privacy, consistent with applicable Federal and State privacy laws.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H65A64D157B7F48EBBE8C846EFA8B61F8"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $500,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><section id="HE366F9C182CB4585BAED8996C0F42134"><enum>340A–2.</enum><header>Pediatric behavioral health workforce training program</header><subsection id="H3675165AC0744E1C9E4403EB12C0B3FB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities for the purpose of supporting evidence-based pediatric mental health and substance use disorder workforce training.</text></subsection><subsection id="HFBEAF1FB908D4D0990F52D70930C0A49"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligible entities</header><text>Entities eligible for grants under subsection (a) include—</text><paragraph id="H5EBF0A7264694882A0CEB3FCE6572E1C"><enum>(1)</enum><text>children’s hospitals;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H270E64D317714C3EBBDF4FA46AC3CC49"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">facilities that are eligible to receive funds under section 340E or 340H;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HC1DB109BEF7C4FE6A6D40314FBFB4554"><enum>(3)</enum><text>nonprofit medical facilities that predominantly treat individuals under the age of 21;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE57FCD206762480AB7D9E143536AA4F7"><enum>(4)</enum><text>rural health clinics and Federally qualified health centers (as such terms are defined in section 1861(aa) of the Social Security Act); </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H3F4710EC214D4E679407B01D7AE6E61F"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">entities that employ mental health and substance use disorder professionals, such as child and adolescent psychiatrists, psychologists, developmental and behavioral pediatricians, general pediatricians, advanced practice nurses, social workers, licensed professional counselors, or other licensed professionals that provide mental health or substance use disorder services to patients under 21 years of age; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9611C247C6FC422AB6E7CA76E4210199"><enum>(6)</enum><text>other pediatric health care providers as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HB2202BE4B0A544BEA5A0590A87CA26D8"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Use of funds</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Activities that may be supported through an award under subsection (a) include the following:</text><paragraph id="HD042104822184B1EB2A806F4729BEBA7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>Training to enhance the capabilities of the existing pediatric workforce, including pediatricians, primary care physicians, advanced practice registered nurses, and other pediatric health care providers, including expanded training in pediatric mental health and substance use disorders, and culturally and developmentally appropriate care for children with mental health conditions.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1A103D07668240E5A2BFB3662C49DDB6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>Training to support multi-disciplinary teams to provide pediatric mental health and substance use disorder treatment, including through integrated care models.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H847CA9D583AA44C29D19105C9BB9E804"><enum>(3)</enum><text>Initiatives to accelerate the time to licensure within the pediatric mental health or substance use disorder workforce.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H02E83CAF0246452BBB14EEBA4903B211"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Activities to expand recruitment and retention, increase workforce diversity, or enhance workforce training for critical pediatric mental health professions, including—</text><subparagraph id="H2F4A5C3329204892B17503214D2245A8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>child and adolescent psychiatrists;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0FB3A3BFE37D4136A46E10351E6B5170"><enum>(B)</enum><text>psychiatric nurses;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7DA3D60F539C449493634D84EFD14C41"><enum>(C)</enum><text>psychologists;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE7BEF603C4BB43D0A0CD30F4E7534456"><enum>(D)</enum><text>family therapists;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H61C3FC6A78584FE29CC5D1A79E3F32CF"><enum>(E)</enum><text>social workers;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H628259E3B88D4E99BB89A38BEFDD4644"><enum>(F)</enum><text>mental health counselors;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3E92648BDAE04DF3BA31B277EE063737"><enum>(G)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">developmental and behavioral pediatricians;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H396BD2BCAF2F46AF88042185FE231367"><enum>(H)</enum><text>pediatric substance use disorder specialists; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HBD48FCC7C33A4E529CAD3602C7535239"><enum>(I)</enum><text>other mental health care providers as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H808CDF6978D04399B57CF2B908DF0E0C"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $100,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection></section><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="H128345599E8248BDBC3F63915BF96CB1"><enum>7.</enum><header>Increasing Federal investment in pediatric behavioral health services</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">The Public Health Service Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/201">42 U.S.C. 201 et seq.</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="H68C9434403204A6085975160D1DEE231"><title id="HCBF89FEE42384734BBF048FCDFAF3C0B"><enum>XXXIV</enum><header>Assistance for Construction and Modernization of Children’s Mental Health and Substance Use Disorder Infrastructure</header><section id="HC776BDA330C14BFFA639C0D037248101"><enum>3401.</enum><header>Increasing Federal investment in pediatric behavioral health services</header><subsection id="HE87B7ECE71634F9A8ECA20269CAA1AAB"><enum>(a)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, acting through the Administrator of the Health Resources and Services Administration, shall award grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements to eligible entities for the purpose of improving their ability to provide pediatric behavioral health services, including by—</text><paragraph id="HBEAC4312AB4B4E22A318B68EE4817A90"><enum>(1)</enum><text>constructing or modernizing sites of care for pediatric behavioral health services;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE10354102B7648E28D7C2473F7886D71"><enum>(2)</enum><text>expanding capacity to provide pediatric behavioral health services, including enhancements to digital infrastructure, telehealth capabilities, or other improvements to patient care infrastructure; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7FC4AC4E30AA48758FA460F4E2539D60"><enum>(3)</enum><text>supporting the reallocation of existing resources to accommodate pediatric behavioral health patients, including by converting or adding a sufficient number of beds to establish or increase the hospital’s inventory of licensed and operational, short-term psychiatric and substance use inpatient beds; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6755278F1D3944AD859013754BF662A6"><enum>(4)</enum><text>addressing gaps in the continuum of care for children, by expanding capacity to provide intermediate levels of care, such as intensive outpatient services, partial hospitalization programs, and day programs that can prevent hospitalizations and support children as they transition back to their homes and communities.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H1EFFE34C8A114434B6E18DA71C0FC029"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Eligibility</header><text>To be eligible to seek an award under this section, an entity shall be a hospital or rural health clinic that predominantly treats individuals under the age of 21, including any hospital that receives funds under section 340E.</text></subsection><subsection id="HA7A037C4E83941DC813ABD8E17BC3C2D"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>To carry out this section, there is authorized to be appropriated $2,000,000,000 for each of fiscal years 2023 through 2027.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF15D726E5BB54460B29CC5D729A4E826"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Supplement, not supplant</header><text>Funds provided under this section shall be used to supplement, not supplant Federal and non-Federal funds available for carrying out the activities described in this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDA9AF89FE91646968261AB5935632A38"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Reporting</header><paragraph id="H5B4618FBBBC54C84BC9CF413A999FFBB"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Reports from award recipients</header><text>Not later than 180 days after the completion of activities funded by an award under this section, the entity that received such award shall submit a report to the Secretary on the activities conducted using funds from such award, and other information as the Secretary may require.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H165F4FE2E40B47CFBC882058B022EEEF"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Reports to Congress</header><text>Not later than one year, the Secretary shall submit to the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Health, Education, Labor, and Pensions of the Senate a report on the projects and activities conducted with funds awarded under this section, and the outcome of such projects and activities. Such report shall include—</text><subparagraph id="HDD0B3736054747E1BD764257B13DDE16"><enum>(A)</enum><text>the number of projects supported by awards made under this section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H976D71C16FFF402C9690029FC482BECD"><enum>(B)</enum><text>an overview of the impact, if any, of such projects on pediatric health care infrastructure, including any impact on access to pediatric mental health and substance use disorder services;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H13CBF5C32E5447EF8E66134D301CE0F7"><enum>(C)</enum><text>recommendations for improving the investment program under this section; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H2D46C116D41E42579BE3D55BFF031F97"><enum>(D)</enum><text>any other considerations as the Secretary determines appropriate.</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection></section></title><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

