<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="H39B35D5CF75F45B2BF2ED3A603D0AAD2" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7294 IH: Pregnant Students’ Rights Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-03-30</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7294</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220330">March 30, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="H001091">Mrs. Hinson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HED00">Committee on Education and Labor</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require public institutions of higher education to disseminate information on the rights of, and accommodations and resources for, pregnant students, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HF1F79DE421364F79B13A82B23104842C" style="OLC"><section id="H63A2006385A043078E75C1589CA55294" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Pregnant Students’ Rights Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H3836068F5DCA454E85E9B0CD7C38D131"><enum>2.</enum><header>Findings</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Congress finds the following:</text><paragraph id="H300C9CC9258F4BBFA3932F5F8329314E"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Female students who are enrolled at institutions of higher education and experiencing unplanned pregnancies may face pressure that their only option is to receive an abortion or risk academic failure. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H37774F20A8064C579E29F0D8F840DB39"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">27.6 percent of all abortions in the United States are performed on women of college age, between the ages of 20 and 24, according to a 2019 report by the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HB49C8CF9F09E40AFAAB34FEF20B287F5"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">A significant proportion of abortions in the United States are performed on women of college age who may be unaware of their rights under title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681</external-xref>) or deprived of an alternative to receiving an abortion.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HDFEB1E211C0140FC8BB0F72776D8C5BA"><enum>(4)</enum><text>Additionally, women on college campuses may fear institutional reprisal, loss of athletic scholarship, and possible negative impact on academic opportunities. </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H28A01BE481E84BE2A71224649EEF1133"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">An academic disparity exists because of the lack of resources, support, and notifications available for female college students who do not wish to receive an abortion or who carry their unborn babies to term.</text></paragraph></section><section id="H5219A930A2F84F70B5F50D583A249DA1"><enum>3.</enum><header>Notice of pregnant student rights, accommodations, and resources</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 485 of the Higher Education Act of 1965 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1092">20 U.S.C. 1092</external-xref>) is amended by adding at the end the following: </text><quoted-block style="OLC" id="HBCB507E657CC4BE29A3C77AC213333CF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="HFFBF2A022807405B992A632B326D000C"><enum>(n)</enum><header>Pregnant Students’ Rights, Accommodations, and Resources</header><paragraph id="H33E5F60382924BFBA4EF008C1F250356"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Information dissemination activities; establishment of protocol</header><subparagraph id="H63CB6AABB9A942868AA265DCB1422622"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public institution of higher education participating in any program under this title shall—</text><clause id="HC43F00C79D654DA89540F6F18AB9B087"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">in a manner consistent with title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>), carry out the information dissemination activities described in subparagraph (B) for admitted but not enrolled and enrolled students (including those attending or planning to attend less than full time) on the rights and resources (including protections and accommodations) for pregnant students (or students who may become pregnant) while enrolled at such institution of higher education that—</text><subclause id="HE4BAF447221E4336B3448A1567B73873"><enum>(I)</enum><text>exclude abortion services; </text></subclause><subclause id="H6030F708EB4F418C9EFBA76851B946C5"><enum>(II)</enum><text>may help such a student carry their unborn babies to term; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H38B5D50B5FE24F05BEC6957B8B21FB96"><enum>(III)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">include information on how to file a complaint with the Department if such a student believes there was a violation of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) by the institution on account of such student’s pregnancy; and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H3C40649267154D07A46212D3D95B4ED8"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">establish a protocol to meet with a student described in clause (i)(III), which shall include a meeting with relevant leadership at the institution of higher education, and other relevant parties.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H761CAA6A958B4441BE25F92A6C7F3978"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Description of information dissemination requirements</header><text>The information dissemination activities described in this subparagraph shall include—</text><clause id="H7EB4D73CE22C455AB639C371F17A780A"><enum>(i)</enum><text>annual campus-wide emails; or</text></clause><clause id="H20FA6FE36BE24FAFBAD97F8911291D9B"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>the provision of information in student handbooks, at each orientation for enrolled students, or on the publicly available website of the institution of higher education.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H69E38A9E9A1E48E2A8D7780C2CBE9402"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Annual report to Congress</header><subparagraph id="H731DE151694F497E975F331003E595C3"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Each public institution of higher education participating in any program under this title shall—</text><clause id="H96DE1F4812CC4FE891263DF62111A776"><enum>(i)</enum><text>on an annual basis, compile and submit to the Secretary—</text><subclause id="HE8725357447047E388D83F249EDFC364"><enum>(I)</enum><text> responses to the questions described in subparagraph (B) from students enrolled at such institution of higher education who voluntarily provided such responses; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H72EBD98A9CB94B0D907525C4764027AB"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">a description of any actions taken by the institution of higher education to address each complaint by a student that there was a violation of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) by the institution on account of such student’s pregnancy, including any actions taken in accordance with the protocol established under paragraph (1)(A)(ii); and</text></subclause></clause><clause id="H18E258B4373C4B32B4043BE2AEB5D2A4"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>ensure that any such responses remain confidential and do not reveal any personally identifiable information with respect to a student.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA6331448187C4047ADCCBE2C5DB4C37A"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Questions for enrolled students</header><text>The questions described in this subparagraph shall include—</text><clause id="H6AADC2A7CD694A74AF3156EA7396F66D"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such student experienced an unexpected pregnancy while enrolled at the institution of higher education;</text></clause><clause id="H0BA447E9F85C4A4E9716434BB221DD48"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such student felt there were adequate resources on campus relating to protections, accommodations, and other resources for pregnant students besides abortion-related services;</text></clause><clause id="H7B469607CC0C4AAE8BF9EE41FEF453FE"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such a student believes there was a violation of title IX of the Education Amendments of 1972 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/20/1681">20 U.S.C. 1681 et seq.</external-xref>) by the institution on account of such student’s pregnancy; and</text></clause><clause id="H730DC6B24A6B4949A0F580091219A695"><enum>(iv)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">if such student considered dropping out or withdrawing from classes because of pregnancy, new motherhood, stillbirth, or miscarriage.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H016EC177E08642F7B23A0858DEB6855D"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, on an annual basis—</text><clause id="H4F7A8BC9E99C42A7B0CF04066BC05684"><enum>(i)</enum><text>prepare a report that compiles the responses received under subparagraph (A) from each public institution of higher education participating in any program under this title; and</text></clause><clause id="H29E3A93AE403451BB670C9CE9FA327A7"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>submit such report to the authorizing committees, and the Committees on Appropriations of the House of Representatives and the Senate.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section></legis-body></bill> 

