<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HE1505EC8358F44989F206F17E26BD849" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>91 HR 7623 IH: Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Improvements Act</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-28</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7623</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220428">April 28, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="D000626">Mr. Davidson</sponsor> introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HBA00">Committee on Financial Services</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To increase the effectiveness and accountability of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network of the Department of the Treasury and to protect the freedom and privacy of Americans, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="H6B5E7684A9EC47ED9EC7B554E72EF032" style="OLC"><section id="HCAABE78A2C9141ACB8F4A3C33B6E7364" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Financial Crimes Enforcement Network Improvements Act</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="H14A9040B22F14FB5A2F5F90ADE5D9E8E"><enum>2.</enum><header>Bank Secrecy Act defined</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">In this Act, the term <quote>Bank Secrecy Act</quote> means—</text><paragraph id="H85BFD5EB38E94F1B916A3C2A87661DCD"><enum>(1)</enum><text>section 21 of the Federal Deposit Insurance Act (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1829b">12 U.S.C. 1829b</external-xref>);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7102A643FF1A42248E92EF9A794CDE29"><enum>(2)</enum><text>chapter 2 of title I of <external-xref legal-doc="public-law" parsable-cite="pl/91/508">Public Law 91–508</external-xref> (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/12/1951">12 U.S.C. 1951 et seq.</external-xref>); and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H9BE1CF7010A447DD9969072E055B1EC6"><enum>(3)</enum><text>subchapter II of <external-xref legal-doc="usc-chapter" parsable-cite="usc-chapter/31/53">chapter 53</external-xref> of title 31, United States Code. </text></paragraph></section><section id="H6E42FBB2B1234DFF87A2681D6879AE80"><enum>3.</enum><header>Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</header><subsection id="H6D3C84D103414CE1A68900F0BD5D3E7E"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Appointment of Director</header><text>Section 310(b)(1) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by striking <quote>who shall be appointed by the Secretary of the Treasury</quote> and inserting <quote>who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate</quote>.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9BB1D6A148194060B4786F082FF3E527"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Pay of Director</header><text>Section 310(b)(1) of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following: <quote>The Director shall be compensated at the rate provided under level IV of the Executive Schedule under section 5315 of title 5</quote>.</text></subsection></section><section id="HC019C8CFFDB642058A47C15CFF11BBF8"><enum>4.</enum><header>Inspector general functions</header><subsection id="H9601C1F0BED0448F9C04A13136F1E281"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Establishment of office</header><text>There is established within the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury an Office of Audit and Investigations for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDD595639D02C4A64A5F979E17B88653D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Deputy Inspector General</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall designate a member of the Senior Executive Service to head the Office of Audit and Investigations for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network. Such member shall be known as the Deputy Inspector General for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDE7E3D3F56474F049AD3731A55625A49"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Supervision, authority, and resources</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall supervise the Deputy Inspector General for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network and shall ensure that the Deputy Inspector General has the authority and resources necessary and appropriate to perform inspector general functions with respect to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></subsection><subsection id="H6810B3FE71734AB993C3F0F23898EA93"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall ensure that the Office of Audit and Investigations for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network gives substantial priority in conducting audits and investigations to protection of the civil liberties and privacy of American citizens by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, including in the implementation of the Bank Secrecy Act and subsections (b), (c), and (d) of section 310 of title 31, United States Code, by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network.</text></subsection><subsection id="HD0B0F06D0C2948C0A90C9020B0D344A0"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Annual report</header><text>The Inspector General of the Department of the Treasury shall submit to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate a report on or about October 31 of each calendar year on—</text><paragraph id="HF6FA9F9028714027934E54B1FCED5B32"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the activities of the Office of Audit and Investigations for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network during the preceding fiscal year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H38534F6CFED846A0A7EC8EFF21FA3C7B"><enum>(2)</enum><text>the planned activities of that Office for the current fiscal year;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEED17685CB4D4105B60788190A69247E"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an overview of reports submitted to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, including the number of reports that—</text><subparagraph id="H90710B1938374FDB80BFD087FD115B57"><enum>(A)</enum><text>have been received by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H849B4679F19543B982F127331244FEE9"><enum>(B)</enum><text>have been reviewed by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA08943CA8AE74C158E704BA19300BF53"><enum>(C)</enum><text>have been requested by other governmental agencies;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H39C6FA29A267471686866CB63AA1F0DA"><enum>(D)</enum><text>led to a secondary investigation by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H60B7378640CF4AA98F53AD4FBE4C66F1"><enum>(E)</enum><text>resulted in a conviction, settlement, or additional charges in other ongoing investigations; and</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H5CE9580E83AE46B799E5EA563EC52CCE"><enum>(4)</enum><text>such other information relating to that Office as the Inspector General determines appropriate.</text></paragraph></subsection></section><section id="H1B5909298C9F4284A36DADE3C57C7F43"><enum>5.</enum><header>Civil Liberties Protection Officer for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">Section 301 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end the following:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="H989026FF23404461815A1885FE943BFF" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H406422621A90498AA8CEDAF9C7A20D6B"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Civil Liberties Protection Officer for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network</header><paragraph id="HD784B32B9ECE42F5AF6AB1D3A73A2793"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Within the Office of the Secretary of the Treasury, there shall be a Civil Liberties Protection Officer for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network who shall—</text><subparagraph id="H4265CC74D4F542A38E4820936CC3115E"><enum>(A)</enum><text>be designated by the Secretary of the Treasury from among members of the Senior Executive Service; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H6D9D4B0D0BE74A90AE0D04C60CE10971"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">report directly to and be supervised directly by the Secretary of the Treasury or, if so assigned by the Secretary, the Deputy Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H19802612B1954A3CB8B7020D4C6D2F3F" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Duties</header><text>The Civil Liberties Protection Officer for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall—</text><subparagraph id="H97B8093C28F0461EB0B382157288B68B"><enum>(A)</enum><text>ensure that protection of civil liberties and privacy is appropriately incorporated in the activities conducted by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HC6AFDACDBB514590AC827A42EBA95D03"><enum>(B)</enum><text>oversee compliance by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network with requirements under the Constitution and all laws, regulations, and implementing guidelines relating to civil liberties and privacy;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H21FF903B6EEA4FEF8C8F64D69F2A5E24"><enum>(C)</enum><text>review and assess complaints and other information indicating possible abuses of civil liberties and privacy in the administration of the programs and operations of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network and, as appropriate, refer such complaints or information for investigation to the Office of Audit and Investigations for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H0161229C54FC4A0091E5576CD053D1A1"><enum>(D)</enum><text>ensure that the use by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network of technologies sustains, and does not erode, privacy protections relating to the use, collection, and disclosure of personal information;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H42CFC9FCEBC342E0AF4709042EF52E26"><enum>(E)</enum><text>ensure that personal information contained in a system of records subject to section 552a of title 5 (commonly referred to as the <quote>Privacy Act</quote>) is handled by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network in compliance with that section;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HE2D01C06E48642B9A97D66842D1DA29E"><enum>(F)</enum><text>conduct privacy impact assessments of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network when appropriate, directed, or required by law; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HD1C1698D5CDC4133A5EF896CA5F30C7E"><enum>(G)</enum><text>perform such other duties relating directly to protection of civil liberties and privacy by the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network as may be prescribed by the Secretary of the Treasury.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HEAB08D7DE29A46D5A11E618133391DD2"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Coordination</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Civil Liberties Protection Officer for the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall keep the following individuals appropriately informed of the Officer’s activities:</text><subparagraph id="HB53CB8C6F0C74E88BC8CA0B8B8EF5E5F"><enum>(A)</enum><text>The Department of the Treasury’s Chief Privacy Officer (as described under section 522 of division H of the Consolidated Appropriations Act, 2005 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ee-2">42 U.S.C. 2000ee–2</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3108CCC5D6C64E1C8064D41D79111800"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Department of the Treasury’s Privacy and Civil Liberties Officer (as designated pursuant to section 1062 of the National Security Intelligence Reform Act of 2004 (<external-xref legal-doc="usc" parsable-cite="usc/42/2000ee-1">42 U.S.C. 2000ee–1</external-xref>)).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></section><section id="HF555DD763A134DFF8D8EDE8CC6C516C9"><enum>6.</enum><header>Transparency in rulemaking and secretarial exceptions</header><subsection id="HB759C7C8E5774C3ABCBABAD164D0C01A"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Reservation to the Secretary of authority To make exceptions</header><text>No officer or employee of the Department of the Treasury, except the Secretary of the Treasury or the person performing the duties of the Secretary of the Treasury when that office is vacant or the Secretary is unable to perform the duties of that office, shall, with respect to a proposed or final rule relating to activities of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, including implementation of the Bank Secrecy Act—</text><paragraph id="H275868D2C8624D34BE37EA4D8004C450"><enum>(1)</enum><text>make findings of good cause under subsection (b) or (d) of section 553 of title 5, United States Code;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8645CED5065643C697E25EEC304206F6"><enum>(2)</enum><text>exercise authority to certify, delay, or waive under section 605 or 608 of title 5, United States Code; or</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H45B06BC1487841C78620C32C29A26C46"><enum>(3)</enum><text>make findings of good cause under section 808(2) of title 5, United States Code.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H720FEEF975DF47F58EF06D0CDF5E9A9D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Covered agency status for regulatory flexibility</header><text>Section 310 of title 31, United States Code, is amended by adding at the end thereof the following new subsection:</text><quoted-block style="USC" id="HBEAC099CB525412BBF2B105E34072AD8" display-inline="no-display-inline"><subsection id="H68A21B1EE8B5426C9F4C31AED4E6E469"><enum>(m)</enum><text>The Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall be a <quote>covered agency</quote> for purposes of section 609(d) of title 5.</text></subsection><after-quoted-block>.</after-quoted-block></quoted-block></subsection></section><section id="H8CC1697BD50F4198B77775221AA0684B"><enum>7.</enum><header>Transparency with controlling documents</header><subsection id="HF946A99ACE9B412B8ECCA777325D6A94"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Definition of controlling document</header><text>As used in this section, the term <quote>controlling document</quote> refers to any record (as defined in section 3301 of title 44, United States Code) issued by or under the authority of the Secretary, Deputy Secretary, Under Secretary for Enforcement, or any other officer or employee of the Department of the Treasury, that delegates authority to the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network or its Director, or contains direction binding upon the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network or its Director, in the implementation of section 310 of title 31, United States Code, or the Bank Secrecy Act, including delegations, prescriptions, regulations, protocols, priorities, policies, standards, guidelines, and requirements issued in accordance with subsections (b)(2)(C), (b)(2)(E), (b)(2)(I), (b)(2)(J), (b)(2)(O), (c), and (i)(2)(C)(ii) of section 310 of such title 31 and subsections (b)(1), (b)(2), (b)(4), (c)(2)(A), (c)(2)(C), (c)(3), (c)(5), (d)(3), and (h)(3)(C)(i)(I)(bb) of section 5336 of such title 31.</text></subsection><subsection id="H2914A9D97283404DBF7E3A8C757F926D"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Disclosure to Congress</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall promptly provide to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate—</text><paragraph id="H003DDFD7984D4547B121CF7F40DD2AEA"><enum>(1)</enum><text>controlling documents in force as of the enactment of this Act;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7D372F332E9C42E8804D9413CD29FFAB"><enum>(2)</enum><text>any controlling documents issued thereafter; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA48861965005421991E7251C71E66790"><enum>(3)</enum><text>any changes to controlling documents described in paragraphs (1) and (2) made thereafter, including any revocations thereof.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H6854D52604784FFDB15B8F7876CAA275"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Disclosure to the public</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall make available promptly to the public the controlling documents and changes that the Secretary is required to provide to the committees listed in subsection (b), excluding such reasonably segregable portions of controlling documents or changes as would fall within an exemption in section 552(b) of title 5, United States Code.</text></subsection></section><section id="HA8D016BCA7E7444D9D308D71D7D86767"><enum>8.</enum><header>Information for constitutional functions of Congress</header><subsection id="H101CA7FA56EA47CC943969F1E9AF1EB7"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Keeping Congress informed</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall keep the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate fully and currently informed of the activities of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, including any significant anticipated activity of such Network.</text></subsection><subsection id="H9154B6D80FBD42C88E63E245F119461B"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Report of unlawful activity and corrective action</header><text>The Secretary of the Treasury shall report promptly to the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs any unlawful activity of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network and any corrective action taken or planned to address that activity and prevent such activity in the future.</text></subsection><subsection id="H85D33696709B4C298B712C6D1C8DAD23"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Appearances before Congress</header><paragraph id="H365E7FC04ADF448A835E14C9BCFC590D"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Director of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network shall appear before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives and the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs at semiannual hearings, as specified in paragraph (2), regarding the activities of the Financial Crimes Enforcement Network, including protection of the civil liberties and privacy of, and minimization of burdens on, American citizens.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H66A035E17B294BA48CCFADE26F65BBBE"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Timing of appearances</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Director shall appear—</text><subparagraph id="H5FAC5B31AB184838AC0C1EAC4866EBE8"><enum>(A)</enum><text>before the Committee on Financial Services of the House of Representatives on or about February 20 of even numbered calendar years and on or about July 20 of odd numbered calendar years;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H69EF5E8D5CDB4CAC89D3A09BEFCCA5FC"><enum>(B)</enum><text>before the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs of the Senate on or about July 20 of even numbered calendar years and on or about February 20 of odd numbered calendar years; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H988FEB8C0AA94C9AACB14D542F27E50F"><enum>(C)</enum><text>before either Committee referred to in subparagraph (A) or (B), upon request, following the scheduled appearance of the Director before the other Committee under subparagraph (A) or (B).</text></subparagraph></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H875EDDC42EE04361833731105A0F8C0E"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Requirements in addition</header><text>The requirements of this section are in addition to the requirements of section 5336(c)(11) of title 31, United States Code.</text></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

