<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="billres.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE bill PUBLIC "-//US Congress//DTDs/bill.dtd//EN" "bill.dtd">
<bill bill-stage="Introduced-in-House" dms-id="HDF8787E74D414F8CBF92FA0CDEB1FD55" public-private="public" key="H" bill-type="olc"><metadata xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">
<dublinCore>
<dc:title>117 HR 7434 IH: Federal Carbon Dioxide Removal Leadership Act of 2022</dc:title>
<dc:publisher>U.S. House of Representatives</dc:publisher>
<dc:date>2022-04-07</dc:date>
<dc:format>text/xml</dc:format>
<dc:language>EN</dc:language>
<dc:rights>Pursuant to Title 17 Section 105 of the United States Code, this file is not subject to copyright protection and is in the public domain.</dc:rights>
</dublinCore>
</metadata>
<form>
<distribution-code display="yes">I</distribution-code><congress display="yes">117th CONGRESS</congress><session display="yes">2d Session</session><legis-num display="yes">H. R. 7434</legis-num><current-chamber>IN THE HOUSE OF REPRESENTATIVES</current-chamber><action display="yes"><action-date date="20220407">April 7, 2022</action-date><action-desc><sponsor name-id="T000469">Mr. Tonko</sponsor> (for himself and <cosponsor name-id="P000608">Mr. Peters</cosponsor>) introduced the following bill; which was referred to the <committee-name committee-id="HIF00">Committee on Energy and Commerce</committee-name></action-desc></action><legis-type>A BILL</legis-type><official-title display="yes">To require the Secretary of Energy to remove carbon dioxide directly from ambient air or seawater, and for other purposes.</official-title></form><legis-body id="HD6731F85E22F4F44A7BACB28FBBC8105" style="OLC"><section id="H8EC3231F79AD44B597ACA6BCD117F992" section-type="section-one"><enum>1.</enum><header>Short title</header><text display-inline="no-display-inline">This Act may be cited as the <quote><short-title>Federal Carbon Dioxide Removal Leadership Act of 2022</short-title></quote>.</text></section><section id="HBCFDAF4EDF78466A9038E551CBC71122"><enum>2.</enum><header>Federal requirement to remove carbon dioxide</header><subsection id="HB35E2974E8AE43C0882D79AF2305B443" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(a)</enum><header>Required amounts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall, to the extent economically feasible as provided in subsection (d), remove—</text><paragraph id="H4D873867F52C42C68F6435EF048B13D7"><enum>(1)</enum><text>50,000 net metric tons of carbon dioxide, calculated on a lifecycle basis, for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2025;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HBEAAE4D03DE3436A9E6040C180753FFF"><enum>(2)</enum><text>500,000 net metric tons of carbon dioxide, calculated on a lifecycle basis, for each of fiscal years 2026 through 2028;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H8930E92D6EF040F3AACE81731B71041C"><enum>(3)</enum><text>5,000,000 net metric tons of carbon dioxide, calculated on a lifecycle basis, for each of fiscal years 2029 through 2034; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H23DFC96CBF7149239ED3FA4E69C754C0"><enum>(4)</enum><text>10,000,000 net metric tons of carbon dioxide, calculated on a lifecycle basis, for fiscal year 2035 and each fiscal year thereafter.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6B8D963BC5F4DB9A78E3217669C3537" commented="no"><enum>(b)</enum><header>Timing</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall remove each amount of carbon dioxide required under subsection (a) by not later than 3 years after the beginning of the fiscal year for which such removal is required.</text></subsection><subsection id="HEC7ABD0D3BDE43818E01DF26DA42EE6B" commented="no"><enum>(c)</enum><header>Small removal project set-Aside</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">To the extent practicable, at least 20 percent of the net metric tons of carbon dioxide required to be removed for each of fiscal years 2024 through 2034 under subsection (a) shall be removed by small removal projects.</text></subsection><subsection id="H55D75E005E4043B9BED43A0E9F5EC061"><enum>(d)</enum><header>Economic feasibility</header><paragraph id="HB1EABDC56A1E47C59AA15825ECFB7DCF"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The removal of carbon dioxide under this section shall be considered economically feasible if such removal can be accomplished or, in the case of a contract, purchased—</text><subparagraph id="HE97AEAF292A545CB9A5982710FB89775"><enum>(A)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to such removal carried out for any of fiscal years 2024 through 2025, at a price per metric ton of carbon dioxide of not more than $550;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H7FED96FC51D94050B837FACBFC4B6390"><enum>(B)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to such removal carried out for any of fiscal years 2026 through 2028, at a price per metric ton of carbon dioxide of not more than $400;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HAB9FE65934524FA9BC87D6ADB2F0DAA4"><enum>(C)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to such removal carried out for any of fiscal years 2029 through 2031, at a price per metric ton of carbon dioxide of not more than $300;</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HFC12E44FA5AD48B982DAF30FB2603EDE"><enum>(D)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to such removal carried out for any of fiscal years 2032 through 2034, at a price per metric ton of carbon dioxide of not more than $200; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HA03E4F799C3C407AA907A8B71CD1C855"><enum>(E)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">with respect to such removal carried out for fiscal year 2035 and each fiscal year thereafter, at a price per metric ton of carbon dioxide of not more than $150.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H6DCA490B68E045269E105A7AF3B630D5" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Inclusion of monitoring, reporting, and verification costs</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">In determining whether the removal of carbon dioxide is considered economically feasible under paragraph (1), the price for such removal shall include any costs associated with the monitoring, reporting, and verification required under subsection (f)(1).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H21DFB9EA84DA44DBB911103B2B757D61"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Multi-year contracts</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Notwithstanding paragraph (1), the removal of carbon dioxide carried out pursuant to a multi-year contract entered into under subsection (h) shall be considered economically feasible if such removal can be accomplished at the applicable dollar amount for the first fiscal year of the contract, as provided in paragraph (1), through the entire length of such contract.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD6A719EA0DFA43F0B33982E2617A7F5B" commented="no"><enum>(e)</enum><header>Federal assistance</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Funds received pursuant to a contract entered into under subsection (h) shall not be considered Federal assistance or otherwise affect eligibility for any Federal assistance, including tax incentives.</text></subsection><subsection id="HF96EB44EE7C74486AE353EAD11F648CA" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(f)</enum><header>Monitoring, reporting, and verification</header><paragraph id="HBB721B9D1D38480AB20B5E7F395DF6AE"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary, or an entity the Secretary enters into a contract with under subsection (h), shall monitor, report, and verify the net metric tons of carbon dioxide the Secretary or such entity, as applicable, removed for purposes of this section.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4BEA665AC21F4B7CB0E7216DB316797F" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Best practices</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The Secretary shall ensure that any project for the removal of carbon dioxide for which a contract is entered into under subsection (h) shall follow the best available practices, as determined by the Secretary, for monitoring, reporting, and verifying the net metric tons of carbon dioxide removed under the project, including best practices—</text><subparagraph id="H9167F335EB3A4DE6B62D88CAF2466A69" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><text>used by similar carbon dioxide removal projects; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H05C7003947CE41A680126E8783182E69" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><text>necessary to ensure safe, effective, and efficient removal of carbon dioxide.</text></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H66ED863EFB9A4202BD518A94519614FE" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Prohibition on double counting</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Carbon dioxide that is removed for the purposes of compliance with any other greenhouse gas emissions management program, including any foreign, Federal, State, local, or private greenhouse gas emissions management program, as determined by the Secretary, may not be considered removed under subsection (a) for purposes of meeting the requirements of such subsection.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HD909870A4269404F882AADFC65D4012B"><enum>(g)</enum><header>Priorities</header><text>In carrying out this section, the Secretary shall give priority to any project for the removal of carbon dioxide that—</text><paragraph id="H06E65FDEFCA24F9BAB509B03A976BBC6"><enum>(1)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">minimizes the amount of greenhouse gas emissions released by carrying out such project;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF3C1121640E4645903A17336D2EEB44"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">supports the commercialization of innovative removal technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HF43E8938CBBE4CE481155C890E7A2752"><enum>(3)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">increases the diversity of commercially available eligible technologies;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H000B1FAA7C73453A94C41316F733776F"><enum>(4)</enum><text>provides the greatest potential for domestic job creation; </text></paragraph><paragraph id="H70C3F99C78784DDCA559D7203D5E980D"><enum>(5)</enum><text>results in economic development or economic diversification in regions or localities that have historically generated significant economic activity from the production, processing, transportation, or combustion of fossil fuels, including through the use of coal mines, fossil fuel-fired electricity generating units, and petroleum refining facilities;</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H7DCEC1F3B8924F56A08F012CCFFB1442" commented="no"><enum>(6)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">quantifies and mitigates the effect of removing carbon dioxide on environmental justice, the environment, and public health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HA6AAF047D19E4E06866F02736D1CE0EA" commented="no"><enum>(7)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">includes robust public engagement and community benefits.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="HC93751DC47B9445D829DDC26D92926BB"><enum>(h)</enum><header>Contracts</header><paragraph id="H424D5D73075A4ED488C3B1A3BC929A1C" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The Secretary may enter into contracts to meet the requirements of subsection (a).</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HE1BFF87A2984415A97FECB797D34BF3A"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Length</header><text>A contract entered into under this subsection may not be for a term of more than 15 years.</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H83EB4892FC19446F87785143AC385F9F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><header>Report</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">Not later than January 1, 2027, and every 2 years thereafter, the Secretary shall submit to Congress, and release to the public, a report on the progress of carrying out the requirements of this section, which such report shall include—</text><paragraph id="HECF235D31CB0463FBF83B02543EE1FD1" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><text>the amounts verified under subsection (f)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H6A457DAF22014EC18F950DA5754E22CB" commented="no"><enum>(2)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">the total price, and price per metric ton, to remove carbon dioxide for the applicable fiscal year as required under subsection (a);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H1AC0441E489648A482CE7C232DC598B8" commented="no"><enum>(3)</enum><text>the methods associated with the monitoring, reporting, and verification required under subsection (f)(1);</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H2344B9DAD70A493E82A23DF5D7923A98" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">an estimate of how removing carbon dioxide under this section affects environmental justice, the environment, and public health; and</text></paragraph><paragraph id="HEF83A5D6EA6F4D46B3D670706EE40695" commented="no"><enum>(5)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">information on potential labor impacts and job creation resulting from fulfilling the requirements of subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection><subsection id="H72CA30F03B8E4B308B3E88B9004F33C1"><enum>(j)</enum><header>Authorization of appropriations</header><text>There are authorized to be appropriated such sums as are necessary to carry out this section.</text></subsection><subsection id="HDEC1166929C84FC09FBDC594C40243F6"><enum>(k)</enum><header>Definitions</header><text>In this section:</text><paragraph id="H157D26C186064E1CA289E243942E79CD" commented="no"><enum>(1)</enum><header>Eligible technology</header><subparagraph id="HF7F3A34849A04456926542B39A75B40A" commented="no"><enum>(A)</enum><header>In general</header><text>The term <term>eligible technology</term> means any equipment, technique, or technology, placed into service after January 1, 2022, that removes carbon dioxide directly from ambient air or seawater, as determined appropriate by the Secretary.</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H9F7D959FE81E42B0B371F116F51E0884" commented="no"><enum>(B)</enum><header>Exclusion</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>eligible technology</term> does not include any equipment, technique, or technology that—</text><clause id="HD21430BD1534454283DA6F1812D2EA5F" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">removes carbon dioxide which is deliberately released from naturally occurring subsurface springs;</text></clause><clause id="HDCAD0FBA3A1342908180A4210A8BA668" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">removes carbon dioxide using natural photosynthesis; or </text></clause><clause id="HD04BDA53AF014E6093273B75AC52D89B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">is related to the extraction, refinement, delivery, or use of fossil fuels, including enhanced oil recovery.</text></clause></subparagraph><subparagraph id="HF68123975E164F87B8855E11CFF2BECE" commented="no"><enum>(C)</enum><header>Expansion of eligible technology</header><text>Notwithstanding subparagraph (B)(ii), any equipment, technique, or technology that removes carbon dioxide using gasification or pyrolysis of solid, nonhazardous, and cellulosic waste materials may be considered an eligible technology under this section if the Secretary, by rule—</text><clause id="HE872CF597CBB486085F1E64E4FC1377D" display-inline="no-display-inline" commented="no"><enum>(i)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines an entity that carries out a removal project under this section is able to adequately monitor, report, and verify the amount of greenhouse gas emissions, calculated on a lifecycle basis (including direct emissions and significant indirect emissions), associated with such equipment, technique, or technology;</text></clause><clause id="HEF5A9AE88D3F4FF9B6784233E0914488" commented="no"><enum>(ii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">determines an entity that carries out a removal project under this section is able to adequately mitigate the environmental impacts (including impacts on biodiversity, land use, and air and water quality) associated with such equipment, technique, or technology; and</text></clause><clause id="H94B544F496A34AFB9743EA09610BF88B" commented="no"><enum>(iii)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">requires an entity carrying out a removal project under this section to—</text><subclause id="HDD2E92C53C594B048FE0DBA98135CBA2" commented="no"><enum>(I)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequately monitor, report, and verify the amount of greenhouse gas emissions, calculated on a lifecycle basis (including direct emissions and significant indirect emissions), associated with such equipment, technique, or technology; and</text></subclause><subclause id="H8051CA2E200A4EB3B25D7775DEE9A7F3" commented="no"><enum>(II)</enum><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">adequately mitigate the environmental impacts (including impacts on biodiversity, land use, and air and water quality) associated with such equipment, technique, or technology.</text></subclause></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="HD6D64899BE0546BEAA2CC11F8471CBB2"><enum>(2)</enum><header>Remove</header><text>The term <term>remove</term> means to—</text><subparagraph id="H09C476D35E1744BABC47F89AC1BFD8F6" display-inline="no-display-inline"><enum>(A)</enum><text>capture carbon dioxide using eligible technology; and</text></subparagraph><subparagraph id="H3D9D5909D5054755A00A3F8A7632BC8B"><enum>(B)</enum><text>permanently store such captured carbon dioxide—</text><clause id="H405ED8703196447DACCB1B843B056B20"><enum>(i)</enum><text>in a subsurface geologic formation or in materials, including building materials and mineralized carbon materials; or</text></clause><clause id="H6E0272B761C24D95852EB30D76FA5C6F"><enum>(ii)</enum><text>using other permanent storage methods, as determined by the Secretary.</text></clause></subparagraph></paragraph><paragraph id="H786EFD64609345768E6FD44E902AA441"><enum>(3)</enum><header>Secretary</header><text>The term <term>Secretary</term> means the Secretary of Energy.</text></paragraph><paragraph id="H4CB24B695AC34127A629645D82DF0263" commented="no"><enum>(4)</enum><header>Small removal project</header><text display-inline="yes-display-inline">The term <term>small removal project</term> means a project for the removal of carbon dioxide that does not remove more than 5 percent of the net metric tons of carbon dioxide required to be removed for the applicable fiscal year under subsection (a).</text></paragraph></subsection></section></legis-body></bill> 

